"Dear Mr. Conan Edogawa"
An eerie atmosphere, the mysterious twosome.
An enveloping attack that closes in on Conan and Haibara.
They seek not to protect their own lives if for the sake of others.
A breathtaking 2 hours and a half is about to begin.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"The Confrontation with the Black Organization"
"The Coincidence of the Two Enemies on a Night with a Full Moon"
An Off-season Halloween party?
Just what month do they think it is?
Isn't Halloween on October 31st?
That's why it's written "off-season", isn't it?
What's written on the invitation card?
On the letter it says,
"Incapable Detective, Kogoro Mouri."
"On the night the full moon cometh,"
"I shall invite thee to this hideous night banquet."
"To the blood smeared party on the ship."
"Be it known that whether thou attend or not,"
"the pitiful lamb that goes passing shall curse its own fate,"
"and the sinner shall be ecstatic over the agonies of death."
So this is a letter challenging
the Famous Detective Kogoro Mouri!
Who on earth would've sent this invitation card to me?
Maybe a foreigner,
because the name of the sender is in english.
V. E. R. M. O. U. T. H.
Vermouth?
I'm sorry, Ran.
But I've never heard that name before.
I see.
I wonder who sent us this invitation card?
Besides...
Isn't Kogoro going to the evening party?
It's tomorrow, isn't it?
Yes.
He says that brave Tokyo people should take on challenges.
Father's making preparations for it
and having Sonoko put on all kinds of makeup on him,
although he's still undecided which makeup he wants to go with.
-Makeup? -Yes.
It says on the invitation card that
since it's a Halloween party,
all participants must disguise themselves as monsters
and come dressed in formal black suits and dresses.
Of course anyone who comes as a companion must do likewise.
What? Companion?
You mean, you're going with him too?
Of course I'm not going to such a monster-filled party!
I guessed so.
And...
I have a favor to ask you, Dr. Agasa.
What is it?
If this invitation came to dad,
it could be that...
he got one too?
Oh, yeah. You mean Shinichi too?
Yes. So could you check the mailbox?
Unless you tell him about mail like these,
I'm sure he'll complain later.
Oh, okay.
If it's here, I'll call you back.
Well, I don't think he got one, though.
Oh, and please keep this a secret from Conan.
Because every time he goes to places like these,
he tends to stick his nose into dangerous things.
Besides...
Besides, what?
Oh, nothing.
And tell him that school will start soon
so to make sure to comes home
and that he shouldn't go here and there till then.
Yeah, okay.
I'll give him your message.
Bye.
Yeah.
How about this?
This is a masterpiece produced by Sonoko Suzuki!
I have this feeling that
I don't look much different from how I usually look.
What're you talking about?
You don't want it to look too drastic, do you?
If I cover you with heavy makeup and goofed,
there'd be no way out!
Well, that's true, but...
Isn't it fantastic?
You look really good, dad!
That amount of makeup is just enough
to bring out the good looks in you, Dad!
Do you think so?
What about you?
What kind of makeup did you decide to go as, Sonoko?
About that... Of course!
I'm going to go in a super cute mini skirt
and knock the monsters out!
Knock the monsters out, my gosh.
Who knows? Maybe there'll be super good-looking monsters?
No way, no chance.
So what?
I'll bet you're after some super whopper body vampire
or something too. Won't you, Pops?
And?
Are you planning to board the phantom ship too?
Yeah.
The sender's name kind of bothers me so...
Do you have an idea of who the sender is or something?
No.
Shouldn't you're the one who has an idea, Haibara?
Because Vermouth, like Gin and Vodka,
are names of liquor.
Beats me.
Never heard of it.
Besides, I don't know much about liquor.
It's liquor from Italy.
Vermouth is the English spelling.
In Japan it's called...
"Bermutto".
Just as I thought.
It's written on your face that the name sounds familiar.
I guess it's the code name of one of The Black Organization members.
Then you mean that invitation card is from?
Yeah.
An invitation from Vermouth who is one of them.
I don't know if they're ready to take us on
or if they just got tired of waiting
but I can't pass up this opportunity.
Don't go.
Don't go! Stop, I tell you!
It's a trap and if you go you'll be killed...
Yeah. It could be...
Then...
Then, why?
Hey, Shinichi.
You didn't have to do that.
Sorry, Haibara.
With things as they are,
I'm stuck and can't move on.
But,
I wonder if it's okay for you to leave Ai here like this
and leave just like that.
Look at the address, Dr. Agasa.
On the envelope that was delivered to my house,
and the invitation card in it,
both were addressed to the name Shinichi Kudo.
But the name on the letter that came with it is addressed to...
Dear Mr. Conan Edogawa?
Hey, Shinichi! This...
Yeah. Everything's out in the open.
My true identity,
the fact that my body shrunk because of Apoptoxin 4869,
as well as the fact that I'm Shinichi Kudo.
And they most probably
know that Haibara is the Sherry,
who used to be one of them.
But, isn't it strange?
If they have that much information already,
why aren't they here raiding us?
Beats me.
I don't know the reason
but I have a hunch
about one of the causes.
Hey. Don't tell me that you caught Ai's cold.
I'm fine.
What is that?
The telephone?
Mail?
Okay.
The only problem left is...
A Halloween Party?
Yeah.
It's going to start tomorrow night at 19:00.
But, Gin,
why do I have to go to a crazy place like that?
Vermouth is in this.
We've got orders to go check out the internal affairs.
I was just about getting fed up
with that lady's secretiveness too.
I didn't get the go-sign, but who cares.
If she acts up,
I'll show no mercy.
Even if she's that person's favourite...
Strange.
It's strange after all.
Compared to when I came here to check the mailbox,
the water meter as well as the gas meter has moved,
although it's really slight.
Who is inside
this house?
I guess this is the best place to watch me and Haibara.
I know I can handle two men,
but what if there are more than three?
Cool head.
Judging from the meter,
the most that would be in here is one or two of them.
Besides...
What a full moon.
Really, it's so appropriate for "A Blood-smeared Party on Board"!
All right.
I'm getting excited!
I'm feeling a positive turbulent rush of blood.
Hey, Pops.
Isn't the werewolf the one who feels a positive
turbulent rush of blood when the full moon is out?
You're Dracula, you know, Pops.
Shut up.
I mean I'm getting a positive turbulent rush of blood as a detective!
Excuse me?
Are you two also going to be attending
the Off-season Halloween Party too?
Right.
I thought it was ridiculous
because it's a costume party, but...
Well, the thing is...
I'm going there too!
I wonder if it's going to be okay
leaving Ai like that by herself.
Yeah.
I left the room warm.
I also left food and water behind with her too,
so I don't think there'll be any problems.
I can't wait to play
that new game you were saying you created.
Do you want to try it?
The position of the things in the drawer
is also slightly out of place.
You looked for it
all by yourself
in order to confront them.
Look at them!
Werewolf.
Frankenstein.
Mummy.
Even Jiangshi is here!
It's full of monsters!
Really! How exciting!
Are you sure it's okay
for the daughter of the Suzuki Financial Group
to be mixed up among guys like this?
It's fine...
Unlike Ran, I kind of like stuff like this!
By the way, Sonoko?
Just what are you disguised as?
How rude!
I'm a witch!
Don't you see that I've got a broom?
What's with him?
Hey, Pops?
Maybe he's saying move over
because the front seats are open?
Darn it.
Then why don't you say so in a way I understand.
He's just really trying to be the character
that he's disguised as.
My... What a beautiful witch you are.
Thank you.
But, I'm...
not a witch.
Medusa?
I'll turn you into stone.
Will the next person show us your invitation card!
Sure...
You're the famous Detective Kogoro Mouri, aren't you?
So, you saw through my disguise?
Oh, no.
Your name's written on the invitation card, see?
Then, please fill in your name.
Yeah.
Kogoro. Mouri.
By the way...
I hope you're not planning to really commit a murder here, are you?
Well, together with this invitation card,
there was a letter hinting that a crime may be committed here!
It's true that this invitation card is what we made,
but I know nothing of this letter or the envelope.
Really?
There will be a "guess who the criminal is" game
played during the party though.
Could it be
the producer decided to do a little extra
to make sure he'll come here.
Producer?
Oh, no, it's nothing.
But, we're sure that you'll enjoy the cursed banquet.
Come on, Pops!
Let's hurry and go!
Oh, Hey, you!
Next guest please!
Your invitation card, please.
Aren't you by chance
the high school detective?
"Shinichi Kudo"
Thank you.
But, they sure got a lot of them gathered here.
You can say that again.
What?
It's finally going to start.
Yeah.
You devilish diabolic monsters
who wander through the nether world,
welcome to our haunted ship named Phantom.
I am Captain Gold and I will be navigating this phantom ship.
There's only an hour more to go before the party.
Please pick your comrades who will be sharing fate with you.
Seven comrades who have received the same seal as yourself.
The same seal?
The tarot card!
You got one when you came on board too, didn't you?
I think we're going to team up with people who got the same card
and play a game or something.
You mean this XV that's written here,
the card of the goat.
Which means we're on the goat team?
That's not a goat.
In Roman Numerals XV is the figure 15.
The name of the card is The Devil.
The card of the devil.
Oh, is that right?
Besides, we weren't divided in groups
just to play a game.
This party is also an audition for a role in a movie too.
An audition?
You know, don't you?
The movie that's played every summer called
"The Diary of Captain Ghost's Voyage".
Yeah.
The one about a load of monsters riding a phantom ship
and coming to get people who performed evil deeds.
Which means if things work out,
I may appear in the movie too?
Yes.
This seems to be the fourth time this party's been held,
and each year the movie staff
seem to be mixed among everyone here
to judge carefully for the cast.
I see.
Everyone wants to play the part of popular monster roles,
so they divide people into teams to make choosing easier.
That's why everyone's
trying to put out their best, right?
The Werewolf who roars towards the moon.
The Frankenstein that moves like a robot
and does pantomime.
The Mummy who keeps his silence no matter who talks to him.
Well, although they're going to appear in the movie,
they're no more than supporting actors
who will appear behind the main stars.
Since it'll cost an enormous amount of money
if the film company has to cover makeup fees
and everything for all the supporting actors,
so they let horror fans appear in their best outfits
and put on their best act.
Besides, holding an event on the this ship that was used in the movie
will serve as an advertisement for the movie too.
All right, all of you!
The time to set sail has come!
We shall cross the seven cursed seas
and show the conceited humans our power
as well as teach them a lesson!
Don't tell me this ship is...
really going to move?
Is there anyone who has the card of Death?
Hermit!
Anybody around who has the card of the Hermit?
What? Shinichi Kudo?
You mean that high school detective is on this ship?
Right...
But I heard that he was involved in some kind of incident
and was killed.
No way! That's nothing but lies!
And? What kind of disguise was he in?
He was bandaged up,
so maybe a mummy?
A mummy detective.
That would be so handsome!
Okay!
All seven of us are here!
They're the people we saw just a while ago.
Now our names...
This is Medusa.
Werewolf, Frankenstein and Mummy.
And can we call you Mummy 2?
What? Do you want to shake hands?
I see.
You're Invisible Man.
So...
I wonder what the seven of us are going to do?
They did say that this was a catch the culprit sort of game.
How do you like the game I made this time?
It's pretty cool, don't you think?
Yeah. It's a masterpiece!
Right!
-I'm sure this'll satisfy them. -Yes, Agasa residence.
-I'll call them first thing tomorrow. -I'm sorry for calling this late.
This is Dr. Araide.
-Is Dr. Agasa there? -I'll have them monitor it!
He's not in.
I think he went out somewhere with Edogawa.
What? But I hear their voices.
This?
It's their recorded voices.
I don't know what prank they're up to.
But it's been playing for some time now.
So, what's up?
Oh, yeah.
Actually, I wanted to talk to you.
Well, your cold's taking a while to get better, right?
So I figured you should be checked at a hospital with good facilities,
and asked a friend doctor of mine,
but was told that he has to go on a business trip,
so he's only available tonight.
That is why...
I know this is really sudden
but can I go pick you up now?
I'll notify Dr. Agasa later for you.
Well, I don't want to force you though.
It doesn't bother me.
I was kind of angry anyway because they're doing their own thing.
Besides, it's boring staying home alone.
Great.
Then, okay.
I'll be there in about an hour
so will you get ready to leave as soon as I get there?
Okay.
I'll see you in an hour then.
All right! All seven of us have finally gathered!
What dense guys.
Pops?
Werewolf, Frankenstein and Mummy are nowhere in sight.
What?
I wonder if they went to the toilet.
I guess so?
If that is the case, let's go see.
The party is about to begin too.
Yeah.
It's over here.
Oh, there he is!
I tell you, Frankenstein!
We looked all over for you!
What a toilet this is, though.
It's dimly lit and full of spider webs,
even the mirror is cracked.
Not only that, men and women have to use the toilet together!
After all, we're all monsters,
so I guess there's no need to differentiate between men and women.
It won't come off.
The blood on my hands won't come off.
It won't come off even if I wash my hands.
Hey, acting your part even in the toilet too?
Excuse me.
Are Werewolf and Mummy here?
They don't seem to be here.
Yeah.
What was that?
Hey, boss! What's up?
Bartender.
Can you give me the same thing he's drinking?
Silver Bullet?
White Lady for me then, please.
Yes, ma'am.
Hey, you don't look too hot.
Are you bummed out or something?
Hey.
What is it?
Is he looking for somebody?
I wonder where Mummy disappeared to?
How should I know? Geez...
Of all things! Talk about not being able to work in groups.
An hour has already gone by.
-What? -What's...
The party has started.
Listen, you monsters.
I've got good news for all of you.
The bait's been set.
It seems that there is a human
among us at this party
that is neither ugly nor possesses evil power.
Go now and join hands with the seven comrades
that you will share your fate with.
Find the good-for-nothing, tear its meat apart,
pull out its guts
and drink up to the last drop the blood
that comes flowing out!
Okay!
If it's looking for the culprit, there's none other than I,
Kogoro Mouri, more suited for the job!
But, not all seven of us are here yet.
Who cares!
If I figure out who the culprit is,
I'm sure they'll come walking out from their side!
I have the keyword which is the hint to who it is.
If you want to get hold of the treasure
that is to be your reward,
come out to deck and receive my revelation...
What's that?
What's the matter?
I'm sorry, the load that was on the construction truck fell off.
We'll clear it up right away,
so please give us a moment.
I'm in a bit of a rush,
so I'm going to go around.
I'm sorry.
Thank you for waiting.
You may go through now.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Take care!
He just went through.
What's that?
That's...
Captain of the phantom ship?
What a grand performance.
This is real blood.
What?
Hurry!
Hurry, somebody get him down!
Yes...
Hi.
Oh, I'm sorry to have surprised you.
I'm an English teacher of Teitan High School,
where Dr. Araide is in charge of.
His car broke down on his way here.
That's why I've come to pick you up instead!
If it's okay with you, will you please unchain the door?
I'm really late.
Jodie.
His chest is pierced through with an arrow of a bow gun.
Moreover,
the card of the devil is here too.
So, the devil's the guide to the world beyond?
I don't think he needed any guide to take him
to the world beyond though,
because he seemed to have died on the spot.
True.
And as for the bow gun that fired the arrow,
it's probably been disposed of somewhere in this vast Pacific Ocean
so virtually will not be found.
So, I wonder if there's a camera on this ship?
I'd like to take a picture of the scene.
We have a digital camera
that we are using to take pictures of this party.
Well, it's something that will serve as evidence
so I'd prefer something on film, but...
Pops,
I've got a disposable camera on me.
See.
Well, I guess it's better than nothing.
I'll take a look at his face then.
I think I've seen him somewhere before.
Isn't he a movie producer that appears a lot on TV?
I think his name was Senzo Fukuura.
I think he became famous
after producing the Unlucky Days series,
before the Phantom Ship Captain series.
Are you saying that the producer appeared in the movie in person
and acted the role of the captain of Phantom Ship?
No, the movie was filmed using a real actor.
Mr. Fukuura loved the captain of the Phantom Ship,
so he used to play the role of his own initiative every year
at the party on board.
Mr. Fukuura is the one who planned the performance of
appearing on the mast with the light shining on him
and giving out hints to the quiz.
Yeah.
You mean that quiz about humans being mixed up here among the monsters.
There's a microphone attached to the inside of the mask.
It seems he was talking directly into this microphone.
And?
What's the answer to this quiz?
Well, the quizzes and hints
were decide on by Mr. Fukuura alone,
so we, the staff know nothing about them.
We heard that the first group to solve the quiz
would receive an invitation to the preview of the movie, though.
Well,
it seems quite definite that one of you among the staff is the killer.
First of all,
Mr. Fukuura who was disguised as the captain of the phantom ship
started suffering while he was announcing the quiz.
He was probably struck by the bow gun then.
However, back then,
we, the passengers,
were still inside the ship at the party hall.
It would've been impossible for us
to fire the bow gun at Mr. Fukuura
who was on the top of the mast.
So high chances the person who killed him
is the one who prepared the lighting
and audio devices when he announce the quiz,
which is one of the staff.
Secondly, this card of the devil.
The killer probably wanted to mislead people into thinking
that one of the passengers who boarded this ship
that received this card is the killer.
Since you're the ones who prepared the cards,
you probably could make as many of these cards as you wanted to.
No.
These cards were made by Mr. Fukuura to avoid foul play.
So, it would have been impossible for any of the staff
to prepare these cards.
Last year he used playing cards.
Besides there was a passenger who was on deck
before the quiz was announced too.
Saying that he wanted to look at the ocean.
I don't remember who exactly that person was
since it was dark though.
Oh, is that right?
I see.
Which means the possibility of the killer being among us
who has received the card of the devil is high!
Are you okay?
The doctor that we're going to see is very efficient!
So, your cold will be cured right away
and you'll feel better in no time at all.
By the way,
when is this ship returning to the harbor?
I think it'll be another hour or so.
I see.
Then, shall we go inside the ship
and investigate the case?
Mr. Sleeping Vampire?
Oh, okay.
What's up, Pops?
It seems we're going to be late
so I thought I'd let Ran know.
She's not answering.
Maybe she's taking a bath?
"Mouri Detective Agency"
Okay, then.
Please show me the card of the devil that you all have.
What?
What's the matter, Mummy?
I wonder if I dropped it somewhere?
You deliberately poked your card with the arrow
and tried to free yourself from being a suspect, right?
You played on the psychology that
nobody would think that the killer himself
would leave his devil card behind with the victim,
unaware that this card
was a one of a kind in this world,
that Mr. Fukuura had exclusively made!
I was fully aware of that too!
How'd you know?
Because...
I was asked by Mr. Fukuura
to sit among the passengers
and choose someone with great makeup on.
After all, I'm also a staff member of the movie!
What?
You're a movie staff member?
So I would never dream of hurting Mr. Fukuura.
Are you the only movie staff
that is mixed up among the passengers here?
No.
Almost all the other mummies besides me are staff members.
When we find passengers with great makeup,
we contacted Mr. Fukuura by e-mail.
Mr. Fukuura was also the one that gave us this outfit, right?
Yeah.
We received all kinds of instructions from Mr. Fukuura
while he was helping us with the makeup.
Instructions? What kind of instructions?
Like, drink a certain kind of wine, et cetera.
I was told to eat only chicken dishes.
I was told to wear this red wig.
All his instructions were varied depending on the person
and the only common instruction he gave us was not to talk.
What kind of instruction is that supposed to be?
How should I know?
It's Mr. Fukuura's instructions!
But...
when we were waiting for the quiz,
you disappeared from before us, didn't you?
I went to the toilet!
These two were with me too!
Right?
It's true.
That you were with us when we went to the toilet.
See!
But...
I didn't see you come out of the toilet.
What? What are you talking about?
I passed right behind you when I left!
Why're you saying something like that?
I guess you didn't notice me
because somebody cracked the mirror.
What? You mean that mirror
wasn't cracked to begin with in order to give a creepy atmosphere?
Yes.
It wasn't cracked until we departed!
Are you sure?
Yes!
We, the staff, decorated this ship together.
But we weren't given instructions
to crack the mirror in the toilet.
Then, just before Mr. Fukuura was about to give out the quiz,
where were you?
I was here!
Near Werewolf! Right?
You saw me, didn't you?
I wonder. I don't remember.
Oh, no.
I was desperate trying to sell myself
because I wanted a part in the movie!
Like this!
Come to think of it,
you were roaring several times.
It seems that nobody's seen you around.
Which means you don't have an established alibi.
Oh, no.
It... It's a trap!
Somebody's conspired to frame me!
A killer who's cornered barks a lot.
Moreover, you don't have an alibi and the devil card.
Mummy, you're the only one...
You're the only one that could've committed the murder!
Detective Mouri, you're a little off there.
What?
The truth is still in the dark.
The voice is coming from the speaker the phantom ship captain was using!
Darn it!
The deck!
Out of my way!
Who is it?
Where are you?
You've already acquired everything you need
to solve the case and yet...
How disappointing.
Why you!
Who are you?
You better shut up or you're going to pay for this!
Have you forgotten me already?
It's me, Detective Mouri.
Invisible man!
Captain of this phantom ship, Captain Gold, that is,
the host of this party
and movie producer, Mr. Senzo Fukuura,
was killed by who?
And...
how was he killed?
Shall we...
begin solving the case then?
That voice.
That tone of voice.
It can't be...
Under the moonlight...
that shines light upon the dark night.
You're...
The detective kid.
Shinichi Kudo?
What? No way!
What brings you here?
-Shinichi Kudo? -Shinichi Kudo?
Kudo? You mean that famous high school detective?
What?
So, he wasn't dead.
It can't be...
No way.
I got rid of that kid some time ago.
See. You have nothing to complain about now, do you?
Hurry and give me the film.
Gin.
Gin killed him with a poison drug.
What is going on?
Hey.
Will you grant me
just one favor?
Detective kid, long time no see!
Sorry for saying this after you've made your grand appearance
but this case has already been solved!
The one who shot Mr. Fukuura
from the top of the mast that you're standing right now
when he was just about to give out the hint to the quiz,
is the one who sneaked out of the cabin, the party hall,
and came out to this dark deck
as well as the one who was able to place the card of the devil
on the arrow of the bow gun that was fired...
can be none other than
the one who has no alibi at that time
on top of not having the card of the devil on him,
Mummy, who's right here with me!
Where in my deduction am I off track?
Hey! Come on, say something!
Oh, excuse me.
I got a bit of a cold and my throat's...
A cold?
So...
You mentioned his alibi and his card, is that right?
The killer probably
pick-pocketed Mummy's card
in order to frame him as the killer.
The killer pick-pocketed?
If you insist that Mummy's not the killer
the only probable deduction is either he dropped it,
or somebody stole it from him!
After all, the card is specially made
so that there's only one card for each person!
Yes.
Whether the killer knew was aware of this or not,
he stole it from Mummy,
inside the toilet!
In the toilet?
Hey, is that right, Mummy?
Beats me.
He, himself says he doesn't know,
so that's out!
Well, it's not surprising that he doesn't remember.
The killer probably
went into the toilet compartment next to the one Mummy went inside
and injected an anesthetic or something with a syringe
from the space of the partition of the toilet.
After Mummy sucked the vapor in and passed out,
the killer probably snuck in from the top part of the partition
and pulled the card out,
taking it from Mummy.
Hey!
Where do you have such evidence!
I have no such evidence.
I just mentioned
the easiest way possible to carry out the murder.
Besides, I believe that the anesthetic and syringe
are already inside the sea.
Just what do you think you're talking about?
Don't tell me you're going to say you don't know who the killer is!
Right?
There is indeed only one person
who could be the killer though.
Detective Mouri.
What?
The one who killed Mr. Fukuura
as well as tried to put the blame on Mummy
is none other than
you!
Werewolf!
What?
Werewolf?
Your head must've dulled from your cold.
We all saw Werewolf come out of the toilet,
as well as just before Mr. Fukuura gave out the quiz!
While on the contrary,
Mummy wasn't seen by anybody!
Just what are you talking about?
When I came out of the toilet,
you were watching me!
What?
Are you doubting my memory?
I was here too,
when the quiz was just about to be announced,
right near you!
Hey,
don't tell me that you're going to say that
you weren't the Mummy but the Invisible Man?
Frankenstein has the key that will unravel the mystery.
Why?
Won't you tell us why,
you were acting your role as a monster
even inside the toilet?
As well as what you were surprised at right afterwards.
It's a well-known thing among we horror fans that
if there is anyone within the party grounds that is sending e-mails,
that person is a movie staff that is judging to see
whether they should give us a chance to appear in the movie or not.
That's why I knew right off the bat that he was a staff member.
So, I followed him to sell myself,
and kept acting my role until he came out.
But the one who came out of the toilet that he went in was...
Werewolf?
What? You mean Mummy was Werewolf?
Hey...
Then, don't tell me that...
That's right.
The killer not only wanted to put the blame on Mummy
who was asleep in the toilet,
he also put something else on Mummy
which is his own werewolf's mask!
He probably cracked the mirror in the toilet
to keep Mummy from finding out what happened.
He doesn't have to look into the mirror
to realize that he's not wearing his original mask, does he?
I mean he's wearing something like this!
Since Mummy was originally wrapped up in bandage,
and moreover, if he was put to sleep.
It's no wonder that he didn't realize what had happened.
On top of that, the mask covers and hides everything from neck down,
so even if the color of the necktie changes, it's hard to tell.
Besides, both of them were wearing white gloves
and their outfits are more or less similar.
So I don't think anyone would've suspected anything.
But their physiques are similar
and they hold the same card of the devil,
both of them are reticent,
and they end up in the compartment next to each other.
Doesn't everything fall too much in place?
The only coincidence here is probably the pattern of the card.
The killer was waiting for the right person
to come to the toilet.
There were a lot of passengers who didn't speak a word
because they wanted to sell themselves as monsters.
So, as for piercing the card with the arrow,
the killer probably thought it up right on the spot.
The person that would be suspected as the killer
would be someone that didn't have his card.
He probably made light of it,
thinking that no one would figure out who the real killer was.
But...
when Sonoko called,
Werewolf came out of the toilet!
If he was drugged to sleep,
how come he came out at such great timing?
Before he came out of the toilet,
you heard something, didn't you?
Oh, I see!
The howling of the wolf!
It seemed that he was playing the howling using a tape recorder.
If he turned the switch on from the toilet compartment next door.
Mummy would be surprised and wake up!
Yeah.
The speaker was probably attached
behind the mask.
The killer attached a wiretap with the speaker
and put the mask on Mummy so that he would react swiftly
to the voices of the people around him.
Even if someone were to talk to him,
Mummy would think that Werewolf was being talked to
because the howling is heard at close range.
I see.
I thought it was strange because each time he heard howling,
he was looking here and there.
That's how Werewolf gave everyone the impression that
he was at the party hall and created his alibi,
then he went up on deck
and fired the arrow from the bow gun at Mr. Fukuura
who was on top of the mast!
Then he used the howling to guide him
to where Mummy was among the crowd
and tore off the mask within the crowd
and put it back on himself.
Then he went back inside the crowd of people.
I guess that is how the story goes.
Right, Werewolf?
Am I wrong in any way?
I don't know if you're a high school detective or what
but you can sure blabber on, can't you?
I put this mask on Mummy, you say?
Do you have proof that I did it, or what?
If it's something that points in the direction that you're the killer,
yes.
I have two!
One of it is this!
The hint of the quiz
about there's a human among the monsters here.
Rooster?
Hey, where'd you get that?
It was tied to a rope here.
I think that Mr. Fukuura with the spotlight on himself
was going to do this!
What?
Suspend it upside down?
Upside down?
The opposite of a rooster is...
"Retsoor"?
"Sterroo"?
"Terroos"?
Just what kind of hint is that supposed to be?
"Retsoor"...
I get it.
What?
Roosters are also called cock,
and he's holding it by the tail.
It is said that long ago, all kinds of liquor
were made by stirring them with the tail of the cock.
Therefore, the drinks have been called cocktails since then.
That's the origin of the word cocktail.
What?
You mean "cocktail" is the hint?
Detective Mouri.
You also drank it too, didn't you?
That cocktail.
I'm a beer drinker!
I would never drink...
Come to think of it, I was looking for Werewolf and...
Hey, boss! What's up?
Bartender.
Can you give me the same thing he's drinking?
I did drink it
now that you mentioned it.
If I remember correctly it was...
A cocktail called Silver Bullet!
We were given instructions
by Mr. Fukuura to drink it at the bar of the party hall!
Which means
you rushed out of the toilet like that back then because...
You fell asleep in the toilet
and still didn't drink the cocktail?
Yes!
That's a coincidence,
because I drank it too.
What?
You didn't!
It was Mummy who you had put your mask over!
It's just as Shinichi had deduced!
Stop putting on airs, brat!
I'm the only Werewolf here!
And Werewolf!
Did you really drink that cocktail?
You, who wanted to sell your act as Werewolf,
and appear in the movie?
Yeah, to pep me up.
Or, are you saying that
Werewolf is not supposed to drink liquor?
You really drank Silver Bullet?
Shut up, persistent brat!
I drank it!
Silver Bullet?
Hey, no way.
Silver Bullet, that's...
-Yeah. -Werewolf would never drink it.
Yes. The name of the cocktail was Silver Bullet.
Just as the name goes, a silver bullet.
It's the only weapon in the movie
that is capable of killing the Werewolf.
It's a thing that any horror fan would know.
And a cocktail with that name
is also used to ward off evil.
Mr. Fukuura probably intended to use this cocktail as a hint
and lure people to the bar
then later ask the bartender
who drank what kind of liquor
and have everyone answer that Mummy who ordered Silver Bullet
was the human among the monsters.
Because no monster would go out of their way
to order liquor to ward off evil.
Isn't that right, Werewolf?
Well...
Since the bartender heard nothing beforehand from Mr. Fukuura,
he seems to have served Detective Mouri the same liquor, though.
If Mr. Fukuura was the one who did the makeup for Mummy,
it's most likely that
the answer is under the bandage.
The bull's eye mark
indicates that you're the answer!
Excuse me.
Here it is!
It says "human".
"Human"
And? What about the other evidence?
Even a marksman at the bow gun
could never pierce a person with an arrow poked
with a card through it.
Of course, he wouldn't be able to do it
from on top this unstable rope too.
In order to make sure he kills his target,
he needs to climb up here and fire at his target at point blank.
The traces of Werewolf having come up here back then is here.
What?
The traces of pieces of glass
that are embedded into the soles of your shoes
that you stepped on when you cracked the mirror in the toilet.
If we have the forensic officers match the pieces
I'm sure they will match completely.
Now, Werewolf,
please show us the soles of your shoes.
And please tell us
why you came all the way up here.
So, please show us then, Werewolf!
Come on and lift your foot.
It's not me!
It... It's not me!
I had no intention of killing him!
That devil is to blame.
What?
It's all that devil's fault!
It's that devil's fault!
The one called Vermouth!
Ms. Jodie!
Dr. Araide, what seems to be the matter?
That's for me to say.
What do you intend to do with her?
No! No!
We were just taking a drive!
Unlike you,
I've got a lot of time on my hands!
Lot of time?
Dr. Araide, it's almost time
for the trial for the homicide case, isn't it?
You've got to testify as would be expected of a good citizen!
And tell everyone that
the home helper, Hikaru Yasumoto,
is the one who pulled the trigger
and killed your father
which is a hidden fact.
Ms. Hikaru pulled the trigger?
No use playing dumb with me!
Detective Mouri told me the facts about everything!
Just what are you talking about?
The killer of the case back then was my stepmother.
And, besides, he died of electrocution,
not bullet wounds!
Did you say Vermouth?
Are you saying that you killed Mr. Fukuura
because that character called Vermouth asked you to do so?
Hey!
No.
It's true that I had a grudge against Mr. Fukuura
because he concluded the Unlucky Days series
that I loved more than anything else just like that
and started this kindergarten-style
Phantom Ship Captain series.
So, I wrote about this on the BBS of a certain Internet site
saying that I wanted to work off my grudge.
Then, this person called Vermouth contacted me.
She said that she'd tell me how to kill him and prepare the weapons
if I'd like to carry it out.
What do you make of the life of a person,
carrying out murder on a motive like that?
Of course, I refused at first!
But, after that...
pictures of my family and I that were taken secretly,
along with tapes of wire-taped telephone conversations,
as well as documents with my daily actions written to minute detail...
A whole cardboard box was delivered to me!
I was told that if I refused or reported it to the police,
either my family or I would die.
Everything I received implicated this!
His cause of death was electrocution and not by a gun?
What are you getting at?
Sorry.
The trigger I was referring to just now was
the electricity breaker.
The killer is the one who rigged everything to commit the murder
but the one who actually lifted the breaker
and triggered the murder
is Hikaru Yasumoto who knew nothing at all.
Therefore, in order not to hurt her feelings,
the killer and the police got together
and made up a fake record of investigation!
It said that the method of killing was something else.
Well, it's only natural that you don't know about this!
Because this wasn't written on the investigation report
that you stole from the police.
It was to learn the case and successfully testify in court
and keep existing as Dr. Araide.
Am I wrong?
Who are you?
"A secret makes a woman, a woman".
Do you remember?
These are the final words you left behind with me.
And the words I kept repeating
so I don't forget them.
The words of the one who killed my father.
Isn't that right,
Chris Vineyard?
Rather...
The other name that you go by...
Vermouth!
Who are you?
It's a secret. A secret.
I can't tell you.
A secret makes a woman, a woman.
Daddy's glasses.
I'm sorry.
Daddy. What's the matter?
Is he already asleep?
He promised to read me a story before going to bed and yet...
Then, will you stay by your father until he gets up?
Okay!
Then, you set fire to my house
and burned everything down to ashes.
All of what my father, as an FBI agent,
gathered behind closed doors,
the investigation data on all of you.
But, I was saved
because after that...
I remembered that there was no more orange juice
that father always drinks upon getting up
and since he was lying down from exhaustion from afternoon
taking care of my mother who wasn't feeling well.
I wanted to be of help and went out shopping.
Oh, so you're the little girl I saw back then!
I really went all out looking for you,
because all that was left from the remains
were the bones of your parents.
My father's colleagues protected me.
They applied for the witness protection program for me.
That stupid system of changing the name and address of a witness
whose life is in danger in order to protect that person
under a different identity.
It must've been really restricting, right?
To live away from your hometown, as a different person.
You went through hard times, didn't you?
And?
You took after your father, and came after me?
FBI agent Jodie Starling?
Just as expected of a witch with a thousand faces, Vermouth.
With your ability of disguise, you can sneak in anywhere
and check on things to your heart's content.
I'm amazed that you saw through the disguise of Dr. Araide.
It's obvious.
Despite of not having that bad of an illness,
you keep frequenting Araide Hospital with no makeup.
You were planning to kill him and become him!
Then you mean that...
the time his car passed right before me with his family
and crashed through the guard rail
eventually sinking into the sea...
was all set up by you?
Yes!
I made it look as if he died of an accident
before you got to kill him.
Because if the car was left at the bottom of the sea
and if nobody knew that he was dead,
it would make it easier for you to go around
acting as Dr. Araide.
Of course,
the people in the car were my colleagues equipped with air pumps.
The real Dr. Araide is living in peace in a place far away.
Then just as we expected,
you established yourself in Araide Hospital
and began checking on something.
It was obvious what you waiting for
the moment we snuck into your room in that hospital.
A picture was poked all over with darts.
The picture of a girl in her 20's with reddish brown hair.
You were planning to find her and get rid of her!
Now I have a question!
The picture of the woman you were trying to get hold of and kill
and this girl that looks just like her.
Of course the witness protection program
will be applied to her but...
Is she really the woman in the picture?
There's still more!
The two pictures that were below her picture,
with the words Cool Guy and Angel that are written on the pictures.
That boy is unmistakably sharp,
but he's more a "kid" than a "guy," isn't he?
Yes. That boy called Conan.
Until that boy left the girl's side,
you didn't do anything.
Inside the bus that was jacked too.
Please don't!
It's just the mischief of a child, isn't it?
Will tell me why you went all out to protect that boy
to the point of almost risking your own life?
If she didn't come around,
things wouldn't have turned out like this.
So...
Nab that person called Vermouth too!
And?
So that name Vermouth, that sounds like the name of some liquor
is probably a fake name, right?
Do you know the person's identity?
You haven't seen that person yourself, either?
No.
Then, what about the receipts of the things
that you received that she used to blackmail you?
Well...
What? No way!
You threw them away?
The address is probably a phony one too.
I guess for now...
until we arrive at the harbor, we'll have to keep him tied up somewhere.
So now, the case is closed.
Come on.
Will you tell me?
Okay!
I'll tell you.
That's...
Don't move!
Gosh.
What a dangerous thing you have there.
Did you get permission from the police in Japan?
We'll request joint investigation
from the police here after we nab you!
Of course, I'm willing to take full responsibility for this.
But before that I have something I want to ask you!
And what may that be?
Why don't you...
Why don't you age at all?
You caught my attention because of what you said
in front of my mother's coffin.
A secret makes a woman, a woman.
I was really excited and started investigating,
then sure enough, there was a perfect match.
Remember back when you killed my father
making it look like he committed suicide.
You picked up his glasses trying to replace it
because of the way it lay unnaturally on the floor.
The fingerprints that were on the lens of the glasses
and yours matched perfectly!
But, I had my doubts.
You were too young to be a suspect of an incident
that had happened 20 years ago.
I didn't think it possible at first,
but when I matched your prints with a certain person's,
I got results that made a shiver go up my spine.
You're the one and the same as your mother, Sharon Vineyard!
And, I finally found the witness
that could explain the mystery
of what was keeping you from being arrested!
You guys! Come out and hold this woman!
When I get custody of you from the Japanese police,
I'll make you spit it out.
You'll tell me everything.
Well, even if you insist on saying nothing,
she will eventually.
Thank you, Calvados.
Don't kill her yet.
I've still got something I want to ask her.
Why?
You all staked out here
and figured you lured me out but...
I came here once already two hours ago,
disguised as you.
And this is what I said in your voice.
This is it tonight! Come back tomorrow!
Didn't you realize?
There was another reason as to why the papers of the cases
that Detective Mouri was involved in were stolen.
All of the documents were stolen
so that the papers we actually needed would not be specified,
however, all of the documents were sent back to the MPD in one batch
because I wanted you people to think that my stay in Japan
had something to do with Detective Mouri
so that you would stake out the detective agency.
Which as a result, it would help me figure out who the FBI agents are.
Just as expected, I figured out how many of you there were,
the place you were all staying
and the way you were all communicating.
I also knew that you were trying to trap me here.
Then, you knew that we snuck into your room too?
Yes. I was just playing dumb.
I thought that if you saw that picture,
you would find her for me.
But you surprised me twice already.
The first is that you are the girl
that I met 20 years ago.
The other is that
you knew what went on behind the scenes regarding Dr. Araide.
How did you get information on it
when nothing about it was spoken to anyone?
I didn't hear about it from anyone.
I was asked to do so by someone.
To corner you and disclose your identity,
and in turn for doing so, she said that she would trust me.
This girl over here.
Oh, I see.
She said so.
Anyway, let's hear the whole story
when we get to the police station!
He solved the case in such a short time!
Just as expected of Shinichi Kudo!
Fantastic!
It's nothing...
The reason I got to solve it right away
is because I used the same trick as the killer.
Just what does that mean?
What?
The same trick that Werewolf over there used!
So, this is it, for our re-encounter after 20 years.
It's time to say goodbye.
Come on and smile
because you're going to get to see your father in heaven.
What?
The same trick as Werewolf used?
The killer put a mask over the victim, who was already disguised.
Which means he double disguised the victim.
Don't you only have bandages wrapped around you?
Just what do you mean by that?
Don't tell me that you're...
Yeah.
So this...
is what I mean!
What?
You're...
Heiji Hattori?
Cool kid?
Conan Edogawa.
A detective!
He wasn't Shinichi.
Heiji Hattori?
Disguise?
It's a disguise?
But his voice and tone were just like Shinichi.
Yes.
Of course.
It's my masterpiece that took me six hours to put him on this disguise.
As for his voice, the microphone on his collar
picks up the deduction that Heiji whispers into it,
then Shinichi says it through the microphone on his mask.
That voice output is the speaker on Heiji's necktie.
How do you like it?
A perfect collaboration by Dr. Agasa and I.
Okay! We're okay on this side, Kudo!
Do your thing on your side too, now!
Don't move!
Your body's the blind spot for the rifle.
Now...
get in the car after Ms. Jodie.
Let's take a drive to the police!
Ms. Jodie.
Quick and get in the car!
Ms. Jodie! Are you all right?
Yes.
Don't tell me that?
Shinichi Kudo?
Remember? The kid that you poisoned to death
with the drug made by the organization back then!
Sorry, Vodka.
I make it a policy to forget the name and face...
of the ones I get rid of.
And?
Are you saying that the kid rose from the dead
and appeared as a ghost?
Yeah, I mean no.
Something strange is happening.
Why are you disguised as Shinichi Kudo in the first place anyway?
Sorry! Pops!
I haven't seen Kudo for some time,
so I got kind of lonely.
I figured that if I came out looking like him
and made a deduction, maybe he just might pop out too.
But maybe he's dead, just as rumor has it, don't you think?
Darn it! Kid from Osaka,
this is the second time you're pulling this trick!
If Ran were here,
you'd be way gone by now!
Scary. Give me a break.
I had no choice.
After all, Kudo e-mailed me asking me to do this.
He told me that those guys are trying to pull him away from Ai
and do something,
so he wanted me to disguise myself as him and find out about it.
That's why I'm on board this ship!
But, it sure freaked me out
when I got to his house
and found his mother there.
She seems to have been worried about him,
and hiding for a while in the house watching him.
Mother?
Hey...
I didn't think she had a special talent to disguise people
but she would even freak Arsene Lupin out too!
Thanks to her,
I didn't have to complete my deduction all bandaged up.
The only one I'm worried about is
the little girl that is left sleeping
and confined in the basement of Dr. Agasa's house.
Kudo says she'll be fine
if she doesn't have the pursuit glasses
hidden somewhere with her
But, if I were her...
knowing that he would be meeting someone dangerous disguised as me,
I wouldn't be able to wait for him just like that.
I would break the door open
and go after him no matter what.
No matter what, Kudo!
I'd go after you.
Haibara. You...
Haibara?
Darn it!
Don't come!
Stay away!
Go back!
You idiot!
No, Kudo.
This is my problem!
This had nothing to do with you.
That's why...
Don't die!
I don't want you to die!
So you had the spare pursuit glasses
hidden after all.
Kudo.
Run for it, Haibara!
Hurry!
Just what are you doing?
Get out of here, Haibara!
Hurry and get out!
Quick!
Goodnight, baby.
And...
Welcome...
Sherry!
The only reason I can think of
for Vermouth to go after Haibara's life
and want me to stay away from her
is because of her identity as actress Chris Vineyard
as well as Sharon since she is both of them.
She was probably acting out two roles under disguise.
If she knows mom,
she would've probably seen pictures of me as a kid,
so she would've easily made out who I am
and I also understand why she wouldn't want
to be messed up with a scandal.
I'll be fine!
Don't worry because I promise to make it back alive!
Is that really true,
Sharon?
Stupid woman.
Screwing up this little boy's plan,
and coming out here on your own initiative to die.
I didn't come here just to die.
I came here to end everything.
Even if you were to be arrested,
as long as I'm alive,
you guys will never stop pursuing me.
But, I'd like you to give me your word.
That you will not lay a hand on anyone else except me.
Will you promise to give me your word?
Okay.
I'll save all the others
except for this woman FBI agent here.
But first, I'll get rid of you, Sherry.
If you want to hold a grudge on anyone,
hate your parents for starting
such a stupid research in the first place.
Cool kid.
No way!
How?
Stop! Calvados!
Could it be...
she saw everything?
Stop! Calvados!
Stop!
Can't you hear I'm telling you to stop?
So...
Get away from that brown-haired girl!
If you don't want to die, you'd better hurry!
No! Don't move!
Come on. Hurry! Get out of the way!
Stop it!
I called the police.
So just put up with this a while longer. Please!
Big sis.
Silver hair?
The story was meant to end this way.
Hate God for what is happening to you.
What are you doing?
Hurry and hang on to my arm!
Hurry or my arm will get slippery from the rain.
Why'd you save me?
Why on earth?
Who needs a reason?
Who cares what the motives are
for a person to want to kill another person?
Why would a person want to save another then?
There is no logical reason for that either, is there?
Get out of the way!
What are you doing?
Hurry and hang on to my arm!
Move it, Angel!
What?
This is a blind spot for the rifle.
When did you...
Throw your gun down.
Throw your gun down!
If not, I'll aim for your head next.
The sound of a pump?
A shotgun?
Okay! Calvados.
We'll attack them from both sides!
This is bad.
He's coming from behind.
Come on, Calvados.
Use that dear shotgun of yours
and blow up the little kitty FBI agent, will you?
So, his name is Calvados.
A rifle, a shotgun and three guns.
I thought he was a weapon vendor or something.
Shuichi Akai?
Shu!
But with two broken legs,
I don't think he'll be doing business for quite some time.
Well, Calvados is like a strong apple spirit.
So, I guess he's just right
for the partner of a rotten apple like you.
Rotten apple?
That's the name we call you by.
Golden Apple was the stage
in which the great actress Sharon stole the limelight.
You're just as beautiful now as you were back then but...
Inside, you're a wrinkled up rotten apple.
A really rotten apple!
Don't, Shu!
Don't worry.
I can tell from the way she moves
that she's wearing a bullet proof jacket
and layers of bullet proof pads all over her body.
I think she'll get two or three broken ribs at most.
Moreover, look.
Look at her face that tore apart with the shot that was fired.
That's the face of that woman with no make-up after all.
The brats are a nuisance!
Cool kid.
To think she can blow up the gasoline tank
by looking over the mirror in that situation.
She's pretty good.
Shu!
This is no time to be amazed by her!
She took a child hostage and got away, you know?
Then why didn't you take the key out of the car?
Well, I'm sorry.
We did get our share though,
because that woman's comrade is...
Hey...
Don't tell me he still had a gun on him?
Could it be that he killed himself?
Look at that.
The Japanese police are here.
This girl must've called them.
Inside the trunk,
it's hard to make out conversation
but bullets can be heard.
I'm sure
she saw the pictures in my room and got suspicious,
and snuck inside my car
in order to investigate me.
She heard the bullets and came outside.
Then protected the brown haired girl, who had a gun pointed at her.
They probably thought they were shot
and both passed out.
Geez.
I don't know if you can say they got guts or not.
Then, I'll leave the rest up to you.
Just go ahead and explain to them that
you're an FBI agent on a long leave of absence came to Japan
and got mixed up in a child kidnapping case.
Since that woman got away,
nobody would believe anything we say anyway.
The big guy behind all this hasn't come up front yet.
And besides I can't have
that girl with the brown hair see me yet.
"Seems that I gave you too much freedom before."
"Return to me immediately, Vermouth."
Okay, boss.
Now...
This child.
What shall do with this child who thinks
he is capable of doing everything?
The electrodes of an ECG monitor?
There is a tracing device as well as a recorder.
Don't tell me that
the sound of the telephone I made just a while ago was.
Don't.
If you pull that out,
it means that my heart has stopped
and the mail address of the boss you sent an e-mail to
will be disclosed to my friend.
The telephone company must protect the privacy of their clients.
But the police
can get that information if they fill out a special form
and have one of the higher-ups put a seal on it,
then have the information disclosed before several witnesses.
If the call that was received was not from a cell phone,
but a regular home phone, even the address would be disclosed!
In other words,
if the sound just now is recorded
and analyzed to decipher the alphabets and number,
the name of your boss, as well as his whereabouts can be tracked down!
That is, even if I were to be killed!
Well,
I did figure that if you found Sherry,
who you guys are going nuts looking for,
you would unmistakably contact your big boss.
Since things began to look dangerous for Ms. Jodie,
I had to change my plans.
So, what are you going to do now?
My friends are waiting for contact from me
at a distant place from here.
If you don't want this to go out,
take me to your boss!
Let's get things over with once and for all, Vermouth!
I want to stop playing hide-and-seek already!
Okay.
I lost.
I'll give up going after Sherry.
It's mere sleeping gas.
You idiot!
If you do something like this, you'll suck in the gas too.
Yes. This is a gamble.
If you get up first,
you go ahead and call the police and have me arrested,
then go raid the boss along with them.
You already know what happens
if I get up first, don't you?
Bad news!
I've got to go wake him up right away.
Shinichi!
Shinichi...
You guys were blasted by Shuichi Akai?
Yes.
He just happened to find us by,
and Calvados ended up with three broken ribs.
You mean that FBI agent that you failed to get rid of
back in New York a year ago,
when you disguised yourself as serial killer.
I thought he'd be off his guard if he figured
I was just an ordinary killer, but...
I should've gotten rid of him back then
even if I had to risk being killed myself.
Our boss said that
that person
could be our silver bullet.
He is to be feared.
A silver bullet that capable to kill us in one shot
doesn't exist.
At any rate, I'm in a phone booth on route 20,
so can you come pick me up?
I got into a bit of trouble,
and can't move.
Before that, I have something I want to ask you.
Do you know a kid by the name of Shinichi Kudo?
No.
I don't.
Why did you save me?
Who needs a reason?
Why would a person want to save another then?
There is no logical reason for that either, is there?
Yes, it's him.
He, the one who pierced through our heart,
could prove to be him.
The one that we have long awaited,
the silver bullet.