"Young Lady at the Lavender Manor Commits Suicide"
"Motive Unknown. The Door is Locked"
"Possibility of Intruder"
Help!
Police, open the door!
"New Truth Disclosed on Suicide of the Lady of Lavender Manor"
"Police Conclude it to be Locked Room Homicide!"
"A High School Student Solves the Case?"
"Suspect Still Denies Charges"
The light of summer is the glory of yesterday.
After the tears come... The 2-hour special.
A long three-day vacation.
Two tough cases to solve.
Here goes, Detective Championship Game.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
"Three Days With Heiji Hattori"
"Light Pink. Cherry Blossom Festival"
What beautiful cherry blossoms!
Really! This place is bustling with the cherry blossom festival too,
so I'm glad we came here!
Yep, thanks, Ran!
Shouldn't you be thanking Detective Kogoro Mouri here,
who suddenly gets a call from a high school student from Osaka
saying that she wants to go flower viewing
and speeds her over here from early in the morning
to grant her wish, huh?
-Yes. -I know!
Well, there seems to be people who rather than feel gratitude
prefer bread to the song of birds though.
Oh boy, I mean Heiji's the one who wanted to go flower viewing.
Hey, Kazuha!
This pinwheel is cute!
Really! I'm going to buy one.
How much, sir?
200 yen.
Oh, one for me too.
Hey, what're you doing standing there doing nothing!
You called me over because you wanted something, right?
Oh, yeah.
Something about a high school student wearing glasses.
Oh, right, Eisuke Hondo.
He's a junior in high school and is Ran's classmate.
I wonder if you could check on something for me.
Huh? Why me?
Does he have something to do with Osaka?
No, the one I want you to check on
is the one whose eyes resemble that of this Eisuke Hondo guy
and is a member of the Black Organization
Rena Mizunashi!
Mizunashi is an announcer for Nichiuri TV, isn't she?
She seems to be on leave right now,
but you mean she's a bad person?
Hattori!
You're talking too loud! Hey!
She's on leave because she got into an accident
during a chase with the F.B.I. and was hurt badly.
She's in a certain hospital right now and lying unconscious there.
And?
The more so, then why me?
If you want somebody to check, why not ask that thin,
what was his name? Officer Takagi.
A picture.
The picture of a woman who looks exactly like Rena Mizunashi
was coincidentally taken 10 years ago
seems to have been uploaded on a website for some time.
The woman was standing in front of Tsutenkaku,
carrying a convenience store shopping bag!
Which means that the woman was living in Osaka?
I can't come to any conclusion yet
but I tried contacting the TV station to confirm thing with her.
However, a few days after I wrote,
the website was closed.
Something's fishy, don't you think?
That's why I want you to hurry and check things out for me.
Make sure Eisuke Hondo
who's sniffing around about her doesn't beat you to it!
If so, wouldn't it be faster for you
to nab that Hondo guy and make him spit it out?
If those two look alike, they may be blood related,
and she may be a villain too.
No, I don't think they're family.
I can't help feeling that
something about the way Eisuke Hondo acts is strange.
How do you do, Detective Mouri?
It's an honor to get to see you!
See! Just like there was no scratch there to begin with!
A new student who suddenly transferred and came to Ran's high school.
Which means that Rena Mizunashi whose eyes resemble his is...
Yeah, a member of the Black Organization.
They probably changed the face of one of their members
with plastic surgery to one of Eisuke Hondo's family
and became that person, quite an easy feat for them to accomplish.
At any rate, please have Inspector Ohtaki
check carefully and in secret
whether there was a woman named Mizunashi or Hondo
living in Osaka or not.
I see. If that woman really existed
and a case of a woman suddenly disappearing is found, it's bingo.
It really disappeared!
Just as if she was spirited away!
It's probably some work of fate that I ran into you here.
Please, I beg you.
Will you please solve the mystery of this case?
-Well... -What?
What's the matter, Pops?
This monk suddenly...
What? A person disappeared?
Yes. I'm a disciple at that temple, my name is Denkyu.
A person who came to visit the head monk the other day
suddenly disappeared from the room.
Suddenly?
She was a woman with long hair,
and spent the night at the annex.
But, when I went to tell her that breakfast was ready...
She was gone?
Maybe she decided to go home before eating breakfast?
No, she was actually in the room at that time
but I found her stabbed in the stomach with a knife,
dead and lying on the floor.
-What? -Are you saying that she was dead?
Yes.
Did you report it to the police?
Of course,
right after I let the head monk who was resting at the temple know.
Then, don't tell me that the one who disappeared is...
Yes, when the police came and arrived at the annex,
only the head monk was in the room.
There were no signs of the woman
nor the blood stain that was on the tatami.
No...
And, what did the head monk say?
That the visitor left early in the morning,
and that maybe I was dreaming.
Are you sure you really weren't still half asleep?
No way. I really saw it with my own eyes!
Okay, if you insist, let's go to the temple
and hear what the head monk has to say, then.
You're that famous Detective Kogoro Mouri.
"Shakuren" -What brings a famed person like you
"A Buddhist priest" -all the way up
to a small mountain temple like this?
Well, you see, Denkyu, a disciple of your temple...
Oh...
You want to know about that dream story of Denkyu
about the visitor who came here and disappeared out of the blue?
Well, sort of...
Well, to be honest, we just came to check things out.
To confirm whether what this monk saw was just an illusion
or whether you cleaned the corpse and everything up
before the police got here.
Heiji!
You have quite an interesting point of view, young man.
All right, let me take you over to the annex in question.
To the room that Denkyu insists swallowed up one whole person.
It sure takes a while to get to that annex, doesn't it?
Wow! The temple looks to be so far away already.
You can say that again!
There it is.
That's it.
It sure is an old looking building.
Yes, it's already been 50 years since it was built.
Please do come in.
One room is 8-mats and there are 4 room all together.
And, where's the place that woman's body was found?
Right around there to the upper right of this room.
-Well? -Nothing.
It's not a reversible mat either.
Oh, a statue of Buddha.
Guardians of the temple?
That's one of the Four Heavenly Kings, Tamonten.
This room facing north is called Tamonten.
To the west is Koumokuten,
the south Zoujyoten
and the east Jikokuten.
A Buddhist statue is inside each of the rooms.
Oh, you may touch it but please don't scratch it.
After all, the Buddhist statues are precious statues
that have been handed down to Shokakuji from one generation to the next.
Oh, is that right?
Well, it's already late today.
I suggest that you spend the night here tonight,
and start investigations tomorrow at dawn?
That is, only if you feel that you have more to check on.
Oh...
Are you serious about spending the night here at this temple?
I'm sure that it's only that the monk was half awake
and made a mistake!
That's right, so let's all head back to Ran's place.
It's you.
This time, in the middle of the room of the annex...
There's a woman with a knife stabbed through her stomach!
Is it in the same room?
Yes. Exactly the same as back then.
There's nobody here?
It can't be.
It was here for sure a while ago.
I guess I'll have to tell you about it after all.
Osho!
The fact is, there was no visitor at this temple on that day.
I've got to also so add that you were just chasing
the shadow of your mother who passed on long ago.
Oh, no...
No.
"Red. Disappeared Bloodstain" -I saw it with my very eyes.
"Red. Disappeared Bloodstain" -I'm trying to tell you that
it's all an illusion you imagined because you miss your mother.
It can't be...
Your poor mother who threw herself in the ocean
after bringing you here to this temple, and placing you in my custody.
In your custody?
Yes, Denkyu here is an abandoned child,
whom I, who had just become the head priest of this temple
adopted and brought up for 18 years.
I'm not good at refusing
and have ended up raising 2 or 3 others too.
But, it seems that they didn't like it here and left,
so only Denkyu and I are at this temple now.
Even after being apart so long,
Denkyu can't forget about his dear mother.
Which means that just like you say,
the dead body of the woman Denkyu says he saw the other day was...
Right, we didn't even have visitors that day.
However, three days ago, that morning,
Denkyu ran in here looking pale.
I thought that maybe someone who got lost in the mountains
came uninvited to this annex
and came here to check.
But, just like tonight, there was no one here.
Yes, I felt sorry for Denkyu who insisted on seeing such an illusion that
when the police came,
I went along with his story without thinking,
saying that a woman visitor came here early in the morning.
So, now has the mystery been solved?
Well, sort of.
No.
I'm sure the woman was here in this room
at least three days ago, when Denkyu said he saw her.
Do you or Denkyu like to dress yourselves in woman's clothes?
Woman's clothes?
You! What stupid thing are you talking about?
Look what I found.
See!
This is the back catch of a pierced earring?
When we were checking to see
if the tatami of this room was double matted
and flipped it over,
this kid found it.
The back catch of pierced earrings easily come off
so it probably came off accidentally
and got stuck in between the tatami
but the problem is, whose pierce it is?
We've got to track down who the owner of this pierce back catch
that is still shiny as if it hasn't been here for long after it came off.
Come to think of it.
The woman that came three days ago also
wore pierced earrings!
Then, the answers simple!
The one who Denkyu saw was not an illusion.
No.
The one who was wearing the earring
was probably either Bunkyu or Rinkyu
who were disciples here at this temple until two months ago.
Bunkyu and Rinkyu?
Remember, I mentioned a while ago that
I adopted two other children besides Denkyu.
Unlike Denkyu, they were both forever prone to mischief.
They used to sneak out of the temple night after night and go to town.
Moreover, they used to disguise themselves as women
so people wouldn't suspect them to be monks.
Disguise?
Yes. I don't know where they got a hold of it
but they wore a wig, pierced earrings and a long dress,
just like those the young people wear nowadays.
Is that true?
Yes.
Those two used to frequently drink liquor
secretly in this annex too.
Osho found out about it, and the two had a good scolding.
They didn't like it, so they both left this temple together.
They seem to have been using this annex to change clothes and all,
so the backing must've accidentally come off.
So, that's the story! Convinced?
You still don't look convinced, I see.
Then do check things out for yourselves to your heart's content.
If as Denkyu says
there was a blood smeared corpse in the middle of the room,
the blood should be found somewhere on the tatami.
Ran.
Don't you think Heiji and the others are a bit late?
Yeah, I wonder if something happened.
Okay, Ran, wait here then! I'll go check!
Oh, I'll go too, then!
Don't you think that it's better for us
to just wait here without moving after all, Ran?
I guess so.
Around where on the floor was that woman?
Oh, yes. She was right around here three days ago,
lying on the floor like this.
Then, what about the woman you saw a while ago?
In the middle of the room,
like so.
Was there a lot of blood?
Yeah.
Three days ago as well as tonight,
there was a lot of bleeding from the stomach.
Then, 10 to 1 it's not possible.
Maybe possible with the corpse he saw yesterday.
But if the corpse he saw lying there just a while ago is real,
there should be a blood stained tatami on the side
but even looks around now, there's no such tatami around!
You think so too. Did I actually see
an illusion of my mother that never existed in the first place after all?
So, are you convinced now?
Yes, very.
Then, Denkyu, please show these people to the gate.
Yes, sir.
I'll stay here in this room for a while
and offer prayer to the Four Heavenly Kings
in apology of having been a bit of a nuisance with all the fuss here.
I'm sorry for keeping you here for so long because of my mistake.
No, don't be, but why were you there at that time in that annex?
I always go and check to see
if the doors are locked before dinner.
Bunkyu and Rinkyu
were actually in charge of cleaning and locking the annex up.
But, after their drinking incident,
Osho did the cleaning and I was in charge of locking up.
Not only did they drink liquor,
but I'll be the two were also smoking in there too?
How do you know?
They both said they succeeded in smoking secretly.
What a conspicuous secret.
There was an obviously burnt spot on the tatami.
Come to think of it, there were remains of spilt beer too.
Yeah but what I don't understand is why both the remains...
They weren't there when we checked at sundown today.
Right, Heiji?
-Right! -Don't tell me that
someone switched the tatami?
I'm just saying that it's possible.
No way.
I'm sure you guys already know if you checked too,
but the tatami at the annex was not double-sided,
and besides, it was old and discolored from the sun.
Even if a tatami from someplace else
were to have been brought in and replaced,
the discoloration would make it apparent.
You mean switching isn't possible?
Switching the tatami of one of the four 8-mat floors.
To go from Pop's car to that annex
would take 7 to 8 minutes going and coming back,
if you run, that's enough time to switch the tatami!
Come to think of it, something always felt different from usual,
each time I found the bodies.
Right? I'll bet
the direction the tatami is placed or something is different?
Oh, but it's only that I have this feeling.
No matter how you replace the tatami,
you can't hide the blood stain.
If the body was lying smeared with blood in the middle of the room,
there should be blood on more than two tatamis!
Well, the only thing that did look suspicious
were the statues of the Four Heavenly Kings in the corner of the rooms
but they were inside transparent glass cases.
When the statue was moved, the tatami under it was in view,
so the blood couldn't have been hidden.
Let's pull out, pull out!
I can't be wasting my time on this silly story!
Huh? A mistake?
Are you saying that there was no corpse?
No, it was this monk's illusion.
I'm sorry.
But, I'm glad that nobody was dead then.
Okay, hurry and get in then, so we can head back to Ran's house.
The pinwheel.
Oh no, I squashed it.
It's okay, because it's not all that bent out of shape.
Why?
Why did the burnt remain that wasn't there at sundown
appear suddenly at night?
It was hidden out of sight?
But, where?
Heiji...
Hey, you...
This is it! This!
I've figured out where the blood stain is hidden!
Yeah, I thought of that too!
Yeah,
completely!
"Orange. Pinwheel Room" -I've figured it out completely!
"Orange. Pinwheel Room" -You meant that the woman
that I saw three days ago and the one I saw tonight were...
Yeah, not an illusion but genuine dead bodies
that were ingeniously hidden and made to look as if they disappeared
using an unimaginable trick.
Trick?
What kind of trick was it?
Please tell us, dad!
The hint is this pinwheel! This brought everything to light!
You thought so too, didn't you?
Osaka kid.
Yeah.
Why did the corpse disappear
when Denkyu took us to the annex with him and returned?
Let's say that this pinwheel is the annex.
There is no railing at the annex
and there are four square 8-mat rooms.
Railing?
Square?
Oh my, you mean the third-rate detective kid of Osaka
can't figure it out yet?
No, I can't make out your deduction.
Yes. It rotated 180 degrees, that annex!
I don't think there's such a contraption in that annex.
You just don't know of it.
I hear that the annex was built 50 years ago.
Even so,
three days ago the police, and tonight you people,
who were called by me, after coming here
investigated every nook and cranny, of all four rooms, didn't you?
Back then,
no blood nor corpse was found in any of the rooms, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Besides,
if such an amusement park like building existed 50 years ago,
it would've become a famous site around here. Dumb-dumb!
Then...
There was no dead body so it was just your illusion!
No, there was blood as well as the corpse.
Although they were hidden and out of sight.
Hidden... where on earth?
Ouch.
Conan!
Are you all right?
I slipped when I tried to pick up the badge I dropped.
You've gotta be careful.
It seems to be quite muddy around here yet
from the rain this morning.
By the way, do you see my detective badge
somewhere around here?
No, I don't see it.
Here's your glasses.
Thank you!
There's your badge.
Oh, yeah.
But, how strange... it wasn't there a while ago.
That's true.
Maybe it's because of the leaf that's stuck on this glasses.
See, you can see the badge if it's like this
but, if you put the glasses with the leaf on it like this,
you can't see it anymore.
Really. It's mixed up with the leaves on the ground.
And it looks like there's no badge there.
Hey, maybe the same sort of trick was used?
Could be.
A trick?
Yeah, if this trick is used,
maybe even blood can be hidden.
Under the case of the statues of the Four Heavenly Kings
that were in the corner of the rooms of the annex.
There was nothing below the cases.
The tatami below was in view under the case
when I moved the statue too.
So if you cut the tatami
and paste the front side of the tatami onto the back of the glass case
and if it were placed on top of the tatami where the blood stain is...
The blood would be completely covered
and it would look as if you're looking at the tatami below
through the glass case, wouldn't it?
True.
But, the trick would give itself away
as soon as somebody lifts the case up, right?
No way.
If you lift the glass case with the statue inside it,
it may fall and crack the glass,
besides if you move the statue that's inside,
it looks as if the tatami below is in view through the glass.
Nobody would think of going out of the way
to move the case after doing so!
I didn't move the case myself either.
But, who for what reason would've set up a trick like that?
Would the killer do something like that to hide the blood?
The ones who set up this trick
were probably the two monks who left this temple two months ago,
in order to hide the liquor stains
and burnt remains from their cigarettes.
They probably went out to look for tatami
that was very close in color to the one in the annex
and pasted it on to the bottom of the glass case of the statue,
to hide the stain and remains of burns.
Those two were in charge of cleaning the annex,
and besides they told you that they succeeded
in pulling the trick, right?
Yes.
When we checked the annex at sundown,
we found nothing like that and yet,
when you came and told us you found the corpse
and we went to check,
it suddenly appeared, that's the proof.
Then, you mean
the two monks who left snuck back in here
and killed a woman from somewhere?
No. The two just set up the trick.
The one who used it
is the one who saw through their trick
and bawled the two out.
That is, no one else could've done it
besides head monk Shakuren, right?
You mean that Osho did it?
You mean he killed the woman?
No.
If he killed somebody, he wouldn't have returned to the temple
and sleep like nothing happened
till Denkyu found the corpse three days ago.
That woman most probably committed suicide.
Osho, who heard from Denkyu that a woman was dead in the annex,
probably came up with the idea on the spur of the moment.
He decided to say that it was Denkyu's illusion
and that there was no dead body to begin with!
Oh, no...
Since the blood of the woman that was smeared on the tatami
was in just about the same place
as the stains of the liquor and cigarette,
he probably used the trick of the case to hide them,
and moved the tatami,
which after he place the case over it!
Then, where's that dead body?
Probably hidden under the porch of the annex or something,
until the police left.
So, the woman I saw tonight
-is the woman from three days ago... -No.
I think that the corpse you saw tonight was probably
Osho dressed in a woman's outfit lying on the floor.
Osho?
Yeah, using the wig that the other two monks used to wear.
He probably used ketchup or something
and made it look as if he was stabbed in the stomach with a knife.
He did so to make us as well as Denkyu
believe that the dead body of the woman was just an illusion.
But, isn't it strange?
The statues in the annex were all placed
in the corner of the four rooms
on the upper right and lower left corner.
The two monks that set up the trick
hid the cigarette burn and liquor stain, that's two places.
Even if the blood from the corpse three days
just happened to conveniently be in that position,
the corpse that Denkyu saw tonight, covered with blood
was lying in the middle of the room.
Which adds up to four blood-stained places.
With only two cases, I don't think
he could've hidden the blood stain that was smeared on today.
No, it's not two. There're four cases.
Osho probably copied the two other monks
and rigged the remaining two cases in the same way.
Therefore, he had four places he could use to hide the stains.
So, today he put ketchup that looked to be blood
on a total of four mats-the two mats
that originally had blood stains on them
and two other brand new ones that he acquired,
dressed in a woman's outfit and lay down on the middle of the room.
He waited for Denkyu to come lock the doors.
He knew that Denkyu would panic and come get us,
so within that time Osho replaced the blood stained tatamis back
in the four corners.
He then appeared looking as if nothing happened from behind us,
who arrived at the annex!
Like I've been trying to say,
if Osho was lying in the middle of the room
pretending to be the corpse,
the blood-like stain wouldn't be on the corner of the tatami,
but elsewhere, right?
If so, wouldn't it be difficult to hide everything right
even if there were to be four cases?
Really? Can you really be sure?
Oh, I see!
All he had to do was switch the tatami
so that the blood stained part comes at the corner of the tatami!
But this way, the location of the blood,
although the upper right and lower left is the same,
the remaining two would be to the upper left and lower right.
So, it won't do.
Oh, maybe it's this way?
This way, the two on the upper right are okay,
but two are on the upper left.
So, he couldn't have just put the Buddhist statues
in the four corners of the rooms to hide the blood stains, could he?
Are you sure those other the only ways you can line them up?
Take a look at this.
Huh?
It's just like a pinwheel, don't you think?
Oh, I see. If you line the tatami up this way...
The blood stains will all come to the upper right.
So, the position of the tatamis were changed after all
when I found the corpse tonight!
But, why did Osho go out this far
to hide the corpse?
Why did he carry things out as he did when he didn't even kill the woman?
Well, why don't we go and ask Osho himself?
"Black. Monk's confession"
Right, why did Osho do it?
Why did he have to hide the fact
despite having to act out the role of the corpse himself?
Because he didn't want the woman
to be identified during investigation?
He didn't want anyone to know who or where that woman came from?
Who didn't he want to let know?
Oh, seeing that you've come back,
I guess I didn't do a complete job at hiding what went on after all.
Of course not!
You could never in a billion years
deceive the eyes of Detective Kogoro Mouri!
I'm sorry to say this,
but before I explain what went on,
I'd like to have Denkyu leave until I'm done...
The monk is already back at the car.
We asked him to stay behind with the girls
so they'd feel more assured!
Since you're concerned about that monk,
that lady who committed suicide here three days ago is...
Yes, it was Denkyu's mother
who put Denkyu into a cardboard box and abandoned him,
leaving him in front of this temple.
Oh, is that so?
Yes, she suddenly came here out of the blue
saying that she wanted her son back.
She also added that she had been visiting this temple every year
and watched him mature.
Therefore, I thought of
showing her the pictures of all the young monks here at the temple.
However, just as I figured,
she couldn't tell which monk was her son,
and she finally breaks out in tears.
She didn't even realize that
the one who brought the album to her was her own son.
After I told Denkyu to leave the room,
I couldn't stop myself from scolding her quite firmly.
I told her to spend the night at annex that night and calm herself down.
To think of sadness that her son
had experienced for the past 18 years,
and to feel the same sadness all the way in her bones.
Then, at the break of dawn, that's how she was found.
I thought it too ruthless to let Denkyu know of this,
so I carried out what I did.
Shall we go then?
You'll take me to the police, won't you?
Oh, yes.
I know I'm in no position to say something like this.
If you still plan on continuing your job as a detective
who corners people with words,
there is something I'd like you to always keep in mind.
Words can be as sharp as blades,
if used wrongly,
they can turn into lethal weapons.
They must be used with great care taking into the consideration
how the listener is feeling.
No matter what kind of person your listener may be.
Why did Osho hide the corpse?
Yeah, hurry and stop keeping us in suspense and tell us!
Heiji! Hey, Heiji...
Shut up!
I'm saying I don't want to talk about it, stupid!
I have a feeling that in his case,
he really doesn't know how to say what he wants to say.
"Mouri Detective Agency"
Shoots! I slept for 10 hours!
Oh, well, a lot of things happened last night
and we did come home late,
and besides today is the Sunday before the start of a holiday.
It seems like Heiji and Kazuha went home already too.
I'm going to bed now, because we're leaving early tomorrow.
He said so too.
But, I wonder if he remembers
my asking him to check on Rena Mizunashi.
Well, I guess I could send him mail later to be sure.
Darn, all gone.
Here, you can use mine.
Oh, thanks.
How come you're still here?
I thought you said you were leaving early in the morning?
Yeah, I was planning to,
but thanks to Pop's snore.
I mean it was so loud I couldn't sleep.
Thanks to him my schedule's all ruined.
Then, shouldn't buy your ticket all over again as soon as possible?
No, it's okay, I'm not leaving yet.
Why not?
What? An uninhabited island?
You mean, you're going there from now?
Yeah, I just happened to be able to view flowers in the meantime.
Do you have a case to check out for someone?
No.
It's this dopey plan of some TV station.
Hey, shut up!
But, is that all right?
Weren't you supposed to leave early in the morning?
No, we'll make it in way enough time
even if we were to head off there from now.
If so, then why?
I just wanted to go there before everyone else
and check out the faces and personalities of the guys
that were invited over there.
That is, what the other high school detectives like me look like.
High school detectives?
Right,
Nichiuri TV's gathering guys from throughout the country
and is going to be deciding who the number one high school detective is.
They have a sign that says, "Detective Championship Game."
"Blue. Beyond the see" -Detective Championship Game?
So, I told him to forget it!
Because he'll just end up being called a fool if he goes there.
I thought so too, but I couldn't help it!
I got a letter asking for me to participate.
For Heiji Hattori, to represent the Detective of the West.
Huh, the west?
Yeah, if I represent the west,
the east would of course be...
Shinichi?
Oh, Ran's crimson red!
Well, it's kind of warm today, isn't it? That's why.
Don't tell me that detective kid is going to be there.
I'm sure he'll be there.
No, he won't.
I mean he should know that I'm not, already.
How about it? Don't you and Ran also want to come along?
They say that there are lodgings for people who come along
and that snobbish high school detective Shinichi Kudo
just might be there too! Right?
You're late, Hattori.
Be on time, will you?
We're moving along by the minute, you know!
Oh, I'm sorry,
I kind of took the wrong road you see.
"Hiroo Tsuchio (41)" -Well, let's hurry on to the island!
Everyone's already on board the ship too!
Is Shinichi already there too?
Shinichi Kudo, the high school detective of the east!
They couldn't get a hold of him,
so they don't know if he's going to be there.
No joke?
Well, I guess so.
I mean, it's only natural...
But, do they really have lodgings
for people who come along to the uninhabited island?
Oh, well...
there's only one old lodge on that island so...
the guardians will be spending the night at that hotel,
and after the shooting is over,
we want all of you to come pick them up.
Can I take this kid along with me?
He's sort of like my assistant, you see.
Okay, if he's going to be sleeping in your room together.
Gee, what a big ship it is.
How many people is it capable of taking?
Don't tell me that there is one detective
from all 47 prefectural and city governments?
No, we just called four detectives from the east, west, south and north.
We used this ship only because it stands out
and thought it would make meeting everyone here easier.
-What? -The ship we're boarding is over there.
It's this ship.
Come, hurry on board because we're pressed for time.
Hey, Hattori.
What?
Are you acquainted with that director of Nichiuri TV?
No. I met him for the first time today.
He told me that he'd be wearing the stadium jumper
with the mark of Nichiuri TV so to keep on the look out for him.
Heiji!
You're representing the Kansai district
so you're going to get it if you lose!
Okay! I'll be sure to leave a message behind
that says, "Heiji Hattori was here!"
So, after arriving on the island,
please stay in your rooms and don't leave until dinner time.
So, if anything's going to happen, it will be after dinner.
But be on your guard,
because the match is already started
as soon as you step foot on the island.
Okay.
Roger.
Strange, I figured everyone would be more excited
because this is a Detective Championship Game.
And why did you bring me along?
Don't tell me that you want me to team with you
so that you can win or something?
No, Shinichi Kudo of the east can't come anyway.
That's why I figured you should come and join us too.
It'll be too boring if I win the game just like that.
You're about the only one here that's an equal match for me.
But, you even brought Ran and the others over too.
I wouldn't come to such a corny game alone myself either.
Are you seasick?
Oh, no. It's a hang-over.
It took a while to shoot yesterday so...
I went out drinking with the staff after we finished, and got wasted.
So, you went "overboard".
"Overboard?"
Well, the shop was really high priced.
Hey, mister, this is in the way, laugh, will you? It's too narrow.
Laugh? A narrow heart.
Oh, you were playing on words using "overboard" and "high."
Those two seem pretty sharp.
Detective Championship Game?
Nichuri TV?
We have no such reservation.
Hey, check it out carefully, will you?
Dinner and breakfast are supposed to be included too.
-Yes, but... -What?
What's going on?
Welcome.
I'm the one who will be taking care of you,
my name is Renzo Koya.
Nice to meet you all. I'll show you to your lodge.
Hey, director.
If the high school detective of the east isn't coming,
I'd like to talk something over with you.
Huh?
The representative from the east
arrived here early this morning and is already at the lodge.
What did you say? Is that true?
If I remember correctly, his name was...
I see.
"Please cancel tomorrow's" -This is indeed
"Please cancel tomorrow's" -an isolated island cut off
"dinner reservation." -from the outside world.
There couldn't be a situation better than this for a mystery.
Saguru Hakuba?
Who is he?
"White. Highschool Detective in East" -So, now
"White. Highschool Detective in East" -since the high school detectives
of the east, west, south and north are all here
let's start with self-introduction!
Okay.
Are you're sure you don't mind the cameras not rolling?
I mean, there are no TV staff here at all!
Oh, the crew and TV talent who is MC for this program
are scheduled to be arriving tomorrow.
I wanted all of you to be here a day ahead.
Okay then.
I'm Natsuki Koshimizu, a junior in high school.
I was born in Fukuoka and is representing the south.
But, I've only solved about 100 cases to date,
so am still a beginner,
so take it easy on me, okay?
My name is Junya Tokitsu.
I was born in Tokyo, but since I was raised in Hokkaido,
I'm here representing the north.
I've solved up to 300 cases up to date.
People have been arrested and indicted in 250 of those cases.
But there were people who escaped
or committed suicide among them too.
I'm Heiji Hattori.
I'm pretty well-known in the Kansai district.
The number of cases that I've solved so far is one, two, three...
Well, with over a thousand cases to my name,
I've lost track already!
A thousand cases.
Wow.
Hey, stop bluffing like that.
It's true,
if I include the times I searched for cats in my childhood.
I see, so you're Heiji Hattori.
My dad used to talk a lot about you.
He said that you're a detective with very keen intuition.
Huh?
How come your dad knows me?
Because he's the same as you, Heiji.
Same as me?
Right, Hakuba?
Yeah, my father is a police commissioner.
So, strangely enough,
I lived in an environment similar to yours being that
your father was the leader of the Osaka Prefectural Police.
By the way, how many cases have you solved?
Well, I guess just about 500 cases.
What? That's only half the number compared to mine!
Yes, but that's if I limit the cases
to those that I solved here in Japan.
What?
I've been staying in England as an exchange student for awhile
and only returned to Japan occasionally,
but my nanny would take on requests
for solving cases of her own discretion.
It's so unexpected that
Hakuba who is famous abroad is here representing the east.
Yep, I was so sure that it was going to be Shinichi Kudo.
Right, the high school detective of the east
is none other than Shinichi Kudo, right? It's not you!
My nanny took the call from the director over there.
He said that he wanted me to participate in place of Shinichi Kudo
who he couldn't get a hold of as representative of the east.
Nanny was hurt by the phrase, "in place of"
and pleaded in tears for me to show the world
that Hakuba is the high school detective of the east.
So, I had no choice but to come back from England.
That's the story,
but it seems that I'm not suited to represent the east, am I?
Of course you're not.
Then, why don't we do this?
I'm a guest participant from abroad.
We'll appoint Conan Edogawa here as representative of the east.
This young man here is pretty good at deductions too.
I'm sure he is equal to if not better than the youth called...
what's his name, Kudo.
"What's his name"?
But he's still a child...
Who cares, no problem.
I'd like to go to my room quickly.
I'm pooped.
I'd like to have dinner too.
Oh, right.
Okay. Mr. Koya is making dinner now
so I'll come get all of you when it's ready.
Oh, and I'd like to check your outfits that you'll be wearing
when shooting the program tomorrow,
so please wear it when coming to dinner.
Make sure you wear outfits that suit the Detective Championship Game
as we talked over the telephone.
Huh, what?
There's no such program?
Is that true, Yoko?
No, I asked around the TV station,
but nobody's heard of a special program
called Detective Championship Game.
Are you sure the man was really from Nichiuri TV?
Yeah, he was wearing the stadium jumper of the station
and his name is Hiroo Tsuchio.
What?
There's no director by that name?
-Then who was that man... -That took the two of them?
I see,
that's what you call an outfit suited for the Detective Championship game.
Yeah, I hate to dress like this
other than to school or funerals.
But, what a surprise that you knew that snobbish guy.
Oh, you mean Suguru Hakuba.
I met him when solving a case in the past.
Did he get you that upset?
Yeah, I hate the snobbish way he talks, like he's looking down at you.
-He so much like you. -Oh...
Well, at least you're cute, so way better than him in a way, though.
I see.
But from here, we're enemies.
Don't talk to me no matter what comes up.
Come in?
Excuse me. Dinner's ready, so please come to the dining room.
This sure is an old lodge.
It looks to be fixed here and there, though.
Who owns this place?
I wonder? I hear that some rich person is renting it out
since he has no use for it anymore.
By the way, has she already gone to the dining room?
She?
No, I was just about to go call her now.
Is there a woman here on this island too?
She was with us all the while.
Yes!
Dinner's ready.
Oh, it's it time already?
Oh no! I guess I took too much time!
You mean, she was a woman?
My school has strict rules.
Skirts have to be 3 cm below the knee,
scarves have to be symmetrical right and left,
socks have to be black,
and of course perms aren't allowed.
If we shave our eyebrows, we get suspended.
God knows how many times I was warned about
this naturally brown hair of mine.
But, I guess it's no big deal tonight
because the cameras aren't here yet, right?
Yeah, I guess so.
Hey, you didn't change clothes.
Yes, because unlike you people
the school that I attend in England has no uniform.
Wow, it looks delicious.
Did you make all this, sir?
-Yes. -Huh, where's the director?
When I went to get him at his room a while ago, there was no answer,
so I though he had already come here.
Please show me to his room.
Mr. Tsuchio.
Dinner's ready. Mr. Tsuchio?
No good, I guess he locked it so he could sleep.
Blood.
There's blood on the door knob.
-Do you have a spare key? -No, there is no key to begin with,
because like your rooms, the key can only be locked from inside.
If the rooms are the same, there should be two windows.
Then, let's look inside through the window.
You...
Mr. Tsuchio!
"Gray. Highschool Detective in North" -Mr. Tsuchio!
"Gray. Highschool Detective in North" -The window is locked.
It seems the door was completely locked too.
Then, this is a locked door murder case?
Yes, but obviously that's only if he's dead.
He's alive.
What happened?
What a relief! What happened?
Oh, somebody knocked on the door.
I answered the door. But, there was no one there.
When I was about to go back into the room,
I was suddenly drugged from behind.
Problem number one of the Detective Championship Game!
Solve this locked room mystery.
After solving the mystery, write it down
and bring it to me.
If your deduction is the truth, you will make it to the second level
and as well as allowed to leave this island.
Which means that the battle has already been launched!
Then, is there a hidden camera somewhere?
But, how unexpected.
I thought that the first level was to see through
the fact that this person is a fake director.
Just what do you think you're saying? I'm really...
Quit playing dumb with us.
Back then, when he said you went overboard,
he meant you had a tough time because the shooting
took all the way till after midnight.
And the remark, "laugh" that the girl made after that
means do something about something.
I mean you're no new AD and all.
There's no director that doesn't understand movie language like those.
Besides, that mark of Nichiuri TV that you have on you is strange.
The groove of the eye isn't right.
The real one grooves in the opposite direction.
That's why everyone figured you were a fake and tested you.
Well, you can explain after we make complete the first round though.
Sorry, but count me out.
I've figured out
this locked room trick.
Would you like me to show you?
You've already solved it.
Okay, show us.
No, you can't.
If you do so, the others will also figure out the trick.
So, please write your deduction down
and bring it to me like I mentioned a while ago.
This is the first round, you know, and not the finals.
Don't worry, he wouldn't do it right before our eyes.
Well, as far as I'm concerned,
the result would be the same even if this were to be the finals, though.
What confidence.
I hope that trick isn't something that goes like,
Mr. Tsuchio who was tied up in the locked room,
after locking the door tied himself up, is it?
No way,
because if so, the representative of the west
who untied him would've noticed,
no matter how incapable a detective he is.
How dare you call me incapable?
That's true, it wasn't smart.
You found blood on the door knob,
broke the door down and entered the room.
In that case,
we should've checked things out by looking in from the window
and then decide whether we should break the door down
or crack the window and enter.
Because if Mr. Tsuchio was leaning against the door
or moreover, dead,
at the point that the door is kicked open, the corpse would move,
as well as disperse the evidence.
Stupid, back then...
Overreaching and carrying things too far
for wanting to make it to scene before anyone else does.
Aren't such people considered disqualified as detectives?
Watch your tongue!
He's not disqualified.
Kudo.
Heiji is just a bit too quick tempered.
Hey...
At any rate, I'm going back up to my room on the second floor
and turn my room into a locked room,
so wait for me while having dinner, will you?
It'll take me at least an hour to do so.
An hour?
I see, the time it took Mr. Koya to show us to our rooms,
to the time what happened at this room
took just about the same time.
The trick is an intricate one that requires that much time.
Well, I guess so.
I'd like to say this, just in case, though.
This trick does not call for the foolish, uncouth detective's
ill-mannered actions,
so please keep that in mind.
Well, I'm sure that he won't repeat the same mistake again.
After all, he's got his local reputation as his father's name
as chief of Osaka Police Department to maintain too.
Right, representative of the west?
But...
I like passionate detectives like you.
It's a ship
-that was anchored around here... -What's the matter, Kazuha?
-and took the children. -Well, I have this bad feeling.
The cell phone, it's still not going through?
-The number you have reached... -No,
it's still in the out of service area,
and just keeps repeating that message.
I see.
Hey, Ran, don't you feel something strange?
Like an unidentifiable eerie something
is closing in on Heiji and the others.
I think you're letting your imagination get the better of you.
I'm sure that Heiji is okay and that he'll come back with Conan.
I know, but something bothers me.
The face of Heiji when he was being escorted off
keep twirling around in my head over and over.
How about Conan's cell phone?
You still can't contact him?
Nope, his is no good either.
I wish that the representative of the east,
Shinichi Kudo were there together with Heiji at a time like this.
I would make me feel way better.
The number you have reached is out of service range...
It's the same with Shinichi's cell phone too.
Don't tell me that Shinichi is with them too?
"Purple. Scent of Lavender"
It's out of service range after all.
Well, this is an isolated island.
What, no joke?
I just went to the restroom for a while
and yet there almost nothing left already.
Hey, mister, you're eating too much.
I know, I was starved, you see.
Gosh.
Okay, so now that you're filled, tell us.
Won't you, fake TV director?
Tell us why you're participating as a fake TV director
for this Detective Championship Game.
If this program is to measure our capabilities,
what's your role?
No. I can't tell you that
because if I do, I won't get paid. I bound by contract.
With Nichiuri TV?
Then, will you answer this question?
I was concerned since I set foot into this lodge
about the fragrance of the lavender flower over there.
Now that you mentioned it, there is a lavender flower in our room too.
Yeah.
There's one in my room too.
It seems to be in every room.
And that toolbox that's sitting over there.
There's a meaning to it too, isn't there?
Well, I wonder.
It is the detective's job to figure that out.
That's how I see it, is it not?
True, but since we're separated from the outside world,
we don't have the means to check.
Homicide at Lavender Manor.
The only thing lavenders bring to my mind
is the incident that occurred in Shikoku a year ago.
I've heard of that case too.
The one who was killed was the lady of the mansion.
Miss!
"Young Lady at the Lavender Manor Commits Suicide"
"Motive Unknown. The Door is Locked"
"Possibility of Intruder"
But it was found six months later that she had been murdered.
And? The killer?
Committed suicide before getting caught.
That's what I heard.
What's up?
No, well, you see...
I forgot my cigarettes in my room.
Wow, it's really raining cats and dogs now.
What's the matter? You're drenched.
Did you go look for a cigarette vending machine outside or something?
Oh, no, I just went to check how things were outside.
By the way, don't you think he's a bit too much time?
Yes, it's been more than two hours since then already.
I'll go ask him
how much longer he thinks it will take him.
Okay, please do.
What? He's not in his room?
No, no matter how many times I knock on the door,
there's no answer.
But, the door was locked, so maybe...
I see, he probably completed the locked room
and is watching from somewhere, snickering at us.
If so, I'm sure he'd appear before us
with that boastful look of his.
I'll go check from outside, so wait here.
Let me go with you!
It worries me to let you go alone.
Suit yourself.
Come on. He's still there.
He was smeared with blood, wasn't he?
Yeah. Let's hurry to the room.
You?
Shoots.
How is it, Heiji?
No good! He's really dead.
How are things?
Just as you can see,
he died on the spot after being hit on the head.
The murder weapon is probably that hammer.
It's got blood on it too.
It was probably taken from that toolbox
next to the lavender flowerpot.
Were the windows locked?
Yeah, they were,
nice and tight until I opened them.
The window frame also seems to be tightly in place with a screw.
The entrance door doesn't look to have been tampered with either.
Since there are no other escape holes or doors...
It's a locked room murder.
Moreover, the killers are either
Ms. Koshimizu,
Mr. Koya or Mr. Tsuchio, no?
What? Brat!
Why us?
True.
After Tokitsu left the room saying that
he was going to turn his room on the second floor into a locked room,
we began having dinner at the dining room downstairs.
I left to go to the restroom, and wasn't there for about ten minutes.
A few minutes after I returned,
Mr. Tsuchio went to his room to get his cigarettes
and Mr. Koya went to check on Tokitsu.
If all during that time, Hakuba and you two were together,
it would be most plausible.
Hold it, I was only hired to come here.
By who?
The TV station would never plan a program like this
where somebody would actually die, would they?
I really thought it was a program
that the TV station had planned to do.
I'm an actor and I belong to an acting school.
I received a letter asking to act the role of a TV director.
I was told I'd be given an advance payment of 500,000 yen,
and if the fact that I'm a fake is not revealed,
I was supposed to have received another 500,000 yen.
It's a great job that anybody would jump at, isn't it?
And, now that everything's out in the light?
Even so, if I just go through with the game,
I was told I'd be given half the pay, that's 250,000 yen.
Then, why did you go to your room to get your cigarette,
and yet go outside and get drenched in the rain?
I wanted to use the wireless radio that's in the shed
to make emergency contact.
But...
it was destroyed!
When I came to check the place out three days ago,
it was just fine.
-Honestly? -Yeah.
But, how strange.
You headed for the shed before this murder was committed.
How did you know that this sort of emergency was going to happen?
I just had a premonition.
Honestly.
Then, Mr. Koya, were also called by Mr. Tsuchio?
Yes, I came here two days ago to look after all of you.
I just happened to get time off
from the household that I serve as steward so.
But, you already knew the answer to the locked room murder, right?
Because you told us to write the answer down and take it to you.
I was told to say so if something happened in the locked room.
The order went on to say to sneak the answer sheet
under the toilet mat.
That's a clever way to put it.
As if there's someone else pulling the strings behind the scene.
No, I'm telling the truth.
Whatever the story, I'm in the same boat as you all are.
I was just told to come here as a high school detective
representing the south by that fake TV director.
I hate thunder!
So, please close the window, quick, please.
Yeah.
Don't worry. I'll silence the thunder
as well as the case soon.
What's with him?
At any rate, we three will check the place
so you three suspects wait in the first floor dining room
-till it's done. -If I could have my way,
I would like you to do likewise and wait with them too.
You're much too hot-tempered,
or should I say reckless?
What?
Look at the shattered pieces of glass!
And the footprints of your muddy shoes left on the desk!
What a dreadful sight!
Don't tell me that you opened the lock with your bare hands too.
Yeah, I opened it!
Bug you!
He's venting his anger out on the wrong person.
You really disappoint me.
From what my father told me about you,
I thought you were way more capable.
After taking them to the dining room,
we'll be resuming investigation
but please try not to get in the way,
representative of the west, okay?
Hey, Kudo. Am I wrong?
No. Not at all.
Not at all?
I'm referring to a ship that a man with a mustache,
three high school students and a child boarded!
There's no way you couldn't have seen them at all, right?
What's the matter, Kazuha?
Something bothers me after all
about the look on Heiji's face back then.
Okay, I'll leave behind a message saying,
"Heiji Hattori was here!"
Heiji was here?
Ran, when Heiji said, "He was here..."
Could he have meant...
"Blue, White and Black. Each person's reasoning" -Well, the thing
"Blue, White and Black. Each person's reasoning" -that bugs me most is...
that the killer deliberately made Tokitsu sit on the desk.
This position.
Is there any meaning to it?
One of the reasons may be that
the killer simply wanted the locked room murder to be visible from outside.
However...
And I wonder about the lavender and toolbox.
There seems to be both of them everyone else's room too.
No use staring from outside.
-I'm opening it. -Wait.
-Let me. -Go ahead!
Wires, nails, a wrench, a screw driver,
a drill, a steel ruler, a plier,
glue for wood products,
a saw, a utility knife.
Just as I thought, there's no hammer inside.
It seems that the murder weapon was taken out of here
After all, with a hammer like that,
a man, a woman
or even an elderly person could commit the murder.
Time wise that's true.
The time that those three disappeared from our sight
was from 19:26 and 32 seconds
to 19:39 and 15 seconds, to go to the restroom.
Mr. Tsuchio, who went to his room to get his cigarettes
was gone from 20:06 and 47 seconds to 21:28 and 21 seconds.
And finally Mr. Koya, who came to check on Mr. Tokitsu came to this room
and was gone from 21:30 and 6 seconds to 21:38 and 52 seconds.
Any of the three had enough time to commit the murder.
He even had the seconds recorded.
But, Mr. Koya seems to have been in the kitchen most of the time.
So, he would've been able to hide and move around freely
without having to worry about us watching him.
Well, but the kitchen windows
are all ones that cannot be opened or closed,
and are only there to let the light in.
As for the kitchen door it's here,
that is, in order to go out,
he'll have to pass the dining room, where we are,
so I'm sure Mr. Koya was in the kitchen all the while.
By the way, this is the blueprint of the second floor
and all the four rooms are very similar except for a light difference
in the direction the windows are facing.
You sure work fast.
I've been here a half day earlier than you all, you see.
Come to think of it,
why is there electricity here?
Right...
it's an uninhabited island and yet.
A simple generator seems to be in the shed.
Would you like to go take a look?
We could go check out the wireless radio
that's supposed to be there while we're at it too.
True.
Talk about destroyed...
So this is the generator,
wasn't there a lock to this place?
There should've been a padlock.
I'm sure that Mr. Koya had the lock.
The padlock's
been forced opened!
Talk about a lot of muddy shoe prints...
It's Mr. Tsuchio's,
since he's the only one who came outside after it started raining.
Isn't that right, Hakuba?
Huh? He's gone.
What's with him? He disappeared.
It's gone.
It's not here.
The wire from the toolbox in this person's room is gone after all.
Isn't Hakuba back?
No, wasn't he together with you?
By the way, did you find anything after checking the shed?
Well, sort of.
No way.
The man's drunk.
You guys all claim that you're detectives
but you're all no more than green horns
that look capable on the outside.
Then, let's have them listen
to the deduction of the green-horn, shall we?
I see.
So, that's the story.
No doubt about it,
the culprit is...
that person.
That man.
Right?
He killed Tokitsu and prepared the locked room.
Mr. Renzo Koya.
Well, it's really simple with a little bit of thinking.
Tokitsu said it would take about an hour
to rig his room into a locked room.
In other words, it was a trick that was that intricate.
You naturally went to check him out
just about when the room would be ready and killed him.
It could be carried out very naturally if you used his room
that was prepared for the locked room murder.
So, it wouldn't have been possible for Koshimizu who went to the restroom
right after Tokitsu said so and left.
Nor for Mr. Tsuchio who left 30 minutes later
to his room to get his cigarette
to commit the murder.
In other words, you, Mr. Renzo Koya, who went to see him alone
just before he was found killed in the locked room
is the only one
who could've killed him.
Oh, boy...
How much do you have to disappoint me before you stop?
I'm sorry to say that he's not the one.
Because the one who committed the crime
is one who can unlock and lock doors and windows just by using a wire.
That person is Mr. Tsuchio.
It's you.
Don't be ridiculous!
The padlock that was on the shed that you headed for
after lying that you were going to go get your cigarette.
New traces of it having been forced opened were seen,
moreover, it found wet and thrown into the shed.
In other words, the one who forced the door open was Mr. Tsuchio,
the only one who went outside after it began raining.
On top of that, only the wire was found missing
from the toolbox in your room.
How did he make the locked room, though?
Mr. Tsuchio mentioned that
he came here three days ago to check the place out beforehand.
At that time he probably,
opened a small hole in the window of that room.
Then, after killing Mr. Tokitsu tonight,
he went outside from the window,
and from the hole in the glass he made previously,
used the wire to lock the window,
He probably figured beforehand that Hattori
would break through the window glass later
and make a grand entrance into the room,
making it impossible to find the hole made in the glass.
He then went to destroy the wireless radio in the shed,
to breed anxiety in us and corner us mentally.
He was ready to kill another one of us after that!
Isn't that right?
No way!
I don't think so.
Even if he were able to predict that
Heiji would break through the glass window,
he wouldn't have been able to tell
which of the four windows he would break through!
Besides, although Heiji is hot tempered,
I'm sure he would've noticed if there was a hole.
Never mind the hot tempered.
But the one who forced opened the padlock of the shed
is unmistakably him.
Yeah, it's true that this man has a bad habit,
but that's about it.
Or, is it that you have an equation in your head
that says, "A thief is the killer?"
I guess I goofed.
So, what with the locked room, trick?
Yep, it's a super simple trick!
First, you remove all the screws holding the window frames in place.
Then, you remove the windows.
Finally, cut all the screws short using pliers and all set!
Then you insert the head of the screw that had been cut off
back into the window frame,
and put glue on the area around the window frame.
Then, you go outside and fix the entire window in place.
In other words, it looks like the window is fixed on with screws,
but the inside is not.
The window was just glued on.
-And, the one who could've done that is... -Hold it.
Right, the very last person who went to Mr. Tokitsu's room...
Mr. Koya.
No one other than you could've done it!
What're you talking about, Heiji? He's...
You caught Tokitsu who was taking
his good old time absorbed in the trick off guard,
hit him and killed him.
No, I hate to interrupt you but...
Mr. Koya couldn't have carried the trick out.
I've got proof too.
This screw with the head cut off that I found in Tokitsu's room!
This guy...
Don't tell me that...
"Green. Message from Heiji" -Well?
"Green. Message from Heiji" -This is what you call
"Green. Message from Heiji" -conclusive evidence!
I guess you couldn't retrieve all of them.
Right!
You never know where the screw would fly off to
if you cut them with pliers.
Just as I thought.
So, it was you
who killed Tokitsu after all.
Hattori.
Tokitsu said that it would take him an hour to prepare the trick,
because he included the time for the glue to dry.
No matter how quickly he removed the screws and cut them,
even for instant glue to dry, it would take over 30 minutes.
In other words, Tokitsu had planned to finish
what he had to in less than 30 minutes
and wait outside for the glue to dry.
So, the person who could kill Tokitsu who was still in his room
is the one who got up right after dinner started.
You're the only one who could've done it!
You probably faked going to the restroom
and headed for Tokitsu's room.
You probably told him that you also figured out the trick
so you wanted to compare answers and went inside.
You caught him off guard and killed him.
Then, you completed the trick that he was working on
and created the locked room.
You then entered from the front door
and came back to the dining room where we were,
as if nothing happened. That's it!
But, this is based on the assumption that you could've done it.
There's no proof.
That's why I used the screw of the wireless radio that was in the shed.
Even if you know that you picked all the screws up,
me showing you this would make you anxious, right?
Moreover, Mr. Koya is suspected, and once you think it's not yourself,
you inevitably go off guard.
I figured you would look towards the place you hid the screws,
so I kept watching you,
but I didn't think you keep them on you, in your pocket.
It surprised me...
seeing you counting them.
Well, you pretended to be afraid of the thunder and picked one up,
so I figured you had one on you.
You knew we were checking the shed.
You weren't afraid of thunder,
but rather, it's proof that you were watching outside.
You bent down then to pick up the screw
that you failed to pick up previously, right?
Am I wrong?
Oh, that's probably...
To hide the hole for your pierced ear.
You covered your ears to hide it, right?
Huh, pierce...
But...
That's why you were wearing a headphone on the ship, right?
Because if your hair blew in the sea breeze,
it would reveal your pierced ears.
Well, there are a lot of students with pierced ears in England,
so I didn't even bother to notice.
But, I thought your high school was really strict
that you could never be allowed pierced ears.
Yes, but it's okay already.
I'm already 20,
and I've graduated high school two years ago.
I took my old uniform out to hide what I could,
but goofed.
I even went as far as to talk about school rules
so that I would look like a high school girl.
But, why did you gather us high school detectives
and do something like this?
I wanted to find out about something.
And, what's that?
The homicide at Lavender Manor.
You wanted to know who the high school detective that solved it was, right?
Yes.
Then, you mean it was... Tokitsu?
Although the name and details of the case wasn't written in the papers.
Yes, he happened to drop by at the mansion
while traveling through Shikoku,
solved the locked room case and left without saying his name.
Because of him,
my best friend who was working as a housekeeper there was suspected.
She was suspected on the grounds
that she was with the lady of the house, just two of them together.
I also went to that mansion as a detective,
a month before that man appeared.
My best friend asked me to investigate the case
because it could be a homicide.
But, I couldn't come up with anything.
I couldn't think of anything other than the fact that
she had locked herself in her room and committed suicide.
Then, why was your best friend suspected?
The high school detective that came two months later
found outside the window of her room
scattered screws with heads cut off
as well as the fact that the window was only pasted on with glue.
You mean you overlooked it?
Overlooked it my foot.
The man called Tsuchio
disguised himself as a cleaning staff
and set up the trick.
He probably rigged the window so that it would come off easily,
when he planned to come back to rob the house later.
That's why when you heard of the Lavender Manor,
you went pale and wanted to escape from the island.
Six months after the incident,
Tokitsu jumps onto the trick,
as if to boast his power of deduction,
reports to the police and the media that this is a homicide.
"New Truth Disclosed on Suicide of the Lady of Lavender Manor"
"Police Conclude it to be Locked Room Homicide!"
"Suspect Still Denies Charges"
If the rust of the screws were checked,
it would've been obvious whether it had anything
to do with the case or not.
Tokitsu, realized that something was not right,
so he didn't disclose his name.
That's why I couldn't tell which high school detective it was.
The only clue I had
was the message that my best friend left me before she died.
A high school detective that speaks with a strange accent
suspects me.
Help me. Help me, Natsuki!
That's all she left behind.
I see.
"A strange accent"
Since I've been living abroad for a while,
sometimes my Japanese is funny.
Hattori speaks with a super Kansai accent,
and Tokitsu talks in old Japanese.
That's why you gathered us all here.
Yes, moreover,
only you three had strong connections with the police too.
Which means that Kudo wasn't included to begin with?
Okay.
Yes, I just used his name to call Hakuba over
because Kudo is famous.
And, at this lodge where you gathered all the detectives,
you first put Mr. Tsuchio to sleep and tied him up,
created a locked room just like the one at Lavender Manor
and got hold of the target you were after.
Yes, if I put the necessary tools in the room
filled with the fragrance of lavender,
the high school detective would recall the case immediately
and see through the trick.
That mansion was really virtually buried in lavender.
Isn't that right,
Mr. Renzo Koya who used to work as the steward of that mansion?
Yes, because the lady of the house loved them very much.
Miss!
Then, why did you call him here?
He knew why the lady of the house committed suicide
and yet he didn't say a word about it.
That's because...
Miss, please don't take anymore medicine!
Quiet, let me do as I please!
I couldn't say a word
to protect the honor of the lady of the house.
I thought that suspicion against her
would clear as investigations progressed.
"Suspect of Locked Room Murder Commits Suicide"
I never imagined something like that would happen.
Please accept my apologies.
But... hold it.
If you called these two here that you have a grudge against...
Right, nobody will come for you.
Back then, I told the captain of the ship that
if he can't keep a secret,
I'm not going to pay him the remainder,
to make sure he wouldn't talk.
I couldn't afford having him run away on me,
even if he were to realize what my plan was.
I had that in mind too.
As for Tokitsu, he kept explaining his mistaken deduction
of the murder at Lavender Manor up to the time he was killed by me.
He was really someone not worth bothering with.
So, you're the one who broke the wireless radio too.
Of course I'm the one who broke it.
We all die together.
I'm sorry, sonny.
No need to apologize!
They'll come to save us, I know!
You said that you came here a half day earlier than us, right?
Didn't you come here with your own cruiser?
No, I just happened to arrive
earlier than scheduled at the harbor.
I heard that it was a lodge that was not in use for a while
and that I was going to be sleeping together with many people so...
I looked for a ship that recently shipped daily necessities and food
to an uninhabited island,
and had them bring me here,
after paying a hefty sum of money.
Which means that nobody knows you're here?
No, and how about you, haven't you told anybody?
Well, I sort of did, but...
She's kind of dense.
What?
A sound?
What's this sound?
Don't tell me that the generator also broke down.
It's not the sound of the generator!
Then, what's this sound?
Heiji!
It's Kazuha!
Kazuha brought a ship along!
Why?
Heiji left a message and landmark behind.
Yeah, I leave a message saying "Heiji Hattori was here!"
Oh, there he is! It's Heiji and Conan too!
Really, it's Heiji!
God, if you spit it out right away,
you wouldn't have had to take on five throws over the shoulder.
It was six.
What?
I'm glad there are hot-blooded detectives like you around.
I smear the door knob with blood and you break the door down,
then you crack the glass window and break in.
Thanks to you, the dead body ends up leaning against the window.
If you charge forward body and all and the entire window falls off,
that's it.
Sorry, that I'm so hot tempered and rash.
Nope, to believe that a person is alive
till you confirm the person's death
is what a famed detective is all about.
Right, sonny?
If god would allow me to...
I would really have liked to have a Detective Championship
with both of you.
If I could only go back to my high school days without worry.
And? Is Kudo there?
I'm not sure.
Of course he's not.
Next Conan's Hint:
Local newspaper.
-Haibara, where is your home town? -Doc's place.
-No way. -Indeed.
Yeah.