Even a gigantic wall that seems to block the path.
Turns out to a large door if viewed from a different angle.
Here comes the one hour summer special!
A serial killer tries to murder a bride and groom
at a wedding party full of cops.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
You did it.
Finally! Finally the day has come!
Defeating all my rivals,
I am now going to have eternal love with her!
Ms. Sato!
Takagi!
Yumi? Is that Yumi?
No, it is not Yumi that I'm going to marry.
Not you, Yumi!
Congratulations, Yumi!
I'm happy for you, Yumi!
Wait a second!
I can't talk?
I can't move my body either.
Please help, Chiba!
Congratulations.
Hey! Chiba, how can you eat a hamburger now?
Inspector Megure?
-Right, left. Right... -It's no good.
Takagi...
Congratulations, Takagi.
No. This is not what you think, Mr. Shiratori.
Gosh, what should I do?
This is bad.
Ms. Sato!
Congratulations...
Takagi!
Ouch.
That hurts...
It was a dream. That hurts, but I'm glad it was only a dream.
"Love Story of Metropolitan Detectives: Fake Wedding"
This is yours.
-Thanks. -No problem.
Well, that was a nice wedding.
It was.
But it would've been nicer if I caught that bouquet.
Oh, please. You're too young for that.
Or do you have someone that proposed to you already?
Well, not really.
I just want to wear a wedding dress.
Then I'll get you a cheap rental one.
You can wear it and take a picture of yourself.
Nevermind.
It'll still be expensive though.
No, please don't!
-Come on! It's just for a little while. -The voice sounds familiar.
Come on!
What are you...
Officer Takagi?
-You're going to get married? -Congratulations!
Well, no...
Why do I have to see them at a time like this?
So who's the bride?
Don't be foolish, Dad. It must be Officer Sato.
Wrong answer!
The bride is me!
Yumi...
-You are Yumi Miyamoto? -What? I thought you liked...
I thought you liked Officer Sato, didn't you?
Well, it's a long story.
Well, well.
You guys look awesome together.
Inspector Shiratori.
Why don't you get married with her right now?
Yeah, that's a good idea, darling!
Hey, Yumi.
Miwako.
You know what's going on, right?
You guys are the target today.
Yes, I know that all too well!
And you're also going too far!
Yes. I know.
-Hey... -What in the world is happening here right now?
Well, actually...
Inspector Megure!
What? Someone is trying to kill them?
Why Takagi and Yumi though?
Actually, they are the fake target.
The true target is the bride and the groom who called us for help.
Six months ago, a masked robber broke into the bride's house.
She was lucky because the groom happened to be there and chased him out.
But the robber said this before running away...
You...
I will never forgive you.
But that's what typical bad guys usually say, isn't it?
Why do they have to pretend to be the target?
It wouldn't be like this if it were a plain robbery.
We found fingerprints on a cooking knife
that happened to match the fingerprints of a man,
who is the suspect of four robbery cases.
The robber took six lives during that time.
Firstly, he broke into the house silently, so nobody noticed him.
Then he killed the victim by stabbing the throat with a knife.
After he took all the valuables
and set the house on fire, he immediately ran away.
And the night before yesterday,
a piece of paper was found in the bride's mailbox.
It said, "Happy marriage. My present should be coming to you soon."
I see.
Now I understand why you guys are disguised as the bride and groom.
But why does it have to be Officer Takagi and Officer Yumi?
What?
Are you saying that I'm not good enough for him?
Well, no...
What else could we do?
The bride, Rei Masudo, and the groom, Masateru Taira look like this.
Here.
I see.
They look just like Takagi and the girl on the police car.
Really?
Then, does the real wedding has been cancelled?
No. The real wedding will be held, as the bride really wanted to.
Well, police officers will be standing at the building entrance
so people with no invitation cannot come in.
So I suppose the only chance the killer can attack them
is when the bride and groom come out of the church after the ceremony.
That's when Takagi and Yumi will come to play.
Of course, they'll be wearing protective vests.
Plus, all the wedding attendants will be undercover officers.
Is it really going to be okay though?
You never know how the killer is going to attack you, you know.
Don't worry about that.
If anything happens, Miwako is going to come and save us.
-Right? -Yeah.
I will save Takagi first though.
Gosh! You choose affection over friendship?
I can't believe it!
What can I say?
It is more likely that the groom is going to be attacked
because he is the one who chased the killer out.
Besides, you are too close to him.
Miwako.
I'm sorry. You look just like my friend.
Sorry if I'm wrong,
but you came to the wedding ceremony of Mr. Taira and Ms. Masudo?
Yes.
Then, all of you as well?
Yeah.
It's going to be at the third ceremony hall at 5 o'clock, right?
All right, see you at the hall then.
Hey.
Good luck, Rei.
Let's see, the third ceremony hall is that way, I think.
Hi, Ms. Masudo.
I'm Karube.
Thank you for the invitation.
This is the first time we see each other in person, right?
Yeah.
All right, looking forward to see you at the ceremony hall.
They completely believe that you're Ms. Masudo.
Does she look that much like her?
Maybe it's a sign that you guys are a perfect match.
Inspector Shiratori...
Maybe that's why I had that dream this morning.
All right, I don't want you to get into unnecessary trouble.
You guys wait in your room until the ceremony.
-Yes, sir! -Yes, sir!
Actually, people are coming in and out of this hall,
so why don't you wait in the other room?
-Yes, sir! -Yes, sir!
Now, we should talk to the bride and groom about the situation.
-Yeah, we should. -Yes!
See you later then, Mouri!
Yes, sir! Please be careful!
Hey, why don't you go with them?
What?
You're that famous Detective Mouri.
You should go and help them.
You're right.
-Hey! Wait, Inspector! -Dad!
-I'm coming, too! -Hey, Conan!
-Excuse me. -Do I know you?
I'm sorry. You look just like my friend.
Hey, hey.
What are you talking about, Rei?
Today is an important day that we've been working on together.
Please don't say that we should cancel it now.
But, Masateru, somebody is trying to kill us.
What if something happens to the guests we invited here today?
Don't worry. He isn't going to come.
Trust me.
But...
Sorry to intrude.
Inspector.
How is it? Any news?
So far, nothing.
We put our officers on the inside and outside of this hall.
Plus, we're going to be with you guys when you move around.
So there's nothing to worry about.
See? You don't need to worry about anything.
By the way, who is the gentleman behind you?
He is Kogoro Mouri, a detective.
He just happened to be here today.
Hello.
That famous detective?
So you're the Sleeping Kogoro?
I'll be helping you guys. I'll try my best.
Now, I need you to tell me about the incident
that happened six months ago in detail.
All right.
It was a snowy night,
actually midnight, past 12 o'clock.
I woke up as I heard a weird noise.
I tried to turn on the light, but it didn't turn on somehow.
It was weird.
So I went to where the noise was coming from.
The man saw me and tried to attack me with the knife that he had.
I ran away desperately in the darkness.
But he caught me at the front door.
Seriously, I thought I was going to die.
But my husband came from the front door and saved me.
Actaually, I had a bad feeling that night,
because she told me that her parents were out on a trip,
and there were only two elderly servants in her house.
Then, he and the robber started fighting.
Hurry and call the police!
So I went back to my room and called the police.
When I came back, the man was telling Masateru something,
and he ran away.
So that's when he said, "I will never forgive you"?
-Yeah. -So, were you both okay?
I didn't have any injury at all,
but he was injured on his left hand.
I landed on my left wrist at a bad angle
while struggling with the robber
and I broke my left wrist and thumb.
I actually had a cast on my left arm until last week.
But we should've gone to that place
if we knew that things were going to be like this.
Where is that place?
Her father told her that we should leave Japan for a while
because such a dangerous man was trying to hurt her.
So he bought us a cottage in Hawaii.
That sounds good!
There, we don't need to worry about a robbery like the other one
because we got all the security systems in the house.
What do you mean "the other one"?
There was a robbery in your house as well?
Yeah. It was in his house.
It happened while she and I were out.
Anything stolen?
Nothing.
Just that my computer was on after the robbery.
Excuse me.
This is Megure.
Hey, Chiba.
What? There's a burned dead body with the throat slashed?
Yes.
It was found in an empty warehouse by Teimuzu River.
It was a man between the age of 30 to 40 years old,
wearing a dark blue suit with a white tie.
I also got important information from the forensic officer just now.
Under his left fingernails...
You found fingerprints from the burglar and serial killer?
A white tie, so it was formal attire.
Hey, did your computer have the guest list for the wedding in it?
Yeah. We made that in his room together.
That means the burned dead body could be one of guests on the list.
The killer murdered him in order to get the invitation.
So it is possible that the killer is already in this wedding hall.
We have to cancel the wedding.
Stop all the weddings in this wedding hall
and get all the people out of here!
I don't want so many people here with a killer on loose.
It's best to get everyone out now.
-Yes, sir! -Yes, sir!
Hold on a minute, Inspector.
It's a wedding.
You can't just cancel and ruin our important day
without concrete evidence that the killer is here.
But, Mr. Taira,
it is likely that you're going to be attacked,
because you fought the robber that broke into Ms. Masudo's house.
Also, a blackmail was sent to Ms. Masudo's mailbox two days ago.
And now, we found a burned dead body
with his throat slashed in the warehouse.
Not only the method of homicide was the same,
even the serial killer's fingerprints were also found on the victim's nail.
Not to mention that the victim was dressed in formal wear,
and after someone broke into your apartment,
your computer that was off was turned on when you came back.
It is reasonable to think that the robber was the serial killer.
He stole the guest list for this wedding from your computer,
called someone on the list
and murdered him in order to get the invitation.
And with that invitation, the killer may be here
in this wedding hall right now.
That's right. He's trying to take revenge on you at your ceremony.
But we don't even know if the dead body was one of our guests or not.
Inspector Megure, we got something for the bride and groom.
It needs to be opened right now.
What is that?
Who gave you that?
Well, the hall staff gave me this,
so I don't know where this came from.
Hey, hey!
How could you bring such an unidentified thing here in this situation?
Well, but...
Actually, I've checked it already.
All right, I see.
Oh, it's from Ms. Shimizu.
You know, our chat friend.
Then this must be that video.
"Chat friend"?
We are into this internet website of hot springs right now.
And we're planning to have a party after the ceremony
with the people on the website.
And this is the video we are planning to play during the party.
We asked Ms. Shimizu to check it before the party.
I guess she finally finished editing it.
Let me take a look.
A day with Mr. Taira and Rei.
Last month, Mr. Taira chased a robber out.
Their relationship has become closer and tighter
and they have finally got engaged.
Now, what does their lovely life look like? Let's take a look.
-What? You came already? -Yes.
Where is this?
-The front door of my apartment. -Wait a second.
I'll get ready real quick, okay?
All right.
Is Ms. Shimizu the one shooting this?
Yes. We found out that we live close to each other.
So we became close friends in the real world as well.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
-We're heading to Tropical Land, right? -Yes.
You put your key on the light.
Do you always put it there?
Yes, it's my habit.
That means Ms. Shimizu could pick up the key
and break into your house any time.
She's not that kind of person!
She was the one who suggested
that we should report the robbery to the police.
She suggested it? You didn't tell the police about the robbery?
Yeah, because nothing was stolen.
But just in case,
the date of the wedding was postponed to the next day
than what was written on the list.
Even if the robber broke into my house and saw the list,
he can't come here.
But still, the killer could've called someone from the guest list,
pretending to be your friend
and confirm when the wedding was going to be
or even tell him to come see him, right?
Then, why don't the bride and groom go and see their guests in person?
The bad man may be there pretending to be your friend, right?
Right.
Seeing the guests in person?
What if the killer attacks them?
Well, seeing them in person maybe impossible,
but we can hide in the next room and check them out.
That sounds reasonable under this situation.
It's worth trying.
We don't want to trigger the killer's criminal act
by cancelling the ceremony all of a sudden.
That's true.
Will you please confirm the guests?
Okay.
Sure.
Sato, tell Takagi and Yumi
that the killer may already be in this building
and that there's a possibility that they are going to be attacked.
Understood.
And one more thing, Sato.
You need to stay here to protect the real bride and groom.
Yes, sir!
Masateru, I'm so scared.
Don't worry. I'm with you.
Hey, guys! Look at me!
Tell me, how do I look?
Do I look good?
Really? Yumi, are you going to get married?
Are you kidding me?
I'm not going to get married.
It's part of my job!
Hey, Yumi.
I don't think you should be talking about this mission to outsiders.
Yeah, I know that, idiot!
Don't you interrupt my phone conversation, okay?
I'm sorry.
What? That man's voice?
No, it's from the television.
Gosh. She is totally opposite from a while ago.
Girls are so unpredictable.
The bride is me!
Anyway, why was I having that dream this morning?
I know we are the scapegoat of the bride and groom
but we don't have to have a wedding ceremony.
That must be a prophetic dream.
There's a subconscious desire deep inside your head
that you want to marry Kitada.
You're just not aware of it yet.
What? That can't be true.
Kitada? Why that nerd?
But people say, "Truth often comes out from lies."
I think it's fate that you and Kitada will be together!
Prophetic dream? Subconscious desire?
No way!
Ms. Sato.
That's nonsense.
There's no such thing as prophetic dreams or subconscious desires.
There's no truth behind them.
What are you talking about, Officer Takagi?
What are you doing here anyway?
You should be waiting in that room. Inspector told you so, right?
Yeah.
What do you mean by that?
You shouldn't be listening to our conversation!
That's right.
Okay. Let's go, Ms. Sato!
Please, stay still.
Why did you have to break your arm just before our wedding?
Ms. Sato.
What is wrong with that couple?
Ms. Sato?
How is it?
Well...
Is there anybody that you do not know?
Is there?
Yes.
I have never seen that person.
The man with tanned skin, brown hair and sunglasses.
And also that skinny man with bobbed hair.
And the man with the beard and glasses.
That's all.
I think the last guy is the most suspicious one.
Huh? Why do you say so, Ran?
Because he was taking pictures of a lot of people
saying that they looked like his friend or something like that.
Then he could be my uncle, Uncle Gunji, because he's a photographer.
But you don't know what he looks like, right?
No.
He used to play with me when I was little.
Back then, he was much skinnier and had no beard.
But since he started working internationally as a photographer,
I haven't seen him at all.
Then what about the other two?
Especially that guy who doesn't take off his sunglasses
even inside the building.
Maybe he is my instructor, Mr. Shimabukuro,
who gave me snowboarding lessons before.
I met Masateru at his snowboarding lesson.
That's why we invited him.
I see.
I quit snowboarding already though.
I think I couldn't recognize him
is because his face was always covered with goggles and a hat.
I understand.
Then what about the man with bobbed hair?
All I can think of right now
is that he is the administrator of the hot spring website.
His name is Mr. Karube, I think.
A hot spring website?
Administrator?
Inspector, internet sites have administrators.
Of course I know that!
He is very shy that he didn't want to come to a party we had before.
We talked to him and finally convinced him to attend our wedding,
so this is the first time we actually got to see him.
But that person seemed to know who you were.
He talked to Officer Yumi who was pretending to be you.
A few days ago, I sent him a summer gift with my picture in it,
so he should know how I look like.
Inspector.
I think we have to call them out, get their fingerprints
and see if it matches the serial killer's fingerprint.
No.
They came here for our wedding. We can't do that!
But there's no other way to find the killer.
Hey, how did you figure out that it was the bad man's fingerprints?
The criminal is a suspect of four different homicide cases
and his fingerprints were found from one of the murder scenes.
We found it on the earring the victim was wearing.
There was a piece of gloves on the victim's teeth.
Which tells us that the killer put his left hand on the victim's mouth
and stabbed the throat but the victim struggled and bit off the gloves.
The killer then tried to silence the victim with his bare left hand
and that was when he touched her earring.
We found the same fingerprints on the cooking knife
that the killer left at Ms. Rei's house.
Not only we got the fingerprints,
but we also got the pattern of his left palm on the knife.
That's how we found
the fingerprints on the earring was from the killer's left ring finger.
Inspector, then the killer wasn't wearing gloves
when he broke into Ms. Masudo's house?
No, I heard he was wearing gloves.
Maybe he grabbed the cooking knife with his bare hand before he broke in.
The killer didn't leave any of his murder weapons behind
in the first four cases.
I guess he didn't think that he would be chased off by Mr. Taira.
So he panicked and forgot to wipe off his fingerprints.
Yeah, since no fingerprints were found other than on the cooking knife.
Let me ask you, Mr. Taira.
Was the front door locked when you came to save Ms. Masudo?
No. It was not locked.
That's because
the house was totally dark,
so I was groping around searching for the front door.
Then I found the door and opened it.
Is there anything wrong?
No. Actually, I think I saw something.
What was it? Tell me.
Please remember.
Excuse me, this is not a place for interrogation.
Huh?
What is it, Ran?
Look at those three men.
The bobbed hair guy has a bandage on his left pinky and ring finger.
The bearded guy with glasses has a Band-Aid on his ring finger.
And the one with sunglasses is keeping his left hand
in his pocket all the time.
They may be trying to avoid leaving their fingerprints anywhere.
All right then.
Why don't you call them and get their fingerprints or whatever?
It will prove whether the killer is here or not.
I don't think any of our guests is a criminal though!
But Conan is already out there asking around right now.
What? Why is that brat always like that?
Mouri.
Now what?
So what happened to their left hand?
The man who had a bandage on said
he sprained his ring finger when he was playing baseball.
The one with Band-Aid slammed his hand with the door of his house.
The guy with his hand in his pocket said it's just his habit.
That's right, he's wearing sunglasses indoors to hide a stye on his eye.
Oh, I remember it now!
I saw it.
I saw it when Masateru came to save me.
It was...
It was a stye that I saw on his right eye!
What?
A stye?
Then the man with sunglasses is the serial killer?
But stye usually disappears within a week.
A stye.
Now I know who the serial killer is.
What?
You're telling me maybe the serial killer is here already?
In this wedding ceremony hall?
Yes.
He killed one of the guests in order to get the invitation,
so he can get in here.
You guys are the scapegoat for the bride and groom,
you have to be careful.
In fact, I have some other ideas about the suspect as well.
What? Other ideas?
-What is it? Is there someone else you can think of? -Hey, Yumi.
I need you to do me a favour.
What is it?
Sorry. Takagi, could you leave us for a moment?
It's girl's talk, you know.
Oh, okay!
I'll go to the washroom. No, I just went to washroom a while ago.
Anyway, I'm going again.
Of course.
I knew it was going to be like this.
So I brought this.
See?
Thanks, Yumi.
We can't just judge who the killer is by his face.
Well, Ms. Masudo is not sure who those three guys are,
so we should take their fingerprints
and see if it matches the killer's before the wedding starts.
Please, you cannot do that.
What if nothing's found?
What if they're all innocent?
I understand,
but the only information we have about the criminal
is the fact that he had a stye on his right eye.
But that information can't prove anything
because his stye must have healed since it was six months ago.
Don't you remember his voice?
You heard him saying "I will never forgive you", right?
Yeah. But he was wearing a mask so his voice wasn't that clear.
If the voice left an impression,
we would've told you six months ago.
Inspector Megure.
The hall staff is saying that we should start the ceremony soon.
I understand. Let's start then.
-Hey, hey! -We'll be there soon!
Wait!
Hey, you...
Let's go.
Mr. Taira.
Mr. Taira!
Regardless, the wedding is still going on no matter what happens.
If you guys are still worried, why don't you guys attend our ceremony
and check what's going on?
I really don't expect the killer to show anyway.
Hey, Mr. Taira!
Just leave him now.
Let him do whatever he wants to do.
You know we cannot do that.
Now, I'll tell you what I think about this case,
but it is up to you whether you believe it or not.
Okay, Inspector Megure?
It is up to you.
Huh? How come nobody is around?
It's Takagi! I'm coming in!
I'm coming in.
What? No way!
No one's here.
What is this?
There you are, Takagi.
I just got a call from Inspector Megure.
He said you should stay in this room until he tells you what to do.
He really said that? What about Yumi?
Oh, Inspector gave her instructions and she left.
Okay.
But where is she going?
Now here comes the bride, being escorted by her father.
Please welcome with applause.
Wait a minute.
It's been half a year, hasn't it?
My two friends!
That's him!
-Arrest him! -Yes, sir...
Hey! Don't you even think about it!
You think I didn't know cops are among those attendants?
Don't worry.
I'll disappear after cutting these two people into pieces.
Please, no more stupid acting.
Officer?
What are you talking about?
I'm the one who broke into that girl's house six months ago!
Are you joking?
You gotta stop this. You look pathetic.
There's no way that you are the killer.
How?
How do you know that he isn't the killer?
What do you mean?
Six months ago,
when you went to Ms. Rei's house and chased the robber off,
the inside of the house was totally dark.
That means it was impossible to recognize him by his appearance.
You obviously couldn't know by just looking at him, right?
It's the voice.
Really?
I thought you said the killer's voice wasn't distinct enough to identify.
I just saw him a while ago.
The police officer who has the same voice as this masked man.
Really? Where did you see him?
I don't know.
I think it was inside the building.
I have to be right.
No one would play such a joke here.
We don't have any friend who would do things like this.
You're right. This guy is my subordinate.
But it's weird.
He was by the Teimuzu River
and he got here just a minute ago.
It's Officer Chiba.
What?
Now, let me ask you again.
Why did you think that he was not the serial killer?
Well, that's...
Also, tell us why you opened the package you received earlier,
without even knowing who it was from.
Normally, people wouldn't open it without checking what's inside
because there might be some dangerous things in it.
What was your confidence based on?
Yes. The confidence that made you think
that no dangerous objects would be delivered to you,
or no such person as "serial killer" would be coming.
I know why you were so confident.
Because you already
murdered that serial killer...
at the empty warehouse by Teimuzu River.
You murdered the serial killer!
Come on! You have to explain it to me!
How come only I have to stay in this dressing room?
Well, they are busy right now.
Then tell me where Yumi and Ms. Sato went.
Just tell me anything.
Sato should be with you right now to protect you.
Well, she's not here.
What? Why not?
That's why I'm asking because I don't see them here.
Hey, we're on a mission right now.
You got to be more serious, Ms. Sato.
What? I murdered the serial killer?
All I said was the serial killer wouldn't come to this wedding
where all the cops are waiting for him.
What does it have to do with murdering him?
You know what?
Before asking me such dumb questions,
you should investigate who those three guys are
because they are people my wife doesn't know.
No. They are clean.
Because all those guys talked to Yumi
whom they thought was Ms. Rei.
I'm sorry. You look just like my friend.
Hi, Ms. Masudo.
Hey.
If one of them murdered and was disguised as the serial killer,
he would have avoided contact with the bride until he takes action.
That's right.
It is too risky to talk to her
because you don't know what the killer said to the bride.
And the bride heard their voice.
They wouldn't know whether she remembers what kind of voice they had.
So if the killer did come here,
he wouldn't want to talk with her too early.
Well, we didn't notice it until Mr. Mouri pointed it out.
Then, what about their left ring finger?
They were all hiding it, remember?
It was just a coincidence.
But let's just that say one of them robbed Ms. Masudo's house.
We found the fingerprint on the cooking knife,
but the robber was wearing gloves.
Which means, he touched the knife with his bare hands beforehand.
If so, then it is less likely
that they remember which hand touched the cooking knife.
Therefore, they would be hiding both of their hands.
Except you, though.
You knew that the police was going to ask you about the fingerprint.
So you lied that you broke your left thumb and wrist
while struggling with the robber,
to hide your left arm with a cast.
That way, you can avoid leaving your fingerprints behind
so the police won't suspect you.
You did it because the fingerprint left on that cooking knife was yours.
You touched the knife while struggling with the robber.
Also, we found only your left hand fingerprint
because your right hand was holding something.
Do you remember what Ms. Rei said?
She groped her way through the dark house and ran.
But she was caught by the robber at the door.
Then you came to save her
and she saw that the robber had a stye on his right eye.
If she could see a stye on his eye when you came to save her,
indicates that you were holding a flashlight at the time.
-That tells me... -That tells me...
that he knew that the electric wiring in her house had been cut
way before he came to save Ms. Masudo.
In conclusion, he was also the robber.
Well, luckily, you were fighting the robber on a rug.
Thus, you left only your fingerprint on the cooking knife.
Otherwise, your fingerprints may have been on the floor.
The reason why you saved Ms. Rei
was because you felt sorry for her while robbing her house, right?
Being betrayed by him,
the robber was waiting for the opportunity for his revenge.
But what you did was you let him break into your house,
display the old data about the wedding on your computer
and make him believe that the wedding was yesterday.
Then you found him wandering around this building yesterday,
trying to take revenge on you.
Saying that you want to apologize,
you took him to the warehouse by Teimuzu River and killed him.
Well, am I wrong?
Yeah, that's almost right.
But the reason I saved this girl
was because I could get more money that way than killing her.
You! How could you say that?
I tried to explain it to that fool.
He didn't get it, so I killed him.
All he could do was to open safes. He was a useless man after all.
Yes, that's right.
Just like the police!
Showing a knife in front of a serial killer?
You police are helpless!
Darn it!
Hey, Conan!
Don't even think about it!
Only police officers are here other than the bride's father!
You cannot run away!
Run away?
My life's over once my fingerprints are checked.
If so...
I may as well kill as many people as I can with me
to the other side.
Yumi?
Yumi!
Sorry!
I am not Miwako.
But that's Ms. Sato's clothes, right?
Right! We changed!
People didn't notice because I fixed my hair in Japanese style.
You changed your hairstyle?
The reason why I was clinging to you
was to make Miwako wants to wear a wedding dress.
She was trying hard to become your bride.
Because she has muscles on her back,
the protective vest could not fit in.
So where's Ms. Sato?
I took her to the ceremony hall as Inspector told me to
but I don't know what happened later.
Yumi!
One down.
No way!
Did you know?
Corset wires are pretty hard.
Miwako?
Sato?
Get out of my way!
Hey!
I can't use my martial art skills in a wedding dress.
Good!
I forgot.
-Get out of my way, kid! -Conan!
Ran, you gotta stop him!
I had to do that, right?
-I guess so. -Ms. Sato!
Wait!
Ms. Sato.
It's over!
Ms. Sato!
Takagi?
Yeah! I got it!
Takagi, why?
Please, don't ask me.
What were you doing, Takagi?
Gotta be careful around those ladies. Seriously.
Really? You already realized that the groom was suspicious, Officer Sato?
Yeah. It wasn't hard to piece everything together.
I noticed the second I saw the video.
Even with his wrist and thumb broken, he was able to change fast.
That's why I thought he had a cast on just to hide his fingerprints.
Besides, he hid the fact that his house was broken into.
I see. If he called the police,
they will find out that he's the serial killer by his fingerprints.
I figured that the bride shouldn't be beside such a dangerous man.
So I became the fake bride instead of Yumi.
But you seemed glad to be wearing a wedding dress.
Not really.
I don't look good in that kind of stuff.
Do you think so?
But it was surprising, wasn't it?
Who would have thought the beard man was a famous photographer
who made the poster for the wedding hall?
Hey, just hurry past it!
It's so embarrassing. Walk faster, guys!
Hurry, hurry!
Go on, Yumi. Go, Takagi.
Come on, everyone.
It was a prophetic dream, but it's over now.
Izawa, Yamamoto and Murakoshi...
Okay. Three more people to go.
It's vandalism if you tear it down.
I know that.
What were you thinking, Chiba?
Next Conan's Hint:
"Stage Light"
Which type of wedding ceremony is it?
-Is it a trick or magic? -Are you joking?