So, that's the story. It's 4, 5, 6...
It's my 6th this month! 6 cases!
How about you, Shinichi?
Me? I solved 7 cases.
Oh boy, I lost again.
But, Shinichi. Aren't there a bit too many cases around you?
Well, if you want to do something about your successive losses,
maybe you should change your name?
After all, my name's Shin-ichi, like in "ichiban"
Idiot. You're number 2.
-Number 2? -Yeah.
There was one guy in the past.
A guy who was really intelligent.
A detective.
A bright step forward to a prosperous future.
My heart is of course prepared for what is to come!
Intermediate school detectives, Heiji and Shinichi.
A deduction battle is launched at the ski slope.
Solve the mystery that is on the lift!
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
"Heiji Hattori vs. Shinichi Kudo!"
"Deduction Confrontation at the Ski Slope!"
Kazuha, are you okay?
If your sprained ankle is hurting,
maybe you should go back to the hotel?
I'm fine! Just fine!
It's no fun staying back at the hotel alone
and besides, it's fun watching all of you ski.
Moreover...
Sorry! Sorry!
I thought that an unattractive statue was sitting in the snow,
but it turns out to be a person.
What's with you? This is the fifth time!
Apologize nicely to Kazuha!
Why should I apologize?
I splattered snow on her to cool her sprained ankle
so that it would heal faster.
Teacher, Heiji is being nasty to girls again!
Just what do you think you're saying?
-Don't pick on us! -Don't pick on us!
The old ladies are angry!
-Old ladies, how dare? -Old ladies, how dare?
Hey.
Kazuha.
Don't push yourself and go back to the hotel.
You'll catch cold.
Yeah.
Why are boys all that way?
I wish the Snow Woman in these mountains eat you up!
Snow Woman?
Teacher said that there's a folk tale in these mountains
called "Legend of Snow Woman's Silver Clothing."
Long ago, in these mountains...
There was a super beautiful woman
wearing silver clothing of dazzling white.
She used to lay her eyes on handsome men that set foot in the mountains
and call out in a blizzardlike voice, and enchant them.
She would say, "Please exchange my clothing
for something that is precious to you."
Foolish men are taken in by her beautiful white skin under her clothes
and listen to her!
And then?
The man wraps the clothes he gets from her in a cloth wrapper and asks...
"The only thing precious that I have on me is this rifle."
"But is this what you want?"
The woman answers from behind the man, "No."
"Then, is it money?"
"No."
"Is it this hat?"
The man's asks the woman, "Then what is it?"
She then, stark naked clings on to the man from behind.
"It's not something cold that I want."
"What I want really badly is...
your warm, very warm...
blood dripping...
heart!"
See.
After that, the man is found dead.
And inside the cloth wrapper, there is no silver clothing,
but rather... a lot of snow. That's the story.
They say that when a blizzard hits these mountains,
many fall victim.
And even 4 years ago,
there seemed to have been a case very similar to this one.
Hey, students of Kaiho Academy intermediate class!
It's lunchtime!
It's already past two o'clock!
Huh? Really?
No wonder I'm hungry.
It seems that there are students from other schools staying here too.
That's why they seem to have shifted lunchtime
to prevent the dining room from becoming crowded.
Isn't that the actor...
"Shohei Minowa (32), actor" -called Shohei Minowa?
What's he doing?
That's right! I saw on TV that they're shooting a movie
after a real case that happened in a snowy mountain.
Huh? I heard that it was a thriller having to do with Snow Woman.
Nonsense.
Well, at any rate, Shohei Minowa's the star of the show
and the fact that he's a detective pursuing some mysterious case
is no mistake.
A detective.
Is it true that this series will be a three-part completed series?
Yeah.
Is it also true that this movie is made
after a case that really happened?
That's true, too.
The guy who died was a friend stuntman of mine.
I was at the scene of the crime, too.
Hey, Mr. Minowa.
I don't want you saying too much about the late Mr. Jiro.
Just what're you talking about?
You're the one who's shooting a movie
using your dead friend as bait.
"Morizo Oyama (56), movie director" -Hey, hey.
This is a movie that was made as a tribute to him.
Well, all is well.
Nothing will bring a dead person back to life.
We can insert something like "A Tribute to Jiro Mikami"
at the end of the movie or something,
"Kosuke Mimata (27), stuntman" -to bring tears to the eyes of the viewers.
And if the movie is a hit, nothing could be better!
Let's be thankful for Mr. Mikami's death
and make a good movie.
Thanks to his death,
you too got to succeed the position you have now.
Well, I warn you, be careful.
You're going to have to do the stunt
"Shizuku Tateishi (31)" -that the late Mikami was supposed to do.
"Special make-up artist" -Let's hope that Snow Woman doesn't seduce you.
Yeah, yeah.
But I still don't understand
why Mizukami would leave a fiance like you behind
and take his own life.
Who knows?
He didn't commit suicide. He was murdered.
I'm sure one of you killed him.
What?
You again, Officer.
No. I heard that you already quit your job as an officer.
Yeah. I was fired working on this case
that was under the jurisdiction of another prefecture.
"Rikuto Katashima (35), detective" -I work as a measly detective now.
I mean, no matter how you look at it, he committed suicide.
True.
4 years ago, a man who rides the lift of this skiing ground alone
had a bullet shot through his head
and was dead when he came down.
He was holding a gun in his right hand,
and on his sleeve there were traces of gunpowder.
Normally, it would look like nothing
more than suicide by shooting oneself,
but something bothers me.
Why was there a load of snow packed
inside the bag that was beside him?
That's because he killed himself
according to the legend of the Snow Woman.
Absurd. I know that guy since childhood,
but he had no interest whatsoever in spook stories.
Besides, even if it were to be so,
I don't understand why he would do something like that.
Who knows?
We'll never know unless we ask the dead man himself.
But this, we know for sure...
if it were a murder case,
it is a case that was impossible for any human to carry out.
Yes, if anyone were to be able to do it,
only the beautiful evil spirit of the mountains,
Snow Woman could've done it.
Idiot.
It's called homicide because some human did it.
Besides, nothing is impossible!
You idiot!
We met a young man like you just a while ago too.
Who said what you just said about this story.
He looked to be your age, an intermediate school student like you.
An intermediate school student?
Heiji!
Maybe somebody's talking about me.
Right.
I mean, you really put on a grand front in the dining room,
so I'm sure somebody's making fun of you now.
Idiot!
I was just trying to wake you up
from that Snow Woman story you were so panicked out about.
I... I wasn't panicked out or anything.
I just thought that maybe it could be true!
That Snow Woman story...
It's sad and there are many similar stories like it.
Yeah. It's true that it's mysterious.
In Japan, they call the monster
that appears in the most famous Snow Woman story is called...
"Woman of the Snow".
English? I thought that Snow Woman was a Japanese story.
Yeah, it's a Japanese folk tale.
But a man called Lafacadio Hern
who was working as an English teacher in Japan heard about it,
and published it in English.
You know him, don't you, Yagumo Koizumi?
That's his pen name!
Yes, yes. You are so knowledgeable, Shinichi.
But thank you anyway.
You said what you did to put me at ease, right?
That's not all I did it for.
I thought I had to say so, to keep out of hot water.
I didn't want a storm to start.
I have this ominous premonition.
Hey, Heiji!
What're you going to do if Snow Woman really appears?
Idiot! If such a woman exists,
I sure would like to meet her.
Heiji.
In order to solve the case of 4 years ago,
first I've to check the lift in question!
And I've got to do it,
before some intermediate school brat beats me to it!
What's the big deal?
It's just that somebody else thinks like you.
That's why I don't want to lose!
I've got to win,
or people will think that I'm only intermediate level too.
I mean, you're only in intermediate school too, after all.
Ugh, really! Always so lovey-dovey.
You idiot! Don't get us wrong.
The snow's going to melt with the spur that you guys make!
She's talking about somebody else.
Well, you still have time
to check the lift after this blizzard subsides.
Well, I guess so. But before that...
I'm sorry.
Oh, no, I'm sorry.
Heiji?
Hey! Will you cut it out?
Taking pictures left and right from some time ago.
Heiji! What's the problem?
She could just be taking pictures of this snowy scenery.
No! No! This lady is taking pictures of me!
She's my mom!
What?
Just as would be expected of you, Heiji!
You've got keen senses just like your dad, Heizo!
What brings you here?
I was worried sick over Heiji
because he's rarely come to the Tohoku district.
Oh, give me a break!
All you want to do is make additions to the growth video
that you've been taking of me since I was born!
I'd like to see it.
It was a bad blizzard back then, too.
4 years ago, the day Mizukami died.
On that day, just like now,
while we were waiting to shoot the film,
Minowa was surrounded by his fans.
It seems the blizzard is subsiding!
Is that right?
Please show us your skiing then!
The awesome ski techniques that you used in
"Love of Snow Woman" and "Mystery!"
Please!
Oh boy. I've got to shoot a film from now, you see.
No! No!
Ever since we've got here,
fans like you have asked him to ski
and he's already skied three times!
If you want to see him ski, please watch his movie!
What shall I do?
Well, we do have a tight schedule,
but we've got to treat the fans nicely, too.
I think this is what Mizukami would've said.
"It'll work out somehow!"
Oh goodness, he's not here anymore!
Will you please cut it out already?
I'm sorry
that I got you involved in making a movie based on the late Mr. Mizukami
who was supposed to have become your husband.
Don't be. After all,
I'm the one who asked you to let me participate.
I sort of felt that if this movie is completed,
the truth of his death would be revealed.
Two places...
I looked from below
there are two places where this lift and ski slope come close together.
You mean you can jump onto the lift from below?
No. They come close,
but there's a space of more than 3 meters.
It'd would be impossible to jump on
unless you use a trampoline or something.
Isn't that Shoehei Minowa that was at the hotel?
He's good!
Encore...
No, no! Just this once for today!
Watch the movie if you want to see more skiing!
It's already 4:00!
We've got to shoot the ski slope above quickly.
Okay, I'll get myself on the lift first!
Because it'll get pitch dark after 5:00.
Hey, Director.
The special make-up artist woman
and the stuntman is nowhere in sight.
They both said that they'd go up before everyone.
Something's fishy.
There sure is something fishy about this lift.
Heiji, this lift is scary.
Kazuha.
You belong to the advance group,
and yet you've never rode a lift?
I have. But it was a different kind.
Gosh. It starting to get windy again.
I can't see the figure of the detective's
who's riding the lift up ahead too clearly.
Hey, Ms. Tateishi!
Oh, Mr. Mimata.
What're you doing? That lift's going down.
I missed the lift.
I'm not good at things like this.
Shinichi!
What was that sound just now?
The sound of a gunshot.
The ones on the lift were...
Director Oyama,
the actor, Minowa,
the detective, in that order if I remember correctly.
Did something happen?
It's you.
Beats me. I just got off now.
Stop the lift!
Can't you tell?
Look at that!
Just stop the lift right this minute, will you?
Then call the police and paramedics!
What? What? Shinichi? Is something wrong?
Don't look, Ran!
The lift stopped.
What's going on?
The thing that sounded like gunfire just a while ago,
and now that scream.
The lift, gun fire...
Don't tell me that
the same thing as the case 4 years ago has happened again.
We are sorry for the inconvenience!
Please allow a little more time for the lift to resume operation!
What is the meaning of this?
It's almost like what happened back then.
You can say that again.
Just like the time when Mr. Mizukami shot himself to death.
Mizukami.
The gun right as his temple and bang!
This is suicide.
Yes. He is after all holding the gun in his right hand.
The problem is this bag that's beside the victim.
If it's just as my ominous premonition tells me,
I'm sure that the contents of the bag is...
Snow, just as I thought.
God. It's the same as 4 years ago.
I think I heard that they were shooting a such a movie here.
Yes.
We were shooting a movie having to do with that legend
and what happened here 4 years ago,
but now after what happened to Mr. Minowa, the star of the show...
Huh? Is Minowa an actor?
If I remember correctly, you were here
when that incident happened 4 years ago too, weren't you?
I am the director of the movie, Oyama.
I was on the left one ahead of him.
Then, I heard a gunshot.
That young man who came along when I got off the lift,
noticed that something was wrong with Mr. Minowa.
Hey, kid! Just what do you think you're doing?
We're going to have to get the lift moving soon
-or the skiers will... -Okay.
After the corpse and his belongings are carried off the lift,
you may move it!
-Do you need help? -No, it's pretty light.
He was slimmer than he looked.
He didn't even weigh 60 kilograms.
That's why he used to only appear in winter dramas and movies.
He didn't want anybody to see how thin he was.
I wonder why he out his skis in the back
instead of wearing them?
Why not?
He was holding a bag filled with snow, you know.
It may have been packed with snow,
but it's just big enough to fit a child inside.
Okay! You can go ahead and move the lift!
Oh, officer.
There are three things that are bothering me.
It finally moved.
Look at the crowd.
It's frightening.
Idiot! My blood's starting to boil!
Unauthorized personnel stand back! Stand back!
What is it? What on earth happened?
It's you.
It's something just I heard briefly,
but it seems to be exactly the same
as the incident that happened 4 years ago.
It seems that a man who was riding the lift alone
had a bag filled with snow beside him
and killed himself with a gun.
It's as if he were possessed by the Snow Woman!
Hey, not you again.
This isn't your jurisdiction, is it?
No. I'm not an officer anymore, but a detective.
Besides, I was riding the lift right behind this victim, you know.
Don't you want to ask me questions, officer?
Victim? He committed suicide!
No. I think it's too soon to conclude so yet.
Hey, Heiji! Help!
Just what're you doing? Hurry and get off!
Yeah, but I don't know how to get off.
Okay then, when you reach the bottom,
I'll have them stop the lift, so make sure you get off!
Okay.
That idiot.
That's why I told her not to come along.
Come to think of it,
there was another person who couldn't get off a while ago.
-Really? -Yes.
She was a pretty lady who had her hair all tied in the back.
No. Mr. Minowa committed suicide?
Why?
Before asking why, will you answer my question?
Why did you want to get off the lift here a while ago?
I couldn't get off!
I'm not at home with these things.
That's strange.
You came here 4 years ago too, to shoot a movie, right?
Back then, I had Mr. Mizukami ride with me.
This time I had Mr. Mimata ride with me.
She's not very physically inclined, you see.
Huh? The director told me that you would be going up ahead.
Why are you riding the lift with her?
Standby for the shooting is was all set,
but the director and main star didn't come up the slope
so I skied down here to come get them!
Then, I saw her coming down on the lift,
so I called out to her, and that's when I heard the gun shot.
I had this bad feeling
so had him ride the lift with me and went back up again!
I mean, the thing about 4 years ago was bothering me, too.
Then, the lift stopped
and I finally got to come down a while ago!
I see. In other words...
Director Oyama, who was riding the lift in front of Mr. Minowa,
Mr. Katashina, the detective who was behind,
Ms. Tateishi, who passed him on the lift going down
and Mr. Mimata who was on the ski slope...
All could've shot at Mr. Minowa.
-Hey. -Hey, now.
Weren't you listening to what we were just saying?
I was with Mr. Mimata when the gunshot was heard.
If that gunshot was fake,
the murder would've been possible.
Is this what you want to say, sonny?
Yeah, right!
But Mr. Minowa was holding the gun in his hand, you know.
It would be impossible to make him to that
if you're some distance away, right?
You can't tell him to hold the gun
because you're going to be shooting him, can you?
Besides, the blizzard was pretty bad back then.
You'd have to be a darn good shooter
to shoot down the target at that time.
Well, I'm not too sure of this yet,
but there's something I realized.
First, the ski poles that Mr. Minowa
is said to have put on the lift!
The loops on both tips of the poles are both upside down.
It's proof that the poles were used for something!
Next is the lift that Mr. Minowa was on.
There is what looks to be a crack on the left edge of the plastic seat.
I'm sure that this is the result of some trick that was used, too.
And last,
is this cloth bag filled with snow
that Mr. Minowa had placed beside himself.
I don't know why but it's frozen stiff.
No, no, don't touch his belongings.
But you intermediate school kids nowadays sure are full of curiosity.
There was another one just like you, an intermediate school student,
who boastfully told we the police
the three points you just mentioned, too.
What?
He was here until just before you got here.
I've finally made it down.
I'll never ride a lift ever again.
-Kazuha. -Kazuha.
You're not supposed to be in advance ski class, are you?
You don't even know how to get off a lift!
Be honest!
You just wanted to be in the advance class
because Heiji was there, right?
I'll bet your sprained leg is fake, too.
Oh, no.
Don't worry.
-We won't tell Heiji about it. -Excuse me!
-I'm really sorry. -Is there anyone here
who took a video Mr. Minowa riding the lift a while ago?
If you don't mind, I've taken him with mine.
Thank you so much!
You sure took nice pictures.
If you're Mr. Minowa's fan,
you could've just kept to shooting videos of him only and yet.
Well, my son asked me to.
He told me to take pictures of the boarding gate of the lift
because he wanted to use it as reference
for the incident that happened 4 years ago.
Is your son a police officer or something?
He's a mere intermediate school student.
Although he thinks he's a detective.
A detective? Just like me.
My, Shinichi is chatting with a beautiful madam.
Really, I wonder who he took after.
No, he's wearing the facial expression of a detective.
He's still green.
And? Has the self-proclaimed world renown mystery novel writer
solved this case?
Yukiko. What a silly question.
What? Have you figured it out, Yusaku?
I came all the way here because I wanted to write a novel
based on what happened 4 years ago,
but to think that a movie based on it was already being made,
and that a similar incident is happening right now...
If you've figured out who the culprit is,
why don't you contact the police right away?
No. Let's leave things to the young ones for a while
and watch how things turn out.
Well, at least give me a hint then.
Do you know?
That there is another Snow Woman silver clothing legend
that exists in these mountains.
It is a heartbreaking and sad story.
What? Mr. Minowa, the actor committed suicide?
Is that true, Heiji?
Don't talk too loud!
It still hasn't been publicized.
But, how'd something like that happen?
Beats me, I don't know yet.
It's dubious whether it's really suicide or not, too.
It's the same as the incident that occurred 4 years ago.
Then, isn't it suicide?
That's why I came to confirm it on video.
How is it? Did you find anything, Heiji?
Just as I thought. This is homicide.
That video is sure popular.
Popular?
There was another person
who asked to see that video besides you.
Don't tell me that he was an intermediate school student too?
Yes, one of them was.
One of them? You mean there were others?
Way before that boy came...
A dandy man with a mustache came.
A man with a mustache?
Another Snow Woman legend...
Is that the hint for solving the incident?
Well, as for the questions,
ask me after you hear me out.
Long time ago, on a stormy blizzard night,
there was a man named Shigekichi,
who was rushing back home from these mountains.
Part way home,
he ran into a long haired, beautiful woman wearing a silver kimono.
The woman lifted her head, and said with pleading eyes...
I sprained my ankle while walking along the mountain path
and can walk no farther.
Will you please take me to my house?
When Shigekichi asks her where her house is,
the woman silently points a dark forest where there is no road.
But, no matter how far he walks,
only the snow gets deeper and there is no house anywhere in sight.
Therefore, the man finally asks the woman...
Is this the right road?
The woman nods without saying a word.
The woman was waiting for the man to throw her down.
Yes. Because the identity of the woman
was "Snow Woman" who would eat the soul of the man
when he ran out of strength.
The man's steps eventually become slow.
After a while, the mouth of the woman
who had been silent up to now slightly moves.
Young lady.
The woman smiles as if she had been waiting
for the time to come and answers.
Yes, what is it?
Shigekichi is heaving heavily
but squeezes out what he has to say...
Aren't you cold?
The woman is flustered by the man's unexpected question,
and is at a loss for words.
Shigekichi endures the cold and exhaustion he feels
and walks on with all his might.
"Isn't it clustered inside the basket? Aren't you hungry?"
He tells her that there's only a little more to go,
so to hang in there.
Although the woman answers him,
her voice gets weaker and weaker.
Then, finally her voice is not heard.
Shigekichi gets worried and stops.
He puts the basket down and looks inside.
The woman is nowhere in sight.
But a large amount of snow was found wrapped in a silver cloth.
I see. Shigekichi's warm heart
melted the cold Snow Woman's heart.
-Yeah. -And, so what's the hint?
So I guess the load is too heavy for you, after all.
But, for him,
I guess it would be a good problem solving exercise.
-Him? -I'm sure that he's watching the movie
that Mr. Minowa appeared in at the hotel right now,
being that he's our son.
See, it's just as I thought.
Mr. Minowa's style of skiing that we saw this afternoon
is different from his style of skiing in the movie, right?
You think so?
I think they're both good, like that of a professional.
That's how people evaluate his skiing.
Take a look at this scene
where Mr. Minowa comes to rescue the heroine.
He comes skiing from the top until he frames out...
See, his cap strap is on.
But after he frames in again
when he carries her up, it's not on anymore.
And it's supposed to be a cut that is connected.
True.
Don't tell me that he's using a double.
-Maybe he can't ski? -No way.
He was skiing just a while ago and it was awesome!
Was it really him?
Of course.
I filmed it on video.
-See. -Hey, Sonoko.
While Mr. Minowa was skiing his way here,
do you know where he had this bag?
Mr. Minowa put it in front of his fans himself.
He told them to watch it for him until he got back
because he had important things inside it.
What? This bag?
An intermediate school boy came to look at it?
-When was that? -Just now.
He didn't buy it though.
If that's too small,
we have one with the same design a size larger.
Is that right?
The belt stretches this much and it's quite convenient.
True.
What's so convenient.
Hey, Heiji. What're you angry about?
It's only natural.
Some intermediate school kid is one step ahead of me each time.
He borrowed the video from the hotel before I did,
and a queer mustached man also seems involved.
If things go as is, they'll solve the case before I do.
Which means that you still have no idea, Heiji?
I do. I know who the killer is and the method that was used.
I found out when we went to that store a while ago.
Then, why not report it to the police right away?
But there's something I can't solve.
The loops on the poles that were on upside down
and the reason the bag was filled with snow.
My deduction cannot be proven unless I solve these problems.
What is it, Shizuka?
I thought I told you not to make private calls to me at work.
What, a case?
-I found it! This is it! -What's that?
Remember the gunshot like noise that Mr. Minowa might've heard
before reaching the top on the lift.
The fact that this hasn't been retrieved yet,
means that the killer is still somewhere unable to make a move.
My, you sound like you know it all already.
No, the most important trick that was used in the murder
is still not solved completely.
The scratch that was left
on the left side of the corpse on the lift...
I can't figure out what it is.
I figured out the snow packed bag and the killer,
but they don't connect right.
You've figured out who the killer is?
Yeah. There are four suspects
who are being interrogated by the police now.
Director Oyama, who was riding the lift in front of Mr. Minowa.
Mr. Katashina, the detective who was riding the lift
right behind Mr. Minowa.
Stuntman Mr. Mimata, who was at the ski slope
to call the director and the others.
And Ms. Tateishi who failed to make it off the lift.
Wait, I can see that you know where Director Oyama was riding,
but how do you know where the other three were riding?
Do your really know who the killer is?
Mrs. Kudo!
I got to hear what the police
was questioning them about, you see.
What? But, how, why?
It just so happened that our trip and Shinichi's ski class
coincidentally turned out to be the same place.
I mean, you deliberately came here.
But Shinichi, you were 30 minutes late.
An intermediate school boy just like you was here just a while ago.
What?
You mean there's another deduction freak just like Shinichi.
That's new to me!
Talking about another, do you know?
About the other Snow Woman legend.
No god, it's pitch dark already.
The killer is being interrogated now and can't move just yet.
But if he's released, he will hide the evidence.
Heiji!
What is it, Mom?
Rain makes puddles.
But with snow, you can make a snowman.
If that becomes ice, a large statue can also be made.
But Yusaku says that this is the key to solving the mystery.
Don't let outward appearance fool you.
By Heizo.
What's he trying to get at anyway?
Why talk about snowmen now?
Heiji?
Will you cut it out?
I'm sorry, but can you answer the phone for me?
-It's in the pocket of my coat. -Yes, sir.
Who is it?
His hands are tied right now.
I've figured everything out.
I've figured out who killed Mr. Minowa under the pretense of suicide.
What?
As well as the trick that made the murder possible.
-Everything! -Huh?
An intermediate school boy again.
I'll bet you want to say that all four of us
were capable of shooting Mr. Minowa, right?
Like I said before, it's impossible for us to have done it!
Since he was riding the lift alone,
we couldn't have made him hold the gun.
Maybe the ex-cop and now detective could've done it,
but we could never aim and shoot at his head
in a blizzard like back then.
Hey, hey, even an ex-cop can't do something like that.
Because the blizzard was so bad
that you couldn't even see the lift in front of you.
True.
Murder would've been impossible in that situation
if Mr. Minowa was really riding the lift alone.
What?
Hey, hey, don't tell me that
you're going to say that somebody was inside that bag?
But that bag was packed with snow,
and no adult would've possibly been inside.
No, no, a bag this size was inside.
The same kind of bag that is one size larger
and of the same design was sold at the shop of the hotel.
It can't be.
Are you saying that Mr. Minowa was carrying a bag
with the killer inside it when he got on the lift?
No, the one who was in the bag wasn't the killer,
but Mr. Minowa himself.
No, that can't be!
Then, the person who was carrying the bag was?
The killer.
Most of Mr. Minowa's face is hidden by his hair,
and he was wearing sunglasses back then.
If someone else were to wear a wig, a knitted cap,
sunglasses and ski wear,
people would be deluded to think it were Mr. Minowa.
But he talked to me and his fans.
It was Mr. Minowa's voice, of course.
-How? -That's because Mr. Minowa himself
was listening closely from inside the bag and responding to everyone.
That's why everybody thought that he disguised killer was Minowa.
-Oh no... -I see.
That's why he was silent until he carried that bag.
You've got to be kidding.
A person as proud as he, would never go inside a bag.
That's probably because...
He was a proud person.
That's why he went inside.
The fact that his skiing was of a professional level
was just a front and fake.
It was probably all a lie.
A lie?
I guess he could ski a bit,
but not good enough like a professional.
I watched the movie, that Mr. Minowa appeared in,
"The Snow Woman's Love" and the "Mystery of Snow Woman"
back at the hotel a while ago.
Then there was a scene where he ran over to the heroine on skis
and framed out once. Then he zoomed back into the scene.
Moreover, when he was skiing, the cap trap was on.
When he zoomed, it wasn't there.
This means that someone else skied for him.
Isn't that right, director?
Yeah. It wasn't that he couldn't ski,
but he hurt his leg in the first movie.
But he insisted on skiing himself,
so in order to persuade him, I secretly used a stuntman in his place.
That ski scene was ironically evaluated highly.
So, I used a stuntman secretly in the 2nd movie, too.
You did?
That's why, when the fans asked him to ski,
he let his substitute ski for him
and went into the bag and waited below.
Then, when his substitute came and carried the bag,
he conversed with the fans to act out his role.
Hey, hold it.
Don't tell me that the substitute is...
Yeah. The one who had that role,
carried the bag that Mr. Minowa was inside, and killed him is...
Stuntman, Mr. Mimata!
No one else but you could've done it.
-Mr. Mimata? -Is it true?
But I think that the one who did the stunt
for the movie 4 years ago was the late Mr. Mizukami,
because the skiing in the movie and today's skiing was different.
It's most likely that before Mr. Mizukami died,
Mr. Mimata secretly took on the role,
and he used it to his advantage to carry out the murder on the lift.
Right! He took only Mr. Minowa's head
out of the bag on the lift and held it down,
stuck the gun at his temple and fired.
He then took Mr. Minowa out of the bag and sat him down
and made him hold the gun.
He then carried the bag and jumped off.
There are two places where the space
between the lift and the ground is only about 3 meters.
The scratch that was found on the seat of the lift
was one that was made when he shot Mr. Minowa.
And the fact that Mr. Minowa was sitting on the left when on the lift,
but was found sitting on the right side when found dead
is evidence that this is what actually happened.
It sure is difficult
to shift the position of a dead person on a lift.
But, when the gunshot was heard,
Mr. Mimata was talking to me.
That was probably the sound of a rocket fire cracker.
After he wore the ski wear
that he had ready by the place he got off the lift,
he probably ignited the fuse of the rocket fire cracker
with a lighted cigarette and poked it into a PET bottle.
He fired it shifting the time a bit to make a witness for his alibi,
by skiing down and talking to somebody when the sound is heard.
But, where did he get the bag that was packed with snow?
I just said that there are two places
where that lift is only 3 meters away from the ground.
That's where the bag with the upside down ski pole
hooked onto it was place, and later carried up to the lift.
I see. 3 meters to the ground...
Ski poles are approximately 1 meter and 20 centimeters.
If the string one side is hooked on to the other pole and connected,
stretching over for it may make it reachable,
but would it be possible to pick it up in that blizzard?
No, no! Only one ski pole was used,
and the remaining 1 meter...
was made by wetting the string of the cloth bag
with water and freezing it.
That's how the remaining one meter was compensated for.
The loops of both poles were upside down
because just one being upside down would draw attention.
But I wonder if you can see that bag from on top the lift?
I mean the blizzard was so bad
that even the lift ahead couldn't be seen, right?
Did you know that the space between one lift and the other
has to be more than 6 seconds apart?
The speed at which a lift moves
is from 1.5 meters to 2 meters per second,
which means that the space between one lift and the other
is about 10 meters apart.
Even if it is hard to something that is 10 meters apart,
the bag that was only 3 meters apart could easily be seen.
More so, if you know that the bag is already there...
But, what proof do you have?
I've got proof, too.
If Mr. Mimata met with Ms. Tateishi
and went directly to be interrogated in the lodge,
he still should have it on him.
The same ski wear that Mr. Minowa was wearing.
Maybe you even have the bag that Mr. Minowa inside, too?
I was enduring all this time.
It was so hot.
Mr. Mimata!
So, you the one who did it, after all.
Which means that you knew, director.
Yeah.
I thought that your skiing had improved in the end,
but when I saw him dead, I realized it was you.
But, why?
I avenged the death of Mr. Mizukami
who was supposed to become your husband.
I killed Minowa using the same trick
that was used to kill Mr. Mizukami 4 years ago.
Just what do you mean?
Remember 4 years ago, that day,
Minowa was troubled surrounded by his fans,
Mr. Mizukami said we can work something out.
He meant that
he would secretly put Minowa inside a bag and carrying him over.
But Minowa took advantage of Mr. Mizukami's kindness and killed him.
He killed Mr. Mizukami who was planning on quitting his job as a stuntman
and become an actor!
He told me when I held him at gun point.
There's no way he can make a living as an actor.
I'm sure that when he gets desperate,
he is going to write a book on me and disclose everything!
I guess he was scared.
How ironic
that a movie that is just the thing to carry out the revenge is to be shot.
The fact is, I too, thought that the killer of the incident
that happened 4 years ago was Minowa.
That's why I decided to make this movie.
I didn't reveal anything yet,
but the real killer of this movie
was scheduled to be Minowa, who was acting the role of a detective.
The trick used is the same as was used 4 years ago
as Mr. Mimata had just mentioned.
I figured that he would give himself in if I showed him the script.
I know that it's not for me, who quit being an officer to say,
but if you knew so much,
I would've wanted you to prevent this stupid murder.
Revenge only breeds revenge,
and the feeling of accomplishment vanishes on the spot...
It's just like the snow that falls onto the palm of your hand.
Well, we'll hear you out at the station.
You'll come along too, won't you?
Inspector, what about the intermediate school boy on the phone?
He is telling of the exact same deduction of as that boy
with the exact same timing.
-What? -What?
Heiji, why aren't you going with him?
Idiot! If I leave,
who's going to piggy back you back to the hotel down below?
Doh-doh.
I finally figured out that
the belt of the bag was frozen only after dad dropped me a hint.
That's why as far as the intermediate school boy
that solved this case alone,
I don't want to see him.
Why not?
Why should I go when you're the one who solved the case?
Take the PET bottle along with you,
and tell him that you solved the case by yourself.
I only figured everything out
after dad told me the story of the Snow Woman
who pretended that she sprained her leg and went into the basket.
That's when I figured out that Mr. Minowa who wanted to pretend
that he was a good skier went into the bag himself.
But your deduction was correct, wasn't it?
No, this case was solved by the intermediate school boy
who figured everything out himself, not me.
-Hey. -Quiet.
That's what you get for coming along with me,
despite having sprained your leg!
I'll bet you sprained your leg when practicing
just so you could brag that you're an advanced skier.
Well, thanks to you showing off,
I figured out why Mr. Minowa went into the bag right away,
and you also helped with a lot of things
so I guess I'll forgive you.
Idiot. I didn't practice
because I wanted to show everybody how good I was.
I wonder why there are two different stories about the Snow Woman?
I'll bet it's because the storyteller was a mother.
It's said that the folk tale of Snow Woman
was created as a warning to people to stay indoors during blizzards,
and while mothers continued telling their children this story,
they began feeling empathy for her
and gradually changed the story.
In other words, it first started as a story
of her killing her victims after exchanging her silver clothing,
but it changed to a story in which, she did not take the soul,
but rather, just melted into snow.
That's why the stories of Snow Woman
are sad and sound quite familiar.
I couldn't see very well because of the snow.
But I'll bet it's him that intermediate school boy.
Well, even if I don't see him, if he's a detective...
We'll get to see each other one day on some mysterious stage.
So, that super intelligent detective left
without giving the police his name.
How about it? Unlike the detective that I know before he shrunk,
this guy is intelligent and modest!
I mean, you know, that's me.
Next Conan's Hint:
"Coin Locker"
This is the closet we get to the Black Organization.
Oh, no, Shinichi and we suddenly approach each other rapidly.
Why is Conan involved?