I'm Kogoro Mouri. A detective.
Just as fish live wherever
there's an ocean...
I find myself present
at murder scenes.
It all started when...
a bartender named Yuzuki Fukui,
who has a liking for me, asked for my help...
and I came to the pool bar
where she works.
Her request was this.
While on shift...
she kept hearing a sound
like a champagne cork popping...
and right after, the scent of yuzu
would drift through the air.
She wanted me to solve
this strange little mystery.
I was deep in thought
trying to work it out...
when suddenly, one of the four people
sitting behind me...
was murdered.
The victim: Chikafumi Usuda, 51 years old.
Apparently a department head
at some company.
Cause of death: poison.
It seems the killer coated the tip
of something sharp...
like an awl or ice pick...
with a nerve toxin...
and drove it into the back
of the victim's neck.
The suspects are three people
who came to celebrate...
the victim's birthday
right here at this bar.
The one who was made to buy
a billiard cue...
as a birthday gift...
Kensaku Hatsumura, 31 years old.
The one made to buy
a set of darts...
Monpei Kogure, 28 years old.
And the one forced to buy
a rare Okino Yoko poster...
along with a roll of camera film...
Mika Kishiura, 30 years old.
The most suspicious are Kogure,
who brought the darts...
and Kishiura, who had been chipping
ice with an ice pick. But...
Heh... alright then.
Let's say I won't be sleeping tonight
until this case is cracked.
♪~
Dark shadows and darker nights,
cut through by the light of deduction.
A deduction show at the Blue Parrot,
unmasking the trick behind the hidden weapon.
There is always only one truth.
The body of a child, the mind of an adult.
His name... Detective Conan!
~♪
"Kogoro is at the Bar (Part 2)"
What?
No traces of poison were found?
Not on the darts or
the ice pick either?
That's right. According to forensics...
there was no reaction to poison
or even blood.
Hmm...
You did search all three of them,
right?
Yes. None of the three...
had any vials or bags that could
have held a weapon or poison...
on their person.
Hmm. I see.
Unbelievable. No murder weapon...
just like that pickpocket case
we had before.
Oh, speaking of that case, Inspector...
did you ever mention it to Jodie?
No. She's not directly involved.
No need to tell her.
I suppose not, but...
Hey, Detective Takagi, what did
you mean by "it"?
Oh? Well, you see...
Takagi.
Yes sir.
Let's sweep the bar one more time.
Right, understood.
I wonder what Takagi meant by "it"...
If there's something about that case
that stood out to me...
it'd have to be that pregnant woman.
Hm... what's this?
(exhales) Hm?
Hey, Yuzuki.
Yeah?
What is it, Conan?
What's that thing hanging
from the ceiling up there?
Hm? Oh, that's just
a scrap of tinsel.
A scrap of tinsel?
Yeah. It was pinned up there
with a thumbtack, but...
when I tried to take it down
it tore and part of it stayed up.
We had a customer rent out
the whole place last week...
for a private party.
The ceiling up there is so dark
you can barely see it...
so I just left it for now.
But can you actually tell it's there?
Yeah. I'm always looking up
when I talk to grown-ups.
Fair enough.
Though all that looking up seems to mean
you're not watching where you step...
little detective.
Hm?
Look.
There's gum stuck to the bottom
of his shoe.
It wasn't there when he crouched down
near the body earlier...
so where did he step in it?
So? Did you find anything?
Nothing.
Hold it right there.
Hm?
Looks like you stepped on
some evidence, mister.
What?!
Evidence?
Takagi, get it.
Right, yes sir.
This is...
It's not gum.
More like clay or putty.
And there's an impression in it.
What?
Letters, in reverse...
four letters: E, P, D, H...
and above them, some kind
of raised bump.
If the impression reads "EPDH"
in reverse...
then the original marking
would be "HDPE."
High-density polyethylene.
A synthetic resin.
And the raised bump above it...
means the clay was pressed against
something with a hollow or indent there.
So it was probably stuck to the bottom
of that thing over there, but...
why would there be clay
on the bottom of that?
Ugh...
Hmm...
I was supposed to be off the clock
by now, you know...
I'd be in the bath humming to myself
by this point.
The bath...
(sharp inhale)
That's it. That's how it was done.
The murder weapon didn't vanish.
The killer used that to launch it
clean off... a liftoff.
Right out of any adult's line of sight.
I've got it, Inspector.
I know who murdered Chikafumi Usuda.
What?
Is that right?
Yes.
The killer is that customer who was
having a dispute with the victim.
It looks like they've already left, but
if they came prepared with a poison needle...
and walked out with it
after the murder...
it would make sense that no weapon
was found inside the bar.
Right, right.
Hmm...
...or so you might think.
But that's actually not the case.
Excuse me? What exactly
are you trying to say?
Ah... well, what I mean is...
There he is. My other self.
Any decent detective keeps a second voice
in their head...
one that looks at their own reasoning
from the outside. But mine...
always picks the worst possible moment
to show up.
Just barging in like that.
Since the Inspector and the others
seem to be hearing it too...
I must be saying it all out loud.
But I'm not even aware of it.
Not even a little.
It's like something I can't explain
has taken over my body.
Well... that aside, the real problem is...
the faint sting that shoots through
the back of my neck right after.
(dart hits)
Ngh!
Ah yes... there it is.
And then, without warning, an overwhelming
wave of sleep crashes in.
I imagine it's the price
my brain pays...
for running at full capacity
like that.
H... hey?
Here it comes. The usual.
Lately... this sleep
actually feels kind of nice.
And the reason for that is...
Hey. Hey!
Hey!
Mm? Ngh...
Hm?
Are you awake?
Mm... mhm...
Everyone's already gone home.
(yawns)
So... the case?
Seriously? What are you on about?
You just wrapped up the whole
Sleeping Kogoro deduction show!
Right... when I come back to my senses,
the case is always solved.
I suppose I pour every last bit of energy
into seeing through the truth...
and laying it all out for everyone.
That's why I can't remember a thing.
So the culprit really was that customer
who was fighting with him?
What? I literally just said
there's no way some random customer...
who happened to have a beef with the victim
would also show up with a poison needle.
Oh... then could it be...
one of those three coworkers
of the victim's...
is the killer?
Yes, exactly.
No way.
Sure, those three all had things
that could work as weapons, but...
there wasn't a trace of poison
or blood on any of them.
You doing okay?
...You thought it was impossible too,
right, Yuzuki?
Hm?
Oh, I see. You were testing whether
I actually followed...
your deduction properly.
Ah... yeah, yeah, that's right.
It made complete sense to me.
It all clicked perfectly.
I never would have guessed
the killer used that method...
to hide the murder weapon.
That method?
The experiment you had Conan help
demonstrate was a nice touch too.
Takagi went and bought a film canister,
filled it about a third of the way with water...
then took a bath bomb...
also picked up by Takagi, crushed it
down to roughly sugar-cube size...
and dropped it in...
then sealed the lid on the canister...
flipped it upside down and set it
lid-side down on the table...
and after about two and a half
to three minutes...
Hm?
...and that's how it works.
Whoa!
We call this the film canister rocket.
The bath bomb reacts with the water
and releases carbon dioxide gas...
the gas builds up
inside the canister...
and blows the lid open, launching the canister
high into the air like a rocket.
Oh... it smells like yuzu.
Right. The killer...
must have used a yuzu-scented bath bomb.
Then that popping sound I heard
a few times before...
The killer was doing test runs here.
Practicing whether placing a weapon
on top of the canister...
would be enough to drive it
into the ceiling.
Wait, a weapon on top of it?
We're talking about something
shaped like an ice pick.
That thing is heavy.
There's no way something like that would fly...
The tip of a hard dart is detachable...
and weighs about 18 grams.
Light enough to be launched
just fine.
On top of that, the killer used clay
to fix the detached dart tip
to the bottom of the canister...
and used a rolled-up poster as a guide tube
to keep it aimed straight.
That way, even if the launch
was slightly off...
it would still reliably reach the ceiling.
Any of that seem wrong to you?
The one who bought his own personal darts
as a birthday present for the victim...
Monpei Kogure.
You could have coated the dart tip
with poison in advance...
and kept it loaded inside the canister.
And this film canister rocket trick...
could only have been set up
by someone standing near that poster...
which was you.
Most likely, after the victim
had drunk himself into a stupor...
you deliberately lost at billiards
and darts against the other two...
and slipped away to get
alone with the victim.
Pretending to drape a jacket
over him or something...
you drove the poisoned dart tip
into the back of his neck.
Then you removed the tip and swapped it
for a spare you'd already prepared.
The one with the poison on it...
you fixed to the bottom of the canister
with the clay...
and hid it by tucking it
between your knees.
After that, all you had to do was
create a small distraction...
and quietly set the film canister
rocket on the table.
Something like...
"Hey, doesn't that person over there
look like someone famous?"
Something along those lines.
Of course, only after ordering
champagne by the bottle.
Come to think of it, back then...
Hey, what about that first champagne
we had?
Yeah, that one was good.
What do you think?
Works for me.
Excuse me, could we get
a bottle of champagne?
Of course.
And three glasses too.
Wait, isn't that guy at the counter
Kogoro Mouri?
No way! The famous detective?
Hm? I feel like someone's watching me...
Photo, get a photo!
Probably just looks like him.
Yeah, the real Mouri wouldn't be
sitting around drinking like this.
To finish it off...
he popped the champagne cork at almost
the exact same moment as the launch...
Ngh... hm?
Man, this cork is seriously stuck.
Don't let it fly over here!
Yeah yeah, I know.
(straining)
Then sprayed the champagne
all over the standing poster...
which wiped away any bath bomb residue
left on the table after the launch.
Gone, just like that.
The proof is in the poster itself.
The wet patch on it...
Hm?
should smell like yuzu.
It does.
But that poster was bought
by Kishiura, wasn't it?
The victim had apparently been pestering
people at the office about it...
repeatedly.
If she hadn't ended up buying it...
he likely would have brought
his own as a backup.
As for the darts, gift someone a dartboard
and it's easy to predict...
they'll ask for arrows next.
And knowing the victim would want
tons of photos taken...
for some birthday blog...
it's perfectly predictable she'd end up
buying camera film too.
He had it all worked out.
Either way, all of this
will be confirmed by...
the murder weapon lodged in that ceiling.
Only someone who bought those darts
could have had...
a matching spare dart tip on hand.
But if it's just the tip lodged
in the ceiling...
then the film canister that launched it...
with clay still stuck to its bottom,
should have fallen back down.
Of course it did. But at that moment...
champagne was splashing all over
the victim's precious poster...
causing complete chaos.
Even if it fell, everyone was scrambling
to wipe the table...
so they would have just knocked it aside
without a second thought.
As for the clay that came loose
when the canister hit the floor...
that's what ended up getting stepped on.
And that clay had...
the letters "HDPE" pressed into it
backwards...
because that marking is typically stamped
on the bottom of film canisters.
Then what about the bath bomb pieces
left on the table?
He probably dropped them
into his own beer glass.
Beer already has bubbles, so a little
extra fizzing wouldn't draw any attention.
His perfect crime...
foiled simply because the Sleeping Kogoro
happened to be here.
You could say his plan
went up in bubbles.
Ha. Nice one.
...You said that yourself, you know.
Oh...
I mean really...
after you solve a case...
the Inspector did say
you remember nothing, but...
I didn't think he was serious.
So you don't even remember the motive?
That the victim had ruthlessly bullied
a coworker into taking their own life...
and this was revenge for that?
Ah... no. Not a thing.
You were so incredibly cool though.
Hm?
Now hold on.
There's no way I remember
absolutely nothing.
Maybe what I thought was
my "other self"...
is actually the true me...
slumbering deep within. Heheh...
Sure. In my everyday life I conserve
my energy...
saving it all up
for the Sleeping Kogoro.
Either way, it's all still me.
All good!
By the way... is Conan okay?
Hm? Come to think of it,
where did that little four-eyes go?
He just left without me?
Yeah. He had a quick word with Takagi...
then bolted out looking completely pale.
What were they even talking about?
I caught something about
a pickpocket.
There's a suspense movie
he's been wanting to watch...
that's airing on TV tonight.
Takagi told him about it.
Wait, really? Why the rush then?
Because it's a real thriller.
Get it? A "thrill"-er! Ha ha ha ha!
Nailed it again.
♪~
~♪
(Conan breathing hard)
Something's off about
the pickpocket victim?
Yeah. Do you remember?
One of the victims from that case,
a guy named Tohei Benzaki...
Right. He was the one taken hostage
during the bank robbery...
along with our teacher Jodie.
Exactly. And when his wife showed up
afterwards, she mentioned...
that Jodie had her eyes and mouth
covered with tape...
by a fellow hostage.
But apparently the robbers specifically
made sure...
to pick someone who didn't know
any of the other hostages to do it.
Something about not trusting someone
to be thorough if they knew the person.
What...?
Alright. Next, anyone here
without a companion or someone they know...
step forward.
You lot. Come get this tape.
Use it to cover the eyes and mouths
of everyone who's with someone...
and tie their hands behind their backs.
People go easy on their own.
Can't have that.
Here.
Don't worry, we'll take care
of you lot ourselves. Heh.
(robber chuckles)
(hostage whimpers)
Um...
Excuse me...
Sorry, let me put this on.
Hmm...
If she said her husband Kirihei
was also a hostage in that incident...
then none of it adds up.
There's no way a pregnant woman would
go out of her way to deceive a robber...
that's too reckless a gamble
for anyone to take.
So did you try
contacting that couple?
Yeah... I went to his place
a number of times, but...
he said he had absolutely no memory
of being involved in
any pickpocket murder case.
He turned me away at the door.
On top of that, this Benzaki guy
is single, no wife...
and says he doesn't know
any pregnant woman either.
I have no idea what's going on anymore.
No way... no way...
Morning sickness is a symptom
that appears in early pregnancy, right?
Y... yeah, that's right.
I have poor eyesight, you see.
Then could it be...
the man with the burn next to you
back then, was he your boyfriend or...
I spotted him a couple days before.
No way...
Stay calm. It's okay. Still okay.
And now she's alone with Ran.
If she's going to slip up, it'll be here.
(groaning)
So all three of them
could have committed the crime.
No.
(gasps)
Next Conan:
"The Restroom Where Ran Also Collapsed (Part 1)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Key to the basement"
That tomboy's coming back again?
Kogoro's getting less
and less screen time.
Hey, Ran-neechan...