- Karuizawa, Nagano Prefecture, Japan.
Yes! Strike!
Nice one, Ran.
Not bad at all.
Tennis was a bust,
but bowling's fun too.
We missed out on
miniskirt tennis girls,
and there's one old man
drowning his sorrows over it.
Come on, you're up next, Conan-kun.
Okay.
Go for it, Conan-kun.
Don't choke, squirt.
So who is it, anyway...
the person you wanted me to meet?
Oh, that would be the person who waited
four hours on a tennis court
in the pouring rain.
They're changing out of their wet clothes,
should be here any minute.
Quit dragging it out
and just tell me.
I rode my bike all the way
here through this rain.
Huh?
What's your problem?
You want to take me on?
Hyah! Hah!
Jeet Kune Do.
He dodged it.
Tch...
Interesting. I'll pound you into the ground.
Blazing sun,
beating the heat,
a slick and stylish
deduction show.
The man Sonoko adores arrives,
a showdown brews at the bowling alley.
There's only one truth.
Looks like a kid,
mind of an adult.
His name... Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"Makoto Kyogoku, A Suspect? (Part 1)"
Interesting. I'll pound you into the ground.
No, wait, Sera-san!
Huh?
That's him. The person Sonoko
wanted you to meet.
Huh?
Ahem. This is my boyfriend,
Makoto Kyogoku-san.
And this is my classmate,
Masumi Sera-san.
Oh... you're a woman?
My apologies. I assumed you were
some lout harassing Sonoko-san.
Don't worry about it.
Getting mistaken for a guy
happens to me all the time.
Honestly, Sonoko, why didn't
you stop them sooner?
But I wanted to see
the two of them fight!
Good grief. What if someone got hurt?
- Kyogoku-san, here. Your glasses.
Kyogoku-san, here.  Your glasses.
Heh heh, my apologies. Ah, much obliged.
Come now, it's fine.
I wouldn't have minded
sparring with him a bit longer.
Honestly.
Who taught you Jeet Kune Do?
My brother. Though he was about
three times stronger than me.
B-but...
didn't you say
your brother passed away?
Yeah, that's what I was told.
B-but...
the other day, didn't you
call your brother on the phone?
Oh, you heard that call?
There's one more of us... my middle
brother, sharp as a tack.
Unlike me and our late brother,
he takes after our dad,
so we don't look much alike.
Seems he's in the middle of
some big job right now,
won't tell me a thing
about where he is,
but every so often I run my
deductions by him over call or text.
That last case, my brother told me
that my reasoning
was on shaky ground.
But with you around,
maybe you'll set me straight if I'm wrong.
Ah... not me, but
Shinichi-niichan, I mean.
Hm? Heh heh.
Don't tell me she...
She knows I'm
Shinichi Kudo?
(clears throat)
By the way, Sonoko-san,
did something go wrong
when you washed that outfit?
Huh? Wrong? Oh...
The collar's all stretched out
and your underwear is showing.
Oh, n-no, this is what's
called off-the-shoulder.
I'm showing it on purpose.
And this is a "show bra."
A... show bra?
You mean that undergarment
is meant to be shown?
Th-that's right.
Sonoko dressed up
just for you, Kyogoku-san.
More importantly, Kyogoku-san,
the back of your right hand is bleeding.
Did that happen just now
when you sparred with Sera-san?
No, this was outside earlier...
Um...
I'm sorry about what happened earlier.
- Monna Michiko (30), junior high school mathematics teacher.
Were you hurt?
It's just a scratch on my end.
More importantly, how is he?
He's fine. He brought it on himself.
My friend's carrying him to the car now.
Did something happen?
When I stepped out earlier
to buy a change of clothes,
this man's companion picked a fight
and caught one to the solar plexus.
Ahaha.
Believe it or not,
he's a middle school P.E. teacher.
- Masaki Sunami (29), junior high school science teacher.
Normally he's a serious,
upstanding teacher,
but Tanba-sensei here turns into
a different person when he drinks.
So... how's he doing now?
Passed out in the car.
In his sleep he was muttering,
"I'm gonna kill that bastard,"
or something like that.
(laughter)
Anyway, what do we do now?
Let's see...
He was supposed to teach me
how to bowl, but...
Ladies.
Hm?
You seem to be
in quite a bind.
(hiccup)
If you'd like, allow yours truly
to give you a lesson or two.
Uh...
The hips, you see, the hips.
Bring your hips this way.
R-right.
When you hold the ball,
keep your pivot foot, the ball,
and your head all in a straight line.
Okay.
Now, go ahead.
Wow, amazing!
That's it. Well done, well done.
My, to be able to instruct
fine ladies such as yourselves,
the honor goes back and forth,
much obliged-ums.
Uh... right.
Nyah ha ha ha!
That old man's going to get
busted for harassment one of these days.
Makoto-san, you can do it!
(crowd murmuring)
This guy's going to get busted
for property damage one of these days.
J-just as I thought...
fancy sports like this
aren't suited to me.
I-I guess not.
Besides, I only got back to the country
today, so I'm a bit jet-lagged.
Oh, then why don't you take a nap
in my father's rental car?
I've got the car keys
right here.
Then I'll take you up on that.
(yawn)
Aw, and this was supposed to
be a date with Makoto-san.
Come on, it's fine.
We're getting dinner after this.
Oh, Michiko, where are you going?
I'm going to check
on Tanba-sensei.
I'm a little worried.
I see.
If he's sobered up,
I'll bring him back.
Huh? He's gone?
Tanba-sensei wasn't
in the car?
No. It looks like he slipped out
and went off somewhere.
Then why hasn't he come
to the bowling alley?
Who knows? Maybe he's
sleeping it off behind a car or something.
Don't joke like that. It's been
raining nonstop this whole time.
W-well, that's true...
If you're looking
for someone,
leave it to me,
Kogoro Mouri.
(hiccup)
Oh, my father's a detective.
K-Kogoro Mouri, you said?
The famous detective?
Sensei.
Tanba-sensei.
Are you in there?
No good. He's not
behind any of the cars.
Maybe he's off drinking again
at some other place.
Don't tell me he's
picking a fight with someone else...
Then let's search the bars.
Huh?
Yes.
Hey, you lot help out too.
Check the places around here.
Aw...
But how?
We don't even know
what the guy looks like.
Here's a photo of him.
If you'd like,
shall I send it to you?
Yeah.
Hey, our rental car was
parked in this lot too, right?
Yeah. Oh, Kyogoku-san.
Right. But if anyone picks a fight with Makoto-san,
he'd fight back until they were beaten to a pulp...
Well, I don't think I'd
beat anyone to a pulp.
Damn it. He's
nowhere to be found.
No luck here either.
He hasn't gone back
to the car either.
And his phone seems
to be switched off.
Hm...
Where on earth
could he have gone?
(water dripping)
What's that? What's
that sound?
Hm.
I checked under the cars too, but
he doesn't seem to be in this lot after all.
Then maybe we should
file a missing person report...
Ah! Kyaaa!
Wh-what's wrong?
Th-the restroom door
was unlocked,
so I opened it, and...
inside there was...
Petechiae in the palpebral conjunctiva.
Frothy fluid from the mouth.
No swelling in the face,
no strangulation marks on the neck.
Drowning, then.
And no restraint marks
on the hands or feet,
and his clothes are
soaking wet, which means...
What? He was drowned
somewhere else,
then carried into this restroom?
Yeah. Judging by the lividity
and the rigor mortis,
he was probably killed
about an hour ago.
Right around when we were searching for him,
heading off to all those bars from here.
And before we came
back here,
the killer dumped the body in this
restroom and made their getaway.
H-how could...
Wh-who would do this...
This guy was pretty well-built,
so it might be multiple culprits...
or the work of someone
with serious physical strength.
Um...
Hm?
Did something happen?
Right. The victim was
Masahiro Tanba, age 32,
a middle school P.E. teacher.
And the one who found the body
was a science teacher
at the same middle school,
Sunami Masaki.
Correct?
Yes.
Now, could you tell me in detail
how you came to find the body?
Y-yes. Today, Tanba-sensei,
my coworker Michiko here,
and I were supposed
to go bowling, the three of us.
But on the way here, he got dead drunk
from the beers he'd had in the car
and caused a scene in town,
which was a real handful,
so we figured we'd let him
sleep it off until he sobered up
and took him to Michiko's car.
Coworker, you said. So you're
a middle school teacher too?
Oh, yes. I teach math.
I see. And then?
After bowling with Sunami
for about an hour,
I went over to the car
to check on him.
He'd been through a lot,
so I couldn't leave him alone.
But he wasn't in the car, so we all
panicked and went searching for him.
"We all," meaning?
That would be the people we happened
to meet at the bowling alley...
That's me,
Kogoro Mouri.
Oh, well, if it isn't
Mouri-san.
So we searched all over
the parking lot but couldn't find him.
Thinking he might be off drinking again
at some bar somewhere,
I split up with the girls
and we spent about an hour
making the rounds of the local bars,
but he was nowhere to be found,
so we came back to this lot.
Figured he might have just
wandered back to the car.
And sure enough, just as I thought,
he'd come back, all right.
As a cold drowned corpse
inside this parking lot's restroom.
Dr-drowned?
Is that true?
Yes.
We can't say for certain
without an autopsy,
but judging by the state of the body,
that's most likely the case.
And the estimated
time of death?
Around 5 p.m.
I see. Around 5, you say.
That's right around when we left
this parking lot for a while
and started making the rounds
of the bars, right?
Yeah.
But when you first
came to search,
why didn't you
check inside the restroom?
There was a padlock on it.
And there was an "out of order"
notice posted on the door, too.
A posted notice?
I saw it too.
But the second time
we came to search here,
that notice had been peeled off
and the padlock was gone,
so... when I opened
the restroom door,
in-inside was
Tanba-sensei.
So in other words, after the victim
was brought to the car by Sunami-san,
sometime before Michiko-san
came to check on him,
he was abducted by someone,
and while Mouri-san
and the others were touring the bars,
he was drowned somewhere,
and then, before Mouri-san
and the others returned here,
the body was placed
inside the restroom.
Yeah. That's how it went.
By the way, is there any chance
Tanba-san was being targeted by someone?
Well... he turned into a different person
when he drank and picked fights with anyone,
which is why he'd said he wasn't
going to drink a drop today.
Hm.
Inspector Yamamura.
There's a bruise
on the victim's abdomen.
A bruise? You're right.
Oh, that was probably me.
Huh?
He picked a fight while drunk
and took a swing at me,
so reflexively, to the solar plexus.
A fight?
He was shouting something
about how I'd made eye contact with him.
Huh. That's awfully
good-natured of you.
You were out searching for
that drunk too,
along with Mouri-san
and the others, weren't you?
No. I was taking a nap inside
Mouri-san's car, which was parked here...
Huh?
I'm placing you under arrest
for murder.
What?
H-hey, hold on, Yamamura.
Who kills someone just because
they got picked on?
What are you trying to pull...
What are you saying, Mouri-san?
He just confessed, thanks to
my masterful interrogation technique.
That he had a motive
and no alibi.
B-but you can't make an arrest
on the spot over just that.
Same as ever,
this bumbling fool.
What are you talking about?
There's no way Makoto-san is the culprit.
Hm? Then can you prove
his innocence?
Yes. I can.
Because... because Makoto-san is...
Makoto-san is?
Because he's such a wonderful,
kind, good person!
(panting)
That proves nothing.
Inspector Yamamura, take a look at this.
Hm?
There's a burn mark
on his left shoulder.
The victim was likely
knocked out with a stun gun.
A st-stun gun?
If the killer used a stun gun,
then I don't think
this guy's the culprit.
Huh? Wh-why?
Because a guy like him could knock
someone out with one punch to the gut,
and since he'd already landed one,
hitting the same spot again
would cover up the bruise.
But maybe he used a stun gun
on purpose to make us think that.
This karate master,
carrying a stun gun around
for self-defense?
I really can't imagine it.
A k-karate master?
He's won major tournaments
many times over.
That's right. The undefeated
Prince of Kicks, 400 wins and no losses.
Huh. Well, if that's the case,
you should've said so... I mean,
please say so sooner.
Heh...
We met during the
Red Handkerchief case, though.
Yamamura, are you
feeling off or something?
Huh?
You used to go around saying stuff like
"maybe you went and did it,
or something like that,"
didn't you?
Th-that was just to
catch suspects off guard,
I used it deliberately.
Now that I've made inspector,
I have no need for
such childish speech.
Nyah ha ha ha!
Oh, is that so.
So if you were here
in this lot the whole time,
did you see anything?
Any suspicious people?
No. I was fast asleep.
I see. Fast asleep, huh.
Whoa... h-hey,
hold on a second there!
Phew. That was close.
Isn't this area
tilted or something...
Oh, this area's apparently sunk
a little due to ground subsidence.
Seems they're planning to do
repair work next month, though.
Hmm.
Ground subsidence...
Wait. If that's the case,
then these diagonal mud streaks
on the wall... could it be...
Ah, rain.
Ugh, it's coming down again.
For now, let's take shelter
in the bowling alley.
We'll continue
the conversation there.
Hm?
What is it, Conan-kun?
You'd better hurry along too.
Hey.
Hm?
That spot on the restroom
vent... doesn't it look strange?
Huh?
That one spot...
the water droplets didn't run off,
they're left in a band.
It's a little sticky.
Maybe something
was stuck on it.
Hey, you two,
get inside quickly too.
Okay.
There are water droplets left
around the door the same way.
It's like it was sealed up
with packing tape.
But that guy didn't suffocate,
he drowned, right?
Yeah.
And besides...
there are no droplets left
on the vent at the bottom of the door.
If it were sealed up,
that wouldn't make sense.
Right.
And also, when we first
went into the restroom,
didn't you smell it?
Yeah.
The smell of kerosene.
You two.
Weren't you listening
to what I just said?
Yes, yes.
We're coming now.
Heh heh heh.
♪~
~♪
Hm? Sc-scorch marks
on the ceiling?
Like I said, hurry up and make
the rounds of the bars around here
and do a proper canvass.
Oh, Makoto-san.
Ah.
Leave him be.
Huh?
Hey, kid. You help me
set up the trick.
You've figured out this trick too, haven't you?
Next Conan:
"Makoto Kyogoku, A Suspect? (Part 2)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Witch"
What's wrong, Ran-kun?
Staring at me like that.
Karate vs. Jeet Kune Do...
Has Ran-neechan
caught fire?