The cherry blossoms are in full bloom!
Flower viewing at a shrine is great too, isn't it?
Really, the weather's nice too.
It's indeed a day for flower viewing.
My stomach is indeed ready for having lunch!
Geez Genta.
It's indeed a case of dumplings over flowers.
Then, Doc.
We'll go draw some oracles
so will you save a place for us and spread out the sheet for us as well?
Okay.
Okay, let's go!
-Thank you! -Conan, let's go!
Yeah.
-What is it? -Huh?
Are you looking for something?
Oh, no. Not really.
The black of shadow and the density of darkness
are slashed by the light of deduction.
Information gets complicated under the cherry blossom tree.
A queer case and the FBI.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"In Reminiscence of Jodie and the Trap of Flower Viewing"
"Bad Luck"
Of all days, why today?
It says I'm lucky.
Mine says medium lucky!
Mine says least luck, so well...
Then let's go tie the oracles!
-Okay! -Hey.
Huh?
You drew yourselves good oracles so take them home!
You tie oracles in order to leave bad luck behind
and change your day to lucky.
It seems that recently a bad custom of tying all oracles
have become prevalent.
So, the only one who has to tie the oracle is Conan?
She snuck a look at mine.
And, what did you draw?
Oh, do you want to know?
Not really.
If you want to know that badly, why not?
Super lucky?
-Wow, Ai! -How lucky!
Will you change it with mine?
But I hear that super bad luck is rarely drawn,
so it actually means good luck.
Don't let it depress you, cool kid!
Jodie!
Hi.
Did you come to view flowers too?
Oh, yes! I love cherry blossoms, you see!
I see?
You called Jodie over so that you could
talk in secret with her, didn't you?
Huh?
They say that parks and shrines
are often used by spies to exchange information.
Okay, everybody. Let's go elsewhere.
It seems they want to talk in secret, just the two of them.
Okay.
But, well, it's a place
where the security police are on the lookout too.
Take care.
Okay.
And? What is it you want to talk to me about?
Well, you said before that
you saw Mr. Akai who had a burn, didn't you?
Yes.
During that bank robbery case.
Shu?
Hey, hold it!
Shu!
Oh, sorry.
Shu...
Are you Shu? You're Shu, aren't you?
Tell me that you're Shu!
A burn scar.
That...
That wasn't Mr. Akai
but one of the members of the men in black,
Bourbon in disguise.
Huh?
In order to check if Mr. Akai really died or not,
he was going around people who knew Mr. Akai
under that disguise.
Because if the FBI were faking his death,
they'd be able to tell by the way you react.
Well, back during the Bell Tree Express incident,
it seems that Vermouth herself, was disguised as Mr. Akai,
although she was the one who made
Bourbon disguise himself as Mr. Akai.
Bell Tree Express?
That train explosion was their doing too?
Yep. It seems so.
Hold it.
If that man with the burn was one of them...
then, Shu really is...
Then, the next time that man with the burn appears,
I'll nab him and peel off his disguise,
then expose his identity.
I know his identity!
Huh?
-As well as his whereabouts too! -What?
He goes by the name Toru Amuro,
and part-times at the coffee shop Poirot
below the Mouri Detective Agency.
-Why? -I wonder.
That's why I had you come here.
I want the FBI to check on it.
On why he's still at Poirot despite having achieved
what he had to do.
Achieved what he had to do?
Yeah, that's...
Huh?
Aren't you the non-Japanese woman
who was held hostage with me during the bank robbery?
Huh?
I was diagonally behind you back then,
and the one who taped your eyes and mouth with masking tape
was my wife.
Don't you remember me?
Yes, sort of.
Then, was that man with the burn scar
who was next to you back then your boyfriend?
No. What's with you?
Oh, no.
If not, it's okay.
I saw him two or three days ago, you see.
-Huh? -Where? Where'd you see him?
-Answer me! -Huh?
Pickpocket! There's a pickpocket!
Ouch.
-Are you all right? -Are you okay? Madam?
Yes.
Somebody put his hand into my bag,
so I was sort of flustered.
It's true that there are a lot of pickpockets
around in crowded places like these.
Yes.
Yes. It's very true.
We've got to be careful.
Goodbye, then.
No, Genta!
You're not supposed to drink that water.
Huh? Oh?
You're supposed to just rinse your mouth
and spit it out on the ground!
And? You can't remember yet?
Where you saw him?
No. I was knocked out in bed because of a cold yesterday
so my memory's...
Your voice is really hoarse.
Then, maybe you should gargle your mouth with this water too?
No, thanks. I don't want to give my cold to anyone,
and I already cleansed my hands a while ago.
Could it be that you saw him
in front of a coffee vending machine somewhere?
Canned coffee? Does he like it?
The man?
Yes. He used to drink a lot of it.
Yes, even back when those guys were about to
attack the hospital.
Shu.
Doesn't he look familiar?
He's one of the men who was added to the investigation team.
Beats me.
As for those on the same team.
I don't forget the faces of enemies, though.
Well, it's only natural that he looks familiar.
He's an FBI agent after all.
Yes.
But, when I look at him, I sense something dangerous.
Shu.
He must've been tired to have dropped the canned coffee.
Rather, an attack?
Oh no, no!
That man and the man with the burn scar
are two different people.
Never mind already!
If you recall something, contact me here, will you?
Yes, I will.
Strange.
In the Bell Tree Express,
Bourbon said that he was convinced that Mr. Akai died, and yet...
Why does he still need to disguise himself as Mr. Akai?
What on earth for?
No, Genta! You shouldn't ring it so hard!
But, Dad told me that I should do things like this energetically.
Exactly!
That bell is to let god know that you've come here.
That's why you have to ring it many times
or else god may not notice you've come.
-Oh. -I didn't know that.
Okay!
I'll ring it with all my might then!
-Hey. -Huh?
The man you were talking about a while ago,
that man called Akai, who is he?
Why?
Somehow he sounds like someone I know.
Maybe not.
Besides Mr. Akai is already...
Huh, dead?
-No joke? -Yeah!
There's a big fuss behind the restroom!
Let's go look!
Doc? What's up?
Bad news, Shinichi! It's a homicide!
I seem to have witnessed a murder!
What? You witnessed a murder?
At any rate, rush over here, will you!
They're a lot of spectators here already.
I'm sure you'll find the place right away!
Over there!
And, did you see the perp?
I only got to see the silhouette,
but the perp was flinging a stick about 30cm
and hitting the victim repeatedly.
A stick about 30cm long? Slugged to death!
Hey.
Out of the way, move!
This person.
No joke?
She's the one that bumped into Jodie a while ago.
Why?
Not much time seems to have gone by since she was killed.
A 5 yen coin painted black with a Sharpie.
'Kurobei'!
'Kurobei'?
The nickname of this pickpocket.
She's called by that name because
she sneaks three black 5 yen coins into the pockets
of those she pickpockets.
Why do something like that?
It's rumored to be a play on words.
The five (go) for a 5 yen coin,
the black (kuro) color of the Sharpie, and 3 (san) coins
make up the word "gokurosan" (Thank you).
In other words, thank you for earning money for me
to pickpocket from you.
Officer, this way, this way!
Doc!
Huh? Who are you children?
Get away from the corpse!
I'm an FBI agent Jodie Starling!
FBI?
Block the entrance and exit of this shrine immediately!
-Get the police detectives. -Yes, ma'am!
Then, the perp is that person called Kurobei?
No.
Since the coin purse that she had on her
was filled with black painted coins.
She's probably Kurobei herself!
-Huh? -This pack of bills
that's bundled together with a rubber band inside her wallet.
Inside it...
This is a GPS transmitter.
Transmitter?
If a cell phone is used with only a discrepancy of five meters,
the location can be specified.
If a thing like that were inside the wallet
wrapped inside a pack of bills of a pickpocket...
Yeah. The one who was pickpocketed by Kurobei
is probably the killer!
We give out the orders, Jodie.
You may be a FBI agent but this is Japan, you know.
Moreover, you're here on vacation, aren't you?
With you going around giving out orders on your own,
we'll lose face.
I'm sorry.
My usual habit took command of me.
But, this site is far from the entrance or exit of the shrine.
Not too much time had passed since the victim was killed.
So by closing off the entrance and exit of the shrine,
I'm sure the perp has been contained.
Right, Conan?
Well, it's true that you did the right thing,
and it helped us out but...
But, is it true?
That this woman who was slugged to death
was who the 3rd investigation division's
been pursuing all these years,
that she's the pickpocket Kurobei?
I think there's no mistake about it.
In the coin purse that she had on her,
there were a lot of black painted 5 yen coins.
It seems that Kurobei actually did leave
three black painted 5 yen coins in the pockets
of those she pickpocketed but...
And?
Is it true that you witnessed Kurobei
being slugged to death, Dr. Agasa?
Yes.
I happened to witness it when I came out here
after using the restroom.
Since this place is in the shade of the tree and dark,
at first I thought that someone was just hammering something.
Did you see the perp's face?
It was mostly all silhouetted.
What I'm sure of is that the perp was wearing a hat,
and also was holding a thin stick about 30cm long.
I see. So, that's the murder weapon.
Any other characteristics of the perp?
Let's see.
Oh, come to think of it, when the perp left,
he was dragging his leg a bit!
So, I called out to ask if he was okay.
Dragging his leg?
And, what about the perp?
He ignored me and left.
By the time I found out that the perp had slugged a woman,
he had already disappeared into the crowd.
I see.
Inspector.
If the perp wanted to get out of here as fast as possible
and the perp was dragging his leg...
It doesn't seem to be an act
to make it off the suspect's list.
But, with only that to go on, it'll be more than difficult
to figure out who did it from among this crowd of flower viewers...
That's close to impossible to do.
I think you can narrow down the target a bit more.
There was something strange in that lady's wallet too.
Something strange?
A GPS transmitter wrapped inside the bills!
Why would something like that be...
If that pickpocket Kurobei was never caught,
it would be impossible to identify Kurobei
until the 5 yen coins painted black
are put into the pocket of the person who was pickpocketed!
So, by making Kurobei deliberately pickpocket
a wallet with the GPS transmitter inside, the perp,
after locating the whereabouts of Kurobei using a cell phone,
waits for Kurobei to go to a lonely place
then slugs her to death!
Then the one who was pickpocketed by Kurobei's the perp?
But, pickpockets frequently work in groups too.
So it could be that they got into a fight and...
True.
I think Kurobei worked alone.
She herself, shouted, "Pickpocket!"
Huh? Just what do you mean?
It's a trick that most pickpockets use!
When you hear that a pickpocket is around,
most people check their wallets, don't they?
That's how pickpockets figure out where their targets
keep their wallets.
And, if she had an accomplice,
she'd make the accomplice do that part, right?
That's why I think she also took your wallet, Jodie.
Oh! My wallet's gone!
She probably took it when you helped her up!
But with the pickpocket dead...
How on earth do we go about looking for the victims
who were pickpocketed?
As to that, I think that soon...
Conan, we found it!
Inside the trash can that was on the side of
where the oracles are tied!
I also found one!
Inside the trash can near the place I drank the water!
Oh! Found another one!
Inside the trash can of the place where the bell is rung!
The shrine owner is taking it for me now!
Here, it was inside the trash can a bit ahead
of the toilet that was the crime scene.
They were about to collect the trash,
but I asked them to let me search the trash first.
Okay, then bring the wallets you found
without putting your fingerprints on them!
-Okay! -Copy.
Right, the wallets!
Pickpockets remove only the money
and dispose of the wallets,
so if we search the contents of the wallets...
We could maybe find the owners of the wallets.
Yes!
Are these four wallets all that you found in the trash cans?
Yes, because the workers said they started
collecting trash from the trash can
that I was searching.
Oh, that blue wallet is mine!
Then, you're one of the suspects too.
What?
No, Jodie's not!
She was with us right through
after she bumped into that lady!
She had no time to kill anybody!
Oh, is that so?
If so, the killer
is highly likely to be one of the owners
of the three wallets that are left.
Oh! Maybe the owner of this wallet can be found right away
since there's a driver's license inside.
Yeah! I saw this man a while ago.
-Huh? -He's the one
who came to talk to Jodie!
He said he had a cold and was wearing a mask!
I see.
It seems that the only wallet with a driver's license inside
is just this black wallet though.
A photo?
I know her too!
What?
She taught us how to ring the bell!
I think she's still around some place.
In the last red wallet, the only thing inside
is an oracle that says "little lucky".
I guess the owner of this wallet won't be found.
I think it's that old man's wallet.
He said that lucky oracles should be taken home.
Yes. Besides, I saw!
He was in front of us
and took money out from that red wallet
to buy the oracle!
Oh! I saw it too!
We thought it was a wallet
that didn't match an old man like him!
Do you know what he looks like?
-Yep! -We'll go look for him then!
Please wait for us to come back!
Hey, all of you!
The person may be a murderer, you know!
Officer Takagi, you go with the children!
Yes, sir!
If one of the three has a stick about 30cm,
then we got the perp.
I think you'll be able to tell right away
even if the perp doesn't have it!
Just what do you mean, Conan?
Because the perp left 3 painted black 5 yen coins
near the corpse, as if to say, I'm paying you back!
Huh?
5 yen coins that are so unique
are not that easy to prepare, are they?
I get it!
So, the person that doesn't have the black 5 yen coins
that Kurobei would've put into his pocket is the perp!
Right!
Hey, what is it?
What do you officers want to ask us so suddenly?
Are you saying we did something?
Before we go any further, first of all,
please let us check to see if in your pockets or bags,
you have any 5 yen coins that are painted black?
5 yen coins that are painted black?
What's that about?
Why would I have something so strange like...
Why is something like this...
I found it, black 5 yen coins.
-I've found one too. -Me too.
This is...
You mean all three have it?
What on earth is going on?
What's this grotesque 5 yen coin about?
That's what the pickpocket Kurobei
left behind for you as a gift, you see.
Huh? No joke? Then you mean I was pickpocketed?
Oh. I realized a while ago that I didn't have my wallet
and was just about to report it to the police.
Well, I didn't have much inside anyway,
so she could go ahead and take it, but...
Did you nab that pickpocket?
No, not really.
Just a while ago, she was found dead.
What?
We think that one of you is the perp.
One of us?
No.
You mean we're not victims?
We'll start with a body check of all of you
then check your belongings and cell phone.
Of course, this is voluntary so you may reject this.
Only if you do reject, I think you'll have more problems later.
-So if at all possible... -Okay!
Go on and check me if you want to!
But, mind you,
I'm fat, so my cell phone may be sticky.
Put up with that, will you?
Jodie?
Did you notice something?
No. I was just recalling a man from a video
you previously took for me.
Remember, the time when we deliberately dropped our cell phone
and made them pick it up to figure out who the spy
the Organization snuck into the hospital was?
The first one who picked it up
was an oily skinned fat man.
But the one who picked it up after him was the spy,
and the last one, an old man had a pace maker imbedded.
And that cell phone... Shu...
Why don't we take her on the car of an acquaintance of mine?
-Huh? -We could lie her down in the backseat.
Because those bad buys probably think that
she's going to be carried off in a large car
that can accommodate a stretcher.
I think they'll never find out!
I guess so, but...
I'll go outside and call him then.
I'm sure he'll come right away.
That's something I can't do, not even for you, sonny.
This is a job for the FBI.
We can't afford to get ordinary citizens
involved in something like this anymore.
Oh, but...
Leave the rest to us.
Jodie?
That's not of any concern now, is it?
I guess so.
I'm sorry.
I think I'm a bit flustered at finding out
that the man with the burn wasn't Shu.
I've got to shape up.
What's the matter?
Raising your voice suddenly like that.
Oh, no. It's nothing.
And how about it, Doc?
Is the perp that you saw among the three?
Well, that old man with the cane is suspicious I guess,
but the perp had a thin stick about 30cm.
He wasn't using a cane, either.
The hat that the perp was wearing
was not a hunting cap that old people would wear
or a knitted cap for women,
but rather, a mountain climbing hat.
Besides, the perp didn't have a cough like that man.
But, maybe he's just pretending to have a cold?
I don't think so.
At the point we met him for the first time,
he had no way of knowing that we were acquaintances of Doc.
So, he wouldn't have needed to pretend
that he had a cold in front of us, right?
Well, I guess so.
Then Doctor, how about the style of walking?
You said the perp was dragging his legs a bit, no?
That old man, rather than drag his leg,
seems unable to stand without a cane.
The other two don't look to be dragging their legs either.
What? You can't find the murder weapon?
Did you look in every crevice and cranny?
Yes, sir. We looked inside the drain of the water spot,
and even inside the offertory box.
Those three didn't have any, did they?
No! We even checked the old man's cane
but there were no traces of it having been used
as a murder weapon.
Besides, we checked the cell phones of the three
but none of the cell phones had an application that enables
pursuit of a transmitter.
Maybe it was deleted to prevent us from finding it, though.
Yes.
But, to check any further, we need a warrant.
Hey, you guys!
When you met those three, did anyone of them act strange?
Act strange?
For example, like somebody coming,
to secretly give them what looked to be a thin stick?
All three of them were by themselves!
The old man taught us to take home the oracle
if the result was good too.
That lady told us to ring the bell loudly
so that god could hear us!
The other man,
said that he already cleansed his hands at the water spot.
It seems he was at the shrine way
before we got here though.
Inspector Megure!
We found the hat and coat that could be the perp's!
Oh, is that so!
There's probably no mistake about it,
because blood is splattered on it.
But it's covered with flower petals.
Yes. It was covered with withered petals
as if to hide it.
What?
Then, maybe the murder weapon is hidden in the same way!
Find it even if you have to scatter the flower petals!
Yes, sir!
What? I mean it looks like a nice pink carpet, and yet!
True.
If you look at them one by one, they're flower petals,
and yet when many of them are scattered over the ground,
they look just like one pink carpet.
Yep.
I see. So, that's the story.
That's why that person
said something like that to the children.
If so, the reason the perp was dragging his foot
was probably because...
It seems that he got to the truth of the case but...
isn't aware of ours.
Hey, how long do you intend to keep us stranded here?
The sun's starting to set already!
I don't know if you're working on a case or what but...
It has nothing to do with us, right?
We're very sorry. Please give us a little more time.
Inspector Megure!
We've got to open the doorways of the shrine already.
I see.
And, the murder weapon?
Too bad, but we haven't got word that it's been found yet.
Maybe the perp already fled this shrine
and took the murder weapon along too.
No, because taking into consideration,
the time from when the incident occurred
and entrance and exit were closed off,
as well as the perp dragging his leg while leaving.
It's highly likely that the perp
is still on the grounds of this shrine!
And that the stick that's about 30cm that Mr. Agasa witnessed
the perp having, is hidden somewhere here too!
If so, the most suspicious
are those three victims of pickpocket.
Yeah.
If there was a GPS wrapped in the bills
of the wallet of the pickpocket who was slugged to death...
Just as Jodie mentioned, the suspect deliberately
made the pickpocket steal the wallet with the GPS inside,
in order to slug her to death in a lonely place.
But, those three, don't look to have hurt their legs.
Besides, the old man, rather than dragging his feet,
cannot walk without his cane.
And moreover, if the perp had an accomplice
who he secretly passed the murder weapon onto,
it would have to be one of the flower viewers here.
We'd have to check all of them.
That won't be necessary.
The perp still has a part of the weapon hidden on him!
A part of it?
Oh, that's right!
The perp bundled that stuff together
and made the murder weapon!
Bundled?
The murder weapon that you saw, Mr. Agasa
was a stick, wasn't it?
What does bundle have to do with it?
The perp bundled it into one. A lot of a certain thing!
And, the perp hid it in a place where it
wouldn't look suspicious
even if there were a lot of it around.
He called out to the children
and nicely set up a camouflage too.
-Huh? -You mean to us?
Then, are you talking about that old man
who talked to us at the location where the oracles were tied?
Come to think of it, there were a lot of oracles tied on,
so no one would know the difference if more were added, right?
But no matter how many oracles you bundle together,
you could never make a murder weapon
enough to slug a person to death with.
It's only paper after all.
Then, is it that man?
The one who said he didn't need the scoopers
that Genta handed to him at the water spot.
I'm sure it was him!
There were many scoopers at the water spot too!
If there was a scooper made of iron among them...
The police would've found it long ago.
I guess so.
Of course there was no such scoopers.
The only one left is that lady we saw at the place
to ring the bell.
But, there were only two bells!
Didn't you guys do something before you rang the bell?
-I see! -We threw in money offering.
We put in 5 yen coins!
Inside the offertory box!
Right. Offerings usually made by throwing in 5 yen coins,
because they symbolize "goen" meaning good ties with others.
That's why most of the coins are 5 yen coins with holes in them!
I see.
If you join all the coins by pulling a string or wire
through them and bundle them together,
you can make a thin long stick.
On top of that, even if a lot of 5 yen coins
were to later be found in the offertory box,
they would be mixed with other monetary offerings
so it wouldn't look suspicious.
The perp can deceive the eyes of the police
who are set on looking for a thin long metal stick!
But in order to make a stick as long as 30cm,
you'll need around 200 five yen coins.
Besides, if you throw in that many coins at once,
the people around will get suspicious, won't they?
That's why the perp called out to the children
and told them that unless they ring the bell loudly,
god won't hear them.
Then...
The perp is...
That's right.
The one who hid a GPS transmitter into the wallet
to confirm the whereabouts of the pickpocket,
then used a lot of 5 yen coins by bundling them
into the form of a stick to make the murder weapon,
then finally slugged Ms. Ikuyo Yatani,
so-called pickpocket Kurobei, to death is...
you!
Then...
The perp is...
That's right.
The one who hid a GPS transmitter into the wallet
to confirm the whereabouts of the pickpocket,
then used a lot of 5 yen coins by bundling them
into the form of a stick to make the murder weapon,
then finally slugged Ms. Ikuyo Yatani,
so-called pickpocket Kurobei, to death is...
you!
Ms. Yoriko Danno!
You called out to the children
and made them ring the bell very loudly,
and erased the sound of the load of 5 yen coins
being put into the offertory box!
You untied the tip of the string
that bundled the 5 yen coins together,
held the edge of the string
and hung it down in the offertory box.
In this way you slid the load of coins into the box at once.
Moreover, the murder was committed
before you rang the bell.
Although by then your wallet
should've been pickpocketed by the victim.
You lied saying that you weren't aware this,
threw money into the offertory box and rang the bell.
This is proof that you're the one who did it!
True.
You should've noticed that you'd been pickpocketed
at the time you opened your wallet to throw in the offering.
Oh my, don't you know?
A saying goes that one should not open their wallet
in front of the offertory box.
If god sees the contents of your wallet,
and finds that you have a lot,
but are only giving a small offering, you may enrage him.
That's why when I come to visit the shrine
I keep 5 yen coins as is, in my pocket!
I see. That's why you say you didn't realize
that your wallet was gone?
That's right!
Well, if you saw me putting a load of 5 yen coins
into the offertory box,
I wouldn't mind admitting it, though.
We don't have to see it to prove it.
So long as we check that shoelace of yours.
You probably used your shoelace
to bundle the 5 yen coins together.
That's why you couldn't leave the site right away.
Because you were missing one of your shoelaces,
your shoe would come off if you walked the way you usually do.
After ringing the bell,
it seems you put your shoelace back on and re-tied it.
If you used that shoelace to commit the crime,
it should be there...
the blood of the victim that splattered
when you slugged her to death.
Excuse me.
It's here.
Blood stains.
But, why did you have extra 5 yen coins on you?
Weren't the 5 yen coins found near the corpse
the ones that were put in your pocket
when your wallet was pickpocketed?
Those were the ones I showed you police a while ago.
Then, what about those 5 yen coins?
I put it near that woman because those coins
were the ones that woman put into my wallet
when she pickpocketed me last year.
The 5 yen coins that took the life of my son!
Son...
You mean the one that was in the photo
that was in your wallet?
Yes. That's right.
When I was pickpocketed last year,
my car keys were also in my wallet.
And, because I didn't have the keys, my son who had asthma
was locked in the car for several hours.
We got to the hospital too late
and as a result, he died.
So, I checked everywhere on the internet about that pickpocket
and ambushed her in places that she was prone to appear.
But, why the photo?
If it hadn't been in your wallet,
we might not have known it was yours.
If you try to take money out of the wallet,
that photo would jump into your eyes, wouldn't it?
I wanted to let her know
that when she pickpocketed back then,
she not only took my money.
But, also took the life of a little boy as well.
Then, may I go home already?
Yes.
I'll be going too, then.
We're still working on the pickpocket case,
so we may ask you some question at a later date though.
Oh, that's okay with me.
Please contact me.
Uh, sir!
Do you have bad eyes, sir?
Huh? Why do you ask?
Because that lady pickpocket
saw your face and looked really surprised.
I think that was because
she just pickpocketed your wallet a while ago.
Why didn't you say anything back then, sir?
In spite it being the second time you saw her.
Right.
I've got bad eyesight, you see.
If you got bad eyes, you can't view the cherry blossoms
unless you wear glasses!
Did you come to view flowers alone?
Actually I came to get lucky charms.
What kind of lucky charms?
For me, right?
Motoe?
For this child.
I see, a baby.
A charm to help assist a safe birth, eh?
I told you to stay still at home, didn't I?
I came to check on you, because you didn't come home
and I got worried!
Then, could you by chance be...
the one who masking taped me during the bank robbery?
Oh, you're that non-Japanese person that was there?
I'm sorry for what I did then,
I was threatened, and had no choice.
Are you all right?
I'm sorry, Motoe doesn't seem to be feeling well,
so could we leave?
Huh? Yes.
Morning sickness is a symptom that seen
during the early stages of pregnancy, right?
Yeah. But the size of her stomach
looked big enough to be six months pregnant.
Well, she could be feeling nausea for some other reason too.
Yes, that's right, Camel.
That man with the burn, wasn't Shu, I guess.
He seemed to have been just a decoy sent out
by the Organization
to confirm whether Shu really died or not.
Oh, Jodie.
Anyway, I'll give you the details after I get back there, okay?
I think the cash has been taken,
but please confirm the contents of the wallet.
Yes.
All my cards are intact
and the contents of my pocket.
This is... back during the department hijacking.
Huh? The edge of the coaster is bent.
Run for it! This area is dangerous.
Shu!
Shu.
If that man with the burn isn't Shu...
Who on earth's doing this? For what?
I'm sorry, Agent Jodie.
Hey, you.
You'll catch cold sleeping in a place like...
Huh?
Hey, you?
Don't worry! He's just drunk and sleeping.
Huh?
My big brother's not a strong drinker.
Twins?
What an incident that was?
To think that the man you disguised yourself as
was pickpocketed.
I did think something was strange
because he didn't have a wallet, though.
Well, it was good for me that I took the queer 5 yen coins
that the man had on him.
But, to go out of the way to return the wallet
that was pickpocketed back to him.
I didn't want him to make a big fuss later!
Because there was a cash card
and driver's license inside too, you know.
Well, you'd better be grateful.
When that kitty cat of the FBI grabbed your arm,
the wiretap that you put into the fold of her sleeve,
I made sure I retrieved it for you.
Thank you.
And?
From that kitty cat,
did you get to listen to any good stories?
Yes. I got a lot of what I wanted.
I got to hear unexpected stories
that went on behind the scenes too besides.
I hope I get to hear the rest of that story from you.
Yes, as soon as I get solid proof, I will.
But, let me just tell you this.
He's a dreadfully intelligent man.
That young man.
So, you're not convinced of Kogoro's deduction after all?
I see!
That's what that left hand meant.
Oh no! I've got to let her know right away!
This is bad!
Kaori!
Next Conan, "A Coded Invitation"
Next Conan Hint:
"Left Hand"