"Detective Conan"
"Special"
Isn't it rare? A museum.
Aren't you curious what he looks like?
I'm sure he's a nice man!
Like Harrison Ford, John Reno or maybe Brad Pitt.
I hear that he collects famous jewellery from the world over
and holds exhibitions.
I hear that you get to see the largest black pearl in the world.
Is that the pearl that is said to bring happiness,
the black pearl called the "Black Star"?
"Saturday night when the moon is full,"
"at the sound of the bell at midnight,"
"I will appear to take the clock that soars high above away."
Three steel crows in the dark of the night.
Still yet beyond... there are two more.
Oops, they've even got an armored vehicle ready.
Just as expected of the Metropolitan Police Department.
They've sure gone all out!
Don't, Kaito.
I have an uncomfortable feeling about this project.
If you are cornered into a fix like before,
and if something should ever happen to you,
I, as your steward, wouldn't be able to apologize to him
before his altar.
Gosh!
You're always like this before a big project.
Give me a break, will you? Here!
But, Kaito...
Besides, tonight I'm not the son of Toichi Kurobane,
the magician whom you served as steward for
nor am I Kaito the 8th grader!
I'm the one who is the talk of the town right now.
I'm just a villain who's putting on airs.
Kaito.
"The Detectives Come Together!"
"Kudo VS. Thief Kid"
"Ekoda High School" -Too easy.
Way too easy.
The next job is duck soup that I could complete it
with the tip of my pinky.
Women fans entranced by Thief Kid are rapidly on the rise!
Talk about just great.
Women fans on the rise, my foot!
That petty thief!
To me, Aoko, he's just a rotten apple of a man
running down the path of hopelessness!
Oh, well...
Cool it, don't be angry.
Just because you father, that dorky inspector
is always being undone by him.
It can't be helped, can it?
After all, the Kid is...
One. Two.
There!
A great thief that is impossible to arrest!
Anyway, as for that Inspector,
he wouldn't be able to arrest the Kid
even if Star Wars were to come up with a completed version.
Gosh! Just because you resemble the Kid
and can perform a little bit of magic,
you're always sticking up for him.
That guy's seeking nothing more than self-satisfaction
by disposing what he steals
and returning it secretly later, a pretentious goody-goody!
Oh my.
That's the very thing I like about him.
He's cute, just like a mischievous young boy.
Oh. Akako. Akako!
Don't let him deceive you!
That guy is nothing but a criminal,
no matter how you look at it! He is a villain!
Besides, you saw what the Kid is after next on TV, didn't you?
Oh, you mean the old clock tower in front of the station?
Right! That belongs to everyone here in this town!
So, don't you think it's terrible of him to steal it?
Yes. I guess so.
Moreover, that place is...
That clock tower is...
But, I heard that the clock tower was going to be moved
somewhere else soon anyway.
That it was going to be used as the symbol of some amusement park.
Keiko.
Everybody was saying that if it was going to be moved elsewhere,
it may as well be taken away by the Kid.
What's not good is not good!
Hey. I don't know what you're up to, but...
I really think you should call off the job
you're planning to carry out this time!
Listen, I've been telling you that I am not the Kid!
The old tower that tells time,
when the 20,000 bells sing.
A malevolent man will come flying from the eastern sky
and the white sinner shall be perished.
Is that some stupid something like fortune-telling again?
It's not fortune-telling.
It's a prophecy that has come to me through the devil, Lucifer.
Luci...
The day that clock sounds its bell for the 20,000th time
is the night that you warned you'll be carrying out your deed.
Whether you believe me or not is up to you, though.
To all vehicles, helicopters circling the sky
and police cars patrolling the vicinity of the clock tower.
Report any sightings of suspicious people to me immediately!
All of you who are in charge of
guarding the inside of the museum,
don't let anybody through without my orders!
Guard the post that you are assigned to
with your entire heart and soul!
But, Inspector Nakamori.
I wonder if Kid's really going to show up?
His warning went like this, right?
Saturday night when the moon is full,
at the sound of the bell at midnight,
I will appear to take the clock that soars high above away.
The Thief Kid.
I was thinking that he would have to use a darn big crane
if he were to take a clock that large away.
You idiot! When he says he'll steal something,
-he will! -The needle of the clock.
This clock tower
is one that my father who was mayor 50 years ago,
dished out a large sum
and asked a famous designer technician from abroad to make.
The short hand of the clock,
along with the signature of the designer
has several large diamonds embedded in it.
It is a highly evaluated work of art.
He's probably after the diamonds.
Why'd you let the owner through?
I'm sorry. He insisted that he wanted to check out
the conditions of security with his own eyes so.
I sure hope you checked thoroughly whether he is really the owner?
Why, of course.
Whatever you do.
Whatever you do, please protect it
from the evil hands of that petty thief that sent me
that ridiculous letter of challenging warning.
The dear clock tower that had inherited from my late father,
do protect it.
Yes. We will, owner.
I'm counting on you.
By the way, Inspector!
I haven't seen Police Superintendent Hakuba's son,
Saguru around lately.
Yeah. Something about he had some unfinished case to take care of
and went back to London.
We sure could've used his help, couldn't we?
-You idiot! -Oh, I'm so sorry!
What makes you think we can be counting on
that costume wearing freak time after time!
Only 28 minutes and 30 seconds till the promised time.
Here goes then.
Residing in Ekoda.
27 years old. Single, police officer Yoichi Sensui.
I'm going to borrow you name and face for a while.
Excuse me!
Kid...
Look at the number of onlookers.
Oh, owner! Owner, how was it inside?
"Sujio Hosokawa (32)" -Perfect!
"Takarada's assistant" -Not an ant can get through.
But I wonder if everything is okay
on the amusement park side.
Since it will not make it in time for the opening unless
the construction for moving the clock tower is started tomorrow,
purchase of the clock tower may be cancelled.
Moreover, if Kid ever steals the precious stones
that are embedded in the short hand of the clock,
and if he finds out that the stones are...
We're the only ones who know now,
that I have already sold the diamonds off
and switched them for fake ones.
Besides, the price of it has jumped high,
now that everyone knows the Thief Kid is after it,
and there wouldn't be a better time to sell it.
Whether they find out about the whole thing
after the relocation is none of my business.
Besides, it would never be stolen!
How could he ever steal that enormous clock tower
in front of all these people?
No matter how great a phantom thief he is!
Don't you dare come, Thief Kid!
Don't give it to him, Dad!
Hey! Hey, Aoko!
You're the only one saying something like that.
I know, but... By the way, Keiko, did you see Kaito?
Nope, not at all.
Oh, right, he said he's going to be watching a magic show
that is going to be aired tonight.
Oh.
I guess I'm the only one
who remembers something so old that happened in the past.
What?
You witnessed a suspicious looking Thief Kid like character
while on patrol?
Yes, sir! He dropped this suspicious looking hat and left.
This is Thief Kid's silk hat and cape!
Will you wait here a while?
-Yes, sir! -Inspector Nakamori, please.
Yes, the silk hat and cape are here.
Yes...
It seems so.
Okay! I've got approval from the Inspector!
Will you explain the circumstances back then
and the features of the man directly
to the Inspector who is at the top most floor?
-Yes, sir! -Kid!
Kid...
Duck soup!
Without Hakuba around, it's so easy that it's no fun after all.
Here they come, Akiko.
Yes. No doubt about it.
It's that helicopter.
He emits the same transparent vibe that Kaito emits.
He has the cunning of the devil,
and possesses a keen eye that sees through the hearts of people.
Who is he?
Hey! What's going on? There is one extra chopper!
It's another support helicopter sent over by headquarters.
Support from headquarters?
I don't recall asking for something like that!
The Thief Kid's silk hat, eh?
I've been informed of you.
Please show me your police I.D. and license, just to be sure.
Yes, of course!
Please give me your name, age and birth date.
Yoichi Sensui, 27 years old, born June 2nd.
Okay, good work!
Inspector Nakamori is waiting for you at the top floor.
Yes, sir.
Right, just in case, give me your driver's license number.
Oh, yes.
Yes, number 628605-524810.
He's the Thief Kid!
Nab him!
This can't be happening?
What?
You found the Thief Kid inside the building?
Yes, sir! The C and D groups are pursuing him right now!
Hey. Hey. I hope he's no imposter?
No, there's no mistake about it!
After he answered his name, age and birth date,
I remember I was told to ask for his driver's license number.
-His driver's license number? -Yes, sir!
The boy who was sent over by headquarters
had informed me that
if the thief is an expert at disguising himself as another,
he would probably remember what others
would usually not be able to recall.
A boy, you said?
I repeat.
Please close off the entrance and exit
of the clock tower immediately!
Please don't open them until we instruct you to.
He's no more than a mole in a hole that cannot move now.
D group, Nakamura and Kawada!
We've lost sight of him near the 3rd floor toilet.
Please calm down, I'm sure he is still somewhere near you.
What?
The ventilation hole that is beyond that toilet.
Aren't the screws removed?
It's been removed...
Then, he's in there! Please resume pursuing him!
There he is! It's him!
Hey. The inspector sure is sharp today.
Or, is someone helping the inspector out?
But, who could it be?
Megure! So, it's you after all!
Just what do you think you're doing,
bringing a kid to a place like this?
I'm the commander of this site!
And, besides, you don't belong in this section!
Well, I'm very sorry.
I promised that I'd let him board this chopper once.
So, I thought I may as well bring him along while I was at it.
-Huh? Hey! -Inspector!
I hate to be rude, but we've got no time debating with you.
If you want to arrest the thief, please follow my orders.
What?
He is thrown off at being identified
before having the chance to carry out his act.
His plan is not going as he planned.
There is no better chance to capture him, but now!
Who are you? Who the heck are you?
I am...
Shinichi Kudo.
A detective.
Shinichi Kudo?
Oh. I know him, I know him!
A high school detective who solves mysterious cases
one after the other.
Then, you're also in the wrong section!
We're after a thief!
Inspector! He's just a high school student
and belongs to no section...
At any rate, this is a job for the police to handle!
Outsiders just stay put in that chopper of yours!
Understand?
Inspector Nakamori!
Nakamura of the D group, after receiving word from the boy,
discovered the Thief Kid,
disguised as a police officer inside the ventilation duct!
They are still pursuing him!
What?
Nakamura of the D group here!
It seems that our target is trying to exit
from the ventilation duct!
What should we do?
Don't panic.
Your target is already caught in your claws.
Please tell me your present location.
Well, since I was moving along in the dark,
I'm not so sure of where I am.
I know that I went up one flight of stairs from the 3rd floor
and that this is the 4th floor.
No problem! The exits of all the 28 ventilation holes there
are within the building have all been closed off!
Please just keep on pursuing him.
There is no escape route for him anymore.
The officers who are blocking off
the exit of the ventilation hole on the 4th floor
should get ready to arrest him.
How dare he giving out orders on his own again?
This is Nakamura of D group!
I lost sight of him near the exit of the ventilation duct!
What is your present location?
This is...
The corridor to the east on the 4th floor!
Huh?
The target has gotten rid of his disguise as an officer
and is fleeing down the stairs.
Please send a support force over right away.
Thief Kid...
Great work, officer.
Okay! He panicked and got rid of his disguise as an officer!
Everyone proceed to the fourth floor and capture the thief!
Don't let him get away!
But, why does that boy have so much information
as to the structure of this clock tower?
Of course! Because I sent him the data
that I have in this computer over to him a while ago.
You idiot.
Strange.
For him to remove his disguise as an officer in the space
that is surrounded by officers,
is like a hermit crab disposing of its shell
and roaming within the sea.
To me, that is incomprehensible.
It's time, Inspector Nakamori.
Oh, yeah.
Inspector!
Smoke has burst forth from the foothold
at the construction site!
What?
Inspector Nakamori! The hands of the clock are gone!
What? They're gone?
It...
It can't be.
Wow! The Thief Kid is really something.
Thief Kid.
I hate you, Thief Kid.
Is anything wrong?
It's swaying?
Yeah, you mean this chopper is swaying?
-No, Inspector! -No?
Inspector, where are you headed?
I'm going to go up and check the engine room of the clock.
Could you please bring the chopper closer to the clock tower?
Darn! What the heck is going on anyway?
Anything new?
No.
What the...
Hey, what happened?
A police officer appeared from the ventilation duct and...
What?
After spraying something strange at us,
he went out from there.
It... it can't be.
If so, he should be clearly visible to those outside.
Thief Kid!
Thief Kid...
It's me! Nakamori! I've found Kid!
He is...
Inspector Nakamori.
My apologies that
I have no time now to be playing with all of you.
What?
Besides, it seems that you have a "joker"
who is pretty sharp on your side too.
On our side?
And, if you're going to summon anybody,
I'd like you to do so after.
I'd like you to decipher the code that has been carved
in the middle of the face of the clock.
Code?
Yes, I'd like you to decipher it before calling anyone.
The face of the clock is swaying?
What is the meaning of this, Kudo?
He is lighting up the face of the clock together
with the curtain of smoke.
The light is turned off, and the face of the clock is covered
with a gigantic screen that has been set up beforehand
and projected on the screen is a film
of the hand of the clock disappearing.
The film is projected from a projector that
has been assembled onto a foothold at a construction site.
But, it's so easy to figure that trick out.
That trick...
fake!
He's probably behind the screen right now
removing the diamonds that are embedded
in the short hand of the clock.
I'm going to borrow this for a while.
Hey! Who is it? Who's firing the gun?
Darn.
With the chopper at such close range,
I can't possibly fly using my hand glider.
What shall I do? What now?
Hey, Kudo!
Don't worry! I won't hit anyone.
No! That's not the point. Kudo!
Now, for the finale of your magic show.
Let's watch the leader of the troupe appear.
What a guy!
To fall onto the crowd together with the screen.
It's impossible to find him among that crowd.
Yes. Megure here.
Hey! Megure! Are you the one who fired?
No. I'm not the one who fired.
By the way, Inspector, didn't he leave a message with you?
Yeah, he did. Something about a code.
Code?
This is Greek to me.
Was a letter like this
really carved in the center of the face of the clock?
Yeah. That's it!
At any rate, that's important evidence.
We've got to have them postpone moving the clock tower
until the code is deciphered.
I don't need you to tell me that.
Well, I guess all is well since the clock tower is safe
and his plan didn't work out.
No, Inspector Megure.
He left a code on the face of the clock
and left the clock tower up to the police to take care of.
He took the clock tower away from the hands of the owner
who was planning to have it moved.
Besides, it's written in the code, see?
You change the Katakana characters to Roman characters,
and move the vowels one space each clockwise and read it.
It says, "The bell will not toll for you."
Come to think of it,
I still haven't asked you the name of the thief.
Oh, well... I guess it doesn't really matter.
Huh? Are you waiting for somebody too?
I'm going out with daddy.
But, he said he may be busy with work,
so we might not be able to go.
Here you go.
I'm Kaito Kurobane! Nice meeting you!
I'm Kaito Kurobane, nice meeting you!
Kaito!
I wouldn't forget, you idiot.
Kaito. Is anything the matter?
Thanks to your remark I just remembered something!
The clock tower incident, when I was really in a fix.
And, whatever became of that clock tower?
Oh, yeah, you don't know about it since you moved.
Then, it has since been moved over after all.
Three. Two.
One!
This is the sound of...
The police investigated afterwards,
and found that the diamonds were fake,
so the city bought it for a cheap price.
Okay! Shall we get going then?
His real target is the "Big Jewel".
The jewel in the possession of the Suzuki Financial Group,
the "Black Star"!
Kaito, I'm not about to stop you at this point.
But, Toichi used to always say.
Making contact with a client is always a battlefield.
Never be conceited, or take them lightly.
Look into their hearts,
and concentrate all your nerves to look through them.
Give it all the skills you have,
yet, keep smiling and be gracious...
No matter what happens,
never forget putting on a poker face, right?
Kaito.
I'm back!
You've got mail.
Oh, no! What is this? It gives me the creeps.
What's all the fuss about, Ran?
Well, take a look at this, see.
"Mr. Kogoro Mouri" is written in calligraphic
white letters on a black envelope.
No stamp, no name of sender.
It's probably a new type of "please join us" direct mails.
I wonder.
What is it?
In honor of your wisdom,
we would like to invite you to a dinner gathering.
See, what did I tell you? Just what I thought it was.
I'll bet they're just trying to add some class
to their party by inviting a detective.
I don't think so.
See, because this fell out of the envelope,
2,000,000 yen is written on it, right?
2,000,000 yen?
Wouldn't it be awfully strange to send something like this
just for something like that?
And, they don't even know if you're going to come or not yet.
Hey, dad.
Isn't the name of the sender somewhere inside?
Now, what is this?
The Phantom of a God Forsaken Child.
How creepy.
The Phantom of a God Forsaken Child...
Be strong I say to my heart.
And step into the essence with strong rhythm.
The curtains are raised for Detective Conan's 21st Century's episode.
Six other detectives appear including Kid.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
Conan, can you check the tire over that side?
What's wrong, dad?
Wow! The tire on this side is super flat.
Huh? A flat tire?
What bummers.
There's no spare tire! Darn it!
-Hey, Pops. -What is it?
See, over there.
There's a service station over there!
Wow, talk about lucky.
A Buddha in hell indeed.
Darn, shortcut, my foot!
How dare that guy at the service station tell us to use this road!
Dad, is this really the right road?
Of course!
He took me into his stand
and sold this really expensive map,
that he insisted was very explanatory of this area too!
If this isn't the right road, he's going to pay for it!
So, we've finally come out to a normal looking road.
I guess he wasn't lying when he said that this was a shortcut.
Because, see, isn't that it on the right hand side?
The place that we're headed for.
It sure is an eerie looking building.
It looks more like Dracula's mansion, than Twilight Inn to me.
Hey, dad, are we really going there?
To a place like that.
You idiot!
We've got no choice after getting an invitation like that.
There was a 2,000,000 yen stamp enclosed in the letter too besides.
But wasn't there something eerie written by the sender?
Oh, about the child forsaken by God thing.
Don't worry about it.
It's just somebody bluffing nonsense.
I wonder.
Let's not go, after all.
We've already come this far.
But, what if a Dracula really appears?
Don't be ridiculous.
There is no such thing as Dracula in Japan.
If there is anything, it would be, a mountain witch.
Mountain witch!
Now, what a way to greet a woman at first meeting.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
What are you doing out in a place like this, granny?
Most obviously, my cute little Fiat stalled on me.
So, I was waiting for someone to come by.
You folks are going to the Twilight Inn too, aren't you?
If it's not too much trouble, would you give me a lift?
Yes, why not?
Go ahead and ride in the back seat.
And, while you're at it,
would you please move my things from my Fiat into your car?
Oh, all right.
Thank you so much.
Do we have a while more to go?
Huh?
We've just got a little more to go,
but, is anything wrong?
I've got to go to the ladies room!
Come on.
Miss?
I guess it's none of the business
but, the principal of the elementary school of our town
used to always say
that people who succeed in life,
are those who never let an opportunity go by.
Once you let the opportunity go by, thinking that
the same sort of opportunity may come by again,
no matter how long you wait for it to come by, it never will.
Why didn't you finish what you wanted to do
when you stopped over at the service station a while ago?
How did you know, granny?
That we stopped over at the service station.
Very easy, little one.
See, over there. The empty ashtray
and the still new cigarette butts on the floor.
Filling the ashtray up
until the cigarettes fall to the floor
goes to show that you are a heavy smoker.
Yet, the ashtray is empty.
The only place you could've emptied it,
is at the service station about 10 kilometers away.
A gentleman who is nice enough
to give a strange old lady a lift
would never throw his cigarettes out of the window of his car
in front of a young lady.
Hey, granny.
Who on earth are you?
I am Furuyo Senma. A detective just like you.
Mr. Sleeping Kogoro.
Furuyo Senma.
The famous one who solves cases
just by listening about cases in a comfy chair.
Come on, flattering an old lady will not get you anywhere.
So, she's the one.
Well then, I guess I'll keep this ashtray for now.
Hey, wait!
Even if we get to the inn, don't ever smoke in front of me.
I hate the smoke of cigarettes.
Darn.
There's the Twilight In right in front of us.
Give it all you got and step on the gas.
"Twilight Inn"
Let's see.
Dad, open the back, please.
The closer you get to it, the more it looks like a haunted house.
Dad, I'm going to go on inside!
The ladies room...
Wow! Look at all those fantastic cars!
A Bentz, a Ferrari, a Porsche.
It sure is full of dangerous cars.
It's an Alfa Romeo!
-Classy. -Hey!
Don't you go touching my girl like that.
This one's a shrewd that I finally tamed after 5 years.
I don't want her to get upset over
some strange man touching her.
Right, flimsy mustache?
Flimsy mustache?
Hi there Mogi, it's been a while.
You were invited over too?
Hey! Granny Senma.
Which means you were invited here too.
Mogi?
He's Detective Harufumi Mogi.
Are you all right, though?
I read in the papers that you were shot
by a Mafia in Chicago last week.
I've forgotten something so old.
And? Have you come around to wanting to get married yet?
You're going to be 40 in three days, aren't you?
Heck... who knows about the future?
Right now, all I want is
something to ease my aching stomach.
Welcome,
Mr. Mogi. Mr. Mouri and Ms. Senma, I believe.
We've been waiting for you.
Please come in.
Oh. Well, this is...
A haunted house?
Please put your umbrellas here.
Oh, okay.
-Hey, you! -Yes, sir!
Please excuse me.
I just went to the kitchen, but...
If I remember correctly, he's...
The gourmet detective...
Shukuzen Ogami.
What? The cook suddenly fell ill and can't come?
You've broken your promise.
I've come all this way looking forward to the dinner!
I'm so very sorry.
I've bought all the ingredients necessary to make dinner, though.
Okay, forget it already!
Lend me your kitchen! I'll make dinner!
Gourmet food and murder
are treasures I cherish that uplift
and stimulate my brain cells!
Darn it!
I'm so sorry
to have kept you waiting.
Why did you summon four detectives up to a remote place
in the mountains like this for?
Well, we actually invited six detectives all together.
Hey,
are you telling me that there are two more detectives?
Yes, another woman and a young man.
Young man? Don't tell me it's Shinichi?
No way! I think it's Heiji.
Right?
No. Two other detectives were also included in the master's list,
but Mr. Kudo could not be contacted
and as for Mr. Hattori, we got a call from his mother
saying that he can't make it
because he's got an exam coming up.
Because those two were cancelled,
the master agree Mr. Mouri
to bring two members of his family.
Oh, and where is this detective lover weirdo?
I have no idea, since I, myself has never met him yet.
Huh? But, you got the list from him, didn't you?
Yes. I did get this list when I came here for an interview
to be hired as a maid.
But, it was a very peculiar type of interview.
Peculiar?
Yes, since it was a high paying job,
people wanting the position crowded over here.
When I entered the interview room,
all I saw there were a computer,
an explanation of the dinner
and a list of the invitees on the desk.
Nobody was in the room.
So, having no choice
I started reading the papers as instructed on the PC.
Suddenly, I heard a noise.
Then, I saw the sentence, "You are hired"
on the screen of the computer.
Then, you don't know why you were hired?
-No. -But, you must've at least heard his voice?
You did say that he gave you an okay, didn't you?
Well, all the details
were exchanged by mail using the cell phone.
Wow. This sounds really interesting.
The thrill is killing me.
I was already electrified the minute I saw
that strange pattern on that door!
It sure does look strange.
I wonder what it is a pattern of?
Be careful, baby.
If I'm not mistaken,
that probably the remains of an old blood stain.
What?
Yuk.
You're joking, aren't you?
No, they're real blood stains.
The remains of blood that had splattered
at just about a 45-degree angle to the door.
Not only the door. On the wall
there are the remains of blood stains streaming downward.
On the floor, there are droplet blood stains.
Although they have been wiped away,
there is blood stains soaked here and there
everywhere in this house.
It seems that these blood stains
are not just those of one or two people.
Just as expected of you.
Luminol.
When it is sprayed onto blood stains,
it is oxidizes because of the active oxygen within the blood,
and emits a bluish purple fluorescent color.
You make good deductions, ex-coroner. Ms. Ikumi Souda.
My, you're smart.
Boy.
I am Saguru Hakuba. Nice to meet you all.
Hakuba?
You mean you're Police Superintendent, Habuba's...
Yes.
Police Superintendent Hakuba is my father indeed,
Mr. Mouri.
An eagle?
Oh, I'm sorry to have scared you.
Whether it was because Watson here was accompanying me in Britain,
I'm not sure, but he has become very sensitive to the smell of blood.
Watson?
I'm sure glad I came all the way back home, though.
After all, here I am standing at the scene
of the tragedy that has been hidden for ages.
One that I have only heard of as rumors.
I'm here at last after a period of 40 years.
This is more than I could ask for to awaken my intellectual excitement.
Tragedy?
No...
You're pretty good.
I've been playing awhile.
How about this, Mr. Sleeping Kogoro?
All right!
Look, look, I've got a straight!
So, I win again!
She sure is as strong as ever.
Wait a minute.
Now, let's not cheat, Ran.
See, the Jack to your very left.
You've got one on top of the other, don't you?
Huh? Oh, you're right.
I'm sorry, I didn't realize it.
They seem to have been stuck together from the start, though.
What's wrong, Ran?
There's blood on the playing card.
My, my, blood has splattered there too, I see.
Come to think of it, the maid was saying,
that the things here
are just as they were at the time of the crime.
That practically nothing had been moved.
Which means that something happened in this room too...
Thank you all for waiting.
Dinner is ready, so please come to the dining room.
The master is waiting for you.
So, the big boss finally makes his appearance.
I can't wait to see him.
I somehow don't seem to have an appetite.
Here we are.
Please go on inside.
Hey, hey, what's with that attire of yours?
I think you've been watching too much TV.
To you all, the distinguished and famed 6 detectives!
Welcome to the Twilight Inn.
Well then, won't you all take your seats?
Take the dishes out just like I instructed to you a while ago.
Yes, sir.
Now, the reason why I invited you all over here is because...
I want you to find the treasure
that I have hidden somewhere in here.
I want you to find the enormous amount of riches
that I have accumulated over the years.
And, risk your lives to do so.
Risk our lives?
What was that sound?
No need to worry.
I just made sure that you'd be stranded here.
What?
I am always being chased around by all of you.
So, I thought I'd experience
being the one to corner you for once.
Besides, I also did away with the bridge
that you crossed to come here,
so even if you had your cars,
you wouldn't have been able to make it out of here anyway.
Of course there is no telephone here
and the cell phone is out of range of the waves.
So it is impossible to get help from someone on the outside.
Yes. Half of the treasure,
as well as the solution as to how to get out of here
will be given only to the one who finds the treasure.
This is the game.
How do you like the idea?
I just don't take well to people like you
who go around fleeing about hiding under a mask like that.
Come now, you can't work on an empty stomach.
Please enjoy the dinner to your heart's content.
A speaker is attached to the neck of a mannequin?
Darn it!
Who...
Who on earth could be doing this?
My. A person as renown as you, Mr. Mouri
had no idea why you were called here?
It was written in black and white in the invitation letter.
"The Phantom Of A God Forsaken Child."
The phantom.
That is something that appears unexpectedly
and has no concrete body.
The word "child" in the sentence
refers to the child of a beast,
because this character is used to write words
like colt and puppy in Japanese.
"The God forsaken beast" in the New Testament,
refers to the goat that could not receive the blessings of God.
Therefore, it refers to a baby goat.
And, of course, a goat is a goat,
but a baby goat in English is called...
-a kid. -What?
Maybe this will make it easier to understand.
Kid the phantom thief.
Hey, don't tell me that...
Don't tell me that...
Right. He never lets the prey that he is after escape.
The way he carries out his feat is practically like magic.
He is a genius criminal that confuses the police
with faces and voices that are as limitless as the stars.
He's the main dish that we, the detectives drool to savor.
He's a stuck up villain
that I would sure like to throw into jail.
He is the only existence so far, that ever threw me off.
People who have seen him in dark dressed in his white outfit
call him...
The Thief Kid!
The Thief Kid.
He's an honest guy.
The minute his name was mentioned,
he showed signs of his identity.
I sensed your piercing, callous presence.
No doubt about it, he is here, inside this house.
I don't know what he's up to, but...
I wonder if he can continue deceiving
the 7 detectives who are gathered here.
Then, are you saying that
the Thief Kid is the one who invited us here?
Yeah, it seems that he gathered the six of us
who have a reputation of being good detectives here
to compete intelligence.
By staking the treasure that he had stolen up to now,
as well as our lives.
He's probably watching us from somewhere this very minute.
I found surveillance cameras all over this place.
What?
This is an appetizer.
So, the last supper that he is referring to has finally come.
Excuse me, maid?
Oh, yes.
Did by any chance the master instruct you on
which order to place the dishes on the table?
Yes. I was told to place the dishes on the table
starting with Mr. Hakuba and continue on clockwise.
Well...
It just bothered me that he was calling this the last supper
despite the game having just begun.
There's no poison in the food,
because I'm the one who made it.
But, the forks, knives and spoons,
the wine glasses and tea cups
have been placed on the table beforehand.
We all seated ourselves according to where we found our name plates.
Well, I don't think he intends to commit murder,
but he may set up an unlaughable joke
to test our capabilities.
It may be wiser to wipe your glass cup and fork
with your own handkerchief before eating.
No doubt about it.
I don't like the idea that things are being carried out
as he planned.
Would you like to do a game of stone, paper, scissors
and change seats then?
But, what if someone ill-fatedly gets the poisoned seat?
That's that, take it as fate, and cry in the coffin.
Oh, no.
Boy, that sure was good.
Just as expected of a gourmet detective!
You've really got fantastic talent for cooking too, don't you?
I went through a lot of training
to satisfy this tongue of mine, so...
It seems we took our imagination a bit too far.
No. We can't be too sure yet.
Well, how did you like the last supper that I prepared for you?
So, here it comes.
I guess it's time for me to talk.
Let me explain why I chose this place which I dished out a lot for,
as the stage for this game.
First, take a good look
at the many dishes that are in front of you.
A bird.
There is a mark of an eerie bird with a large beak.
Isn't this a crow?
Then, this is probably...
Have you figured it out?
That's the millionaire who died a mysterious death
a half a century ago.
It's the crest of Renya Karasuma.
Renya Karasuma?
Not only the dishes
but also the doors, floors, railings,
the men of chess and the playing cards in the living room
were all specially ordered and made by his request.
In other words, this is a villa,
which had been built by Karasuma
or, rather, it used to be a villa.
40 years ago, a blood-chilling tragedy occurred here,
on that stormy night.
Being that you are all superb detectives,
you may have already noticed
the minute you set foot into this place,
the remains of the enormous amount of blood
that splattered and shed.
Yes, it was on a certain night 40 years ago,
when this place still retained its beauty.
The prominent figures of the financial world were invited here,
and a certain gathering was held.
He passed away at the age of 99.
It was entitled "Memorial for the late Renya Karasuma".
But, in actuality,
the gathering was an auction of the various artworks
that Karasuma had collected during his life time.
More than 300 items were auctioned.
And, it was scheduled for a period of three days.
On the 2nd night, that stormy night.
Two men who were drenched with rain came to this place.
The two men were freezing and with trembling lips, remarked
that they had lost their way in the storm,
and they would like to spend the night until the storm subsided.
The host of the auction was hesitant about
letting the two stay over at first, but...
the man handed the host over a small parcel
saying that it was in exchange for letting them stay over.
The contents of the parcel
seemed to be something like a cigarette,
and the host smoked it just as he was told to.
Then, he gradually got merrier and merrier,
and let the two men inside.
The other guests who were watching
were urged by the two to smoke likewise,
and the whole place was covered with smoke.
Don't tell me that the parcel was...
Marijuana.
The guests had enjoyed a merry, boisterous time for a while,
but after a while, things began to change.
A man screamed as if he had seen the devil,
carried the item that he had bid for and now owned, and ran.
A woman started crying as if asking someone for forgiveness
until her tears dried out.
Yet another man, delightedly poked his arm time and again
with the pen that he was holding.
The guests finally
began to snatch the works of art from each other,
and using auctioned items,
such as long swords and jeweled daggers,
started killing each other.
The auction grounds
had transformed into a scene of massacre and hell.
The day after the hideous and nightmarish night,
the two men had disappeared with the art work and all,
leaving 8 dead and as many as over 10 people in a comma behind.
But, why is such a serious crime not known to the public?
Probably because among them,
there was a powerful figure of the financial world,
or maybe a member of the family.
I see.
If conditions were that no one could tell who killed who,
those involved may have come to the conclusion...
That it would've been better
to keep the case under cover, rather than solving it.
It was probably within
the calculation of those men too, wasn't it?
Well, this age old story sure does whet my appetite.
So, now do you understand
why I chose this place as the stage for the game?
I would like all you detectives
to re-enact the tragedy that occurred here 40 years ago.
That ugly scene of people fighting over the treasure
and killing each other.
Really stupid.
I figure it's too cruel to make you all
just search blindly all through this building,
so let me give you a hint.
Hint?
When the two travelers looked up at the sky,
a devil descended near the palace.
The king carries the treasure with him as he flees.
The queen collects tears in the chalice
and asks for forgiveness.
The warrior falls dead by the sword stained with his own blood.
That must be...
Don't you think that these sentences are more than suited
to describe the competition of intelligence,
staking your lives that is about to be carried out here?
Don't be ridiculous.
To kill someone,
you need to have someone who wants to kill you,
as well as, the will to kill yourself.
Of course, you do not have a choice and cannot have out of this game.
Because you are all
already under the magic spell that I have chanted.
So when someone among you lets out a scream,
that is the start of the game.
Understand? The one who finds the treasure
must enter the location of the treasure
in the computer that is in the room
on the fourth floor in the center tower.
I will give you half the treasure as promised,
as well as instructions on how to get out of here.
Mr. Mogi.
Mr. Mogi, are you all right?
Just kidding.
What a bad old man you are, really.
Sorry, sorry.
In token of my apology, I'm out.
I'm not at all interested in treasure hunting.
But, how do you intend to get out of here?
Don't worry.
This is not some isolated island in the middle of the ocean.
I'll get somewhere if I keep roaming the mountains.
See you all then, detectives!
Hey, mister, it won't work twice.
22:34 and 51 seconds, verified breathing stopped.
Judging from the circumstances here,
I think it is impossible to try to resuscitate him.
What?
No sign of cyanosis, in which the lips turn purple is seen.
And besides, this almond odor distinct of hydro cyanic acid gas.
Which means cyanide was in the tea that he just drank...
Nope, there is no redox reaction.
I guess it's not the tea.
Then, what on earth happened to him?
So, the dice has been thrown.
For the sake of Detective Ogami who has died
to make way for the grand start
of this life risking competition of intelligence,
go search for the treasure with all your might...
Cut out your stupid talk!
While you are still alive.
A cassette tape.
It seems to be connected to a timer.
A timer?
Were you also instructed on the time at which to bring the food in?
Yes, in detail, appetizers, soup, main dish and dessert.
Which means that he wasn't talking while watching us, but...
The tape was being played.
So, now we know two things.
That the killer intended to kill Mr. Ogami to begin with.
And, that maybe, the killer is among us.
The killer may be among us?
Take that tape for instance.
Somebody in this room could've recorded the voice beforehand,
and pretended listening to it, like everyone else here, right?
That is possible.
And sit in this same dining room as Mr. Ogami,
without us noticing.
He was made to drink the cyanide
and poisoned him to death.
Yeah, right in front of the very eyes of all 5 of us.
Moreover, from the contents of the tape,
it sure sounds like the killer
knew what time the victim was going to die too.
The question is,
there was no cyanide compound reaction from the tea
that he was drinking until just before he died.
Then, maybe the poison was on the rim of the cup
and not in the tea itself.
No, because he drank from the cup two to three times.
But, the criminal that you're referring to is,
the Thief Kid, right?
I've heard that he never kills anyone.
No, this is the first case that something like this has happened,
as far as I know.
Well, talking is not going to get us anywhere.
Shouldn't we go take a look?
Whether our cars have really been blown up or not.
I agree.
There could be a car that was spared being blown up.
Yeah. The explosion that we heard a while ago
could've been a bluff.
Ouch!
The car that I rented.
My Ferarri's done medium to.
My Alfa as well as Ogami's Porsche are all gone.
Is that Bentz yours, then?
No. I had my granny drive me over here.
Strange. I had Mr. Mouri give me a lift here.
Who's Bentz is that, then?
I think it's the master's car.
When I got here early this morning,
it was already here.
Which means that
there is someone else besides us, here, after all?
Could it mean that my car that is on the other side,
has also been burned?
On the other side? You mean you didn't park your car here?
No, because I was instructed to park it at the back gate.
What's the shortcut to the back gate?
Go through the enclosed garden.
Go to the back gate from the kitchen to the left beyond!
Oh, your car's just fine!
Isn't there something fishy about this car?
The rat probably forget to set the bomb.
Then, maybe we should go check to see
if the bridge is really gone.
-I'll go with you. -I guess I will too.
Me too.
Come now, too many captains will sink the ship.
True. We'll end up not the "Phantom Thief"
but rather, a "Phantom Ship."
Then, why not decides which detective goes,
by tossing a coin?
I just happen to have exactly 5 coins on me.
My, you're pretty well prepared, little one.
This is a very primitive way to decide, however.
I guess we've got no choice.
Then, the one who gets heads...
Get to go drive over to the bridge and check it out.
The ones who are going are me, Mr. Mouri and Mogi, right?
Please be careful, dad!
Don't tell me that...
It couldn't be...
Come, let's go back inside.
Come on, let's go!
Oh, okay.
What a sight.
The bridge is completely downed.
Hey, Granny Senma!
Will you bring the headlights up closer?
I want to look at my feet.
Okay! Uh... closer...
I wonder if the killer will move.
Yeah. I don't think this is all there is to it.
Sen...
Ms. Senma!
What? Senma died?
Yeah, it was rigged
so that when you touch the lights of the car,
it would explode.
Oh, no.
Waiting here is just going to get us killed.
Let's split up and go check
if there is really someone else in this house!
Then maybe we three women should form a group.
That way we can even go to the restroom together.
Hey. By the way,
where did that brown haired, fair skinned young man go?
Beats me. Maybe he's feeding the eagle
that he brought along with him?
Oh. What a fancy thing to find here.
There is a brand new scratch on the piano cord.
That was probably made by the claws of the eagle.
It shows that the young man also came and searched this room.
Huh? There is something stuck between the keys of the piano!
This is the secret code that indicates
the location of the treasure that he was talking about?
But why is it mimeographed on rice paper?
Somebody probably printed a whole lot of this
when no such things as copy machines existed yet.
And, for some reason, distributed it to many people.
In other words, the thing he was referring to...
The story about the tragedy that occurred here 40 years ago
as well as the secret code indicating the hidden treasure,
are all a bunch of baloney.
Huh? This piano is leaking.
Come to think of it, yes, it is.
This is that young lady's luminol fluid.
Which means that she's been in this room too.
Hey, flimsy mustache, turn off the light!
Quick!
What the...
Huh? Where is Aki, the maid?
She said she'd be waiting in the corridor outside the restroom,
but you go check?
Oh, okay.
Aki.
There are letters written in blood on the piano.
Something did happen after all, 40 years ago.
An ace...
Don't tell me that...
Just as I thought, it was you, after all.
The killer would never risk danger,
such as to ride a car that has been rigged with a bomb.
In other words, the possible killers are those who stayed behind.
You and me.
Ran and the maid, Aki.
Oh, my, sonny, that stuff can be dangerous.
It was under the pillow in my room.
Although you probably put it there
so that you could set me up as the killer later.
Oh, what a coincidence.
I was thinking exactly the same thing.
I made the exact same deduction as you.
Gun fire?
It came from the center tower!
No good, the bullet's gone right through his chest.
Darn.
The stairs?
Somebody's using the stairs!
Why, you...
A computer?
He said to come here after we find where the treasure is.
So... Ms. Souda?
Take a look.
If I turn the knob that is on the inside,
a needle is set up to come out.
When the one who finds the treasure
inputs the location into the computer
and is ready to leave the room, that person is poisoned to death.
But...
where on earth is the killer?
Don't you play dumb with me.
This woman
couldn't have got done with by a trap she set up herself,
and the maid and your daughter
are snoozing away in the toilet.
If that gunshot was a fake,
the only two people who can commit murder are you and me.
I know it's not me, so it means that...
You're the one, right?
Punish the suspicious.
No offense.
Mr. Sleeping Kogoro.
This can't be happening.
Even gathering the detectives
did not result in a solution after all.
Cut off? The picture of the hidden camera.
What?
Somebody is inputting data?
Who on earth could it be?
What?
The code of the room has been deciphered.
I'd like to verbally say it directly to you,
so come to the dining room.
The 7th detective!
It can't be!
All the detectives that I invited should all be dead!
There is no such thing as a 7th detective!
Then, who can it be? Who on earth...
It is difficult to think that
the person who set a bomb to the car ride the car
unless it was a suicidal plan.
However, there are exceptions.
That is, in the case you want to make it look like you,
yourself died in the explosion.
Right?
Detective Senma.
Yes. Before the explosion,
you snuck out of the car,
hid in the bushes, and confirmed the car falling over.
After sneaking back here,
you were watching all of us from a room somewhere in here
through all the hidden cameras.
Don't be ridiculous.
I got out of the car in the nick of time
after I realized the car was going to explode.
I just got back here.
Besides, didn't we decide at that time
who was going to ride the car by tossing coins?
Not really. It was already decided that
you were going to ride the car even before the coins were tossed.
You set the coin with the head facing up on the back of your hand
even before you tossed the coin.
You covered your right hand over your left hand
from above the coin that you were holding,
and pretended to catch the coin that you flicked.
You dropped that coin on the ground,
and show the first coin you put on the back of your hand.
No matter how many times you repeat it, you get heads!
Since you had a 10 yen coin on you,
when checking the tea that Mr. Ogami was drinking,
so it would've been able to carry this out, wouldn't you?
"The God Forsaken Child"!
Oh. Are you saying that the host who carried out the supper
and killed Mr. Ogami is me?
Then, tell me.
How did I make only Mr. Ogami take the cyanide in this dining room,
and just how I was able to predict the time?
There was no poison in his tea,
Mr. Mouri was sitting in between Mr. Ogami and me.
Besides, didn't we play stone, paper, scissors
to decide where to sit?
The seating has nothing to do with it.
Because you had swabbed
everybody's cup with cyanide beforehand anyway.
You swabbed the cyanide in the upper part
where the handle joins the cup.
That is the place where Mr. Ogami's right thumb tip touches
when he holds his tea cup.
It is also very close to his nails
that he unconsciously bites when he thinks.
He started biting his nails
right after the tape recording of you changed voice
announced the code to the hiding place of the treasure.
If you gave instructions to the maid
to serve the tea a little before the tape was to be played.
Mr. Ogami, after hearing about the code, would start thinking
and you would be able to kill him alone just as scheduled.
But, back then, I remember that everyone wiped their dishes
before using them, just to be safe.
True.
It was too careless for a renowned detective, such as Mr. Ogami.
Unless, he was your partner all along.
Being so sure that nothing could ever happen to him,
he skipped the safety precautions that everyone else took.
From the time I heard that when Aki arrived early in the morning,
the Bentz was already parked, I was suspicious of you.
In order for anyone to abandon a Bentz
in such an remote mountain area,
there had to be someone to ride the Bentz,
as well as, somebody else to come pick you up.
You would need an accomplice.
While I'm at it, the reason why you went out of your way
to wait for Mr. Mouri, and make him give you a lift
was to leave an impression on him, that you don't like cigarettes.
In order to work it out
so that only Mr. Ogami dies in the dining room.
If Mr. Ogami were to put a cigarette in his mouth
after grabbing a cyanide coated cigarette with his fingertips...
He would immediately go to the world beyond.
The reason why you chose Aki to be your maid is because
you found out that she has a habit of biting her fingernails
by watching her through the hidden camera during the interview,
and you figured that you could kill her using the same method
that you used to kill Mr. Ogami at any time.
Yes, you killed Mr. Ogami who was your accomplice,
made yourself look as if you'd been killed by someone,
psychologically cornered all the detectives
that you've invited here into deciphering the code,
and once you found the treasure,
you were going to massacre everyone here.
Just like Renya Karasuma did 40 years ago!
I found the name "Kyosuke Senma" at the end of the words
written in blood on the piano.
That was probably...
That's my father's name.
My father who was an archaeologist
was invited to this Twilight Inn 40 years ago.
The story was that a millionaire who was over 100 years of age,
inherited estate from his mother
and found out that there was hidden treasure in the building.
He wanted someone to find the treasure for him
before his time to die.
It seemed to be an easy job that paid well,
and cash was sent to us everyday with a letter,
so my mother and I were delighted.
But, 6 months later, the letters and cash suddenly stopped coming,
and my father who did not tell us where he was going
could not be contacted since then.
We found out the truth,
only after we raised the last letter we got
from my father up to the light.
It was a letter that my father had written by opening holes
using a needle.
The letter was about a code that indicated the location
of the hidden treasure,
that there were many other scientists
other than my father who had been summoned to the place.
And that Karasuma, who was almost at the end of his time,
became impatient and started killing the scientists
as an example of what would happen
if they didn't hurry and find the treasure.
My father had also written that even if the treasure were to be found,
he would not be able to make it out alive.
Did you tell the police about this?
No. I only found out about the letter
written with a needle 20 years later.
And, besides, Renya had already passed away,
and the building was handed over to someone else.
But, it all started when I happened
to talk about this to Ogami 2 years ago.
He went all out and found this place
and started like mad to look for the treasure.
However, he couldn't decipher the code.
He bought this place and had a large debt because of it.
So, unable to reverse what had already been done,
he said the following.
Let's gather all the well-known detectives here and have them decipher the code!
The bait to get all the detectives to come, is the Thief Kid!
We'll set him up as the host, and set up a game
in which everyone would have to stake their lives on!
By making it look as though both you and me
have been killed part way through the game.
Right! Maybe we should actually kill the maid?
Once they find out that they really have to be risking their lives,
they have no choice but to get serious!
No problem, we'll just put all the blame on the Thief Kid.
Which means the one who chose that maid was...
Mr. Ogami.
He was delighted saying that he found a maid
with a habit just like his, that he could kill.
I guess he never thought that he'd be killed in the same way.
Yes, he bit his nails at that time,
because I had recorded something he had not expected to hear.
Because he was thinking of killing the maid after the dinner.
But, why did you kill Mr. Ogami?
Because I realized that
he had found the location of the hidden treasure,
and was planning to kill everyone, including me.
By making it look like we all killed each other using the gun
that he had set up in all of our rooms.
If I were to stop Ogami, who was obsessed by Karasuma,
as well as let the detectives continue to decipher the code.
I had no other choice but to carry things out the way I did.
The result ended up the same as 40 years ago.
The code could not be deciphered, and the tragedy was repeated.
I think your father did decipher the code, don't you?
Huh?
Don't you think it's strange that
there is only one clock in this large building,
the one in the dining room. Why?
Yes. The sentence at the top of the code,
"When the two travelers looked up at the sky" means
when the long hand and the short hand of the clock
point to the same direction at the top, 00:00!
So, let's do that by making the hands of the clock point at 00:00.
And the key to solving the rest of the code
is what your father had left behind by writing in blood,
"the final ace"!
This refers to playing cards in English.
The King, Queen and Jack in the code,
are the King, Queen and Jack of the playing cards.
The treasure is diamond, the chalice is heart
and the dagger is spade.
In other words,
the treasure and the King is the king of diamonds.
The chalice and the Queen is the queen of hearts.
The dagger and the warrior is the jack of spades.
Then you move the hands of the clock
in accordance to the direction their faces are turned.
Left 13.
Left 12.
Right 11, then.
The polish has rubbed off,
and gold is in view on the inside.
Moreover, this clock is heavier than it looks.
I see. The inside of this clock is pure gold.
Well, well...
to think that my father had to die for something like that.
I guess that's life.
So, you promised, Ms. Senma.
Tell me the way out of this place!
There is no way out of here to begin with.
I was planning to bury my bones here.
Although Mr. Ogami did believe me
when I told him that I would tell him the way after dinner.
Just as I thought.
Granny Senma.
What're you going to do about the only valuable I had on me?
Remember, I told you
that something childish like this isn't worth it.
Oh? Complain to sonny over there if you got any gripes.
He's the one who said that she may tell us the way out,
if a child asked to know.
You mean you all pretended to be dead,
just so that I would tell you the way out?
Yeah. Because you were even trying to kill
the ones who figured the code out.
We figured that you wouldn't tell us even if we cornered you,
so long as we were alive.
Besides, through the monitor, even ketchup looks like blood.
But, at least...
we did right in putting Ran and Aki to sleep.
This act of bad taste
would have been too harsh on the hearts of young women.
Since when did you know I was the killer?
From the time, that boy over there made I toss the coin.
Back then,
you stretched your hand all the way over to take the coin
that was farthest away from you, right?
That's when it flashed through me.
That you didn't want anyone else to take the 10 yen coin.
If anyone with cyanide on their hands touch the 10 yen coin,
redox reaction would occur,
and the whole trick would be disclosed!
That's why we all took you to be the killer,
and joined hands right off the bat.
I had seen through the trick as soon as I saw
Mr. Ogami's nail of his right thumb.
You little brat.
So, the problem is how do we make it out of here?
My, what's that sound?
Oh, probably the police choppers that I contacted.
You called them?
Watson probably took the letter that I had attached to his anklet
to nanny who was waiting in the car below the cliff,
as soon as morning came!
I'm glad that I marked the car with an X
so that he'd be able to tell it apart from other cars.
Why didn't you tell us sooner?
Talk about having to put on such a crumby act.
No, that's not only the sound of choppers.
I hear the sound of something collapsing too.
Don't tell me that...
So, the Thief Kid never showed up, huh?
Did you want him to?
Oh, not really.
But, granny.
The thing about psychologically cornering us
was Ogami's idea, wasn't it?
Why did you pretend to be dead after you killed him?
I wanted the code that my father left behind
to be deciphered no matter what the risk.
I wanted to find out in this life time.
I didn't think I could ever have such renowned detectives like you
gather together like this, ever again.
Maybe it was I, who was obsessed by Renya Karasuma.
Granny?
What the...
Shoots!
Dad!
Thief Kid?
Hey, granny!
I think you're already too old to rush to your death, huh?
Don't be ridiculous!
I saved you.
As an apology for using your name to hold the supper.
You would've never been able to escape
the grasp of those two boys unless I did it this way.
Especially from the little one that was aiming
a strange looking watch at you.
Oh, so you knew.
Cigarette. Kogoro Mouri is a heavy smoker.
You didn't smoke one cigarette since arriving at the inn, right?
Who are they, anyway?
Lovers that I most definitely do not want to encounter, I guess?
How unfortunate.
You came because you were after Karasuma's treasure, didn't you?
Yeah, at first maybe, but I guess not, after all.
It won't fit into the cloth I carry my stolen goods in.
The walls have collapsed and gold is showing from inside.
That clock was the switch to bring the walls down.
Just a would be expected of a residence owned by Karasuma.
It's worth at least zillions.
I see.
Twilight means the time when the sky glitters yellow at sunset.
It is indeed the Twilight Inn.
Where is my real dad?
Huh?
Over here.