Using the long weekend,
we Detective Boys...
first came to Kyoto.
Kyoto, at last.
I'm so excited!
Yeah!
But still...
we don't board the ship till tomorrow,
so why'd we come a day early?
Well, that's obviously...
since we came all the way to Kyoto,
we want to eat something delicious!
Especially Kyoto wagashi.
Right, right!
And sipping local sake
under the night cherry blossoms...
Hold on a second.
Listen up.
The reason we came all the way to Kyoto
isn't to drink sake...
and it isn't to eat sweets either.
It's for the experience cruise
on the Aegis ship Hotaka.
You grown-ups...
only came along
to chaperone us.
Even if you say that...
you can still do things
on the side, right?
Right?
Riiight?
(laughs) Which one of us
is the side thing here?
No matter how many times,
it's fine, isn't it?
Love and deduction,
today and tomorrow.
The day before the Aegis ship cruise...
a shocking case
we ran into in Kyoto.
Seeing through
the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid,
mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"Famed Shop's Sweets Disappears".
Into a mold shaped like
the Kyoto bird...
they brush rice oil as a release agent,
then pour in the special batter...
Man, that looks
really tasty.
Not just looks tasty,
it actually is tasty.
Ran tried it at my place
and got completely hooked.
That's why we came
all the way to buy some.
So this was the real goal
all along, huh?
Huh?! No, that's...
What's wrong, Ran?
Listen, Sonoko.
The chocolate flavor
is completely sold out.
Geez... don't scare me like that.
I thought something happened.
But that's the whole reason
we stopped in Kyoto!
But this isn't the only place
that carries the chocolate flavor, right?
That's right.
Besides us...
there's the shops on Arashiyama,
Shiokoji Street, Shinkyogoku, and Shirakawa.
Hey, is it really true?
The chocolate flavor
all vanished?
The chocolate flavor's gone?
What do you mean, gone?
That's right.
How did something
like that happen?
That's the thing,
we really don't understand it.
You don't understand?
This morning... the craftsmen
from Umehara...
definitely delivered them, but...
Forty boxes of Ogura, forty of matcha,
and forty of chocolate.
Right, good work.
Well then, let's get them
on display.
Huh? You haven't finished
the display yet?
Huh? Why not?
That's strange.
We definitely set them out just now, right?
Yeah... that's odd.
Anyway, we'd better display them quick,
the customers will be here soon.
(drawer opens)
Huh? They're not here.
The chocolate flavor's gone.
Huh?!
Who did this? Where'd they put them?
W-Why?
So now, to get some shared
from the other shops...
the craftsmen are...
Hey, this is a disaster!
The chocolate flavor's gone from
the Shirakawa and Shinkyogoku shops too.
Huh?!
No good. The chocolate flavor's
gone from the Uzumasa shop too.
It's not at the Shiokoji Street one either.
W-What did you say?
So the chocolate flavor vanished
from all five shops?
Th-That's what it
comes down to, yeah.
Something like that...
What's all the racket about?
Uncle.
This is no time to be
rummaging for souvenirs.
It's a case! A case!
The sweets that were here
have vanished, apparently.
Listen, I'm a famous detective.
One or two missing sweets...
A famous detective?
Yep! This is the renowned
Kogoro Mouri, also known as...
Huh?!
The famous Sleeping Kogoro?
Indeed.
I am the great detective Kogoro Mouri.
Please, we beg you.
Lend us your help.
No, no... I'm about to go enjoy
sake and Kyoto's cherry blossoms.
Don't say that.
Please, we're begging you.
That's right, Dad.
It's a huge case.
A-A huge case, you say...
Hey, hey.
Hm?
Isn't that thing on the ceiling
a security camera?
We only have footage from when we
opened the shop at 10 a.m., though.
What's this?
The shelf where the missing sweets were
isn't even in the shot.
Right... the Kyoto bird display
is directly under the camera.
Ah, that's right when we noticed
the chocolate flavor was gone.
After this, everyone searched
the whole shop, but...
Pause it for a sec.
What is it, Conan-kun?
That person in cherry-blossom pink
in the top-left screen... isn't that a bit odd?
Huh?
Because they got close
to the Kyoto bird shelf?
No matter what, there's no way to steal them
in such a short time.
And besides, this person showed up...
after the chocolate flavor
was already gone.
No, not that.
It's pretty chilly today, right?
For that, isn't this person
dressed awfully light?
Oh...
Now that you mention it,
yeah...
...wait, who cares
about something like that.
Well, well.
And who might this be...
Isn't that Mouri-han?
Hm...
Who?
You're Inspector Ayanokoji
of the Kyoto Prefectural Police, right?
Heh. So what's an inspector
doing in a place like this?
Well, I'm off duty today...
so I was taking this little one for a walk.
- "Ayanokōji Fumimaro, Kyoto Prefectural Police,
Criminal Investigation Division, Inspector.
Huh, I see.
Do chipmunks
even need walks?
Who knows...
...I mean, that's not really
much of a walk anyway.
Anyway, you came at a good time.
It's a theft case.
This is a job for the police.
I'll leave the rest to you.
Huh?
We're truly sorry.
We'll have stock again tomorrow.
It's not even noon yet
and you're sold out...
isn't that a bit early?
We were really
looking forward to it.
The chocolate-flavored Kyoto bird.
Um... can't you make
the chocolate flavor right now?
Today's chocolate has all
been used up already, I'm afraid.
The chocolate we use for that flavor
isn't made in-house...
we purchase carefully selected
chocolate from overseas.
Tomorrow's batch won't arrive
until tomorrow.
So the chocolate flavor's
on hold till tomorrow, huh.
Yeah...
No, it had to be today.
"It had to be today"?
Why's that?
Today is the anniversary
of the former president's death.
Oh...
That's why we wanted to launch
the new product today, but...
I'm sorry,
we've sold out.
Sold out, she says.
Huh? Already?
Ugh... above all, I feel awful for the customers
who were looking forward to it.
Is that so? Really?
I see. Understood.
I asked a fellow detective
to do me a favor...
and had him canvass
at the Uzumasa shop, and...
The shop that carries
the Kyoto bird?
Yes. Turns out, when the
chocolate flavor went missing...
someone saw a suspicious car
parked in front of the shop.
A suspicious car?
What model and plate number?
A cherry-blossom-pink compact car.
But they couldn't make out
the model or the plate.
A pink compact car alone
isn't much to go on...
Um...
I saw a pink compact car too.
What?
Huh?
You saw it? When?
Let's see, that was, um...
When the chocolate flavor vanished
and we were searching for it.
You saw it too?
Yeah, it was parked
in front of the shop.
But still...
if we could at least
get the plate number...
Then why not ask
the other shops too?
Huh?
I mean, if the person in that car
is the culprit...
they might've been spotted
at the other shops too, right?
Then send some people out
to ask around.
H-Hold on a moment, please.
If you need that much manpower,
ask the local theft division.
I'm off duty, you know.
Don't sweat
the small stuff.
I'll go to the
Shiokoji Street shop.
Huh?
If we dawdle,
they'll get away.
Then I'll take Shinkyogoku.
Yeah.
Dad, you take the last one,
the Shirakawa shop.
Huh?!
Ayanokoji-san, you stay here
and wait for everyone to call in.
Huh, me too?
Listen up, you guys.
Ayumi, go with big sister Ran.
Genta, with big sister Sonoko.
Mitsuhiko, you go
with the old man.
The suspect's plate number...
even in pieces, draw it out of them
and report back to me.
Got it.
Understood.
I'll piece it all together.
It's a cherry-blossom-pink
compact car...
Ah, now that you mention it,
it was parked in front of the shop.
Really? The plate number?
Ah, I didn't get
that far, sorry...
Even a little is fine.
If you remember any of the numbers, tell me.
Even if you ask me that...
I'm pretty sure
it was a Shiromi plate.
Wow!
Thank you so much!
Yeah, I saw it, I saw it.
It was a Shiromi plate, I think...
and I remember it started
with "11."
Starts with 11.
But still, for it to vanish
from every single shop...
Do you have any idea
what could've caused it?
It might be a curse
from the late former president.
Eek...
Conan-kun, this is Mitsuhiko.
About the plate number,
all I could find out...
was that there was an 8
near the end.
An 8 near the end.
Got it.
I see.
A pink compact car, and we've got
this much of the plate...
We might be able to run
a registered-owner check now.
We've identified the owner
of the spotted car.
Huh?
Mako Kawasumi, 22,
living in Shiromi, Osaka City.
Does that name
ring any bells?
No.
Not at all.
It's the first time
I've heard it.
I see. Anyway, we're using
the N-System right now...
to track down
that car's location.
Right.
Hey, you kids...
Conan, you eat too.
Big sister Sonoko
bought these for us.
(giggles)
The matcha flavor's delicious!
Right? I got hooked on the Kyoto bird
through the matcha flavor too.
But you know, it seems the former president
wasn't fond of it.
Huh?
Hm?
Originally, the Kyoto bird
only came in Ogura flavor...
and the matcha flavor was launched
under the current president.
Huh. But since the matcha
got such good reviews...
that's why they decided to put out
a chocolate flavor too, right?
Yeah... but a craftsman
over at Shinkyogoku said...
"If the old president heard about a chocolate flavor,
he'd drop dead from the shock."
...or something like that.
So you know,
maybe this is...
a cuuurse!
Eek! Stop it, Sonoko!
Gyaah...
(thud)
Huh?
Ah...
Ow ow ow... I forgot how much
Ran hates ghost stuff.
Ah, sorry...
(laughs)... hm?
Inspector Ayanokoji.
Ah, Detective Kurumazaki.
Good work.
The suspect's car
was photographed...
ten minutes ago by...
the N-System camera
on Marutamachi Street.
That's near
the Shirakawa shop.
Yes.
And this is the photo.
Huh?
This is...
The person in cherry-blossom pink...
Mitsuhiko, are you still
at the Shirakawa shop?
We're here. Mr. Mouri...
started drinking sake
and won't budge.
Pwah! (laughs)
Ahh... so there you go.
Hmm...
That drunkard!
W-Where are you going, Ran?
To grab him by the scruff
and drag him back.
Ah, it's gonna rain blood...
Yeah...
Hey, ma'am,
what are you doing with that?
Ah, this?
This part's gone soggy,
so I've got to swap it out.
Ah, that's from earlier...
Ugh... above all, I feel awful for the customers
who were looking forward to it.
Hey, let me see that
for a sec.
Look, this is the Ogura-flavor Kyoto bird
they pulled from below to restock.
This one's the Ogura Kyoto bird being swapped out,
gone soggy from tears.
And this is the Ogura Kyoto bird
that was displayed underneath it.
Doesn't this look
a little smudged?
Maybe it ended up like that
when they stuck the label on?
But look, the area around the label
on this one pulled out for restocking...
isn't smudged at all.
Conan-kun,
what's bothering you?
Maybe I've been...
making one heck of
a mistaken assumption.
Hey, mister.
Let's head back to
Conan-kun and the others now.
Pwah, ha.
Come oooon, don't rush me.
(chuckles)
It's not even
a big case.
Oh? "Not even
a big case"?
Hello there!
Yeah, yeah, not even a big
ca... se?
Out flower-viewing
in the middle of a case... you've got some nerve.
N-No, w-w-wait, Ran!
You've got it wrong, I...
(smack)
Th-the cherry blossoms!
It's the cherry blossoms' fault!
Hm?
That person...
Um, excuse me.
You've been to
all of the shops, haven't you?
Every shop that carries
the Kyoto bird.
Huh... why? Why do you ask?
At every one of them, the chocolate
flavor of the Kyoto bird has vanished.
Uh... eek!
Mouri-han, Mouri-han.
Mouri-han, h-huh?
Mouri-han's not back yet?
Ah... the old man, he said
he'd be back soon.
So, how did it go?
Ah, just like Mouri-han
said on the phone...
something strange
was detected from here.
You mean, could it be...?
Hm?
Huh? That's right.
How did you know?
Ah... the old man, Kogoro,
figured it might be that.
Well, well.
As expected of the great detective.
Ah, Mouri-han.
Ugh...
(snoring)
Huh?
What happened to him,
Mouri-han?
Ah... the drunk...
I gave him a little punishment
and he ended up like this.
Please, don't mind it
at all.
A "little," she says...
(laughs)
Well, this is good timing.
Huh? Come to think of it,
where's my Kurumazaki...
Ah, the old man Kogoro asked him
to do something over the phone earlier.
Oh.
Mouri-han, what did you
ask Kurumazaki to do?
More importantly, Inspector Ayanokoji,
did you look into it?
The packaging of the Ogura flavor
that was on display.
Yes. Rice oil was found
around the Ogura-flavor labels.
Huh?
Huh? Rice oil?
Rice oil... we use that
as a release agent.
Ah...
Hey, what's a release agent?
Ah, before baking the batter,
you brush it on the mold...
it's an oil that makes it easy
to get the batter out of the mold.
But why was it...
on the Ogura labels?
It wasn't simply on them.
It was applied there.
Before the Ogura labels
were stuck on.
Forty boxes of Ogura, forty of matcha,
and forty of chocolate.
Right, good work.
Well then, let's get them
on display.
The first ones put on display
were ten boxes of each.
So they only needed to tamper
with ten boxes of chocolate.
With cotton soaked
in rice oil...
hidden in their palms, they traced
over the chocolate labels...
and peeled the labels off.
Then they stuck fresh
Ogura labels on top.
Two people, ten boxes...
The ten boxes of Ogura first on display
went into the restocking drawer...
and the ten relabeled Ogura boxes
were slid into their place.
In other words, in this shop, no...
in all five shops, there was no
chocolate flavor from the very start.
Huh?!
Detective Mouri.
Kurumazaki-han.
Just as Detective Mouri said,
in the fridge at the Umehara workshop...
the chocolate that was supposed
to be used today...
was sitting there untouched.
Hm?
In other words, no chocolate flavor
was made today to begin with.
And the only ones
who could pull that off...
are you confectioners.
Huh?!
Why would you do
such a thing?
(sobbing)
The former president
truly hated the matcha flavor.
And a chocolate flavor,
all the more...
Over something like that...
It's not just "something like that"!
It's not just "something like that"...
That's exactly why,
on the former president's death anniversary...
we just couldn't bear
to sell the chocolate flavor.
But we never thought
it would blow up this big...
We're terribly sorry.
(craftsmen sobbing)
♪~
~♪
Are you sure?
Not filing a complaint?
What the former president left behind
is the skill of those craftsmen.
I see.
Um... what's going to happen
with the chocolate flavor?
We won't sell the matcha or chocolate
on the former president's anniversary.
Not until the craftsmen themselves
say they want to.
But I came to love the Kyoto bird
through the matcha flavor, you know.
Thank you kindly.
Huh? Come to think of it,
Mitsuhiko...
Heey, everyone!
Mitsuhiko, what were you
even doing?
Ah, sorry.
The thing is...
Huh... why? Why do you ask?
A-At every one of them, the chocolate
flavor of the Kyoto bird has vanished.
Eek!
That's right.
There's no chocolate flavor anywhere.
Huh?
This is already
the fifth shop...
I've searched this hard,
so why isn't there any?!
(laughs)
Isn't that just like Ran?
"Next Episode"
I wonder where Kengo disappeared to though.
Okay, shall we all go then?
Ridiculous! It can't be.
He couldn't be dead.
Hey! What do you mean by he couldn't be dead?
Next Conan,
"A Rose in a Vineyard".
Next Conan's Hint:
"Type of grape".
The movie will start today!
The Sleeping Kogoro is the star of the movie!
You never learn.