We were supposed to play tennis
in Karuizawa,
but the rain canceled it,
so we ended up going bowling instead.
So? Who is it?
This person you want me to meet.
Oh, that would be the person
who waited four whole hours
on a tennis court in a downpour.
He's changing out of his wet clothes,
he should be here any minute.
Quit dragging it out and just tell me.
I rode my bike all the way here
in this rain, you know.
Huh?
What are you?
Jeet Kune Do.
He dodged it? Ha.
Not bad. I'll knock you flat.
No, you've got it wrong, Sera.
Huh?
That's him. The person Sonoko
wanted you to meet.
Huh?
Over Sonoko, Sera and Kyogoku
ended up trading a few punches,
but in the end we were enjoying bowling
with the junior high teachers we'd just met.
But the PE teacher,
who was supposed to be asleep in the car, vanished,
and we all set out to look for him...
Aaah! Kyaaa!
Wh-what happened?
Th-the bathroom lock was open,
so I opened it, and... and inside...
The sun's blazing,
undaunted by the heat,
a slick and stylish deduction show.
Sera's suspicious behavior over email?
Clear Makoto Kyogoku's name.
Seeing through the one and only truth,
Looks like a kid,
mind of an adult.
his name is Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"Makoto Kyogoku, A Suspect? (Part 2)"
Huh? No mistake, it was drowning?
Really?
Yes. There was water
in the victim's airway,
according to the medical examiner.
But even if he was knocked out
with a stun gun,
drowning a man that big
without even tying him up...
wouldn't that take two or three people?
True. Well, a karate master
could manage it alone, though.
What? You're still
suspecting Makoto?
N-not really.
Oh, and there's also a report of
cord-like compression marks on the victim's lower abdomen.
The lower abdomen?
Yes.
The marks didn't reach up to the waist,
so the culprit may have carried the body
by grabbing the belt.
I see.
In that case, the culprit must have
considerable physical strength.
Someone like, say, a karate master.
Ugh... gh... uh...
I-it's just an example. Just an example.
Come to think of it, the man who was killed
said something about going through a lot.
What happened?
Ah.
Mr. Tanba
- Masaki Sunami (29) junior high school science teacher
- Monna Michiko (30) junior high school mathematics teacher
had promised to marry my sister,
but his parents were against it.
The truth is, he had a fiancée
their parents had arranged for him.
When they found out,
it was a shock for them both,
and for a while it seemed
they were going to elope.
But in the end, only my sister
threw herself into the sea, drowning herself.
Hmm.
You were the one she talked to
about eloping?
Yes. I got an email from my sister.
"The two of us are setting off now," it said.
That email came to my phone too.
She and I were classmates
and best friends.
It was after that, wasn't it?
That Mr. Tanba started getting violent
whenever he drank.
Yes. So while we were bowling,
he must have woken up,
gotten into a fight with someone, and...
Hey, do you teachers
come to this bowling alley a lot?
Yes. Because the woman who passed away
loved bowling.
Come to think of it,
it was raining last time we came too.
Hmm.
Inspector Yamamura,
from the trash can next to the bathroom,
we found a wet towel
and four strange empty cans.
Empty cans?
Yes. All four had
scorch marks around the openings.
Did someone use them as ashtrays?
Hmm, no, but...
There's a smell of kerosene inside.
Kerosene?
Ah, wait, Conan.
- Sunday Bowl Parking Lot.
Excuse me, forensics?
Hmm?
Could you check something for me?
On that shelf up there...
No, no, no.
Kids, go play over there.
But Mr. Mouri told me
that behind the spare toilet paper,
there might be something.
Huh?
Sheesh, fine, fine.
If Sleeping Kogoro asked for it...
Hm? A scorch mark on the ceiling?
Hey, take a picture. A picture.
A-ah, yes.
Just as I thought.
This explains why the lower part
of the bathroom wall was oddly wet.
No doubt about it.
The culprit is that person.
"It seems he's reached the truth too,
but whether it matches my own deduction,
lately I've been feeling
a little short on confidence."
(phone vibrating)
Oh, that was a fast reply.
"Who is 'he'?" huh.
Yeah, figured he'd ask that.
(camera shutter)
(phone vibrating)
Oh, here it comes. Huh?
"If it's him, there's no problem," he says.
It's a fight. A fight.
The victim, who was sleeping
drunk in the car,
woke up, went to some bar for another drink,
got into a fight with someone,
got dragged off somewhere,
and was killed.
But when Mr. Mouri's group
went around the bars looking for the victim,
nobody said they'd seen him, right?
Hmph. They were just
playing dumb, no doubt.
If word got out that
customers had a fight at the bar,
the place's reputation would suffer.
But why would the culprit
have a stun gun on them?
And we don't even know
where or how he was drowned.
On top of that, why the body was
left all the way over
in the portable toilet in the parking lot
where the victim's car was, makes no sense.
How should I know.
Anyway, the victim, Mr. Tanba,
was taken by this Mr. Masaki
to the car in the parking lot
to sleep it off until he sobered up.
About an hour later,
before Ms. Monna went to the parking lot
to check on him,
he woke up and slipped out of the car.
When we heard Mr. Tanba had gone missing
and went around the bars looking for him,
he got into a quarrel with somebody somewhere,
was drowned, and before we got back
to the parking lot again,
he was stuffed into the parking lot's toilet.
No doubt about it.
Well, this karate guy here,
who was napping that whole time
in a car in the same parking lot,
isn't entirely free of suspicion either,
but considering the culprit used a stun gun,
he's in the clear.
So go around the local bars right now
and do some proper questioning.
Ah... right.
Inspector Yamamura,
the experiment is ready, apparently.
Huh? Experiment?
Ah... yes.
Detective Mouri said it was necessary
to solve the case,
and forensics said you'd approved it, Inspector.
Huh? What's that supposed to mean?
I don't remember
saying anything like that.
Huh? B-but forensics said
the boy was the one...
Ah, anyway, let's go check.
I love experiments!
Has a first-grade brat
ever even done an experiment?
Well, maybe at the professor's house.
Anyway, let's go
and hear what's going on.
Right.
"If it's him, there's no problem"?
Why?
Why does he know?
My brother knows about this kid...
Hey, hey, what's all this?
The area around the toilet
is completely flooded.
Ah, but Detective Mouri
told us to do it this way.
Huh?
He said to stuff a towel in the drain
to dam up the rainwater and collect it.
I see.
They said this area's tilted
from land subsidence,
so the rain that was falling earlier
all pooled up.
But doesn't this
ruin a crucial crime scene?
If you mean the toilet where the body was,
we moved it elsewhere and we're investigating it.
Huh?
This is a different portable toilet.
We heard Detective Mouri
instructed us to do this too...
Hm?
Like I said, I never...
(tranquilizer dart)
Ow! Hanyon.
Hanyon.
Ah, Dad,
there's water pooled right there.
So my pants get wet,
that kind of thing doesn't matter,
I'm telling you.
Not if I can prove this trick.
Huh?
A t-trick?
Don't tell me he was drowned
with this pooled rainwater?
But collecting this much rainwater
would take a fair amount of time,
and even if he was knocked out
with a stun gun,
forcibly drowning a grown man
without binding his hands and feet,
in a place like this,
means the culprit, after all,
must be someone with
considerable physical strength.
That's why I keep saying
Makoto isn't the one.
Right, Makoto?
Ah, Makoto.
Ah, he ran off!
Leave him be.
Huh?
He probably just went to the bathroom.
Besides, he's got nothing to do with this.
Huh? But...
Because this trick
requires no physical strength.
The culprit locked the victim in the toilet
and drowned him
without laying a hand on him.
Just like magic.
Magic.
Seeing is believing.
Let's try it for real.
Whether a person can really drown
inside a toilet.
Of course, Inspector Yamamura,
you're the test subject.
Huh? M-me?
It's fine.
I had them prepare portable oxygen.
...wait, isn't this
an oxygen tank or something?
Hey, tomboy.
Hm?
Help me set up the trick.
You've figured out this trick too, right?
Yeah, more or less.
First, put the victim in the toilet.
Seal the vent on the back of the toilet
with packing tape.
Next, prepare four cans filled with kerosene,
each with a cloth wick in the mouth.
Light those cloths,
line the cans up on the toilet's shelf,
then just close the door
and seal the gaps with packing tape.
So how does that drown someone?
Just watch.
Ugh... sheesh.
The water only comes up
to above my ankles.
As if a person could drown in this.
Still, it's sure getting hot in...
ah, they went out.
(water rushing)
Wh-whaaa?
(banging)
Wh-what?
What on earth is happening inside?
Now, behold.
(heavy breathing)
Haa, haa, ugh...
You okay?
Ugh, what a thing
to put me through, Mr. Mouri.
I nearly drowned to death in there!
But why was there
so much water inside the toilet?
Because the pressure inside
the toilet dropped.
Look, haven't you seen this
in a science experiment?
You stand a lit candle
in a deep dish filled with water,
put a beaker over it,
the flame goes out, and in no time the water
gets sucked up into the beaker.
It's the same thing.
On the shelf of the sealed toilet,
the cans were burning,
the air was heated and expanded,
the oxygen level inside the toilet dropped,
and when the flames went out,
the air cooled and contracted.
By that amount,
through the vent under the door,
it sucked in a huge volume
of the pooled rainwater.
This explanation is correct, isn't it...
science teacher,
Sunami Masaki?
First, on your way to taking
the drunk Mr. Tanba to the car,
you lured him into the portable toilet.
Probably telling him
you'd forgotten the car keys,
so you'd wait out the rain
inside the toilet, or something like that.
And once he was inside,
you immediately knocked him out with the stun gun,
passed a cord through the back of his belt,
tied it to the joint of the toilet seat lid,
so Mr. Tanba couldn't stand up,
placed four cans of kerosene
on the toilet shelf,
put a padlock on the door,
and stuck up an "out of order" sign.
After that, you sealed the vent
on the back of the toilet with packing tape,
stuffed a towel
into the parking lot's drain
to let the rainwater pool,
and the groundwork was complete.
You lied to Ms. Monna,
saying he'd fallen asleep in the car,
waited for the rainwater to collect,
and after a while,
when the worry-prone Ms. Monna
went to check on Mr. Tanba,
it all went according to plan.
Well, if she hadn't suggested it herself,
you'd have
invited her along to go check on him.
Just as you expected, she came to report
that Mr. Tanba wasn't in the car,
and we decided to search the parking lot.
You confirmed that
the rainwater had pooled enough,
peeled the sign off the toilet,
removed the padlock,
lit the cans you'd placed on the shelf,
and sealed the door
with packing tape.
After that, just like the experiment,
the rainwater got sucked into the toilet,
and around the time Mr. Tanba drowned,
you, together with Ms. Monna,
were going around the bars
looking for Mr. Tanba,
building an alibi, the goal in sight.
Then you returned to the parking lot again,
took the towel out of the drain,
drained the pooled rainwater,
peeled off all the packing tape,
threw the cans that had burned on the shelf
into the trash, cut the cord on the belt,
and to hide the fact that
water had pooled inside the toilet,
you fitted the fresh toilet paper
from the shelf onto the holder,
and then, as if you'd
just discovered the body,
let out a scream.
The key to this crime
was how to speed up the discovery of the body.
If the discovery was delayed
and the estimated time of death widened,
the alibi would be wasted.
That's why the culprit can only be you,
the one who found the body first.
You're also the only one who
could make the time to pool the rainwater.
And by now, forensics is finding
the packing tape with your fingerprints on it
in the toilet tank.
Since it wasn't in the trash,
you must have flushed it down the toilet,
and packing tape is hard to peel off
without bare hands.
...that's right, isn't it?
Sleeping Kogoro.
Ah... yeah.
This is some kind of mistake.
I mean... I mean, Sunami
had no reason at all
to kill Mr. Tanba...
I did.
Huh?
A perfectly good motive...
my best friend was left to die
by that man.
Y-your best friend...
don't tell me, my sister?
Yes.
Your sister,
who'd promised to marry that man.
Huh? But my sister
threw herself off a cliff by the coast,
and there was a proper suicide note,
And before that,
you got an email from her, didn't you?
"The two of us are setting off now."
Huh? Y-yes.
That wasn't an email about eloping.
It was a message about the two of them departing to the next world together. A suicide pact.
- "From now on, the two of us will set out on a journey."
Huh?
And yet... and yet,
that man suddenly grew afraid of dying,
and without even saving her as she drowned,
he walked away from that cliff.
Is that... is that true?
Yes.
While Drunk that man blabbed all about it.
Crying that he was
a hopeless, spineless coward.
Well, even a man like that
was someone my best friend loved enough to die for.
So I sent him to her.
Into the water, where she was waiting.
♪~
~♪
Huh? You went off to look for the culprit?
Yes.
B-but you didn't even know
who the culprit was, right?
So how?
Well, the culprit seemed to be
quite a formidable one,
so I figured I'd know them on sight,
from their killing intent.
Huh?
And if you got lucky,
you were hoping to
trade a few blows, weren't you?
(yawn)
W-well, that too, a little.
You were planning to fight!
Hahahaha.
Man, even so,
that's Sleeping Kogoro for you.
Solving it so brilliantly like that!
Hm? W-well, yeah.
That's me, the real deal.
But, but, that experiment...
(Ha, that hack... his usual way of talking is totally back.)
If you'd told me beforehand...
But, well, the good parts...
he went and stole every single one of them.
Ah, that reminds me, Dad,
you'd better change your pants soon
or you'll catch a cold.
Huh?
I mean...
you were sitting in a puddle
doing your deduction earlier.
Huh? Ah!
Wh-what is this? I'm soaked!
But, mister, you were the one who said
you didn't care if your pants got wet.
Did I? I said that?
You did, you did.
It was super cool!
Super cool?
Enough already, hurry up and change.
(phone notification)
Hm?
Email? It's from my brother.
Ah, so that's what it was.
Hm. A postscript?
(tapping)
"Have you already met the magician?" (Kaito Kid)
Yeah, you bet.
I heard. Kid's coming again, right?
Kid.
Kyogoku and Kaito Kid
are going to face off?
Well, you'll find out when you get there.
"Let's have a fair fight - Kaito Kid"
I'll protect it, no matter what.
I stake this fist on it.
Next Conan:
"Thief Kid vs. Makoto Kyogoku (Part 1)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Unexpected Security System"
There will be no broadcast next week.
Let's drink!
Let's do some work for once.