Dad.
Is this really the road? Yeah.
You got lost, didn't you?
Shut up! The roads in the countryside
are way too dark.
Hahahaha...
Ah, Dad! Look out!
Whoa! (Brakes screech)
...Geez. Who parked here?
I'll give them a piece of my mind.
Stop it, Dad.
Uncle, over there. Hmm?
No good. She's dead.
Huh...
Ah, this is...
Huh?
A dying message.
♪~♪
The blackness of shadows, the density of darkness—
the light of reasoning cuts right through them.
An unexpected reaction to the mail.
Expose the whole alibi trick.
See through the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~♪
Um, the victim is Hirose Nana-san, 27 years old.
She's an insurance saleswoman living nearby.
On her way home from work,
she stopped by this park,
and it seems she was attacked.
Cause of death is asphyxiation
due to neck compression.
The culprit carefully—
strangled the victim's neck multiple times.
There were multiple overlapping
strangulation marks on her neck.
And the estimated time of death?
Ah, between 10:00 PM and 10:30 PM.
That was shortly before we came here.
Are you sure you didn't see anything?
Yes, sorry.
If we had seen something,
we would've said so by now.
That's true.
But it's okay. The victim conveniently
left us a dying message.
So the culprit's name starts with "Na."
Ah, come to think of it,
the victim's name is also Nana.
Ah, I see! The culprit is herself.
So it's suicide.
The victim must have had a split personality.
Hahaha...
But still, this character looks strange.
And this smell...
No, Conan-kun. Don't get close to the body.
Hey, from this lady's clothes—
There's a strange smell. Huh?
(Sniffing sound) Ah, you're right.
(Sniffing sound) It smells like gunpowder.
Why don't you have the forensics team check it?
Ugh, I was just about to...
Huh? Her face is wet,
and her makeup is a little smeared.
I was just about to check that too...
Nana! Huh?
Nana! Please let go... Nana!
Who might you be?
Well... he seems to know the victim.
My name is Samon Osamu.
I work as an primary school teacher.
And what is your relationship
with the victim, Hirose-san?
Yes.
She and I were engaged.
I see.
So, has Hirose-san shown
any unusual behavior lately?
Actually, Nana and I had plans
to have dinner together tonight,
and then I received this email from Nana.
"I'm going to be a little late
because I'm talking with Migita at the park. — Nana"
The received time is 9:45 PM.
That's a little before the estimated time of death.
And who is this "Migita"?
He's a man who dated Nana before me.
Migita kept pestering her,
trying to get back together with Nana.
So I thought, maybe...
I see! I've got it! That's "Migita" written with the "migi" of "migi-hidari"
and the "ta" of "tambo", right?
Huh? Yes, that's right, but...
So the victim wasn't writing
the katakana character "Na."
She was trying to write the kanji
character for "right" and ran out of strength.
I see. As expected of Mouri-san.
Neeheeheeheehee!
Anyway, let's go to Migita's place.
Please let me come along too.
Well, but...
Please. I want to help with the investigation
as much as I can.
Oh, all right.
Just please don't get in the way
of the investigation.
Got it.
Are those your students, Sensei?
Yeah. Today, they threw me
an engagement party.
They're good kids, aren't they?
Yes.
I don't know what to tell them either...
Ah. You noticed?
Yes. If I tried to write my name, "Samon,"
it would also become that dying message.
Huh? (Clears throat)
Of course. I was well aware of that.
That you are also a suspect.
Hahahaha...
Ugh!?! Are you serious?
Yes, in the park where you were
supposed to meet her tonight.
Don't screw with me! We never made plans to meet.
Then what is this email?
I don't know anything about that.
She probably used it as an excuse
to meet some other guy.
That's not all.
The victim left us something.
It's called a dying message.
The victim was trying to write your name,
Migita-san,
but ran out of strength.
No, that's not necessarily true.
Nana might have been trying
to write "migi" (右),
Ah.
But it could also be the katakana "na" (ナ),
or the kanji for "big" (大) or "dog" (犬).
Hmm, that's true.
Yeah, yeah. If she was trying to write
that Samon guy's name,
it would look like this too.
Oh, you're right. Hmm...
Besides, it's impossible for me
to have committed the crime.
I have a perfect alibi.
Hmm...
I was working here all night.
That should be recorded
on the security cameras too.
It's around here. I'm glad I had the security system installed.
It's true. You're on camera the whole time.
Ah, you left the frame.
Ah.
What? You came right back.
Even I need to go to the bathroom sometimes.
...Geez. That's confusing.
I see. So the only time Migita-san
wasn't on camera
was the single time he went to the bathroom.
It's about a 20-minute round trip by car
from here to the crime scene.
So committing the crime would be impossible.
Hmph. See? I told you so.
I have a perfect alibi.
I do. Hmph.
At first glance, it certainly looks
like a perfect alibi.
But what about that earlier?
I see. Then the culprit is Samon-san.
It's you.
Why would you say that?
There's no way I would kill Nana.
I didn't even meet with Nana at all today.
Then do you have an alibi?
Well, that's...
It's also possible that you faked that email
to frame Migita-san.
Huh? That's...
No. The dying message points to Migita-san.
And there's that footage too...
But that alone isn't enough evidence.
Hmm...
Ah.
Could this be...
Anyway, we'll hear the details at the station.
But... I didn't do it.
There, there. All the culprits say that.
N... no, I...
Hmph. Let's go, let's go.
No, so I...
Whoa! Wahoo! Hohaha~
Oh my. Could this be...
Sleeping Kogoro!
Dad.
The victim's dying message was not pointing to Samon
It was pointing to you, Migita-san.
Huh? Hmph. How can you say that for sure?
M... Mouri-san.
It's true that with just this,
we can't tell if she was trying
to write "right" or "left."
You can tell exactly which one it was. Hey, Conan.
Okay!
Samon-san, here. Hmm?
Samon-san, you're an primary school teacher, right?
So write "right" so everyone can see.
Huh? Ah...
Oh, so for "right," the stroke order
is the diagonal stroke first, then the horizontal.
Wha... Ah.
Ah... Huh?
Look at the part where the diagonal stroke
and the horizontal stroke intersect.
You can clearly see that the horizontal stroke
was written after the diagonal one.
I... indeed. That's exactly what happened.
It's not the katakana "Na" or the kanji for "left."
That stroke order is only possible
when writing the kanji for "right."
Th... that alone isn't evidence.
And did you forget?
I have a perfect alibi.
That's right. Migita-san was
on the security camera the whole time.
That's true, as long as the security camera
was running.
Huh? Ah.
Ah... Yes.
People tend to assume
that a security camera is always
running continuously.
Migita-san took advantage of that.
That one time you said you went to the bathroom,
you actually turned off the security camera.
Then you took 10 minutes to reach the crime scene
on your scooter,
and killed Nana-san.
(Heavy breathing)
Then, after another 10 minutes,
you came back, Migita-san,
turned the security camera back on,
and returned to the camera's field of view.
Hmm...
That's how you made a recording that was
actually missing over 20 minutes
look like it was continuous.
This store's security camera
doesn't have a time stamp display.
So it was easy to fake.
So you really are the one who killed Nana...
Then... evidence?
Where is the evidence that I did it?
You can come in now.
This is a student who lives nearby.
Would you tell us what you witnessed?
Ye... yes. It was around 10:30.
I was about to turn on the TV
because my show was starting.
(Brakes squeal) Then...
(Crash) Ah, huh?
Ah!
Huh?
(Engine sound)
I see. That's definitely 10:30 PM today.
Probably a drunk driver's car.
We should find it if we search around here.
A white car with a broken headlight.
The sound would have been very loud
inside the store too.
But in that footage, you never reacted to it.
Why is that?
Because the footage from that time is missing.
10:30 is the time of the murder.
Migita-san, you weren't in this store
at that time.
Damn it. I thought I had fooled everyone.
It's your hair.
Huh? My hair...
When you left the security camera's view,
your curly hair was sticking up.
But when you came back, it was flat.
Just like when you've been wearing a helmet.
When I saw that, I realized the trick.
It's her fault... Nana's fault.
She kept sending me images like this to harass me.
Damn it.
And on top of that, that woman would say,
"I never did that,"
and make a fool of me.
I knew it. Now the rest...
(Cell phone rings)
Hello?
Huh? Gunshot residue?
Hmph.
It's fine, it's fine. We've already
arrested the culprit. Good work.
Good work.
Did gunshot residue come from the victim's clothes?
Huh? How did you know?
Good. Now it all fits together.
That's the stuff that appears
when you fire a gun, right?
Yes, but? Hey, I never used a gun.
I know. The victim's cause of death
was strangulation.
But then why is there gunshot residue...
It must be some mistake.
I don't think it's related to the case.
Hmm... Oh well, whatever.
Well then, Migita-san, let's head to the station.
Wait, please.
The case isn't over yet.
What are you talking about, Mouri-san?
The culprit is right here,
Of course, Migita-san is the culprit.
He attempted to kill Nana-san.
Huh? "Attempted to kill"? Then...
Yes. The real culprit is someone else.
Huh?
The real culprit who killed Hirose Nana-san—
it's you, Samon Osamu-san.
Huh?
Detective, I'm not trying to protect him, but...
I did kill Nana with these hands.
That's right. Besides, the stroke order
of the dying message
pointed to Migita-san.
That very stroke order is what indicates it.
It wasn't Nana-san who wrote the dying message—
it was you, Samon-san.
First, that dying message.
I highly doubt Nana-san wrote it.
Judging from the emails, she always referred
to Migita-san as "Migita"
in katakana.
Would that same Nana-san, at death's door,
suddenly decide to
write Migita-san's name in kanji?
I see. That is certainly unnatural.
But that doesn't mean I wrote it.
No, that possibility is extremely high.
Huh?
Recall the stroke order Migita-san used
to write "right."
And the stroke order that the teacher,
Samon-san, used.
Ah!
But I definitely...
Let me explain step by step.
First, Samon-san's plan began with him
sending harassing emails from Nana-san's phone
to Migita-san.
Knowing Migita-san's personality
and his twisted affection for Nana-san,
Samon-san manipulated him into killing her.
That's outrageous. Why would you say that?
It's the email's writing style.
Wri... writing style?
The emails that Nana-san herself typed
had no punctuation like dots or circles,
and they always ended with the signature "Nana."
But the emails that angered Migita-san
had punctuation
and, conversely, no "Nana" signature.
You can't easily change
the writing style you always use.
Just like stroke order.
It's clear that someone else wrote them.
And the plan succeeded perfectly.
Just as you intended—
Migita-san's hatred for Nana-san grew,
and he killed her.
When you went to the park to check,
and saw Nana-san collapsed,
you must have been certain.
That your plan had succeeded.
But then, something unexpected happened.
When Migita-san left the scene,
she was probably still in a state of suspended animation.
Nana-san regained consciousness.
At that time, Nana-san washed her face with water
to remove the dirt that had gotten on it.
That's why the victim's face was wet
and her makeup had come off.
And shortly after, she was finished off.
By your hand.
Then, you tried to write "Migita" on the ground
using the victim's finger.
But in the middle of it, you noticed us approaching,
and had no choice but to leave in a hurry.
That is the truth of this case.
It's true that it might be consistent.
But it's all circumstantial evidence.
There's no physical evidence.
There is physical evidence
— Huh?
The gunshot residue found on the victim's clothes.
Gunshot residue...
Why would gunshot residue appear at a scene
where no gun was used?
The answer was in the photo on your smartphone.
What do you mean?
In that photo,
you were being celebrated with lots of party poppers.
As you can tell from the sound,
which is like a gunshot,
party poppers that explode gunpowder
show a gunshot residue reaction.
That residue got on your clothes at that time,
and when you strangled Nana-san,
it also got onto her clothes.
If they check, the same gunshot residue
that came from her clothes should appear.
You said earlier
that you didn't even meet Nana-san today.
Can you explain that?
Why would the same gunshot residue appear
on the clothes of you, who didn't meet her,
and on Nana-san's clothes?
How ironic.
That the children's celebration of me
would become evidence.
But why did you kill Nana-san?
You looked so happy in that photo.
The motive was Nana-san breaking off
the engagement.
How did you know that?
The ring.
You're wearing an engagement ring
on the middle finger of your right hand.
But there was no ring on Nana-san's finger.
That's when I realized.
That your feelings were one-sided.
I couldn't stand it.
As long as Nana was alive,
I would continue to feel miserable.
I just couldn't bear it anymore.
(Sobbing)
♪~♪
Are you sure we turn right here?
Yeah, I think it's right.
Hmph. If you say so, then it's left.
That's mean! It's right, right. Definitely right.
No, it's left. Definitely left.
I said right! I said left!
(Arguing) Just pick one already!
I wanna go home!
Welcome to my Cooking Arena!
Heheheh. How's that?
This time too, we've brought in
carefully selected delicacies from all over
the country, so rest assured.
It's the key.
You're not coming in.
Beyond here is our domain.
Today's fruit is...
Next Conan...
"A Treasure Chest Filled with Fruit (Part 1)"
Next! Conan's Hint:
"Padlock"
Next time, an incident at the TV station.
I hope I get to see Yoko-chan.
Whatever you say.