Reasons and hints are all connected.
With these, the truth unravels.
The love was misunderstood.
Today's case makes everything clear!
Seeing the one and only truth...
A kid with the intellect of an adult...
His name is... Detective Conan!
Okino Yoko-san invited us to a party.
Okino Yoko (22)
Idol
She was a member of the idol group, the Earth Ladies.
Okino Yoko (22)
Idol
She was a member of the idol group, the Earth Ladies.
Kaoru Kusano (20)
Actress
It turned out to be Kusano Kaoru-san's engagement party.
Kaoru Kusano (20)
Actress
It turned out to be Kusano Kaoru-san's engagement party.
The other members of the Earth Ladies,
Yuki Takeno (22)
Multi-talented
Takeno Yuki-san,
Yuki Takeno (22)
Multi-talented
Hoshino Terumi (23)
Actress
and Hoshino Terumi-san also showed up.
Hoshino Terumi (23)
Actress
However, when Kaoru-san was taking a bath...
she was attacked!
(Part Two)
The Idol Stars' Secret
Shouldn't you be searching for the most important thing?
The murder weapon...
The dagger that slashed Kaoru's throat.
If you find it in this apartment or among our possessions,
then the murderer is one of us.
I don't think an outsider would leave the
murder weapon inside the apartment.
Even if it was wiped clean, there would still be traces
of blood that forensics would find with luminol.
It's not something that one can easily hide, right?
Yes.
You sure do know a lot.
I'm into mysteries these days, because of someone.
Okay. Takagi, you search Kenzaki-san while
the policewomen search the ladies.
The rest of you, carefully search for the murder weapon!
But Inspector, if the culprit is Makuma-san, then
he could've disposed of the weapon by now.
That would be bad.
Don't worry.
I asked the people in the ambulance to call
me if he tried to do anything strange.
I see.
Takeno-san, if you don't mind stepping in now.
Right away.
Hey, wasn't Yuki-san a regular on
the show "Detective Samonji"?
Yeah, she was the annoying journalist
who kept following Samonji.
However, when she sent in her resignation
in order to take care of her sick father,
she was replaced by Kaoru, although
Terumi was their first choice.
Terumi would've gotten the role if it hadn't been for
Makuma-san's begging. That's why Kaoru got the part.
But Kaoru-san described Makuma-san as a depressing man.
Makuma-san wanted to be a star as well.
He was in the same studio as us, but he
gave up and became Kaoru's manager.
But even though Kaoru speaks about him like that, the
truth is that she cares a lot about Makuma-san.
She always said that he lacked resolve,
and that he gave up too quickly.
I see.
So you weren't able to find the murder weapon...
That's right. It's neither in this apartment, nor in any drains.
Did you also check their accessories?
Yeah.
Yuki-san's fake nails, Terumi-san's earrings,
and even Kenzaki-san's necklace.
But they all turned up negative on the luminol test.
And what about Makuma-san?
I heard that they even tested his
glasses, but they found nothing.
And until the detectives arrived, he was
sitting in a chair with his head down.
Then was the murder weapon really
taken outside by the criminal?
It seems likely that the criminal came
from outside the apartment.
No, you're wrong.
If they didn't know that Kaoru-san was in the bathroom,
then suddenly walking into the apartment and
committing the murder is not possible.
But if the murderer is someone from inside, then
the murder weapon must be somewhere.
Why can't we find it?
Inspector!
We found a listening device in this doll.
It must be from one of her fans.
What?
It also seems that her drawers have been tampered with.
That means that if someone had been spying on Kaoru-san,
he would have known about her engagement
and her location in the bathroom.
So, if the person was one of her biggest fans, he could have
attacked her and taken something as a gift for himself.
Contact her studio immediately and ask them if there are
any dangerous fans out there that we should be aware of.
Understood.
This is her room.
These must be the drawers that man was talking about.
The drawers containing pens and scissors are messy.
The ones containing makeup and jewelry
haven't even been touched.
This picture!
You!
Don't.
You shouldn't be invading someone's privacy.
I'm really sorry.
Women have things that they don't
want others to know about.
For that reason, they do some stupid things.
That picture, please put it back where you found it.
If it's no longer there, Kaoru could get extremely upset.
Alright, I'll put it back.
I see!
So that's why!
I've got it. I know what weapon the murderer used!
Not to mention,
how they got rid of it!
In any case,
the murder weapon isn't in this room.
That means this was an outside job.
There's a chance it was one of her angry fans.
Right now, all we can do is hope that she recovers
fast in order to help solve this mystery.
She might have seen the culprit.
H-Hello?
Yes, I'm Kaoru's friend.
Yes.
Huh? Kaoru...
Yoko...
What happened? It's the hospital, right?
Don't tell me that Kaoru is...
Don't worry. The surgery went fine!
She'll wake up in a couple of hours.
Oh, really?!
Thank goodness!
Then, you should be there when Kaoru-san
wakes up, since you're her fiance.
Yeah.
But are you sure that's okay?
The hospital is swamped with reporters
who have heard about the incident.
I could always go later.
I don't wanna annoy the patients or mislead the reporters.
Mislead them?
So it's over.
You have to tell everyone the truth
about the engagement party now.
The truth?
Uh... well...
T-The thing is...
It's unfortunate, isn't it?
Your plan didn't work out.
You're the one that did it, right? The criminal
that drugged Kaoru-san and slit her throat.
Boy...
While you're smart enough to be a detective,
you can't find the murder weapon.
The tool that was used to cut her
throat is nowhere to be found.
And I certainly don't have a knife on me.
If I'm really the criminal, then can you tell
me where I hid the murder weapon?
I don't know where it is, but I know what it looks like.
It's a sharp tool stuck on your finger.
Oh, you mean these fake nails?
Unfortunately, the police have already checked them, and—
No. Those nails are for camouflage only.
The truth is that the weapon is hidden
underneath those fake nails.
The next hardest thing in the human body after the
teeth, and a weapon only a woman could use:
That's her real, edge-sharp nails.
My guess is that you used your strong right thumb nail.
Before using it, you covered it up with a fake nail.
Afterwards, you clipped your nail
until it reached normal size.
Finally, you covered it up again.
No one would notice that the real
nail was as long as the fake one.
That's why you used old gloves.
You put a hole in them so that the nail could pass through.
You even used a raincoat to avoid the splattered blood.
And finally, you intentionally threw the coat and gloves
outside so it would appear that the culprit ran outside.
Effectively making it seem like the
crime was committed by a stalker.
You even sent the letters and the doll to Kaoru-san.
Isn't that right, Yuki-san?
I'm sorry.
So, the murder weapon was a real nail.
If that's true, then there must be a nail clipper
with traces of Kaoru's blood, right?
Your plan was to find one of Kaoru-san's in her room.
You needed it to hide the weapon.
However, you weren't able to find one among her stationary.
Maybe Kaoru-san uses a nail file instead of a nail clipper.
If it was me, I'd use scissors to cut my nail.
You would never use scissors because the police would
check them as a potential murder weapon.
If blood was found on them, this case would easily be solved.
A nail clipper would never be tested because
it can't be used to cut someone's throat.
You couldn't bring your own nail clipper
with you, it would be too suspicious.
You knew that all of the suspects' belongings
would be checked, including yours.
But, you said yourself that I couldn't have used a nail clipper!
How do you think I cut my nail?
Didn't I just tell you? There is something stronger
than the nails in the human body.
The teeth.
You clipped your nails by biting them,
then threw them down the drain.
As a result, it wouldn't look threatening enough to be
considered a weapon, and would be overlooked.
But I have proof that you did it.
Here, look at your kiss mark on this card.
It isn't very obvious, but you can see where it's darker.
That's Kaoru-san's blood on your lips,
left from when you bit off your nail.
Even without your deduction, Kaoru
could've told you the truth.
I called her from outside the bathroom,
and drugged her when she came out.
Could she have...
Could she have taken something before I followed her here?
I fell in love with Kenzaki-kun the
first day we performed together.
But, Kaoru stole him and my role from me.
No, you don't understand!
And when I congratulated her, you know what she told me?
It's all made up. It's just a rumor started by the press.
I was shocked, but before I knew what happened,
I was engulfed in a frenzy of jealousy
that I never felt before.
The real reason...
the reason Kenzaki-san and Kaoru-san never got engaged...
Most likely...
I'm so stupid.
I could have killed her if I had cut deeper.
When I saw her face, I just froze... I knew I couldn't kill her.
She really was...
my friend...
I'm t-truly glad that... that she didn't die.
What? What did she take?
Her face is pale and blue...
Her hand is shaking and her pulse is rapid...
Also, she just fainted...
My father is in the hospital for diabetes.
Maybe, it could be... the diabetes medication!
Blood Sugar Medication
Diabetics are usually prescribed a
medicine that lowers blood sugar.
It can be deadly if it's abused.
If a normal person took the drug, their
blood sugar would drop drastically.
If I leave her like this, she'll die!
Yuki-san must have prepared it ahead of time.
There!
Dammit, I won't let her die!
Not because of this senseless delusion!
I won't let her die!
Kaoru...
I'm sorry, Kaoru...
I'm really sorry.
Kaoru...
K-Kaoru?
She woke up!
Where am I?
Haido Hospital.
You were unconscious for two whole days.
You really are silly.
How could you mistake your father's
medicine for your vitamins?
I'll go tell Terumi that you're awake.
Kaoru, I...
I'm...
Don't worry. I told the police everything.
I told them that someone attacked me.
I told them it was an old fat lady!
I said, I told them it was an old woman.
I didn't want them thinking that some
psycho stalker was after me.
But, it was me...
Well, I should thank you for giving me this wound.
It's my punishment for lying for so long
without considering your feelings.
Lying?
Yes, the engagement party was fake.
I asked Kenzaki-san to play along.
I was trying to make a certain someone jealous.
Haven't I told you this before?
I want to marry in my 20s, just like Kudo Yukiko!
Yeah.
And now, my dream has come true.
It's front page now!
He finally proposed.
What? You still like that weakling?
Hey, watch it!
I know he seems like a chicken, but he's a marvelous man.
You should hear what he said in front of the reporters...
I don't want to lose that someone that I treasure the most.
So, a lot has happened today...
But thanks to Terumi, the plan was
able to work out pretty well.
Huh? Terumi was in on it?
We never actually had a fight.
When the Earth Ladies were still together, Terumi
used to visit me and give me a lot of advice.
We made up that fight as the reason our group was
breaking up. Sorry we never told you about it.
I see. You made up the fight so it would
be easier for us to break up.
But, what was the "Sorry to hear about it" on the card for?
Oh, that boy said she probably meant that
she was sorry the plan didn't work out.
That boy?
Conan-kun! Apparently, Detective
Mouri has trained him well.
He saw Kenzaki-san trying to cover me up with
a towel before getting me out of the bathtub.
That's how he knew we weren't really engaged.
He saw a picture of me with Makuma-kun, but
Terumi's attitude is what made him suspicious.
So, he kept asking me questions.
He's the one who fed you all that sugar when
he saw you passed out on the floor.
I see...
He saved me...
So, what about Kenzaki-san? Hurry up and tell him
how you feel before Terumi beats you to it!
Why?
Conan-kun said Terumi likes mysteries, and that she
must like the man who plays Detective Samonji.
Unfortunately, he's mistaken.
Kenzaki-kun told Terumi how he feels about
her but was completely ignored.
Huh? Then who's the person that she likes?
Who knows, but she usually likes younger guys.
Okay!
Scene 7, Terumi forces her opponent to surrender.
As usual, you have to act like a cool, heartless woman.
Okay.
Alright.
Haven't you noticed?
You made a fatal mistake that will bring about your defeat.
Your pieces look as though they have
a strong formation, but they don't.
She's more of a detective than a Shogi player.
Your pieces look as though they have
a strong formation, but they don't.
She's more of a detective than a Shogi player.
The move you made with your bishop was your downfall.
That is true.
Impossible.
Next Conan's Hint:
"Horseshoe"
Next is horse!
Did someone call me?