After all the commotion
over the calico cat Taii's owner...
we learned the real owner
was a man named Masuko.
But when we went to visit Taii there...
(cat meowing)
Huh? What's with this cat?
Mister, is something wrong?
Oh, no, it's this cat.
It doesn't look hurt or anything,
but there's blood on its paw...
Wait... that means... could Masuko-san...
No way...
A refreshing autumn breeze blows through
the gaiety of summer for a stylish and dashing display
of deduction.
The Detective Boys and a locked room trick...
what's the secret of the cute calico cat?
Seeing through the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"Lucky Calico Cat Case (Part 2)"
Masuko-san, if you're okay, please answer!
Masuko-san!
B... boy...
Maybe he's just sleeping.
And the door lock is on, too.
But the neighbor heard
a strange sound, right?
Y... yeah, a loud sound,
like something crashing...
And there's blood on the paw
of Masuko-san's cat.
Something happened in there.
- Haibara, call an ambulance.
- Got it.
You guys...
- Do you have any string?
- Huh?
And tape, or wire?
I've got some yarn.
I've got bandages.
I have paper clips.
But what are you going to do
with stuff like this?
I'm going to open this door lock.
First, tie the string to the
U-shaped bar of the door lock.
Fix the knot to the tip of the bar
with a bandage.
Run the string through the clip,
and the clip...
fix it to the inside of the door,
and we're all set.
Then just close the door
and pull the string hard...
Ah... it opened.
Where's the neighbor's room?
R... right there...
Then the closest one to next door,
left when you enter.
Ugh... Oi, Conan!
The back room, huh?
- An accident.
- Yeah.
He stood a chair on the bed
to change the fluorescent light,
lost his balance, and bashed
his head on the side table.
I do it sometimes too,
but standing on a bed...
it's unstable and dangerous.
Oh, please don't do things like that.
Your mattress is high-end
and super fluffy, Sato-san.
How do you know about
Detective Sato's bed?
Have you slept in it?
Ah... no...
Ayumi wants to sleep over
at Detective Sato's place too!
Never mind that nonsense, what about
the condition of this room's owner?
Ah... the surgery's done, but
he's apparently in critical, unconscious condition.
Well, when he comes to, he'll be grateful.
Thanks to Conan-kun opening
the door lock so quickly,
- he was saved.
- No, before that...
when he wakes up,
I think he'll tell us...
who it was that attacked him.
A... attacked?
W... wasn't this an accident?
Look, the chair is sitting on the comforter.
If you were standing a chair on the bed,
wouldn't you pull the blanket back first?
And look, Masuko-san still has
one slipper on.
If you were climbing on a bed or chair,
wouldn't you take your slippers off?
Th... that's right.
And what's broken on the floor...
I figured it was the old fluorescent
light he took out to replace,
but the ends aren't darkened at all.
Like it's brand new.
Which means...
someone shoved Masuko-san in this bedroom,
gravely injuring him,
then staged it to look like an accident.
The neighbor heard a suspicious sound,
and apparently it took nearly an hour...
for the building manager to arrive,
so there was plenty of time
to set up the trick.
B... but there's apparently
only one spare key,
and both keys were sitting
on the shelf in the living room.
And the front door lock,
how would they even...
That's already been solved.
Right, Conan-kun?
If you can undo a door lock from outside,
locking it would be...
Ah, no, I haven't gotten that far yet...
Hey, look at this.
- Something's on here.
- It's true.
Hey, you kids, what are you
doing without permission...
It's the intercom.
The intercom here...
records footage of whoever rings
the bell at the first-floor entrance.
There you go. In the hour before we arrived,
there were three people.
The audio's recorded too, and they
even said their names,
so if we cross-check with the address book,
we should figure out who's who.
There's no time for the
two of you to be flirting...
- None at all.
- Wha...
Geez, this is all because
Takagi-kun said something unnecessary.
S... sorry.
Wrapping paper on the table,
and an old-ish carrier bag.
So he really was trying to give
that calico cat to someone as a gift.
There's tape and creases
on the wrapping paper,
and torn marks here and there,
which means...
did someone open it
once after it was wrapped?
Hm? There's tape and scissors,
but...
And the trash can nearby is empty too.
Why isn't it here? That thing.
We found them pretty quickly.
The three people on the intercom.
Yeah, but the only one let into
the victim's room...
was the first one. The second one
was dealt with at the entrance,
and the third one rang the bell
at the front door,
but says they left when
there was no answer.
All three are suspicious, aren't they?
That's right.
If the second person came while
the first was still visiting,
then after the second left,
the first could've done it too...
Come to think of it,
when you kids rang...
the intercom at the entrance,
where was Masuko-san?
We didn't ring anything.
We were going to, but a resident
was just heading out,
so we slipped in
when the door opened.
We wanted to surprise him
by showing up suddenly.
And we had an appointment.
And we knew the room number.
I... I see.
Yes, I did meet with Masuko-san today.
- Furuyo Tsuyuguchi (41), Snack Bar Hostess
He treated me to some
tea in the living room.
It was the length of one record...
so I was there about ten minutes.
A record?
Yes, I...
collect vintage jazz records.
Masuko-san told me he'd found
a record I'd been searching for,
so while I was there to pick it up,
he let me listen to one track.
Did the doorbell ring
while you were there?
I wouldn't know,
I was listening with headphones.
Oh, sorry, could I borrow
your bathroom for a moment?
Yes, of course.
Then, excuse me...
Shoo, shoo.
Huh?
(water running)
Hey, boy.
Why don't you turn off the light
when you're done?
Whoa, sorry.
Oh, I can't stand wastefulness,
so I just...
(laughs)
Like I said earlier...
I only spoke with him
at the entrance.
I didn't go inside the room.
- Mari Aso (28), former employee of Masuko.
I didn't have an appointment,
and it seemed like he had...
a guest over.
What was your business
with Masuko-san?
Actually, I got fired from
President Masuko's company,
so I came to say
a final goodbye to him.
Don't tell me you came
to complain?
No, the opposite.
Getting fired was because of
a huge blunder of mine,
and on top of that,
the president...
arranged a new job for me,
so I came partly to thank him...
(cat meowing)
Hm?
Oh, what a cute kitty.
Can I hold it?
Sure.
So cute.
Dai-chan's wagging his tail.
He's happy.
Oh, you're right.
(cat meowing)
Don't you have any
cats of your own?
No, my parents hate animals,
even though I love them.
Don't make me say it again.
Yes, I did come as far as the front door,
- Rinpei Urushiya (53), novelist.
but no matter how many
times I pressed the bell,
he didn't answer,
so I gave up and went home.
Then how did you get
inside the building?
When I pressed the intercom
at the first-floor entrance,
someone buzzed me in.
There was no voice, so I can't say
for sure if it was him who opened it.
What's your relationship
with Masuko-san?
We've known each other
since our university days.
We're writers who debuted
the same year.
Though his novels didn't
sell at all,
and it seems he gave up
on it early on.
That said, for me too,
only my first work sold...
Looking back, maybe he made
the right call switching careers.
So why did you come here?
To brainstorm novel ideas
together.
Whenever I got stuck, he'd often
help me out, like he always did.
(cat meowing)
Hm...
Get that cat away from me.
It's annoying.
Mister, do you hate cats?
Yeah, a stray scratched me
this morning too.
I've got a bandage right here.
Ah.
No need to worry.
I've already treated it.
Thanks.
Well, if this cat were a great
detective like in that novel,
that'd be a different story.
Hmm.
The order they rang
the intercom...
Tsuyuguchi-san, Asou-san, then
Urushiya-san, that part checks out,
but the time the neighbor
heard the suspicious sound...
is too vague, so we can't
narrow it down to one person.
Looks like we'll just have to wait
for Masuko-san to regain consciousness.
No, we won't even
need to wait for that.
Huh?
Look...
Hm? Hah.
That's the face of a little prankster.
So then?
Around the time the neighbor
heard the suspicious sound,
those three were the ones who
came to the victim's place?
Yes.
But still...
the front door had both the key
lock and the door lock on, right?
Is this really a crime?
Ah... yes. C... Conan-kun said
the scene wasn't an accident...
And is this Conan-kun
in the room?
No, he said he had
some shopping to do...
I'm back.
Conan-kun, what did you buy?
The thing that was missing
from Masuko-san's room.
The missing thing?
This is it.
Wrapping ribbon.
When you tie a ribbon,
you cut the leftover ends...
with scissors to make
them even.
The fact that there were no ribbon
scraps in the trash can means...
even though scissors
were prepared,
maybe the length just
happened to be perfect?
The contents were a used carrier bag,
and there was tape too,
so it wasn't from a store...
It was something Masuko-san
wrapped himself.
B... but what does
that have to do with anything?
Are you half asleep? The fact that
it disappeared from the scene...
means the culprit obviously
used it for something.
H... half asleep?
For example, to make the room into a
locked room and stage an accident.
Anyway, let's experiment.
See if it can really be done.
First, the method for
setting the door lock.
Thread the ribbon through the gap
between the door lock and the door,
hold both ends of the ribbon,
step outside, and close the door.
Then just pull both
ends of the ribbon.
Good, Mitsuhiko.
Roger.
Pull it, please.
Got it.
I... it's locked.
Next, the method for
setting the key lock.
Open the door,
confirm the door lock is set,
pull the ribbon out, and make
a knot in the middle of the ribbon.
I made the knot.
So that the knot catches,
thread the ribbon through
the gap of the lock's thumb-turn.
Run the end of the ribbon outside,
close the door,
and pull the ribbon up
at an angle from outside...
A... amazing.
The key really locked with a ribbon...
Hm?
But unlike the door lock, can't you
not pull the ribbon back out?
Hey, pull it with all your might.
A... alright.
But the door's shut, so the knot
catches and...
That's strange. It should
have worked...
Hmph. Just a child's
shallow scheme, after all.
When you all came in here,
there was no ribbon like this, right?
Right.
There was nothing.
So the method to lock the key
with this ribbon is impossible.
Yeah. The ribbon would
be left behind.
If only someone could pull this ribbon
out from inside the room...
and carry it off somewhere.
Huh?
Someone, you say?
The only one inside
was the victim...
who's still unconscious, you know?
Guess there's no helping it.
Look, over there.
You can do it.
Keep the ribbon moving
like that.
Got it.
Hm?
(cat meowing)
Ah, the... the cat...
grabbed it and ran off.
A... after it.
Y... yes.
Behind the bookshelf?
So this is the cat's
treasure hiding spot.
Hm? Th... there it is.
Different from the
earlier ribbon...
another ribbon.
It has a knot too,
so there's no mistake.
Mm...
The question is who set up
the trick with that ribbon.
I do think it was the work of someone
who knows cats well, though...
Ah, well enough to know that the cat
wouldn't just carry the ribbon away,
but would hide it somewhere.
Then maybe it was the lady
with the glasses.
Dai-chan was wagging his tail
when she held him.
No, unlike dogs, when a cat wags
its tail, it means it's annoyed.
Asou-san didn't know that, so
isn't she not very familiar with cats?
Then Dai-chan was annoyed...
because she was the bad person
who hurt his owner.
If that were so, she wouldn't have
asked to hold him herself.
She'd think she might
get scratched.
The remaining two are Tsuyuguchi-san,
who was oddly concerned about saving electricity,
and Urushiya-san, who picked up...
what Genta-kun dropped
from his pocket,
but both of those are habits,
or rather...
Things they do without thinking.
Yes.
But you know, back then, Genta
dropped a bandage,
a handkerchief,
and a bottle cap,
but the only thing he picked up
was the bottle cap, right?
Now that you mention it,
that's true.
But why?
Then shall we test it?
Here.
(cat meowing)
I see. This little guy loves
bottle caps too.
I see. So the cat grabs it...
and carries it off to its
treasure hiding spot,
and they feared the ribbon used
in the trick would be discovered.
Well, it seems to have been a spur-of-the-moment
crime using items at the scene,
so if they weren't wearing gloves,
fingerprints should come
off that ribbon.
Alright, time to question
Urushiya-san again.
Hey, what made you think
that novelist was suspicious?
Was it because Dai-chan stood
his tail up at that person?
That's a gesture they only
show to someone close...
when they're happy
or feeling affectionate.
Well, that's part of it, but the moment
he said someone opened the door...
when he rang the
first-floor intercom,
I had him pegged as the culprit.
Huh?
If the culprit was the one who opened it,
then he was still inside the room at that point.
He'd have to use the trick
at the entrance...
to create a locked room, so
summoning someone to the front...
of the door is just unthinkable.
Indeed, I was the one who shoved him
and gave him those serious injuries.
But to come up with a trick
like that on the spot...
I once wrote a mystery
like that long ago.
The truth is, I came today
to beg him for money.
We were actually supposed
to meet tomorrow,
but this morning he called and said
he'd prepared a nice gift,
so I couldn't sit still
and ended up coming today.
But what I was handed...
was a used pet carrier bag,
inside wrapping paper that
looked hastily done.
And on top of that, inside
was that calico cat.
Worse, he kept being coy, grinning,
saying he couldn't hand it over yet today.
That cat was a stray I picked up
in the first place.
So you were the one
who had it at first, mister?
Yeah, just for about six
months when it was a kitten.
His wife was down from losing a pet,
so I gave it to her.
Well, giving it away
was the right call.
After that, my novels suddenly
stopped selling,
and I was in no position
to take care of a cat.
His company, on the other hand,
seemed to be on the rise.
And yet he tried to push...
that stray cat off
on someone like me.
Yes, the cat grabbed the
ribbon I'd untied...
and dashed into the bedroom,
and while holding it, he said this:
With this cat, you'll be fine.
It was your cat to begin with, so
you're the more fitting owner.
But Dai-chan is
an amazing cat.
Male calico cats are a rare breed,
hardly ever born...
They're super expensive,
you know.
Huh?
But the reason Masuko-san tried
to return the cat to you, mister,
wasn't for money. It was because
that cat brings good fortune...
a lucky beckoning cat,
wasn't it?
♪~
~♪
That's great. Dai-chan's owner,
the mister, was discharged, right?
Yes, and apparently
no lasting effects either.
So what happened to that cat?
In the end, Azusa-san from Poirot
ended up taking him in.
(cat meowing)
Hm?
Huh? Dai-chan?
No way, did you become
a stray cat again?
But isn't it kind of small?
The pattern's identical, though.
Come on, time to go home, Mugi.
(cat meowing)
Honestly, Grandma.
You can't open the lid
of the carrier bag.
Sorry, it just looked
so cramped.
That old lady... I think she's...
And they all lived
happily ever after?
You sure about this?
I'm a peeping tom.
Suzuki-san, you're
still here?
The landlord told you to
hurry up and move out, didn't they?
Hey, I've got a guest over.
Please, stop it already,
Katsuko-san.
Whoaaa.
I... inside... Katsuko-san is...
(three people screaming)
Next Conan,
"Share House Blind Spot".
Next Conan's Hint:
"Refrigerator".
Leave the refrigerator to me.
That makes no sense.
After all, it's autumn. Genta's all for food, that's why.