While flourishing as a high-school detective,
I was shrunken into a child by the Black Organization
with their mysterious drug.
Hailing from an immoral criminal syndicate,
they placed little weight on the lives of others.
"The Black Organization"
As such, the war between myself and the Black Organization
has continued day after day.
Yes. The war fought as Detective Conan Edogawa.
"Ai Haibara"
The codename for that drug is APOPTOXIN 4869 (APTX 4869).
It's something I developed for the Black Organization.
However, it remains in prototype testing.
Ai Haibara.
Her real name is Shiho Miyano.
In the Organization, she was known as Sherry.
I began to distrust the Black Organization
and escaped by taking the drug.
That's after my elder sister was murdered.
By him.
Gin.
"Gin"
This man was precisely the scoundrel
who is responsible for changing me into this state.
"Vodka"
Along with his partner Vodka,
it's likely they've been involved in numerous crimes.
By chance, we once ran across Gin's car in the middle of town.
We tried to tail them
but Haibara was soon captured by their compatriots.
Haibara, you're in danger!
They're coming!
I instructed Haibara to drink Paikar,
an alcohol that would temporarily revert her body to normal.
And tried to aid her escape.
But...
Gin had been lying in wait there.
Hurry into the chimney!
It was exceedingly dangerous,
but somehow, I managed to retrieve Haibara from them.
The FBI agents, Jodie and Akai,
began their investigation in secret.
Those two were after...
"Vermouth" -Vermouth.
Vermouth disguised herself as the school physician,
Dr. Araide, while searching for Sherry.
And eventually, she found us.
I inadvertently requested a house call without suspecting anything
since Ai's cold had become severe.
Our cover was blown.
Both Haibara's and mine.
My apologies for being so last minute,
but would it be all right to take you there now?
I disguised myself as Haibara and accepted Vermouth's invitation.
The FBI also set up a trap.
Vermouth, the FBI and I.
It became a spectacular battle between us three.
Vermouth's plan of targeting Haibara went astray.
From this incident, we acquired some information on the Organization.
Right. It turns out the dial tone for their boss's e-mail address
resembles the "Seven Kids" melody.
"Seven Kids"
And tonight, along with this "Seven Kids" melody,
an assassination plot will soon be put into motion.
Just who is their target?
Ladies and Gentlemen, thank you for waiting!
We're proudly presenting you, the next vice president,
candidate for the whole town, Kevin Brown.
Please give a big hand.
-Kevin... -Kevin...
I did it!
500 yards.
Cleared.
It's your turn next!
Just as expected!
600 yards, cleared!
Kevin Brown dies three times!
Four times.
They're pretty good.
Too bad!
If I clear this one...
It's my win!
I got this.
It seems 600 yards is as far as they can go.
That's it...
Gin!
Wait! Let me try once more!
There's no need to.
Our prey this time will be only 200 or 300 yards away at most.
That means...
Chianti.
Korn.
You got work to do.
I don't have all day!
I'm sorry!
Victory, sincerity, charging for the truth.
Endless impulse to aim for the best!
Finally, a confrontation with the Black Organization!
Dire straits comes one after another and ultimately the target of terror!
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"Black Impact! The Moment the Black Organization Reaches Out"
How was it?
That concludes our "Yoko Okino's Four-Minute Cooking".
Today's guest was Detective Kogoro Mouri.
All right, then!
See all at the same time next week!
Great, okay!
That's all for today!
That's right!
You were great, Dad!
Really! It was a live broadcast
but you were so calm and just great!
No... It wasn't all that great.
Yoko, you're way too beautiful that the noodles have gotten too hot
and excited that the Yoko's Soy Sauce Ramen that I made,
as you can see, have become soggy and soft.
It's knocked out.
You're the one who's soft with women.
We're lucky though!
Since "Morning Live Seven" was filmed on a holiday,
we got to come and watch the program being shot live!
Yep.
Come to think of it, we didn't have breakfast yet.
If it's okay with you,
why don't we have breakfast at the restaurant at this TV station?
That sounds good!
Then, please go ahead and wait for me there!
I have someone I want you to meet, Mr. Mouri.
So I'll make a call now.
Sorry for the call, this is Okino. Were you sleeping?
What's the matter, Conan?
No, it's nothing.
This is bad.
Whenever I see somebody using the cell phone,
it immediately brings back memories of Vermouth.
The e-mail address of the of the boss of the Black Organization
who shrunk my body with a drug.
That melody, "Seven Kids"...
That e-mail address is one that you should never open
since it's Pandora's box.
Yes... I know.
Really?
Maybe I should've made Japanese omelette rice.
Mr. Mouri!
Thank you for waiting!
Yes...
Huh? If I remember correctly,
you're usually sitting on the side of the screen
on the "Sunday Night News".
Yes! She's Announcer, Rena Mizunashi!
Nice meeting you.
I'm the Famed Detective, Kogoro Mouri!
I'm his daughter, Ran.
This is Conan.
Hello!
Pleased to meet you.
Come on!
Hey, Yoko?
Are you serious about discussing something like that
to a famed detective?
Don't worry!
I'm sure that Mr. Mouri will be able to work something out!
But...
Is something bothering you?
Yes.
Come on, Yoko...
Ring... Ring the bell and run away?
Are you asking me to catch the one who is doing that for you?
See... It's rude to ask him something like that, after all!
But it doesn't seem to be just a simple prank.
What do you mean?
Well...
The person rings the bell only early in the morning on Saturdays.
I was waiting again today in hopes of finding out who was doing it
but when I opened the door...
as soon as I heard the doorbell rang,
there was no one in sight anywhere.
-No way! -I've been afraid to open the door since then.
You mean it happened where you live?
Yes. At my condominium in Haido-cho.
If it's okay with you,
why don't you have Mr. Mouri go over to your place
and check things out?
I can't go because I have work after this but...
What do you think, Mr. Mouri?
What?
There's nowhere for people to hide near the door.
Yeah.
Why don't we try ringing the doorbell then?
Are you ready?
Then, I'm going to ring the doorbell.
Dad?
Are you all right?
Yes, sort of...
But now we know that there's practically no time to hide.
Yeah. Could you tell me more about it inside?
Sure. Please come in.
Sorry for intruding.
Let me get you slippers.
I don't need slippers. Thank you.
Of course, there're no slippers for kid!
Thank you!
This way, please.
Sorry for intruding.
You sure have a lot of locks, don't you?
Really. You got four locks all together.
Living alone as a woman could be a bit dangerous.
Well, I guess so.
Would you like something to drink?
Coffee, please.
I'll help you!
Okay!
I guess I'll set a wiretap to pick up the sound at the front entrance
when the doorbell rings.
I'll set it up on the wall outside the door.
If I put it here, I can easily retrieve it later.
Just in case it peels off and gets lost,
I'll wrap this transmitter in the chewing gum too.
Okay, all set!
Just now...
Just now, I feel like I was being watched by someone.
Conan?
Will juice be okay?
Oh, yep!
Is anything the matter?
No, it's nothing.
Okay then, juice for you.
Is it just my imagination?
Or...
So somebody's been ringing your doorbell from two months ago.
Yes. It happens every Saturday at around 6:30 am since then.
Did something happen two months ago?
The only thing I remember is that,
I was shifted from the program "Morning Live Seven"
to "Sunday Night News".
Although I'm not the main announcer for either program.
You got to know Ms. Yoko doing "Morning Live Seven", then?
Yes. We were both working the program
on Tuesday, Thursday and Saturday.
If so, the prank could've started being played on you
since two months ago.
Yes. Because when I was still doing "Morning Live seven",
I used to leave for work at 4 am on Saturday.
Is the prank being played on you throughout the two months?
It is. Every Saturday.
Oh! But there was just one time that nothing happened.
I was abroad the week before last from Monday to Friday to cover news.
On the Saturday, a day after I came home, nothing happened.
It could be that I was tired and couldn't hear the doorbell, though.
And on the Tuesday after the three day holiday in October,
the same prank was played.
That was the only day the prank was played on Tuesday, though.
And just once there was something weird outside the door.
Something weird?
A bottle with some drug inside was found outside the door.
I had a doctor acquaintance check it after that
and found out that it was a sleeping drug.
Sleeping drug?
It's a stalker.
It's probably a warning that he's planning to put you to sleep
and do evil things to you.
No way.
Did you notice anything else left by the door?
Besides the sleeping drug.
Something else?
What is it?
Around three nights ago,
it seems that someone was in the house next door
that is supposedly vacant.
What?
Three nights ago is Tuesday, right?
Yes. At a little before midnight,
I finished taking a bath and was relaxing on the bed.
I thought next door was supposed to be vacant
so I take a look from the veranda.
It was pitch dark next door,
so I thought that the sound came from outside.
So I called the management company in the morning
but I was told, "You must've been dreaming".
There's a high chance that the man is a stalker.
That man had the spare key to the house next door.
Not only three nights ago,
but especially on Friday nights he slept in the house next door.
And the following day, he rang your doorbell.
I see. If it's the house next door,
he can hide right after ringing the doorbell.
That's why you couldn't find the culprit.
Since when was the house next door vacant?
Probably from about six months ago, I think.
Just as I thought, it's locked.
We may be able to get clues on the man if we go inside.
Why don't we call the management company and have them open the door?
But from the feeling I got last time,
I don't think that they'll help at all.
No good.
"Ki-Mi-Wa"
"Ki-Mi-Wa"?
"Ki-Bi-Wa".
What's this supposed to mean?
I wonder what "Ki-Bi-Wa" means?
"Bi"?
What? I wonder why I read the kanji character as "Mi"?
"Ki-Bi-Wa".
Thursday. (Same kanji character as Thursday)
Beauty. (Same kanji character as beauty)
Japanese cuisine. (Same kanji character as Japanese cuisine)
What is it?
Ms. Rena.
Haven't you done a TV program having key words like those?
No.
Rather, maybe it's somebody's name?
Somebody's...
Somebody's name?
Yes, First Investigation Division.
Megure speaking...
Conan!
Yeah. I think he's here.
Hold on a second.
Let's see, the hold button...
So, that's the story.
Takagi, your extension is ringing.
Yeah.
Yes! Takagi here.
Officer Takagi!
What?
Inspector, didn't I teach you already?
About extension number...
Well, no big deal!
Oh yeah. Never mind that. Officer Takagi, from Conan on number one.
What? From Conan?
I wonder what he wants.
From Conan?
Yes. This is Takagi.
Oh, Officer Takagi?
There's something I'd like to ask you.
Three nights ago,
didn't you go inside unit 305 of a condominium Haido-cho?
Yeah.
I did.
The reason?
So, this vehicle was under...
I can't really tell you why...
Were you by any chance, Officer Takagi,
on a stake out the house of the condominium the other side?
-What? -What?
What?
Is anything the matter?
No, not really. It's nothing.
I wonder what's going on.
To be honest with you, that's right.
I stake out in the condominium unit
where I can see the house across from the window.
The ex-fiancee of a crime suspect lives in that condominium
and since there is a possibility of that suspect making contact with her,
we got permission from the management company and were staking out.
Just as I thought.
Just as you thought?
In the end, the suspect was arrested in Toriya-cho.
The stake out was cancelled at around midnight.
But since we're still investigating on the case
so the management company was told not to say anything.
And yet, how did you know I was staking out?
Officer Takagi.
While you're staking out,
didn't you doodle on the glass door?
You wrote "Miwako Takagi".
What is it, Officer Takagi?
Officer Takagi.
What's with him?
-I'm sorry! -He sure is acting jittery.
Conan, please don't tell her about this.
Okay?
Okay. I understand.
But Ran and Pops are here too!
No way!
Takagi!
Which means that while Officer Takagi
were staking out the ex-fiance of the suspect,
he was reminded of Officer Sato.
And as he was fantasizing marrying her,
he wrote that name on the glass door.
Right after that, he got a call from Inspector Megure
telling him that the suspect was caught.
As he left in a hurry,
so he forgot to erase the name on the glass door.
I see!
So as three days went by, the first two words of his last name
and the last word of Officer Sato's first name disappeared.
Come on. What a nuisance!
I'm sorry!
But it's just like him and kind of nice.
Really. That's so much unlike an officer and sort of cute.
I know, right?
But now we're back to where we started.
Yes..
And tomorrow is already the Saturday in question.
The only thing we can do now is to arrest the culprit in the act.
Ms. Rena!
Yes?
Please let us spend the night here today!
I, Kogoro Mouri, will nab that lowly and dirty guy tomorrow!
Shall I help you clean up?
Don't worry about it.
Tomorrow is recyclable trash day.
So all I'm doing is getting together magazines and newspapers
and tying them together.
I'm required read a lot of newspapers and magazines on the job so...
You're cleaning up?
"Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde"
It's Jekyll and Hyde!
How nostalgic.
I read it during my junior high school days and was really scared.
Conan, do you know this story?
Yep...
Dr. Henry Jekyll, who has a peaceful personality,
drinks the drug that he invented
and becomes Mr. Edward Hyde, a man with an evil personality.
A story about dual personality, right?
You really know a lot.
You brat!
This brat knows a lot about weird things.
I'm really sorry.
Not at all.
Here.
Do you always leave it out here?
Yes.
If I leave it out here,
I can take them out as I go out in the morning.
I see.
Besides, this is a corner unit,
so it won't get in anyone's way if it's just for a night.
Is Tuesday also a trash day?
Yes. For combustible trash.
I leave the trash for Tuesday out here on the day before too.
I see.
So that's the story.
Hey. Even if we figure out who the culprit is,
will you promise not to get too angry?
I'm sure he's a great fan of yours!
I'm sure he is!
After all, he's a stalker.
Wake up, Pops.
Pops!
Pops. It's almost time.
Here it comes?
Please stay where you are, Ms. Rena!
Just you wait!
You rat.
I'm going to nab you right now.
And teach you a lesson!
What?
Dad?
Nobody's here.
No way!
You gotta be kidding?
How can it be?
I don't believe it!
It can't be! How?
How's it possible, Dad?
How should I know?
Right here.
He's here.
You said he's there?
Those are magazines!
Conan...
I mean, behind here.
Idiot! How can an adult be hiding in a place like that?
A...
A child?
You brat!
Was it you?
So you're the one who's been pushing the doorbell and running away!
I see! He wasn't found because he was a child.
I didn't think that someone would be hiding in a place like that.
I see.
You didn't do anything the Saturday the week before last week
because there were no stacks of magazines in front of the door, right?
That week Ms. Rena was out on a business trip and wasn't home,
and probably didn't have that many magazines to recycle!
Hey, what were you doing?
Why did you do what you did for?
You're an elementary school student, aren't you?
Well, if you don't want to tell us about it, it can't be helped.
Let's go to the police, your parents and all
and get a good teaching there.
I think he rung the doorbell to wake her up.
So that Rena would make it in time for "Morning Live Seven".
I'm sure he thought that Ms. Rena isn't on "Morning Live Seven"
because she can't get up in the morning.
That's why he used to ring the doorbell at 6:30 am on Saturdays!
Since there's no school on Saturdays,
if he rushes home right after he rings the doorbell,
he can also confirm whether she's on the program or not!
But somebody pushed the doorbell on just one Tuesday too, right?
Don't tell me that you skipped school and...
I think there was no school.
There are consecutive days off in October, that is, the second Monday
because it's sports day.
If field day is held on that Monday,
usually, there is no school for grade school kids
on the following Tuesday.
Which means that he placed the sleeping pills there,
so Rena could sleep well and get up early in the morning.
Yep.
Because mother used to drink it saying she could sleep very well.
I see.
But why?
Why do you do so much for me?
Because you look like her.
You look like my mother.
My mother died last year of a traffic accident.
What?
That's why...
Sonny.
I understand that you're lonely because your mother's gone.
But if you keep clinging onto to your mother,
you'll only worry your mother who is in the heaven.
You're a boy,
so you got to be strong and let your mother rest in peace.
So, you shouldn't come here anymore.
For your mother's sake.
For your own sake too.
Understand?
Yep.
Bye, miss!
Bye.
It just...
I had a little brother about his age too back then.
Rather than that,
I have to pay you for detective fees.
Oh, no need for that!
We had dinner here too.
But...
Let me pay you at least as a token of my appreciation.
Oh, really?
Then I'll mail my bank account number to you later.
So can you give me your email address?
Hey...
Geez...
What a stale case it was...
But I'm glad that it turned out well.
It wasn't a weird stalker or anything.
Rain.
This is bad. I didn't retrieve the transmitter!
What's wrong, Conan?
I seem to have forgot something in Ms. Rena's house earlier.
What? Seriously.
Dad, you can go on ahead.
I'll go with Conan.
I'll go get it right away.
What? Conan.
Then we'll be waiting for you in the parking lot then!
Footsteps? Which means that...
Ms. Mizunashi stepped on it.
The sound of a cell phone being switched on.
"Seven Kids"!
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me that she...
Yes.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I had a bit of a problem and had my cell phone switched off.
It's all right.
It was no big thing.
I reported it to the person concerned by e-mail just now.
Don't tell me...
Yes. No problem.
Let's meet as we were scheduled to at 10 am.
Gin.
What?
Why?
What did you just say?
Are you serious, Shinichi?
Yeah. No doubt about it!
I found a member of the Black Organization
after a chain of unusually coincidental events!
This is bad. The movement of the transmitter's becoming faster!
She's using a car.
Dr. Agasa! Rush over here!
Come pick me up with your Beetle!
Make sure that Haibara doesn't find out about this.
What?
Okay...
And Shinichi.
Yeah. I'm at Haido-cho's...
You're not getting away!
Conan?
Did you find what you were looking for?
What? What's up?
Conan says that he coincidentally ran into Dr. Agasa
and they're heading off to Tropical Land from now.
Come off it... It's raining.
What's with those two?
I'll call you again when I'm ready to go home!
Hey, wait...
I see...
You coincidentally became acquainted with an announcer,
who asked you to take on a job and went to her condominium,
where for investigation purposes,
you used chewing gum to stick on a transmitter and wiretap to the wall.
But the chewing gum came off and stuck to the sole of her shoe.
And that woman, again for some reason,
coincidentally turns out to be one of them.
Is that right?
Hey, Dr. Agasa?
I thought I told you not to bring her along!
Well, but you see...
So? Are you sure that
the announcer called Rena Mizunashi is one of them?
Yeah. She was sending mail to the mail address of their boss.
She also addressed the one who called her after that as...
Gin!
So, you see!
But you're sure lucky.
You got a clue to who they are thanks to a string of coincidences.
Rather, it's just the opposite.
It's the opposite. Really bad.
Think about it carefully.
If the transmitter and wiretap are found by them,
they'll naturally try to figure out who set it up.
And, the first person to be suspected would be the one
who was at that announcer's place until just a while ago,
Detective Kogoro Mouri!
Hey, don't tell me that...
Yeah.
Even if Pops were to have set them up
to investigate the case she asked him to take on.
The chance that he may have heard their conversation cannot be denied.
If this happens, those guys would most likely...
Get to work trying to shut him up.
Not only Kogoro Mouri.
But if need be, every single person around him.
No way...
In other words, the more information comes through the transmitter,
the more the necks of both Pops and I are being choked.
Then, we have to retrieve them
as soon as possible before those guys find them.
But I just don't get it.
That announcer asked Detective Mouri
to nab the one who was ringing her doorbell and running away, right?
Moreover, the culprit turned out to be a kid.
If she were one of them, she would never...
Yeah.
That's the part that bugs me too.
The movement of the transmitter has slowed down.
Besides the sound of the engine is echoing.
Which means...
She went into an indoor parking lot somewhere.
Which means that she'll be meeting those guys in that building somewhere.
She's approaching something...
Is it a car?
This unique uneven sound of idling...
And...
The sound of the engine revving is that of a horizontally opposed engine.
Hey, don't tell me that...
Yeah...
The only cars equipped with this engine
are either Volkswagens, Subaru or...
that guy's beloved vehicle.
Porsche. That's all.
What's up, Kir?
You promised to be here at 10 am.
Gin!
I'm sorry.
A car seems to have been tailing me
so I was trying to throw it off track, just in case.
Don't tell me that she's referring to our car?
No, because we kept more than 600 m away from her car.
It couldn't be us.
Are you sure you're not in trouble?
Yes. I was just being too overly concerned.
So, will you put that Beretta that you're aiming out the window
back into it's case?
If you shoot me because you don't trust me...
You won't be able to kill DJ, right?
DJ...
What does that mean?
Okay.
We have 500 m of all the four directions of this building covered.
If an unwanted car approaches,
we'll know right of the bat.
Dr. Agasa.
Will you pull the car over slowly to the shoulder of the road.
What?
After stopping wear your hood and go outside.
Then, pretend that you're checking the car.
Quick!
Okay.
Here goes the final confirmation.
Go ahead.
Time is 13:00.
Place is Edie P...
I, as the interviewer, will guide DJ to the designated place.
Yes...
We'll be waiting for you, Kir.
Shove the prey right into the center of my scope
and excite me.
My, Chianti...
Korn's with you too, isn't he?
How encouraging.
Kir, Chianti, Korn.
How many of them are they, anyway?
I'm counting on you all.
Our achievements will never see the light.
But when we fail, the word goes around really quickly.
Whether we succeed or not, nobody will know about it.
That's how the organization works.
Yeah. That's right.
Okay. It's almost time.
Hurry and finish what you have to.
Will you work it out
so that I don't have to do anything?
Vermouth!
Hey, what's that supposed to mean?
How come?
Why is this lady here?
Nobody told me!
How come this lady who took Calvados out on his own and left him to die
is included in this project!
Go back to the car, Chianti.
We're keeping her here just in case.
But...
This is his order too, you know?
The place is Edie P.
I guess there's no better place for hunting?
What?
What do you mean by that?
You should at study a bit of their history too, Vodka.
Yeah.
What's more of a problem is the rain.
Don't worry.
It'll clear up before noon. The weather forecast...
Darn it! It's raining so hard
that the sound's...
Haibara, do you know?
Who's DJ?
Where's this Edie P that they're talking about?
They mention about that just now!
It's a code or something, right?
Well...
I don't know who is DJ
but if Edie P is a place,
P probably stands for a parking lot or a park.
Then, do you know who Kir, Chianti and Korn are?
I don't remember Kir.
But I've heard of Chianti and Korn.
They're supposed to be competent snipers.
Which means that they're going to assassinate somebody after all.
Hey, what's going on?
Don't tell me that the two are there too?
Darn it, I don't have enough information.
I've to get closer!
The transmitter is 580 m northeast from here.
Probably at the basement parking of that building over there.
Haibara, wait here together with the Dr. Agasa!
Hey, just where do you think you're going?
Never mind that! Just wait here!
That's as far as you go.
Kudo!
Shinichi?
Hi!
Cool Kid.
Ms. Jodie?
Hi!
What brings you here?
We, FBI agents, have been tailing her.
Ever since Vermouth disguised as Dr. Araide,
that announcer, Rena Mizunashi,
has been frequenting his clinic.
But it really shocked me,
when we were staking her out and...
Detective Mouri went into her place.
Then...
Just now, I feel like I was being watched by someone.
That was...
Yes! That was me!
And I found out that she had asked Kogoro
to investigate the prank that was being played by the child.
Just when I thought she was innocent
and about to quit staking her out...
I saw you running with a dreadfully serious look on your face.
Cool kid?
I figured there had to be something going on.
So, I continued to pursue her.
I knew she was trying to throw me off track,
so I didn't gone all the way and dropped pursuing her altogether.
I see.
So the car she was referring to was...
I'm sorry.
A car seems to have been tailing me
so I was trying to throw it off track, just in case.
The car she was talking about was Ms. Jodie's car.
You people lost track of her car too, didn't you?
Leave the rest to the F.B.I and go on home!
"You", you said? Do you mean you have a clue?
I can't give you the details,
but it seems she going to be interviewing three people today.
I'm thinking that maybe there is a person among the three,
who's being manipulated by them
and that some sort of transaction
or information exchange will be carried out.
No, it's no transaction!
Those guys are planning to kill one of the three
at 1 pm in the afternoon today!
What?
How do you know?
The transmitter coincidentally got stuck to the sole of her shoe.
So I've been pursuing her with my pursuit glasses...
This is bad! It's coming closer!
-Get in! -What?
Dr. Agasa, you too! Get in quickly!
Yeah.
Jodie here.
Our target is heading southward on Toriyakaido!
Please pursue.
Gin's car is taking a different route...
Are we pursuing them too?
No. All we'll end up doing just pursuing them blindly is go in circles.
Besides, we're finished if they find out that we're tailing them
But we have to do something or someone's going to be killed, right?
In other words, we have no choice
but to figure out who DJ is
and figure out the place called Edie P
and get to both before they do.
Yeah.
So, will you tell me in detail
about the three people
that the announcer is scheduled to interview today?
The three people she'll be interviewing are
the candidates who are running for the House of Representatives
for the first time.
The first person is a professor
of the pharmaceutical department of Teito University,
who has researched and developed many new drugs, Eisaku Tokiwa.
The second person is a famous actor from a distinguished family.
Moreover, if he wins, he will be a second generation Dietman.
Junji Sendou.
The third person is the son of the former official of the Defense Agency,
who he himself served as a higher up in the Self Defense Force,
Yasuteru Domon.
But we weren't able to get information on what time,
where and who she would be interviewing.
We were told that it was all up to her and the TV crew.
Maybe she's going to be holding a no appointment interview.
If so, high chances that the TV crew is also one of them.
But all three of them do not have the initials DJ.
Eisaku Tokiwa is ET.
Junji Sendou is JS.
Yasuteru Domon is YD.
If we can at least figure out the place.
There are so many parking lots and parks.
DJ usually stands for Disc Jockey, doesn't it?
The etymology is disc...
In other words, records are changed one after the other
to play a variety of songs.
This was deemed analogous to one riding records,
that is, to a jockey who rides horses
We have no information that any of the three
is into music or hooked on gambling either.
Gambling?
What's on your mind?
It's about time that...
Gambling.
It's about time that we go after her
or we'll really lose track of her...
No. We're not pursuing her.
Let's call the election offices.
And ask what the candidate is scheduled to do around 13:00.
Don't tell me that you figured something out?
Yeah. One of the three is their target DJ!
The clue is the Jack of Diamonds.
The Jack of Diamonds?
Are you saying that's what DJ stands for?
Yeah.
They always referred to their targets using playing cards!
If so, diamonds symbolize material possessions and financial wealth.
DJ is comes from a rich, distinguished family
and will become a second generation Dietman if elected...
He's Junji Sendou.
Wrong.
In playing cards, The Jack of Diamonds symbolizes
the one who serves the Court,
either a retainer or a soldier who has be appointed as an official.
It doesn't have the meaning of Prince or son.
What?
But...
He's the only rich one around.
It's true that diamonds symbolize money,
But in astrology it symbolizes other qualities.
In other words, a former self defense executive,
with a name that describes the character Earth in his name, which means
Yasuteru Domon.
He's their target!
He has a strong sense of justice
and made repeated radical comments regarding violence
and crimes on TV and in the papers.
He also has a great number of supporters.
Therefore, he had snipers being sent out after him
by crime related organizations,
but he's a super tough guy who beat them all up instead.
It seems that he doesn't need us to protect him though.
No. The one who is after him is The Black Organization.
They can't be taken lightly.
I got it.
The telephone number to his election campaign office.
It says on the website that he is scheduled to play golf this afternoon
but it doesn't say where.
So, the parking lot of the golf range
is where Mr. Domon is going to be shot.
At any rate, I think it's fastest to call this office and ask.
Here.
Ms. Jodie, here's the number.
Okay!
There. Okay.
What?
No. I just thought you changed.
Because when any of them were involved before,
"Stop it!"
"It's dangerous!"
"You'd better run!"
That's all you used to say!
Most naturally.
This time the transmitter and wiretap that you carelessly set up
is stuck on the sole of the shoe of one of the members.
If they find the devices,
not only you, but all the people around you,
in other words, all of us as well may be dunked into hot water.
That's true, but...
Besides...
I...
I'll go see him after all.
If I see the culprit close by, I may be able to recognize him.
No! I already explained to you that
if the culprit is not caught,
there's a possibility that you'll get into big trouble.
But...
Not only you,
but there is a possibility that all the people who helped you
will end up being their target.
I understand your feeling of wanting to punish evil.
But to hold yourself back,
endure and back off is also a type of courage.
But...
But I...
I don't want to run!
I can never win if I keep on running away!
Never!
Besides... What?
What? You don't know?
What do you mean?
Wasn't he scheduled to go golfing?
Well.
He cancelled it yesterday.
Something about he suddenly promised to meet someone.
Then, contact him quickly!
And tell him not to meet anyone
because his life is in danger!
We get a lot of calls like yours.
But no need to worry.
Mr. Domon is strong and he has two bodyguards accompanying him.
Please don't worry.
Please excuse me because I've other things to attend to.
Hey, wait!
It seems he took your call to be a prank.
-No way! -Well, it really can't be helped, though...
Darn it.
We've to locate Edie P which is the other hint we have.
That announcer who's supposed to be interviewing Mr. Domon.
Where is she now?
About 18 km southeast from here.
That's just around Nichiuri TV station in Shiodome.
She's probably going to join the crew there and go with them.
A phone call?
What's up?
Just confirming.
I have a very wary and persistent personality.
Don't worry.
Everything's fine.
I'm going to join the crew
and head for Edie P on the TV station wagon now.
The rain has cleared.
And it's turned out to be a great day for hunting.
Kir.
I've been thinking from this morning,
Your phone's very static.
Yeah. Maybe because I'm in the basement?
I answered the phone in the basement this morning too.
Okay, Gin.
We'll go on ahead then!
Hey, Chianti!
Good luck.
I'll kill her!
I'll kill!
I'll kill her for sure!
I hate Vermouth too.
Calvados used to love her.
She used him to her advantage.
That's why I hate her.
Yes. I would've killed her long ago if I had my way.
And that woman was not our boss' favorite.
Darn it!
We have less than 30 minutes to go
before the assassination time that they mentioned!
Edie P...
Where on earth is it?
Edie P!
I think we should head over to the TV station too, don't you?
Yes, I agree.
We're not getting anywhere wasting our time here.
Even if we were to locate their hunting ground.
If we're too far away from the TV station wagon,
we can't possibly beat them to it.
Hunting ground.
Come to think of it, Vermouth was saying.
I guess there's no better place for hunting?
What? What do you mean?
You should at study a bit of their history too, Vodka.
History.
Oh, a phone call?
It's mine.
Well...
This sound is...
Conan's cell phone.
Hello?
What do you mean, hello?
Gosh. How dare you hang up on me like that?
I'm sorry, Ran.
If this horse comes, it'll be a big win!
Please put Dr. Agasa on the phone!
It's already our turn to ride the Ferris Wheel!
So I'll call you again later!
Hey, Conan!
Geez!
Oh, cool kid!
It's like you have dual personality!
Dual personality?
Wait a second.
Hunting ground.
History.
Park.
Dual personality!
You're cleaning up?
"Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde"
It's Jekyll and Hyde!
How nostalgic.
I see! Dr. Agasa!
Take a left at that traffic light over there and get on the freeway!
The freeway?
If we go on the freeway,
we'll be driving away from Nichiuri TV, you know?
It's okay.
Because we're beating them to the hunting ground.
Beat them to it?
Don't tell me that...
Yeah.
I finally figured it out!
The location Edie P that they're planning to assassinate Mr. Domon is...
Haido Park!
Haido Park?
But what makes you think Edie P is?
It flashed upon me when Ms. Jodie said "dual personality" a while ago.
That Eddie is the short form of Edward!
I see.
Edward Hyde.
Edward is the first name of a character
that appears in Stevenson's bizarre novel,
"Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde".
Which means, Edie P stands for Haido Park!
I'm sure there was a parking space in that park, though.
No.
They mentioned that there was no better place for hunting.
In the real Hyde Park in London,
until around the 16th Century, deer and wolves existed
and it used to be the hunting ground of the nobles.
That's the hunting ground!
There's no mistake about it!
This is bad.
If we go as is, the TV station wagon will be there before us.
Dr. Agasa! Hurry!
Okay!
Hey, Gin.
Isn't Kir here yet?
I'm dying of boredom.
Hold it. She's on her way there while bringing DJ along with her.
Don't you dare hunt some other prey to get rid of your boredom now.
The same goes for Korn.
That boy.
And FBI agents!
Why?
Listen.
Only Ms. Jodie and me are going!
Both of you don't come out of the car, no matter what!
Okay.
Ms. Jodie!
We don't have time!
Where is it?
Sorry for all the trouble.
Thank you so very much for agreeing to our scoop interview.
No problem. Anytime.
Was this the place the interview is to be held?
Yes.
It's a wonderful park.
It's my usual jogging course.
Well, at that time, my two bodyguards here
end up running with me though.
I wonder what's taking her so long.
Kir.
By the way, about the, you know what...
In place of my accepting this interview,
you'll approve of the condition I set forth too, won't you?
Yes. Of course.
I appreciate it.
Okay, Kir.
Guide DJ to the designated place.
This is going to be some heavy film.
Too bad it's not live broadcast.
90 m more!
Please make it in time!
We shouldn't just stand and talk.
Let's go some place where we can relax and talk.
True.
Well...
How about sitting on that bench over there?
Bench?
Great.
Good. That's right.
Let's get it over with as soon as possible, Mr. Domon.
What? Isn't that Mr. Domon?
What?
Amazing, he's for real!
Please shake hands with me!
It's fine.
I support you!
Please change Japan!
Oh, thank you!
I got him.
Can I shoot him?
Not yet, Korn.
There're too many sheep in the way.
Wait until DJ sits down on the bench.
There he is!
Hey. Isn't he Mr. Domon that appears a lot on TV?
For real?
But where's the snipers?
They were concerned about the rain.
So they're probably...
On the roof of a building!
Over there?
And the other one.
It's under the water tank.
I'll go save Mr. Domon.
So you go ahead and take the others to a safe place.
No.
If I carelessly charge in there and he fires at random,
he may hit the spectators in the area!
In order to prevent them from shooting.
In order to make them give the whole thing up.
Umbrella?
Well...
Let's shake hands after the interview.
How annoying.
Hold your horses
and wait.
There!
Sprinkler?
Hey, Ms. Jodie.
Do you have a gun?
Mr.Domon!
Thank you...
A gun?
Well, yes.
What about a silencer?
Yeah.
Then, will you shoot what I tell to shoot at?
But do it so no one notices!
So, like I said, let's shake hands later.
Mr. Domon!
I support you!
So please do your best!
Yeah.
Thank you!
Will films like this come in handy later during the election?
Yes, of course.
Understand, Korn?
I shoot his head!
And you shoot his back.
I want to shoot his head.
Okay! Suit yourself!
What's up, Kir?
Hurry and make DJ sit down!
Kir?
Mr. Domon?
It's about time we get the interview going.
Yes, I guess so.
Excuse me.
Will you all back off a bit?
We'd like to film the interview.
Sprinkler?
Rain?
Hey, come on. Give me a break.
Seriously?
Come on, and sit down.
Quickly!
Thanks.
DJ has a navy blue umbrella.
Can I shoot him?
Wait.
Shooting him through the umbrella will reduce accuracy.
But how strange.
It's not raining on this side.
It's begun raining on this side too.
It's really started raining.
Blessed rain.
Chianti.
Kir, Korn.
Withdraw for now!
I'll be waiting for you at the place in an hour.
Then...
Will you tell me?
The synopsis of the second part of the assassination scheme is?
We have no choice.
Let's continue the interview at the summerhouse within this park.
Yes.
Shall we get going then?
Excuse me. May we go with you too?
Yes, of course!
-Then, me too! -Same here!
Chance!
-Hurry up... -Wait...
I'd better get the transmitter and wiretap
that on the sole of her shoe now!
Okay! It's mine now!
Sonny?
I found it!
Don't tell me that you followed me here?
No. I didn't.
It's just a coincidence.
I see.
Thank you.
For picking my shoe up for me.
Thank you very much.
Director!
Could you substitute someone in my place to hold the interview?
-What? -I'm sorry.
I'm having trouble with my shoe since earlier.
Hey...
Gin.
The announcer found you?
No way!
Don't tell me she found out that we were tailing her.
No, I think I pulled through okay on that one.
She hasn't noticed the transmitter and wiretap either.
Then, why didn't you retrieve them?
All you had to do was tell her that
something was on the back of her shoe and take them.
Yeah. I thought of doing so too,
but she...
Thank you very much.
I sort of felt strange.
But thanks to you, we can pursue going after them!
Besides, there seems to be more to their assassination scheme.
Yeah.
Is it okay to leave things as they are?
The TV crew, that she brought along with her, are with him, aren't they?
The crew aren't involved in this!
She deliberately tried to find a reason
for acting on her own without the crew.
So my guess is...
Those guys are probably going to get together somewhere.
And get on with their next plan.
Well, leave the rest to us, FBI agents,
and you people get on going home with the Beetle.
I'm going to keep him with me for a while, though!
Then, how do you intend to pursue them without a car?
No problem.
My boss offered of his own initiative to be my driver.
Then, Dr. Agasa.
Smooth things out with Pops and Ran for me.
Invite them over to your place and make sure they don't find out anything.
Okay!
Just to be on the safe side,
we'll have two or three of our members stay on guard too.
Then, I'm counting on you!
Hey!
I'm sure you already know.
But your prime purpose is to retrieve the transmitter and wiretap!
If you hesitate because of curiosity or a sense of justice,
you may end up losing everything!
Yeah, I know.
You shot the sprinkler and broke it
to make them think that it started to rain,
and prevented those guys from going through with their plan
by making the crowd as well as the target to use their umbrellas.
It's no wonder you respect this boy.
I'd like to scout him to the bureau myself.
He's James!
You've met him once before, haven't you?
Conan.
The last I saw you was that Panda car incident?
You were a life saver then!
Panda?
What?
It's true!
James left behind for us.
I'm telling you that the code "P&A" means police car!
So, why does "P&A" mean police car?
Try changing the "&" in "P&A" into the alphabet!
Let's see.
P&A.
P and a, n, d and a.
Panda?
I see! Panda!
I see.
The color of a police car is black and white
Hey! Hurry!
Use the hostage as a shield and run for it!
Okay!
Help!
What the...
Officer!
Please help us!
Excuse me!
I'm Officer Takagi from headquarters!
Please help us arrest the kidnapper!
Darn it, that almost scared me.
Okay, after keeping them company for a while, take a side road!
Okay, got them!
Okay. It's about time we take a side road.
If there's no road to the left, take the right!
But...
There's another police car to the right too!
Then, reverse!
Slow down and reverse.
There's a police car behind too.
What?
Hey, we're completely...
surrounded by cops!
So, this James guy is also an FBI agent.
But why are they going after Yasuteru Domon who's not even a Dietman?
Probably because his father used to be a famous government official,
he's well known in the world of politics.
He's got charisma
and is a solid clump of righteousness.
Rumor already has it that he's a candidate for the future Prime Minister.
I see.
They want to get rid of anyone that is bound to resist against them
while still a bud.
That's how they work.
Besides, if they kill him now,
they can make it look like Kiriko Busujima did it.
Kiriko Busujima?
Yes. A woman executive of the Deisan Organization
that is suspected of having sent out a sniper to kill him.
I see.
Take a left at the next intersection.
Well? Anything from them?
No. Still too early for anything.
By the way,
do you know where Shuichi is?
Yeah. I'm looking for him too.
You explained this to him, didn't you?
Yes.
Including info about the transmitter and wiretap that this boy set up.
This is what he said over the phone.
I see.
That's it.
I haven't heard a word from him since.
Ever since he lost his girlfriend,
it seems he's got a tendency to close up like a clam.
Not that he had an open heart to begin with, though.
I hear him.
This voice is...
At about 16:00, DJ will pass over and cross a bridge.
That's where he's going to be assassinated.
Gin!
Chianti and Korn, you both go around to support this time.
What? Support?
I want to shoot.
Well, think about it.
He's riding a specially ordered bulletproof car.
It's not the same as killing him in the park.
But...
Besides, he's tightly guarded on both sides by bodyguards
who have been trained in the Self-Defense Force.
The 7.62 mm bullet may pierce though the thinnest part of the car.
Though the thinnest side window.
But will not reach DJ.
Then, how do you intend to kill him?
Do you might me to stand on the bridge stark naked and hitchhike,
then get myself in his car or something?
My, Chianti. That's pretty good thinking.
Vermouth?
I'm going to ride this motorbike
and fall right in front of DJ's car and stop him.
When he comes out of the car,
I'll come from behind
and get him.
The job of you both is to get rid of the two bodyguards
that come out of the car together with DJ.
But I wonder if that cautious man will come out of the car that easily.
Don't worry.
If a woman bleeds from her head
after her helmet flies off and is lying on the ground.
A man of justice such as he is will probably come dashing over, no?
What?
Cut out the joke!
There are going to be other cars on the bridge too.
If a famous actress like you expose your face.
Idiot.
I'm going to be exposing...
This face!
Kiriko Busujima of the Deisan Organization!
Just as would be expected of you, Vermouth.
You're a complete duplicate.
I see.
That's why you've come out front.
Where's the place?
Gin.
We're going to kill DJ at Vane B.
Bein B?
Is that the next assassination site?
Yeah. The time is 16:00.
It seems that they're going to kill Mr. Domon
when his car passes over a bridge somewhere.
In other words, the "B" of Bein B means bridge?
But if we can't specify which bridge it is,
we can't stop the assassination.
Quiet!
They're checking the map now.
Maybe they'll say the name of the place.
Korn, you position yourself here.
Chianti, you go here.
We're counting on you both!
Where's my motorbike?
Oh, yes.
Behind that container.
Thank you.
Let's get together in the foreground of Vane B.
Hey, Kir.
Don't tell me that you...
I hope you're not. Are you?
Idiot.
Of course not.
What is it?
Well, I'll go on ahead.
Make sure you back me up if something comes up.
I have a bad feeling
about this assassination scheme.
Leave it to me.
If things start looking bad and you're in danger of falling in their hands,
I won't hesitate firing a bullet right through your head.
Yes. If such time comes, make sure you aim at my face, okay?
You don't want the world to know that
I was part of the assassination scheme, do you?
Things will turn out badly, right?
Is there something bothering you, Vermouth?
No.
It's just this feeling I have.
Don't worry about it.
Okay.
Let's get going too.
Okay, I don't know how much you know.
But I wonder if you can stop me?
My dearest...
Silver Bullet?
So, we don't know where the location is.
Yeah.
The sound is getting worse from a while ago.
The only clue we have is that it's on a bridge somewhere.
Maybe we can find out by calling Mr. Domon's election office
and asking them
where he's headed for now
and what bridge he'll be crossing.
I called them several times but...
They won't tell me.
Since I was quite persistent,
they seem to suspect me of being up to no good.
Well...
Unless we find out what the "Bein" of Bein B is.
This bad direction of the wind won't change.
Direction of the wind?
Bein sounds a lot like V. A. I. N.
Which means useless, worthless, and conceited.
I wonder if there was a place with that sort of name in Tokyo?
No, that's not it.
It's not V. A. I. N.
But V. A. N. E. As in Vane!
What? You mean the vane as in weathervane or a windmill?
Yeah.
A word that at the same time means the arrow feather of a bow.
The name of a place around here that suggests an arrow feather is.
Toriya-cho!
In other words, Vane B is Toriya Bridge!
That is Toriya Grand Bridge!
That's good news!
We still have two hours till 16:00,
the scheduled time of the assassination!
We finally get to take the lead!
There are a total of six of them,
three women and three men!
The two women will be riding motorbikes
and the remaining four will come on two different cars.
One of which is a Porsche 365A.
Let's send the investigator's vehicle to the bridge on the double
and block off all the roads leading to the bridge for now.
We're going to round them up, right?
No, we're going to stay low and sneak up from behind.
And make sure we fish them all without fail, one by one.
Geez!
Why do I, the Famed Detective, Kogoro Mouri,
have to play a TV game at your house, Dr. Agasa?
Well, no big thing, is it?
You didn't have anything to do anyway, did you?
Besides, that's a deduction game
that I developed that I'm quite confident of!
And there's no one else than you to be the first to try it out.
This game is filled with a lot of cases, isn't it?
This is already the third case.
Who cares?
Nobody's dying for real.
And if a bit of the painful feeling is felt by the player,
it's served its purpose.
Well, I wish people would keep homicides confined
to games and TV dramas.
The grief that one goes through when someone really dies
can't be compared to the one felt through games and TV dramas.
By the way, where's Conan?
Wasn't he with you, Dr. Agasa?
Oh, yes.
He went on home before us.
Because it started raining quite heavily.
I guess I'll start heading on home too, then.
I don't want Conan to be starving.
Well...
Don't go home!
Edogawa will be fine.
Don't worry about him.
So, don't go! Please!
-Ai. -Ai.
Okay, if you say so.
Then I'll stay.
Well, let's take a look back at the Black Organization.
How about where you are, Korn?
Clear view.
Yes.
I'm already in position.
Okay! All we need to wait for is Kir.
Hey, Vodka.
I keep hearing static on your side.
No.
It's nothing.
Yes. Only a few minutes until we get there.
Let us know when you get there, Kir.
Roger!
Excuse me.
I'd like to ask you something.
Will you please stop your motorbike?
That is bad!
She's still breathing!
Rush her to the hospital!
Okay!
Rena Mizunashi?
What's Rena Mizunashi doing here?
According to your story,
wasn't the woman riding this motorbike
supposed to be Vermouth in disguise?
I thought so
because she was quite some distance away from the transmitter.
I thought for sure that was the case, but...
She changed into leather overalls and boots somewhere.
The transmitter and wiretap that are on her loafers are probably there.
But where did she change?
Not yet?
Gin.
Men who keep people waiting are not liked!
Hold your horses, Chianti.
We haven't got word from Kir yet.
Besides, DJ's car is still...
This might not mean anything
but I can't hear a thing because your voice is full of static!
Static?
What's up?
Quiet.
What?
You're playing the game, Ran?
Yes.
And I don't see Mouri around.
Oh. He went home saying that
the main derby is going to start pretty soon.
What's the matter?
The transmitter switched off.
How? About the noise?
I can hear something faintly.
But the sound is muffled.
What?
Cancelled?
You telling us to quit after coming this far?
Yeah. I got boss' approval just now too.
To change the target.
Change?
Change the target?
And, where is it?
The next target.
The place is Beika-cho, Gochome.
Mouri Detective Agency.
Mouri Detective Agency?
The horses have turned the fourth corner
and are running the straight course!
What's this?
I'm hitting the bull's eye left and right today!
What? Two black cars together?
They are pulling away from Toriya Grand Bridge?
Are those cars really theirs?
Yes! One of it is a Porsche 356A.
And the other one is a Viper!
The Harley was abandoned.
So that who was riding the motorbike is probably also in the car.
It can't be!
I mean...
The car that Mr. Domon, their target is on,
is speeding right before our eyes at this moment.
It's not even on the bridge yet.
In which direction did the two cars head for?
Where are those cars headed?
They turned left on the intersection of Toriya Yonchome
and headed towards Haido-cho?
Strange.
They're headed back to where they failed to assassinate their target?
No. Those guys are probably headed for Beika-cho!
What?
They found the transmitter and wiretap!
Leave Mr. Domon's car up to the FBI agents car pursuing from behind,
and head for Beika-cho!
Pops is in danger!
What's going on with the car behind?
I was thinking it strange that they were tailing us close for some time.
Let them be!
If you get too nervous,
you won't be able to handle things when you'll really need to.
I'm really grateful for all you're doing for me.
Well, I, myself have become a man worthy of being protected by you two,
and overcome the fix that I'm in now too.
A fix?
I just got word about that.
It's bad news.
But is it really true?
But is that story about Kogoro Mouri
setting a transmitter and wiretap on the sole of Kir's shoe true?
Yeah, no doubt about it.
According to the info we got,
the one that Kir was in touch with before meeting us today
was that guy.
But that's not enough to suspect him.
I don't know what he set it there for but...
He's the one that did it.
If it had been set some days ago, even more so.
Kir would've realized.
If it was that famed detective.
Are you saying that Kir disappeared because of that detective?
Keep your voice down.
The wiretap is still going.
What? Didn't you crush it along with the transmitter?
I have it hidden in my coat, wrapped heavily in cloth
so that it won't pick up what we say.
This way, we can throw him off a bit too.
I have something I want to ask that detective
while he's still here in this world with us.
What? Pops went home?
Right.
Ran's still here,
but Mouri left the minute we took our eyes of him.
Would you like me to go his detective agency
and bring him back here again?
No! Don't!
It seems that he left before the FBI arrived at Dr. Agasa's place!
What's up?
I'll explain later!
And until I contact you,
don't step an inch out of the house until you hear from me!
Please, Pops.
Please...
Please be okay!
This... This is scary.
Too scary.
I've already won 11 races in a row from the first race!
The God of Horse Races must've finally descended upon me?
Hey. Come on...
Darn it! This clunker of a TV!
This always happens at the wrong time!
Geez!
Hey! Pops?
Pops?
Gosh!
I've a 12 races straight win on my shoulders now!
Now for the odds of the final race...
I can't be answering the phone at a time like this!
Seriously!
What a simpleton.
I blew up the TV antenna and he shows his face.
His ear. He got...
Something and...
He's probably just listening to the wiretap that he set up
with all his might.
Then, let's make him hear our voices just as he wishes.
Do you hear me, Kogoro Mouri?
Gin!
Don't you dare to move.
We've target locked your back.
I have something I'd like to ask you before we open a ventilation hole in your suit.
The relationship between you and Sherry.
The transmitter and wiretap that you set up.
Looks a lot like the ones that woman set up previously.
I won't take coincidence for an answer.
I'll give you 10 seconds.
If you decide to answer,
take your left hand away from your earphone and raise it up.
Earphone.
If the horse makes it, it'll be my win!
I see!
Pops is listening to the horse races on the radio.
There, I see it!
Mouri Detective Agency!
Ten.
Nine.
Eight.
The roof of the car! Quick!
Seven.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One! Go for it!
A soccer ball?
Hey! Who the heck are you?
I'm sorry, I kicked the ball a little too hard!
Why you...
By the way, how did the horse race go?
You were listening to it through the earphone, right?
Horse race?
Thanks to you, I goofed it!
It seems that he had nothing to do with this.
Get rid both of them.
Okay!
Punish when in doubt, right?
Wait!
We don't even conclusive proof,
and yet if we kill this man who has deep connections with the police...
Enough, Vermouth!
Gin.
Do you have something going with that detective?
So?
What if I do?
Never mind.
The one who set this up seems to have carelessly left fingerprints behind.
After we get rid of him,
if we check his surroundings
we'll eventually be able to figure out who set it up.
What?
Behind you at 8 o'clock.
It's from that building!
It can't be! It's 700 yards away.
Give it to me!
Shuichi Akai?
We've finally met.
My dear and dearest arch-enemy.
My dear.
The FBI. So that's the story.
Gin.
We're splitting!
But what about the detective and kid?
Never mind!
Get out of here, quick!
Their car is headed west from Beika-cho Gochome.
Please pursue.
Well, they may throw you off track part way, though.
That gun fire a while ago was shot by an FBI agent?
Yeah, we fell into their trap.
If they didn't know that we were going there from some time ago,
they couldn't have positioned themselves on that building.
Then, you mean that Kogoro Mouri and the FBI joined hands and...
I don't think so.
To the FBI, he's no more than just a bait to lure us out.
I wonder if they would risk the life of one of their comrades.
They probably got info that he was going to have contact with Kir,
and after the two parted,
the FBI probably set the transmitter and wiretap onto Kir's shoe.
That way, just in case we all get caught,
we would all suspect him because of it.
Let's say that's what happened.
Kogoro Mouri seems to be your favorite detective after all.
Thank you.
The problem for now is Kir.
Don't tell me, the FBI...
Yeah.
There's probably no doubt that she fell into their hands.
Well, but I don't think Kir is the type to spit things easily.
I'll search her out no matter what it takes.
Do you have an idea where she is?
Hints are everywhere.
It's not that I believe that Kogoro Mouri
is completely innocent yet, either.
Did you see the TV program on this morning?
Yeah. The news about Mr. Domon passing up
being a candidate for election this time, right?
The reason is suspicion of his father, a government official,
having an extra-marital affair.
Which was 20 years ago.
Mr. Domon seems to have agreed to a special interview with Nichiuri TV,
under the condition that they keep this affair thing a secret,
but it was found that Rena Mizunashi had made up on her own.
Which means she was not commuting to work to the TV station.
Well, if they had known that he was such a righteous guy
that would give up candidacy for something like that.
They wouldn't have had to go through all the trouble.
Only if we could arrest two or three of those guys.
I could've blown off his leg,
but I fired through his bullet proof jacket and left it at that.
I didn't want to stop them carelessly
and start a gunfire battle in the middle of town
while risking the general public falling prey to bullets.
Besides, in this case,
it was our top priority to make them think that
it was the FBI who set up the transmitter and wiretap.
Right?
That's true, but...
Besides, it's not only that.
All ties have been severed with them either.
Although her life is not in danger,
she seems to be still unconscious.
I guess all we can do is wait for her to recover.
I've asked them to keep the fact that she's been hospitalized hidden.
But if an announcer suddenly disappears,
the TV station will not overlook it, will they?
That boy said don't worry.
He'd work something out.
That boy again.
Who is he, anyway?
A detective.
He's my favorite.
Personnel manager?
This is Rena Mizunashi!
I'm very sorry to say this,
but I'd like to take time off for a while.
How lucky you are.
Detective Mouri who was hanging around you was suspected,
and escape being killed by them by a hairsbreadth.
But he was saved at the very last moment.
That guy foresaw what was going to happen and ambushed them
to make those guys think that it was the FBI who schemed all this.
Well, you'd better thank that Akai guy.
Yeah, I really appreciate what he did.
As well as Dr. Agasa and you for sheltering Ran at Dr. Agasa's place.
By the way, is everything all right?
It seems that nobody's keeping guard over Detective Mouri since then.
It's safer not to have anybody guard him
so I refused the FBI's offer to guard him.
I mean this is the chance to show them that
Pops has nothing to do with the FBI.
If I carelessly ask the FBI to guard him,
and they suspect that Pops is involved after all.
That would be more dangerous.
True, but...
Besides, we got a card that they left behind for us.
Announcer Rena Mizunashi, right?
I hear she's unconscious and in the hospital.
Yeah. I hear that the FBI are on guard around the clock
waiting for her to get up.
But if those guys find the hospital...
Don't worry!
I called the TV station using her voice and told them that
she'll be going on a long leave of absence.
So, I'm sure those guys won't think that she's in the hospital either.
At any rate, always keep on your guard.
I'm sure that those guys are frantically looking for
her whereabouts right now, too.
Yeah. Those guy would do anything to achieve their purpose.