(Conan breathing heavily)
Don't tell me that couple...
were Bourbon and Vermouth...
And what if they overheard
my conversation with Jodie?
I... I've got to find Haibara
and check, fast.
Dammit. Why didn't I
catch on right away?
If they're saying
her husband Touhei...
was also a hostage
in that incident...
then nothing adds up.
Even though they pulled
such a huge blunder...
Huh... a blunder?
Wait, could this be...
a trap?
Huh?
Lately, have you sensed
their presence at all?
Uh... yeah, you know...
You said before you could
smell them, right?
I haven't sensed anything.
I haven't been on my guard.
You told me yourself
they think I'm dead.
Ah... right, right.
Then it's fine.
Wait... what?
Don't tell me they found out
I'm still alive...
It... it's just a check.
Just checking.
Anyway, sorry for calling
this late.
Got to stay calm
and not make a fuss.
♪~
Black shadows and dark gloom,
the light of deduction cuts through.
Ran collapsed during the investigation
with Sera. What on earth happened?
Seeing through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance,
with the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
~♪
"The Restroom Where Ran Also Collapsed (Part 1)".
Hey, Conan-kun?
Conan-kun, hello?
Ah...
Huh? What?
What do you mean "what"?
You keep looking around.
Is there someone
suspicious here?
Oh... no, don't worry about it.
It's nothing like that.
Really?
This is bad.
Ever since then, I keep feeling
like someone's watching me.
I told Jodie...
that couple might've been
the ones in black...
just in case, but...
If they've caught on
to that one thing...
Calm down. It's fine.
It's still fine.
Oh... are you feeling sick,
Conan-kun?
You're drenched in sweat.
Huh? What?
We were going to have lunch
with my mom in Chinatown later...
Should we cancel and go home?
Ah... I'm fine.
I was just thinking about something.
Is that so?
I got assigned some
tough homework, that's all.
(camera shutter)
A shutter sound?
I'm not imagining it.
Someone really is
watching me.
But who... and why?
(camera shutter)
Again.
Closer than last time.
Where? Where are they
shooting from?
(camera shutter)
Hey, you two.
What are you doing
in a place like this?
Sera-san, what about you?
I'm working.
You know a girl in Class A
named Keiko Kitao?
Oh, Kei-chan?
Through her, her older sister
hired me for a job.
See...
Sitting in that chair over there...
That's Rumi Kitao,
a third-year university student.
And the man sitting next to her...
is Kenya Settsu,
a fourth-year student.
Those two have been dating
for the past six months.
She wants to introduce him
to her parents as a marriage prospect...
but rumor has it
he's a playboy...
and she suspects he hasn't fully
cut things off with his ex.
Huh.
So I've been investigating that.
I see.
So it's an affair
investigation.
So, how's it looking?
Hm? Right now, it's gray.
He still hasn't returned the spare key
to his ex's apartment...
and this place happens to be
that ex's building.
But is it okay to be telling
us all this?
It's fine. You two can keep
a secret, right?
Ah, haha...
So, what are you two
doing here?
This is Kanagawa Prefecture,
you know.
My mom took on a job
from a resident here...
and she's in a meeting
right now.
We were supposed to have lunch
once it wrapped up, but...
(phone ringing)
Oh, it's from my mom.
What? No way.
You can't get away?
But I'm starving.
Sorry, sweetie. The meeting's running long.
If you're hungry, go ahead and grab
a quick bite with Conan-kun first.
Let's meet back in this lobby
in the evening.
Okaay.
Guess I'll just buy
a rice ball at the convenience store.
Then why not have those two
treat you to lunch?
Huh?
They've got plans
to have lunch today...
with the ex joining them.
Quit joking.
We've never even met them.
It's an undercover operation.
Huh... undercover?
For Keiko-kun's sake,
in Class A.
Huh? You're kidding?
Wasn't your little sister
supposed to come later?
It's a pretty famous place...
and it was a real pain
to get a reservation for her too.
It can't be helped.
She said something
suddenly came up with a friend.
What? Don't tell me
you're after my little sister.
Of course not. I just thought
she'd liven up the mood.
Today's supposed to be a make-up dinner
between me and Wakka, right?
I haven't really spoken to Wakka
since we broke up.
Right. Well, Kaga's coming
later...
so he'll get things lively.
Oh, um...
Huh?
Are you by any chance
Kei-chan Kitao's older sister?
Eh... yes.
I'm Ran Mouri. I was in the same class
as her last year.
She showed me photos of you
a few times...
so I thought it might be you.
Oh, really?
Heh, what a coincidence.
Actually, today I was supposed
to take Keiko-kun's place...
and join the meal myself.
If that guy's a playboy
like the rumors say...
I figured he'd make eyes at me
behind her sister's back.
But you've got a better figure
and you're cuter than me...
so could you take this role?
Huh?
If he really is that kind of man...
I'm sure he'll bite
if we dangle some bait.
All right.
First, casually cast the bait...
Um...
Hm?
Co... Conan-kun.
We're hungry, but we haven't
decided what to eat, right?
Y... yeah.
That wasn't casual at all.
Then why not eat with us?
Huh?
One more kid won't make
much difference.
Th... thank you so much.
He took the bait
that easily.
Perfect.
Still...
Wakka's late. It's already
past noon.
Can't be helped.
She was drinking until five this morning...
- Kaga Mitsuaki (22), university student.
so she's probably
still out cold.
Oh, you're here, Kaga.
This lobby has a restroom,
doesn't it?
Yeah, past the elevator.
Then I'll go take care
of business real quick.
In that case, I'll go check on Wakka.
Oh, if you're going
to Wakka's room...
return this spare key
for me.
Huh?
I don't need it anymore.
Kenya...
Ah... oh...
Hey now, don't drop it.
Sorry.
And now she's alone
with Ran-kun.
If he's going to show his tail,
it'll be now.
Ah... sorry, but could you
go along with her too?
Huh?
If Wakka still hasn't
sobered up...
she might lash out at her.
That's true.
I did steal Wakka's
boyfriend, after all...
so with an unfamiliar girl along,
Wakka might stay calmer.
I don't mind, but...
Then please come along.
Oh, okay.
(sighs)
Maybe she just suddenly
didn't want to see my face...
and she's holed up in there.
If so, tell her I want to meet
in person and apologize...
for everything.
Okay.
Hmm.
Surprisingly...
this guy's
pretty decent.
(doorbell chiming)
No answer.
Maybe she really
is asleep.
Then I guess I'll use this.
Wakka?
Are you sleeping?
(phone ringing)
Oh.
Sorry, it's a call.
Sorry, but could you go
wake Wakka up?
Huh?
When Wakka comes home drunk,
she has a habit of sleeping in weird spots...
so check inside the closet too.
Oh, okay.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Huh? Hard to hear me?
Then I'll step out
onto the balcony.
Wakka-san,
are you here?
Wakka-san?
Wakka-san.
This is troubling.
She's nowhere... oh.
(shower running)
Oh.
The bath?
Um, I'm a friend
of Rumi-san's little sister...
I was asked to come
get you, Wakka-san...
Wa... Wakka-san?
Are you okay?
Wakka-san!
Please hold on, Wakka-san.
Wakka-san.
Wakka-sa... ngh.
Ran-neechan.
Ran-neechan, wake up.
Ran-neechan! Ran-neechan!
Ngh... Co... Conan-kun.
Thank goodness.
You came to.
You okay?
Sorry about all this.
Sera-san.
What... what happened to me?
Ow, ow...
You collapsed
in the bathroom.
Oh no... it's terrible.
Wakka-san was collapsed
in the bathroom, bleeding...
Yeah, that's why... see.
Oh... oh...
The police are here
investigating now.
What happened?
I heard the shower running
in this bathroom...
and when I went in, Wakka-san
was collapsed in the steam...
I tried to wake her,
but I suddenly blacked out...
Did you see anyone
suspicious?
No.
I searched the closet too,
but there was no one...
Huh?
Why the closet?
Wakka-san has a habit of sleeping
in odd places when she comes home drunk...
Rumi-san, who came to get her
with me...
Oh, that's right.
Where's Rumi-san?
I'm fine.
I'm sorry for dragging you
into this mess.
Rumi-san.
Unfortunately...
after I found you and Wakka
collapsed in the bathroom...
I passed out too...
so I didn't see the culprit either.
Since we didn't
come back for so long...
Kenya and the others
came up, right?
Yeah.
Even after 30 minutes
you didn't come down...
and you didn't answer
your phones either.
So we explained the situation
to the building's management office...
and had them unlock the door.
Right?
Yeah.
And then we found the three of you
piled up, collapsed in the bathroom...
so we hurried
and called the police.
Ngh...
But what was that smell?
I got woozy in the bathroom.
It was chloroform.
Hmph... it's a type
of anesthetic...
Inhale a large amount
and you lose consciousness...
and in some cases,
it can even kill you.
It vaporized and filled
this entire bathroom.
Huh?
Well, seems this kid
turned on the ventilation fan right away...
so you're all fine now.
So Wakka was killed
with that anesthetic...
Hey now, can't you tell
just by looking?
She was beaten to death.
Someone struck her head
with a blunt object and killed her.
But if that's the case,
why use anesthetic...?
And is the dead person
really Wakka?
Her face is hidden
by that mask.
Then let's have you
confirm it.
Ah...
Ah.
Ah, Wakka!
Whoa now,
don't come in.
But what a strange corpse.
She's winking.
And... something's
dripping from the corner of her eye.
Mascara?
At a glance, it looks like
someone struck Wakka-san...
from behind as she was about
to take a bath...
but this might just be...
So, to sum it up...
Today, you four had plans
to eat lunch together...
and you were going to gather
in the early afternoon...
in the lobby of the victim's
apartment building, here.
But worried that she
wasn't coming down at all...
Rumi-san and Ran-san,
who happened to be there...
came up to this room
to check on her...
but there was no answer
to the doorbell.
So, with the key entrusted
to you by Settsu-san...
who used to date the victim...
you opened the front door
and went inside.
Then, at that moment, a call came
from Settsu-san to Rumi-san...
so Ran-san ended up
searching for her alone...
and found her collapsed
in the bathroom...
but passed out
from the chloroform...
and Rumi-san, who came afterward,
also fell asleep.
Then, 30 minutes later...
worried about the two of you
who wouldn't return...
you all rushed here...
and found the three of them
collapsed in the bathroom.
Yeah, that's pretty much it.
The front door's deadbolt
was locked...
so it took time to open it,
which delayed our call to the police.
I... I'm the worrying type...
I have a habit of locking up
right away wherever I go.
Hmm... by the way, is it true
the victim was drinking...
until five this morning?
Yeah. Just the two of us,
in this room.
I invited Settsu and Rumi too, but they said
they'd see her tomorrow anyway.
I got an earful of complaints
about her ex, Settsu...
right up until she
drank herself to sleep.
So what about the front
door key?
O... of course...
When I left, I managed to wake Wakka
and had her lock it properly.
Hmm...
Still, this is some apartment
for one person to live in.
Wakka's father is an executive
at a famous company.
Well, the only one who wasn't
surprised by this place...
was a first-year girl who joined
our club this year.
Her parents... the chairman of an affiliated
group of that company, apparently.
Hey.
Hm? Oh.
When you and Ran-neechan
entered here with the spare key...
it seems there was a call
from Settsu-san...
What was it about?
He asked me to look
for something.
Back when he was dating Wakka,
he left something here...
and he wanted me to find it
and bring it to him.
Well, he'd asked me before...
so I was going to do it
even without the call.
What did he leave behind?
A wristwatch.
One he was fond of.
He figured it was probably
still left in the living room.
If Wakka was still asleep...
he wanted me to slip in
with the spare key...
and quietly retrieve it...
but it seems
I couldn't find it.
Maybe Wakka found it
and threw it away.
The living room...
that's the big room
with the balcony, right?
Yes.
A call came in and I stepped out
onto the balcony...
so it was good timing
to search, but...
This is a high-rise
apartment...
so the signal's weak unless
you go out on the balcony.
That's why you asked her
to look for Wakka, right?
Oh, yes.
Which means...
Rumi-san came in the front door
and went into the living room on the left...
while Ran searched the right side,
where the bedroom is.
Speaking of the balcony...
when Wakka came home drunk...
she slept on the balcony
sometimes too, right?
Yeah, I heard that story before.
She called me pretty drunk...
saying she was sobering up
in the breeze...
but she fell asleep
mid-call.
I came over worried...
and she was leaning against the balcony,
sound asleep.
She slept under the bed
once too.
But this time...
it wasn't the balcony or under the bed,
but the bathroom where she slept.
As a corpse.
And the one who put her
through that...
is one of the two of you...
who had the key
to this room.
H... hey...
Hold on a second.
Settsu, the ex, had the spare key,
but I don't have any key...
You drank until this morning
and got the victim drunk...
then secretly took the key home,
didn't you?
When you rushed here...
you could just leave it lying around
and cover it up.
Ah...
Maybe...
you were even here right up until
the gathering time in the afternoon...
A... and Rumi might have
a key too.
Hm?
She used to share this place with Wakka
before Settsu and Wakka started dating.
I returned my key
ages ago.
I see...
If all three of you
could have had a key...
then all three of you
could have committed the crime.
No.
Ah...
The only ones who could have killed Wakka-san
before Ran-kun found her...
are Settsu-san and Kaga-san,
the two of them.
Ah...
What?
Kaga-san arrived just before...
Ran-kun and Rumi-san went up
to call on Wakka-san's room...
and about 30 minutes before that,
Settsu-san stepped away to the restroom, right?
If those two had the key
to Wakka-san's room...
they could have used the stairs,
which have no security camera...
and killed Wakka-san
without anyone seeing.
On that point, Rumi-san...
was with me the whole time until we got here.
Ah.
She didn't even go to the restroom
until we went to Wakka-san's room...
so she couldn't have done it.
You were with Rumi?
Wait, who the heck are you?
A detective.
Huh?
Rumi-san hired me.
♪~
~♪
In any case...
Ngh...
Ah.
Ah... sorry.
Thanks for picking it up.
Here.
Don't drop it again.
Hm...
If that corpse
wasn't Wakka-san...
then that changes things.
Huh?
Ah...
Wh... what did you say?
Next Conan,
"The Restroom Where Ran Also Collapsed (Part 2)".
Next Conan's Hint:
"Wink".
It's almost June. From May to June.
Mascara from the eyes.