(Bell chime)
(Sonoko Suzuki) Congratulations, Masaru-san!
(Ran Mouri) Congratulations to you both.
(Crowd cheering)
(Conan Edogawa) Ha ha... Huh?
♪~
(Conan)
The shadow's blackness and the darkness's depth,
The light of deduction cuts right through.
A gunshot aimed at the bride and groom,
Solve the impossible crime's mystery.
See through to the one single truth.
Looks like a child, mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
~♪
"The Wedding Reception and Two Gunshots"
Hmm, the food's pretty good.
But, honestly, was it really okay for complete strangers—
like us to come?
It's fine, it's fine.
If I'd come alone—
which table do you think they'd have stuck me at?
Nothing but stuffy old men and ladies, right?
And besides, if I come to one of these things by myself—
people trying to introduce their sons to me
come up to greet me one after another—
I can never eat in peace.
Wow, even a financial conglomerate heiress has it tough.
Yeah. I'm sure Masaru-san must have had the same experience.
And then he fell in love at first sight—
with the woman managing the villa...
So romantic!
Ha ha ha ha...
Ladies and gentlemen, I apologize for interrupting your conversations.
We would now like to receive congratulatory addresses from our distinguished guests—
but before that, we have an announcement for everyone.
Huh?
The groom, Masaru-san, and the bride, Miho-san—
who just held their solemn wedding ceremony at the chapel earlier—
actually submitted their marriage registration at the ward office the day before yesterday.
Oooh!
What?
Mother, did you hear about this?
No, I didn't know either.
Honestly, doing whatever they please...
Everyone, once more for the couple—
please give them a huge round of applause!
What? Seriously...
We're out of wine.
Hey, Arisa, you're drinking too much.
Oh, shut up, Dad.
You insisted I come,
so I came.
She was one of the girls hoping to be Masaru-san's bride, too.
Really...
That wine, right? I'll bring it right away.
Yoshifumi-kun.
You're the bride's brother,
you should let someone else handle it.
No, I'm just... not really comfortable at these sorts of gatherings.
I feel more at ease
if I'm moving around.
It's less stressful for me.
Just for today, you could at least
sit down and relax.
In the end, a caretaker is still just a caretaker.
Honestly, the thought of that woman
doing whatever she wants with the Hatakeyama family fortune...
Dad must be turning in his grave.
Now, we will receive a congratulatory address from the groom Masaru-san's uncle—
President of Hatakeyama Bank,
Kenshiro Hatakeyama-sama.
(Applause)
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Just... restroom.
Hey there, little guy.
Huh?
What's up? Looking for the bathroom?
Yeah.
Do you know where it is?
I'm fine.
You're... the kid who came with the young lady from the Suzuki financial group, right?
Yeah. Hey, you're the caretaker of this villa, aren't you, big brother?
Ah. Well, originally, when this villa was first built—
my old man and my mom became the caretakers, but—
both of them died in an accident.
Huh... What did you do before that?
We were farmers.
But around here, the damage from monkeys and wild boars was awful.
Partly because of that, we quit farming and became caretakers.
Hmm.
Anyway, little guy, shouldn't you be getting to the restroom?
Ah! I forgot. See ya.
...is what I told them!
Hey, how's it going?
Was the food to your liking?
Yes, we're completely stuffed, thank you!
Oh, glad to hear it.
When we get back from our honeymoon—
you three should come visit our house in Tokyo.
We'd love to, but we're counting on you for souvenirs!
Ahaha! Got it, I'll remember.
More importantly, is it okay to leave your bride alone?
Staying beside two beauties like us—
She might get jealous, you know?
Huh?
That's not true.
Because I trust Masaru-san.
Ah~ Burning with passion!
Huh? Miho-san, you look a bit pale...
Yes, I'm feeling a little tired.
Then leave the rest to me—
You should go back to the hotel and rest.
Yoshifumi-kun.
Yes?
Have you been drinking?
No, I don't drink.
Then, sorry to ask, but—
could you take Miho in my car and drive her back?
Understood.
(Yawn)
Maybe we should be heading out soon, too.
Yeah. Let's say goodbye to Masaru-san...
Huh? Where's Masaru-san?
About ten minutes ago—
he said, "It's a call from Miho-san," and went out.
Th-this is terrible!
What's wrong?
By the... by the van in the parking lot—
th-the groom is collapsed there!
What?!
What?! No way!
What?
It can't be...
Ah...!
Shot at point-blank range with a gun.
Masaru-san!
Wait, don't get any closer until the police arrive.
Conan-kun!
Ran-neechan, hurry, call the police!
Right.
Is it true that Masaru-kun is down?!
Old man...
(Gunshot sound)
Ah!
What was that sound just now?
It sounded like it came from across the river...
Yeah, it was from the direction of the hotel.
It can't be...
(Knock)
Miho-san! Miho-san!
Ah...!
I see.
So when that sound like a gunshot was heard—
everyone here, besides Conan-kun, was gathered right here, correct?
Yes, we received a call from Conan-kun—
and he said, "Everyone should wait here for the police."
Alright. Let's go check the other crime scene, then.
Yes, sir.
Hmm...
(Sobbing)
What are you doing, Takagi-keiji?
Oh? Ah, just searching to see if the culprit left anything behind.
I see~
Found something!
This looks like it's definitely the murder weapon.
Excuse me, can we get a photo of this?
Hm... Bamboo?
Why would that be here...
Tatsuya-kun.
I hate to bring this up at a time like this, but—
what's going to happen to the shares Masaru-kun holds?
The biggest concern is the employees becoming uneasy.
Well, since that boy didn't have any children—
wouldn't they naturally go to me, his sister, or his mother?
No.
Assuming Masaru-kun died before Miho-san—
at the moment of Masaru-kun's death—
all of his assets would belong to Miho-san.
What? What do you mean?
Didn't the wedding host announce it last night?
"The two have already registered their marriage."
Wait, so what happens to Masaru's fortune?!
If Miho-san died after Masaru-kun—
then Miho-san's heirs would inherit it.
What? That's ridiculous...
I will absolutely never accept that!
Accept it or not, that's the law.
A stupid law like that is just wrong!
Sorry to gather you all at a time like this.
Our mother is resting in her room due to severe shock.
Very well.
Among the attendees from last night—
anyone with a solid alibi for the estimated time of death for both victims—
has been allowed to go home for now.
Are you suspecting us?
Yes. You are all particularly closely related
to the two who have passed away, so—
while your anger is justified, please cooperate with the investigation.
Tatsuya-kun and I were beside Masaru-kun's body
when Miho-san was killed.
At least regarding Miho-san's case, we have an alibi.
Indeed. The bullets removed from the two victims' bodies—
both match the handgun found in the flower bed.
In other words, these two murders are believed to be the work of a single culprit.
Then, we...
However, at that time, Rikako-san and Arisa-san—
had already returned to the hotel, hadn't you?
Are you saying I'm a murderer?!
Now, now, please don't get agitated.
It's merely a discussion of possibilities.
Since it's still early in the investigation, we don't yet know the motive for killing
the bride and groom one after the other.
So, what we'd like to ask—
Yoshifumi-san, the bride's younger brother.
Yes.
According to the results of our investigation from last night until now—
you have outstanding debts of several million yen
across multiple financial institutions, is that correct?
Ah... That's...
Whether that's true or not, could you please answer?
Yes... Yes, I do.
But I didn't kill anyone!
Why would I kill my own sister...?
When she's my only family left...
Ah, Chiba-keiji, what were you doing?
Conan-kun, I was checking the security footage.
See, that security camera installed on the inside of the entrance—
it should have captured the area near the flower bed where the gun was found, right?
So I thought, and I watched all the recordings from last night, but—
No one approached the flower bed.
Huh? Then how did the gun end up there?
Maybe they threw it from a window on the upper floor of the hotel.
Hm?
What are these four dents?
Ah!
Oh yeah, last night—
we got a call that the streetlight over there was out, so I came by.
Did you see anything at that time?
Umm, now that you mention it...
(Door closing sound)
Hm?
About what time was that?
Hm? Erm, let's see...
Ah! I got the call at 9:40, so—
it must have been around 9:45.
9:45...
What's the significance of that time?
9:45, you say?
That's just after Miho-san left the villa—
a full 30 minutes before we found Masaru-san's body.
Hm...
So that's it.
Ah! But, if that's the case, then that thing...
Hey~ little boy!
Huh?
A kid shouldn't be wandering around at this hour.
Sorry.
There are hungry monkeys roaming around this area—
you'll get bitten.
Ha!
I see... If we use that...
There's no way we could have killed Masaru!
Deep down, you wanted to push Masaru-san out and put your own husband
at the top of the Hatakeyama Group, right?
We know all about it.
Don't say stupid things, you foolish girl!
You're the one who couldn't become Masaru's wife,
so you killed Miho-san...
and then killed Masaru when he found out, didn't you?!
Who's the fool here?
Masaru-san was killed first!
Has your greed for money driven you completely crazy?
Ah!
Stop this shameful display right now!
Inspector Megure!
Ye... Yes?
Can we go home now...?
(Tranquilizer dart sound)
Oww... Funya...
Sonoko, here it comes? That usual thing...
Funyanyo...
I don't want to say unnecessary things either, but—
if I stay silent now, the real culprit benefits the most, right?
S-Sonoko-kun... Are you saying you've figured out who the real culprit is?
What?!
Yes. If the police would just hurry up and arrest that person—
I wouldn't have to act like a know-it-all.
Rikako-san.
You said one thing that was correct.
Huh?
Miho-san was killed first.
What?
But the only ones who returned to the hotel first were Rikako-san and Arisa-san...
I told you, it wasn't me!
Me neither!
I know it wasn't either of you.
Hmph!
The time of the murder was shortly after Miho-san arrived at the cottage.
That's why she hadn't changed out of her dress.
You likely drove Miho-san there—
and killed her immediately, didn't you?
Yoshifumi-san?
Ha...
What are you talking about?
You're drowning in massive debt.
When your older sister's marriage was decided—
you thought this would let you repay those debts, but—
things didn't go so smoothly.
So, you slipped something into your sister's drink.
When she started feeling unwell, you drove her to the cottage—
and killed her with a hidden handgun.
Muffling the sound with a cushion or something.
(Gunshot sound)
After that, you used Miho-san's cell phone to call Masaru-san out—
and killed him the same way.
(Gunshot sound)
Wait a minute. What about the murder weapon, the handgun?
It was found in the hotel flower bed, right?
Until the police came—
wasn't I with everyone else beside Masaru-san?
I had no chance to get rid of the gun!
That's the part that bothered me most, too.
Why did the culprit discard the gun in a place like that?
And then I understood.
The gun wasn't thrown to that location—
it fell there.
Ah...!
The villa and the hotel are almost directly opposite each other across the river, right?
But after killing Masaru-san—
throwing the handgun to the opposite bank is physically impossible by human strength.
So, you used that thing.
(Sound of falling)
How could I have done something like that...?
Isn't it obvious?
Rikako-san and the others were just saying it earlier.
To make it look as though Masaru-san's fortune
was first inherited by Miho-san—
it was absolutely necessary that Miho-san
appeared to have died after Masaru-san.
For that to work,
the handgun needed to be found on this side of the river.
Th-that's just speculation! Do you have any proof?
Do you remember the old man with the stepladder?
Huh?
The hotel employee who came to change the fluorescent light
on the path near the cottage—
he remembered seeing a figure rush out of that room.
Before Masaru-san was even killed.
Meaning, Miho-san was the one murdered first.
Then what was that gunshot everyone heard in the parking lot?!
That gunshot is precisely—
the very centerpiece of the alibi you worked so hard to create.
Go ahead, you can come in.
Ah... uh...
Looks like you recognize it.
It's only natural, since it was found in your family's shed.
Wha... what is that?
It's a bird-scarer.
It's a tool that uses fireworks to scare away
sparrows that come to eat the rice grain in autumn.
Around here, they seem to use it to scare off monkeys.
While we're at it, I should mention—
it was set to make a sound only once.
That's what everyone heard.
Damn it... It's my sister's fault!
Becoming part of a family worth billions—
and yet she wouldn't do anything for me...
How could she be so cruel?
(Sobbing)
♪~
~♪
Ran's completely devastated.
Well, after what happened, I guess that's only natural.
Ran-neechan!
Let's eat something delicious tonight and cheer up!
If you want, I can even make it.
I saw this cooking show on TV the other day—
they showed how to make curry with a special twist.
No, no, curry is off-limits! It's surprisingly high in calories.
Sigh... Even though such a sad event just happened—
when I got back from the wedding and weighed myself—
I'd gained two kilos. Shocking, right? Two whole kilos!
Ha ha ha...
So *that's* why she was down.
Ran!
Good morning.
Morning... Sigh...
Sonoko, you look tired.
Listen to this. When I got back from the wedding and weighed myself—
I'd gained three kilos!
I gained two. We have to lose it before summer...
We won't fit into our swimsuits!
But hey, don't we have like, a weigh-in or something before that?
Aaah...
Ran, what do we do?!
Ugh... Exercise! We'll run, Sonoko!
Let's go!
Good grief. I'm worrying so much, I'm the one who's gonna lose weight.
Oh wow! The cherry blossoms are in full bloom!
It's the perfect day for flower viewing!
G-Great fortune?!
Heh heh.
Th-this is terrible, Shinichi! It's murder!
It seems I have witnessed a murder!
A 5 yen coin painted black with a Sharpie...
Kurobei!
Next Conan Special,
"Tribute to Jodie and the Flower Viewing Trap".
Next Conan's Hint:
"5 yen coins".
Next week is a one-hour special.
The FBI, the Men in Black... it's packed.