(panting heavily)
They said it wasn't
going to rain today...
Heh
(Startled with heavy breathing)
(suspense)
(confused)
Ran!
Conan-kun, Dad...
You came to pick me up.
Thank you.
Geez, it's already past nine.
Sorry, club ran late.
Here, umbrella.
Thanks, Conan-kun.
Tch...
♪~
Slicing through black shadows
and dark gloom is the light of deduction.
A string of robberies,
a chance prank, an unexpected turn.
Seeing through to the one and only truth.
A child in appearance, with the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
~♪
"Coincidences Come in Twos"
Be careful out there.
Word is there's been
some nasty business around here lately.
Yeah, that hooded
robber, right?
Let's see...
They call him the Hood Man.
He attacks women with an expandable baton
and snatches their bags, right?
Yeah, so far everyone's
gotten off with minor injuries, but...
if they don't catch him soon,
the attacks are gonna escalate...
Kyaa!
Huh?
Hm?
Ow, ow...
Hey, you okay?
The hooded guy went that way...
Got it.
Hey, mister.
Uh...
Conan-kun?
How come you're not wet?
Your clothes, mister.
Huh?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
We gotta hurry or the culprit'll...
The rain that started suddenly.
His shoes are dirty,
his pants are soaked.
And yet he's got no umbrella,
but his clothes...
aren't wet. That's weird, isn't it?
Yeah, you're right.
Ugh...
Mister, weren't you wearing
something else over that a minute ago?
Like, say...
a hooded jacket?
Damn it!
Stop right there!
Out of my way!
Hyah!
Gwaah...
Heh, yeah, figured
it'd end up like this.
Hey, you okay?
I'm fine over here.
Not you.
Hm? Oh, more importantly...
The person who screamed earlier?
Oh, this way.
Huh?
Miss, are you okay?
Ngh, ugh...
Really, you saved us, Mouri-kun.
The Hood Man's been
giving us a real headache.
Ah, all in a day's work, Inspector.
Nyahaha...
Shh, this is a hospital.
Huh? Pipe down,
I know that.
Heh, hahaha...
Well then, Inspector.
If anything else comes up,
contact me anytime. Yes.
Uh...
Thank you so much.
Excuse me.
How did it go?
She's fine. No abnormalities
on the CT or the EEG...
and the doctor says
she can go home.
Thank goodness.
Thank you so much.
- Tachibana Mizuki (25), victim.
It's all thanks to everyone.
Oh, right.
I should call my roommate.
She's probably worried.
Still, I'm glad
it was just a minor injury.
A blessing in disguise, I'd say.
(phone buzzing)
Oh.
Sorry, excuse me a second.
Yes, Sato speaking.
That's strange...
Huh? What's wrong?
Yoko, my roommate,
isn't answering the phone.
She should've gotten
off work ages ago.
Huh?
Hm?
A woman's body found
near the scene from earlier?
Yes... yes.
Mizuki-san, do you know
what this Yoko was wearing?
Huh? Let's see...
A white jacket
and a beige skirt, I think...
Tachibana-san,
is that true?
Uh... yes. Oh...
H-hey, don't tell me...
No way...
What a mess.
- Katsuragi Youko (25), Mizuki's roommate.
There's no mistake.
It's Yoko.
(crying)
This morning when we said goodbye,
she was perfectly fine...
I never thought that
would be the last time.
Yoko!
(crying)
Mizuki-san...
Ran, stay with her.
Judging by the body's condition,
she's been dead one to two hours, I'd say.
Yeah.
She worked at an apparel shop
nearby...
and it seems she was attacked
on her way home from work.
She was struck on the back
of the head with a rod-like object.
The Hood Man's known method,
the area, the time of day...
it all matches.
The cash was also taken from the victim's wallet.
He probably intended to leave her
with minor injuries like the others...
but something set him off
and he ended up killing Yoko.
Then, before the rush wore off,
he attacked Mizuki-san.
Hmm...
Who'd have thought roommates
would be attacked one after the other.
But that's what led to
the culprit's arrest.
Maybe the bond between them...
is what brought about
such a miracle.
Hm... what's this?
(sniffing)
The smell of coffee... hm?
This is...
Whoa!
This brat, snooping
around again...
Ahaha...
Huh, where's everyone going?
We're going to ask Tachibana-san
some questions down at HQ too.
We need to take her statement
about her own case as well.
I figured I'd go
along with Mizuki-san.
Oh, I wanna come too!
That's okay, right, mister?
Mm...
Heheh.
Just to confirm,
the one who attacked you...
was that man, correct?
Yes, it was definitely him.
Understood.
Hey, isn't that guy mad about something?
Ah, him...
He confessed readily
to the string of robberies, but...
he stubbornly refuses to admit
to killing Yoko-san.
He says he attacked Tachibana-san...
only because she saw his face and
he panicked, not knowing what to do...
and that he never intended to kill anyone.
Huh.
Hey, what's the meaning of this?
Tell us.
Hey, are you listening?
Detective.
No, like I said...
We're currently searching...
What's going on, Detective Takagi?
Ah, Conan-kun. Well...
So you caught him, right?
The Hood Man.
Are you ladies, by any chance...
That's right,
victims of the Hood Man.
You're going to get them back
for us, right?
Our wallets.
Mine had my license in it...
Are you really even looking?
We are searching.
Hold on a sec.
You ladies all had
your whole wallets taken?
Yes, that's right.
What's going on here?
Yoko-san, who was killed,
only had her cash taken...
and her wallet was left
behind at the scene.
Alright, Takagi-kun,
I'll leave them to you.
Right, I'll see them off properly.
Wait, Detective Sato.
Hm?
There's a thread on your skirt.
No way, ugh.
The basting thread
was still on it.
Basting thread?
On the slits of a brand-new
skirt and the like...
there's a thread called basting thread.
(snipping)
So the fabric doesn't shift...
see, like this,
the end is knotted...
and it's lightly tacked in place.
Oh...
The skirt I wore today
got torn...
so I bought this new one in a hurry.
So that's how it is.
(phone ringing)
Ah.
Yes, Mouri here.
Inspector.
What, really?
Yes, understood.
(call ending)
Did something happen?
The blood on the Hood Man's
expandable baton...
has been confirmed
to be Yoko-san's.
What?
Then that means...
Yeah, we've got
physical evidence now...
so the Hood Man's confirmed
as Yoko-san's killer too.
That's good to hear, Mizuki-san.
Yes, I'm sure Yoko is
happy up in heaven.
Phew... ate my fill.
Miss, another beer
and some fried chicken.
Come on, give it a rest.
What's the harm?
The case is solved.
I'm telling you to read
the time and place.
Mizuki-san just lost
her best friend.
Now, now, you two...
Heheh, hehe...
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yoko and I used to fight...
and chat here all the time too...
so it just brought back memories.
Mizuki-san...
But I'm glad
the culprit was caught.
It really is thanks to all of you.
Ngh, ugh...
(nose blowing)
Hey, wait, Dad.
That's my hand towel.
Yours is over there.
Huh, it is?
Geez, unbelievable.
Sorry, sorry. Here, take it back.
Ew, no way I can
use it like this.
Huh? What's the big deal?
It's basically the same thing.
Totally different.
I see... so that's how it was.
No, you mustn't, Tachibana-san.
Please, let me get this.
As a token of my thanks.
No, it'll cause problems
for us later. You understand.
Is that so?
Sorry. Well then,
I'll take you up on it.
That'll be 10,250 yen.
Huh? That added up
to quite a bit.
You... gonna be okay?
Thanks for the meal.
Sorry about that, Takagi.
Thank you so much, really.
Um, I know it's hard,
but please hang in there.
If you ever get lonely,
contact me anytime.
I'll come running.
Ow, ow, ow...
Sorry, don't worry about it.
Heheh... well then,
I'll be going.
Ngh...
Whoa, wha...
Huh?
Dad?
Mouri-san?
The pain finally
woke me up.
This case isn't over yet.
Mouri-san, what do you mean
"not over"?
The one who killed Yoko-san
wasn't the Hood Man.
What are you talking about?
The evidence just came in...
No, if he were the culprit...
there's something that doesn't add up.
Something that doesn't add up?
The cash was taken
from Yoko-san's wallet...
and the wallet itself was
left behind at the scene.
But money was
the goal, right?
No. In the previous three cases...
the culprit always stole
the entire wallet.
Why was this time
the only exception?
It's certainly odd,
but that alone...
Next, the wound on the body.
Yoko-san's wound was on
the left side of the back of her head.
Yoko-san was attacked from behind.
Which means the culprit
held the baton in their left hand...
and struck Yoko-san.
In other words,
the culprit is left-handed.
But the Hood Man...
Ah, he's right-handed.
By the way, Mizuki-san...
you made your phone call
with your left hand...
and you tried to pay
with your left hand.
Huh...
It... it's true, I'm left-handed.
But there are plenty of other
left-handed people, aren't there?
There's more.
On the white inner shirt
Yoko-san was wearing...
there was a fresh coffee stain.
But the stain stopped
at the line of the skirt...
and there was no stain
on the skirt itself.
And on that skirt,
there was basting thread.
Basting thread?
Yes, the kind that's on
brand-new skirts...
to keep the fabric
from shifting...
that basting thread.
Thinking it might be the case...
I checked with the manager
of the shop where Yoko-san worked.
Right before Yoko-san left her
workplace, the apparel shop, today...
she apparently spilled coffee...
on the clothes and skirt
she was wearing.
So she bought a new
jacket and skirt right there...
changed into them,
and left the shop.
That's why the coffee stain on
her shirt cut off partway...
and the basting thread was
still left on the skirt.
And what does that
have to do with anything?
You said this to
Yoko-san's body, didn't you?
This morning when we said goodbye,
she was perfectly fine...
I never thought that
would be the last time.
Yoko!
You only parted with her in the morning
and hadn't seen her since...
so how did you know?
The outfit Yoko-san changed
into on her way home from work.
Ah...
Mizuki-san?
I... I'm sure she was wearing
a similar color this morning.
So I just mistook it for...
Mizuki-san, the mister
says to look at this.
Ah...
This is...
What's this...
I had the manager send it to me.
That's a photo of Yoko-san
today, before she changed.
Please tell me, Mizuki-san.
How could that possibly
look like a white jacket...
and a beige skirt?
You met her, didn't you?
Yoko-san, on her way
home from work.
Ah...
But Mouri-san, that alone...
isn't enough to say Mizuki-san
killed Yoko-san, is it?
Yeah, it's true these are
all circumstantial.
Hardly conclusive.
That's awful. Treating me
like a criminal over just that...
Yoko was my best friend.
That's right, Dad.
If you're going to go that far,
you need solid proof...
Solid proof, eh?
Well, I've got it.
Right here, right now.
Huh?
Ah.
Mizuki-san, at the restaurant...
you took your wallet out of your bag
and, for some reason, put it in your pocket.
Why didn't you put it
back in your bag?
You were scared, weren't you?
That when you put the wallet away...
someone would see
what was inside your bag.
Inside your bag...
is something you can't let
us see.
Isn't that right?
I thought it was strange
from the start.
Tonight's the kind of chilly evening
you can't go without a jacket...
and yet you're dressed far too lightly.
But if you had a reason
you couldn't wear a jacket...
then your outfit makes sense.
What's in your bag is probably a jacket
splattered with Yoko-san's blood.
Huh...
What?
No, that's not all.
The expandable baton the
Hood Man originally carried...
should be in there too.
Ah...
Then the Hood Man...
what he was carrying was...
That's the very weapon Mizuki-san
used to kill Yoko-san.
Isn't that right?
First, to make it look like
the Hood Man's doing...
you examined the expandable baton
he used in the string of attacks...
bought the same type...
and killed Yoko-san
with that baton.
But on your way home,
ironically...
you were attacked
by the real Hood Man.
Unlucky, wasn't it.
But then a chance came along
to turn that misfortune into fortune.
Hey, you okay?
The hooded guy went that way...
In that moment,
you had an idea.
A way to make the most
of the accident...
of being attacked by
the real Hood Man.
I see... so you swapped
your own baton...
with the Hood Man's.
That's why Yoko-san's blood...
was on the Hood Man's baton.
Yeah, I almost got
fooled myself.
But that whole hand towel thing
gave me the hint.
The weapon, just like
the hand towels...
had been swapped somewhere
along the line.
Mizuki-san, even after
you were rescued...
Ran was with you the entire time.
You wouldn't have had any time
to dispose of the jacket or baton.
Now, please show us
what's inside that bag.
Ah...
Mizuki-san...
You see, Yoko...
was truly like the sun.
Bright, selfish...
always the center
of her own world...
And before that sun,
I was nothing but a powerless moon.
Taking advantage of that...
Yoko always took
everything from me.
My clothes, my money,
the person I loved.
Acting like it was
only natural.
And still, I endured it.
Until I heard those words.
Sorry, Mizuki's coming home soon.
Ugh, I wish that girl would just
get done in by the Hood Man or something.
She's such a pain.
Heheh, hahaha...
So I turned it around on her instead.
Made it look like
the Hood Man's doing.
(crying)
♪~
~♪
Hey, Dad.
You snuck a bite again,
didn't you? My cake.
N-no, I didn't.
Sure, it's usually me, but...
this time it really was
that thieving cat...
Huh, pinning the blame
on Goro-chan again.
(punch and Kogoro yelling)
Huh... hm?
Haha... you pulled off
a perfect crime.
(cat meowing)
Ah, so you heard that phone call.
Your collar's stretched out and your underwear's showing.
Oh, th-this is called off-the-shoulder...
I'm showing it on purpose.
Ah, kyaaa!
Drowning, huh.
Huh?
I'm placing you under emergency arrest for murder.
Huh?!
Next Conan:
"Makoto Kyogoku, A Suspect? (Part 1)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Bowling alley"
At the bowling alley...
Karate vs. Jeet Kune Do
Why there?