Stars are somehow fascinating.
Sometimes a criminal, sometimes an actor...
A strange code from the Professor.
The Detective Boys face an unexpected struggle.
Who will be the first to solve it?
See through the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
The Surprising Shrine Torii Gate Code (Part 2)
♪~♪
One hot summer day, we came to collect insects.
The Professor gave us a code quiz
indicating the location of a treasure—
called "Marumushini Tento."
Even I couldn't solve it.
Meanwhile, from Ran and Sonoko,
who were spending time at the beach—
at the hotel where they were staying—
we received word that a murder had occurred.
Sonoko said that on the window glass
of the hotel room where that man was murdered—
there were strange characters written.
Huh? Strange characters?
Yeah, like a code...
So, who found the body?
The three friends of the murdered man,
Miyama-san.
They all had a dinner appointment, but
Miyama-san didn't
show up,
so the three went to his room.
The key was left in the lock,
and when they went inside,
the window glass was broken,
and Miyama-san was collapsed beside it—
that's what they testified to the police.
After that, we...
Then, could it be—
that "Tento" in this code
means the Tento (Floating Lantern) Festival?
Even if that's it, the meaning
of "Marumushi" before it is still...
That area does have a hot spring
called Marumushi Hot Spring.
Light the Marumushi... Huh?
Does it mean turn on the light?
Hey? There are a lot of people.
Maybe there's a gathering.
No way, take a good look.
Everyone's holding a washbowl, right?
Ah, you're right.
Probably, the village bought the ruined inn
and they're using it as a public bath.
I see.
Public bath? Public bath...
Could this "Tento"—
actually mean public bath?
Um, Genta-kun,
no matter how you look at it,
this "Te" doesn't look like "Se."
And it's not about lighting either.
There's no "U" after "Tento."
Ugh.
Ah, damn it!
I don't get it anymore.
Hey, Genta, don't lie down in frustration.
I'm not frustrated.
The Professor said,
if you lie down and think carefully,
you might figure it out.
Even so...
Come to think of it, Ai-chan also said,
if you absolutely can't figure it out,
wash your face and start over.
Well, since there's a public bath,
shall we wash our faces and bodies
and refresh ourselves?
Ah... that sounds good.
It's useless.
Huh? Ai-chan.
Going to that inn is pointless.
There's nothing there.
Hey, do something about it.
Come on, Professor, just tell us.
Where is the treasure?
Please, tell us.
Well, I suppose I could tell you.
If someone gives up.
Eh?
Who would do that?
Ah.
A mail.
From Sonoko.
Huh? I thought her phone and bag
were snatched by a bag-snatcher...
Hmm?
"I found a bag on the roadside—"
"There's nothing inside
to identify the owner,"
"so for the time being,
I'm emailing the—"
"most recent recipient recorded—"
"in the cell phone that was in the bag."
"I would like to return this bag,"
"so I would appreciate it
if you could tell me your address and name."
Seems like that bag-snatcher
took the wallet and threw away the bag.
But if they're going to do that,
why not just ask for the owner's
address and name?
And why specifically email?
Check the call log—
wouldn't it be faster to call someone?
It's surrender, right?
Eh?
Ah, hey... hey, wait a minute.
More importantly, if you find a bag,
you should turn it in to the police first!
Ah... hello, Ran?
I just got an email from someone
who found Sonoko's bag,
but...
Eh, really?
Yeah. I think you'll probably get
a call or email too, so you handle it—
You handle it—
Ah, sorry.
Ah... what's wrong?
Well, my phone battery is dying.
I'm at the police station now,
but I'll call again
when I get back to the hotel.
So you said those characters
might mean "call"?
Yeah. The police and
Miyama-san's three friends
said they could understand that.
But since that message
can't identify the culprit,
we decided to go back
to the hotel for now.
Hey hey, be careful.
The bag-snatcher might
still be lurking around...
It's fine, it's fine.
Ah... This time, I asked Kanou-san
to drive me and your wife
back to the hotel.
Wife...
Wh... who's this Kanou?
You heard Ran mention him earlier,
Miyama-san's handsome friend. Handsome!
Sonoko.
It's fine, it's the truth.
The other two friends
are together too, right?
Ah... it seems like it's just Kanou-san.
The deceased Miyama-san's lover,
Yanuma-san,
is taking a long time for questioning,
and Kanou-san was just waiting
in his car for that to finish.
It seems Bito-san went back
to the hotel first.
Yanuma-san's questioning seems
like it'll take more time, so—
Kanou-san said he'd drop us
at the hotel and then come back.
Ah, I see.
Well, I'll hang up.
My battery is really dying.
Ah...
...geez.
I should have gone to the beach too.
Beach?
Speaking of the beach, Ayumi,
I found a jellyfish!
What are you saying, Ayumi-chan?
There's no way there are jellyfish
in the mountains like this.
There are! Huh?
Look, over there.
Really?
Huh? See, a jellyfish.
I... indeed.
If you turn the hot spring mark
upside down, it looks like a jellyfish.
See? Oh, it's a jellyfish!
I can see it.
If you turn the hot spring mark
upside down, it looks like a jellyfish.
I see. So that's it.
So it means lie down and wash your face.
I can't believe I
was stumped by such a simple code.
Well, sometimes these simple codes
are unexpectedly harder to solve...
Professor, isn't it fine now?
Please tell us the answer to the code.
What is "Marumushini Tento"?
Hahahaha, well...
No. I can't tell you
until everyone gives up.
Then I give up,
so secretly tell only me.
That's cheating, Genta-kun.
Why is Ran...
Hey, Conan-kun. Huh?
You still haven't solved it?
Ah... yeah, I'm completely clueless.
Then just give up already.
Conan-kun, you're being a sore loser.
You guys give up too easily.
Hahahaha.
It seems even Shinichi
hasn't solved it yet.
Anyway, let's think carefully
from the start.
First, these characters
written only in katakana.
I understand "Marumushi" and "Tento"
being in katakana,
but don't you think it's strange that
the "Ni" in between is also in katakana?
Th... that's true.
Second, if you look closely,
the balance of each character is oddly off.
You're right.
But isn't that just because
the Professor's handwriting is bad?
Hahahahaha...
And thirdly—
the hints from the Professor and Haibara.
Eh?
Did they give hints?
Yeah. Saying "think carefully
while lying down" and—
"if you don't get it, wash your face
and start over"—
are things the Professor and Haibara
don't usually say.
They're clearly hints.
Maybe it means to lie down
and look at these characters.
Ah... Okay!
So we just lie down, right?
Hmm...
Nothing different... ah!
Wh... what is it, Genta-kun?
Did you figure something out?
Ah...
Ah... ah? Ah... oh?
Oh, Genta-kun, what is it?
Ah... no, I feel like I almost got it...
"Almost"?
Be clear!
Shut up! When I laid down,
I felt like I could read it.
Whew, close, close.
No.
That hateful, smug face
with the loosening lips.
Probably, he has already...
Huh?
Hmm, even sideways,
I can't think of anything.
Yeah...
Well then, let's try the other hint.
Hmm? The other one,
the "wash your face" one?
But telling us to wash our faces
in the mountains...
Ah, could it mean to soak
in the hot water of that inn?
No way. Both Haibara and
the Professor said it:
there's nothing at that inn.
Then where are we supposed to wash?
That's right.
Beats me. Maybe it's not actually
washing your face—
but related to something
you do when washing your face.
Huh? First, turn the faucet...
Splash water on your face...
Dry your face with a towel...
...and then?
And then...
Um... Hmm.
Let's eat!
Genta-kun, we're talking
about washing your face!
After you wash your face, you eat, right?
A mirror. Huh?
After that, you look in the mirror.
A mirror? Looking at that,
all you see is your own face.
It's getting more confusing.
But I think the mirror is a good clue. Look,
like that hot spring mark,
if you turn it upside down,
it can look like
a completely different jellyfish.
Eh? Even if you turn it upside down—
it doesn't look like
a sea bream or flounder.
And I can't read the characters.
Wait a minute.
Could it be that
"lie down and wash your face" means...
turn the vertical characters sideways
and reflect them in a mirror?
Lay them sideways, flip them,
instead of reflecting them in a mirror...
Ah.
Ah...
"Mura Matsuri no Torii."
Village festival's shrine gate.
Oh? That shrine.
Right? Professor, Ai-chan.
Ding dong.
Correct! Hahahaha!
Alright! We did it!
We did it! Ahahahaha!
Let's go right away.
Okay. Yeah! The treasure!
Oh my, a self-satisfied look,
as if to say they taught the children
that they can do it if they try.
Ah, pretty handsome, right?
Hmm? Phew.
More importantly,
aren't you going to see, Shinichi?
I'm sure you want to know
what the treasure is.
I don't need to see something like that.
The location indicated by the code
is the shrine gate that's lit up at night—
that shrine's torii gate.
If they smear tree sap
on the pillars of that torii gate...
they'll come swarming.
Ah, found them!
Wow! Amazing!
Beetles and stag beetles.
Hah, that's right.
Still,
this code was well thought out.
It can be read both forwards and backwards.
It's thanks to Ai-kun.
At first, I thought about
making it an animal code.
I was thinking of various things,
like putting paper with animal names
on a windowpane.
Ai-kun, watching from outside,
said to me,
"Isn't 'Sanso' too difficult for children?"
...he said.
I see.
When you look at the characters "Kirin"
from the back, they look like "Sanso"—
and that's how I came up with the code...
Eh?
Shinichi?
Glass...
Back...
Transparent...
Wait a minute.
Th... this is...
Damn... is that it?
So that's how it was.
That's why Ran's face
crossed my mind earlier.
Ran is... Ran is in danger!
♪~ (cell phone ringing) ~♪
Ah, Shinichi? Where are you now...
I told you earlier.
We're heading back to the hotel
in Kanou-san's car.
Eh? Get out of this car right now?
I figured out the real meaning of "teiu."
Before the "t" in "teiu,"
there was actually a small dot
like a punctuation mark written.
Turn it vertically and flip it over.
The culprit's name...
Hey, Ran! Ran... Ran!
Ah... the battery died.
What did he say, dear?
Oh, Sonoko. Ah...
What does "get out of the car,
turn it vertically, and flip it over" mean?
He's not lying, is he?
Fufufu. No way...
Eh? Ran and Sonoko
are caught up in an incident?
Yeah, Sonoko saw it.
The characters written by the man
murdered in the hotel room.
Ch... characters?
They were written horizontally
in lowercase letters: "teiu."
To be precise, there was a dot
before the "t,"
the "i" was closer to an "l,"
and the "u" was closer
to the hiragana "shi."
It's the same as the village festival's
shrine gate.
If you take those horizontally written
characters, turn them vertically,
and look from the back?
It becomes "Marumushini Tento."
If you take "Sanso" vertically
and look from the back?
It becomes "Kirin."
So what about "teiu"?
Ah, that is...
It becomes "Kanou."
Ah.
Kanou?
Oh!
But why leave such a hard-to-understand—
dying message like a code?
It's not a code or anything.
The victim, lying on the floor,
wrote those characters
on the window glass from inside the room,
and Sonoko just saw them
from outside the window.
Then we need to tell Ran and the others
about this right away.
Even if we want to tell them,
Ran's phone is dead.
And on top of that, Ran and Sonoko
are in that man Kanou's car right now.
Hey, isn't this different from
the road to the hotel?
It's fine. It's a shortcut.
Hey, where is the hotel
those two are staying at?
If I knew that,
I'd contact the nearby police.
I heard they went to the beach,
but I don't know where...
Damn. I should have realized sooner.
When I received that strange email
from Sonoko's phone,
which should have been snatched,
the photo email sent to my phone
showed that dying message.
He wanted to erase it,
so he emailed me to ask
for my address and name.
Wait, that means...
Hee~
So that Shinichi-kun you mentioned
is a high school detective?
Yes, I suppose.
Amazing. Having a detective as a boyfriend.
Ah... no, he's not my boyfriend or...
They're so lovey-dovey, it's embarrassing.
That's why earlier today,
she sent him a photo mail
of her in her swimsuit.
Hey, Sonoko.
Fufufu.
But that's too bad.
Shinichi-kun isn't here, is he?
I wanted to meet that famous detective.
Sonoko... Right about now,
he's probably rubbing his cheek
against that photo mail, isn't he?
♪~ (cell phone ringing) ~♪
If the culprit is waiting
for me to contact him,
he should be carrying Sonoko's phone
with the power on.
Please realize it. That man is the murderer.
♪~ (cell phone ringing) ~♪
Huh? That ringtone
is the same as Sonoko's phone.
Come to think of it, that's my...
You're right.
Huh? But... why?
Heh. That's right.
Because I snatched it from you earlier.
Eh?
To erase the evidence of the murder.
Ehh?
Now, let's go further in
and have a nice, long talk.
And also about where that kid Shinichi is.
Still not connecting?
♪~ (phone ringing) ~♪
Just be quiet.
Ah, well...
(Connection sound)
Connected.
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
♪~♪
Don't "hello" me.
What were you doing
while Ran was in danger?
Hey, are you listening? You...
Ah, no, what do you mean...
We had a hard time over here
when the car crashed into a tree!
Huh? The car hit a tree? Why?
What do you mean, why? We had no choice.
Ran's side kick exploded
right in the face of the murderer
who was driving!
Ah... I see.
After that, the police Sonoko called arrived,
and the culprit was apprehended.
The motive for the murder was that
his friends found out he bought his way
into university and threatened him.
To cover up his crime,
he committed an even greater crime—
a classic pattern.
And...
Huh?
I thought I saved it here...
Hmm? Oh.
I deleted that woman's swimsuit photo.
Huh... huh? Why?
Why? Because it's against the law.
Sorry. I asked Ai-chan to delete it.
Ha... Haibara?
(Yawn)
You little...
Damn!
Next Conan's Hint: "The two cups"
What's the title of the next episode?
It's half of the complete,
so if eel over rice is used as an analogy...
Huh?