What? Ran, you're the
strongest in the karate club?
That's right, Yasuko.
She can send the boys
flying with one kick.
Wait... hold on, Yayoi.
That's going too far.
Wow, a real karate master.
- Yasuko Kawakami (25), sharehouse resident / office lady.
No, not really.
As a fellow member of the karate club...
- Yayoi Yajima (21), sharehouse resident / university student
I'm so proud.
Oh no, look at the time.
I need to take my bath.
Then I should be going too...
Aw, you came all this way
to visit...
Stay a little longer.
Someone's picking you up, right?
Yes, well...
Then it's fine. We finally
got to know each other.
That's right.
I'm home.
Oh, welcome back, Suzuki.
I'm back.
This is my junior from school,
Ran Mouri.
Sorry to intrude.
Hello, I'm Suzuki.
- Hidehisa Suzuki (26), sharehouse resident / company employee.
Oh, Suzuki, would you
like some cake too?
You sure? I'm the peeping tom,
you know.
What?
Nobody believes that, you know.
It's best 15 minutes out of the
fridge, so wait a little.
(Katsuko Kanou) I'm home.
Welcome back.
Oh, Suzuki, you're still here?
- Katsuko Kano (25), sharehouse resident / dancer.
Didn't the landlord
tell you something?
To get out, and soon?
You're the one who lied.
Saying I was a peeping tom.
Because it's easier in
lots of ways with just us girls.
Don't be ridiculous.
We have a guest, you know.
Please stop, Katsuko.
Oh, Yayoi, dear.
You're one to talk to me?
Well, never mind.
I need to practice my
tap dancing before my bath.
Um, Katsuko...
What?
I've said it before, but could you
ease up on the tap practice?
My room is right below yours,
remember? So...
Oh, there's cake.
You like it, don't you, Katsuko?
Oh, buttering me up?
No, it's not that...
I'll have some later, then.
(door opens and closes)
Phew. Well then...
- I'm off to the bath.
- Okay.
I'm sorry, Ran. You had to
see us at our worst.
Oh... no.
Hm?
Oh, it's fine.
Suzuki would never
do any peeping.
Katsuko just spread that
rumor on her own.
Enough about that.
I'll settle things with
that woman properly later.
Thanks for the cake.
I'll eat it in my room.
- Take it easy, then.
-  Oh, thanks.
A refreshing autumn breeze blows through
the gaiety of summer for a stylish and dashing display
of deduction.
A shocking case in a shared house...
What is this calculated alibi trick?
Seeing through the one and only truth.
Looks like a child but has the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"The Blind Spot in the Share House"
There's a lot to it,
share houses too.
When I first came here,
I thought it was so stylish.
Even the door to this common space
is made of glass.
And there are potted
plants set out.
It's been renovated so anyone can
come in here without hesitation.
Well, we are living with
complete strangers.
So there's plenty of stress too.
And there are all kinds of rules.
- Rules?
- Yes.
Take a look at the back
of the chair.
Oh.
Like putting name stickers
on your own belongings.
It's true.
(door slides open)
Ah, that was a nice bath.
- Well, I'll go in now.
- Okay.
So, what were you two talking about?
Gossip about you, Yayoi. Like how you
always forget to take out the trash.
Ha, I just slip up sometimes.
I hear there are set times for
cleaning duty and baths too.
And even a message board.
Sounds tough.
Yeah, but compared to the going rate,
the rent here is really cheap.
So nobody wants to leave.
Huh.
(phone ringing)
Ah, Yasuko?
Katsuko's cake?
Yes, yes.
If she doesn't come within 15 minutes,
I'll put it back.
(ticking of a clock)
Yayoi, let me help you.
It's fine, just the dishes.
You're a guest.
- Huh?
- Is something wrong?
No, nothing.
Um, did something happen
with that Katsuko person?
She never came for the cake,
Katsuko.
(ticking of a clock)
I owe that woman money.
- Money?
- Yeah.
I see.
Since your father suddenly passed away...
And my little brother's still in
middle school, so it costs money.
I can't ask them to send
me much from home.
But it's okay.
For now, I'm getting by with
scholarships and part-time work.
Oh...
(door slides open)
Oh... Katsuko never came.
Really? That woman...
So selfish.
(doorbell)
Oh, could that be...
Your ride. Coming.
(Kogoro Mouri)
Sorry to trouble you.
Keeping her out this late.
Ran, let's go home.
Yayoi, Yasuko,
thank you so much.
- Come visit again.
- Okay.
Aaah!
What's wrong? What happened?
Suzuki?
Inside... Ka... Katsuko is...
(three people screaming)
(Wataru Takagi)
The victim is Katsuko Kanou, 25.
The weapon is the knife found at the
scene, no doubt about it...
but there were no fingerprints on it.
The estimated time of death is
between 7:15 and 7:45 PM.
And on the floor at the scene...
from the contents of a plastic
bottle that had rolled there...
sleeping pills were detected.
I see. So she was
stabbed after being knocked out.
Now, Suzuki, you found the body.
Tell us how it happened.
Oh, yes.
This morning, Katsuko left a
message for me...
on that message board over there.
"Tonight before 8, I'll come
to your room."
"Let's settle things," it said.
Hm? There's nothing
written there at all.
Did anyone else
see this message?
It said, "Keep it a secret."
So I erased it myself.
And I'm always the last...
one to leave the house, so
Katsuko probably...
waited until I'd be...
- alone before writing it.
- And then?
Just like the message said, I waited
in my room the whole time. But...
even past 8, Katsuko
didn't come...
so I went to her room...
and Katsuko was on the bed...
I see.
It's true. Please believe me.
No... that's wrong.
I didn't do it.
That's right.
Yayoi, Yasuko.
Oh, do you two have some
idea about this?
The truth is, Katsuko and Suzuki
have been fighting nonstop lately.
Tonight too, before they went to their
rooms, they got into a bit of an argument.
- Ran, is that true?
- Yeah.
It's not just me.
Yasuko and Yayoi...
both hated Katsuko too.
Please wait.
I don't think those two
are connected to this.
Ran, how do you know that?
Between 7 and 8, were those two
in the bath right on schedule?
They were here with me.
On schedule?
- It's all set.
- Huh?
The bath times.
It's a share house, after all.
Right. And aside from getting
up once for the bathroom...
I was sitting here the whole time.
From here, you can see the
hallway through the glass door.
A sliding glass door.
You can see right through it.
To get from the bath
to the second floor...
you absolutely have to pass
through that hallway.
During the time Yasuko
was in the bath...
nobody passed by, I'm sure of it.
I see. So both of them
have alibis.
Now, Suzuki, I'm sorry, but
at the scene on the second floor...
could you explain once more...
- the situation when you found her?
- Yes.
"Write your name on
personal items," huh...
Come to think of it, the bottle at the
scene had a name on it too.
- Want something to drink?
- Oh... no, I'm fine.
Don't be shy.
Hey, was that cake Katsuko's?
That's right. I took it out of the
fridge and got it ready.
Yasuko called from the bath...
since she was undressed.
But in the end she never
came to eat it, Katsuko.
So I put it back in the fridge.
It's best 15 minutes out
of the fridge.
I wanted her to eat it when
it was tastiest.
I see.
Something wrong, Conan?
Oh, no.
Was there anything else strange?
Anything strange?
Oh, now that I mention it...
Yayoi, when you were
doing the dishes...
- you tilted your head, didn't you?
- Hm?
Yayoi, let me help.
It's fine, just the dishes.
You're a guest.
Huh?
Ah, normally when someone's
in the bath...
the water pressure gets weaker, but at
that time it was running normally.
Oh, the bath was that way, right?
Hey, wait, Conan.
Oh, here too.
A wiped spot and a footprint.
What's the matter?
Hey, what's this?
Huh? Oh, no, that's shampoo.
When I refilled it with a new one today,
I spilled some.
I thought I'd wiped it up nicely,
but I guess I missed a spot.
The window.
You can see the
dining room clearly.
Which means, doing it this way... hm?
Why is just this spot white?
There, a picture used to
hang there...
but the landlord took it down
and carried it off yesterday.
This is...
Inspector Megure.
Come here, quickly.
From inside Suzuki's
shoe cubby...
this towel was found.
I see, so that's how it was.
The culprit is Suzuki,
just as I thought. It's you.
You and Katsuko were
on bad terms to begin with.
And tonight's fight pushed it over the
edge, so you killed Katsuko upstairs.
At that time, you wrapped the
knife handle in this towel...
so no fingerprints
would be left.
You hid this away, planning
to dispose of it later.
- That settles it, Inspector.
- Yes.
Hidehisa Suzuki, would you accompany us
to the station as a person of interest?
It wasn't me. I didn't do it...
That's wrong.
This man is not the culprit.
The culprit is one of these two...
Oh.
So that's how it is.
Ugh, ha-nyo, ha-hii-fuu...
Please wait, everyone.
M... Mr. Mouri? Could it be?
It's too early to declare
Suzuki the culprit...
just yet.
B... but Mouri, just now you...
I'm truly ashamed
of myself.
One look at Suzuki and
it should've been obvious.
Recall the scene of the murder.
Katsuko died with her
artery severed...
and blood was splattered
all around the area.
And yet, take a look.
Suzuki's sweatshirt
is pure white.
Could the culprit possibly
have avoided getting any blood on them?
What if he changed clothes and then
pretended to find the body?
If that were the case...
those clothes would have
already been found.
He'd have had no time
to go dispose of them.
You're... right.
Then who is the culprit...
The culprit's actions
were these.
First, pretending to be Katsuko...
they wrote a message addressed
to Suzuki on the message board.
To pin Suzuki down in his own
room at the time of the crime...
and strip him of an alibi.
Then, at the time of the murder...
the culprit slipped out of the
bath and went to the second floor.
Hold on a moment, Mouri.
By Ran's testimony, no one passed
through the hallway at the time of the crime.
- Conan.
- Yes.
Detective Takagi, in front
of that door...
there's a large potted
plant, right?
Look at the floor underneath.
There's a mark where it was moved.
Ah.
Just like that mark...
move it a little toward the door.
Ugh, like this?
Then step out into the hallway...
and close the door for me?
Got it.
Now, Ran, go over
to the fridge...
and when I give the signal,
open the fridge door.
Okay, got it.
Everyone, come over here.
Watch Detective Takagi closely.
All right, Ran, open
the fridge door.
Okay.
Th... this is...
How about it?
From where Ran was sitting,
Detective Takagi disappeared from view.
I heard from Conan that around
the time of the crime...
the fridge door was opened twice.
To take out and put back
Katsuko's cake.
Before the crime, the culprit
shifted that potted plant...
while Ran was away
in the bathroom.
And then quietly
slipped out of the bath.
There's proof of that too.
In the changing room...
the culprit stepped in
the spilled shampoo.
Those traces were left
in the hallway.
Then, in the brief moment the
fridge door was opened...
the culprit headed for
Katsuko's room.
There, Katsuko, who'd been
given sleeping pills...
was fast asleep.
The culprit crept in and...
After the crime, the culprit put the
bloody towel in Suzuki's shoe cubby...
then, the next moment the cake was
being returned to the fridge...
After that, they just had to
return the pot when no one was looking.
Wait, Dad.
Then I was...
Ran, you...
were used to create the alibi.
The guest always sits there.
Wait. I'm the one who
opened the fridge.
Which means... the culprit
is Yasuko?
I'm the culprit? That's absurd.
You're wrong.
Huh? Miss, isn't your
shoulder injured?
There's blood
seeping through.
That's the very...
proof that you went
up to the second floor.
Take a look.
At that window facing
the staircase.
Though it's up high, when committing
the crime, Yasuko...
didn't want to be seen.
So she crouched down, passed by smoothly,
and when she tried to stand back up...
(snagging sound)
Yes. On the wall past
the window...
exactly at shoulder height,
a nail was sticking out.
Please wait. You...
said Suzuki had no
blood spatter on him, right?
But there's no blood of Katsuko's
on my clothes either, is there?
The moment I saw that wound,
I understood right away.
The nail injured your body...
but that T-shirt isn't torn.
The clothes you wore before this
probably weren't torn either.
What does this mean?
After going to the bath, you
stripped off all your clothes...
and killed Katsuko
while completely naked.
(panting)
In that case, the blood spatter...
you wiped off roughly with the towel
you used to hold the knife...
then, being careful not to leave any
traces on the floor, returned to the bath...
and just washed it all
off in the shower.
You're wrong. I...
In that case...
shall we have the bath's
drainpipe examined?
Katsuko's blood is surely
going to be detected.
Ah... ah...
Aaah.
Yasuko, why?
Click, click, click, click...
it kept echoing down.
From right above me, every night,
every night, the sound of her tap shoes.
No matter how many times I asked,
she wouldn't stop.
I just couldn't take it anymore.
Over something like that...
She said it to me.
"You know, it actually
feels really good."
"Like I'm stomping on you
from right over your head."
"So just put up with it."
"A third-rate, unremarkable
woman like you..."
"that's about all you're
ever good for to me."
(Yasuko sobbing)
♪~
~♪
Hey, hey, Dad.
I just thought of
a great idea.
Huh?
Let's make our place a share house too.
It'd help the budget.
What nonsense are you...
I see. And here we have a...
beautiful career woman who
earns a great living.
Hm?
What a shame, what a shame.
(clears throat)
Well, if it helps the
budget even a little...
Really? Yes!
Then I'll go post this in
the empty room.
Hm?
This way the family can
live together again.
I have to call Mom.
H... hey, Ran, stop. Give me that.
Oh, hello, Mom?
Wait.
Hahaha... wait, hold on.
Ms. Kisaki's cooking is...
Aaah, wait, wait.
Ran, please, wait.
Huh?
Here, a printed-out photo. Good luck.
Right. That was 15 years ago.
At another rental cabin
near here...
When the officers rushed in
after hearing the commotion...
Red...
Inside the bathtub.
Next Conan,
"The Tragedy of the Red Woman (Bath Steam)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Tomato".
- Greengrocer.
- Woodpecker.
Newspaper.
Conan's a weird kid.
Wha...