Parfait, parfait!
I'm absolutely sure it's going to be
the Tropical Strawberry Parfait!
No way, I've got a feeling today's gonna be
that gorgeous strawberry chiffon cake!
And now, the announcement.
The winner of tonight's strawberry battle is...
The one who made the Tropical Strawberry Parfait,
Patissier Shuhei Kurimura!
(Crowd cheers) He successfully defends his title as champion!
Wow! Oh man...
I really thought the champion was gonna lose today.
It's amazing. That's six weeks in a row now!
We'll see you again next week
on "Which Sweet Will Show"!
Phew...
Hey, delinquent girl.
Don't you have to go home? It's almost 8 o'clock.
Tch.
I'm just scoping it out. I'm coming as an audience member
with Ran next week.
Hmph.
Oh, right. My dad's got connections. You wanna come too, Uncle?
Who'd want to go to some saccharine, lazy excuse for a food show...
Oh? Too bad. I heard Yoko Okino's gonna be
a guest judge.
I'll be going, Lady Sonoko!
Heheheh.
This old man's so easy...
So then, would you be so kind as to escort us
in your rental car that day, Uncle?
Hmph. As you wish.
Heheheh. But what about the other person?
We've got invitations for five people.
And my mom said she has to work...
Oh, then how about...
Hmm?
♪~♪
The black of shadow, the depth of darkness—
the light of deduction tears right through them.
An impossible crime during the recording.
The mystery hidden inside the fruit box.
He sees through the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~♪
"A Treasure Box Full of Fruits (Part 1)"
Huh? You mean I can go too?
Yeah, Conan-kun insisted.
Is... is that so?
Uh... yeah.
Well, if you're inviting me, I can't say no.
There's something I wanna ask her anyway.
Well, we just have to make sure we don't stand out too much
and catch the eye of the judge,
Mr. Takegi.
Mr. Takegi?
You don't know him?
He's a giant in Japan's patisserie world.
The Legend of Sweets, Shoutoku Takegi.
So what happens if he does notice you?
In the middle of the show,
Mr. Takegi picks someone from the audience
to do a taste test.
If you guess the fruit used correctly,
you get to eat the winning sweets
from that round.
But if you get it wrong,
they kick you out of the studio immediately.
Is this Takegi guy really that strict?
Yeah. I mean, the current champion's been winning
for six weeks straight,
but Mr. Takegi's scores are always harsh.
Well, the challenger's scores are even lower.
Oh, come to think of it,
I heard that champion Kurimura's shop
is opening another branch.
I wish he'd open one in Beika Town too.
But don't you think
that champion's kind of suspicious?
I mean, yesterday he just happened
to bring ice cream and jelly that go with strawberries,
the theme fruit.
What are you saying?
That the champion's cheating?
I don't think that's it.
Even the TV staff don't know
what the theme fruit is until the box is opened.
The box is that old-fashioned iron box
they open at the start of the show, right?
Any TV staffer could just
sneak a peek, no?
That's the thing—they made it so you can't.
Each time, this fruit selection expert
packs the box full of the theme fruit.
After packing it,
they lock the box and send it to the TV station.
The producer who receives it puts a different lock on it and sends it back to the expert.
The expert opens his own lock,
sends it back to the TV station again,
and at the start of the show,
the host, who gets the key from the producer, opens the box.
That's the first time anyone finds out
what the theme fruit is.
I see.
It's an old code.
A code?
Back when communication devices
weren't as advanced,
that's how people exchanged secret documents.
With this method,
only the people with the keys
can see the contents.
Oh, right!
So even the people transporting it
can't sneak a peek
even if they wanted to.
So how do we avoid standing out?
How do we not get noticed?
There are a lot of women in the audience...
Why don't you try wearing something more girly?
Girly?
Well, the one who'll stand out the most
is that mustached old man anyway.
Oh, Mr. Takegi.
If you're asking about the fruit for tomorrow's show,
I've already finished packing them.
Oh?
We've brought in choice fruit
from all over the country again this time,
so rest assured.
Well then, let me confirm.
Ah, no.
Even you, Mr. Takegi,
can't see the contents.
That's what we agreed, isn't it?
Don't worry.
It's not the contents I want to see.
It's the key.
Hmm... seems it's properly locked.
Of course.
I trust no one saw you packing the fruit?
Yes. As always, I packed it alone
in this storeroom.
As camouflage, I also brought in
fruit boxes meant for restaurants and other businesses,
so even the delivery services had no idea.
If that's the case,
it could only leak from your mouth.
Oh, has the forbidden fruit box arrived?
-- Then hurry up and lock it and send it back, Furuya-chan.
Oh, right.
The padlock is in my desk as usual.
No matter what, don't you dare try to peek inside.
Okay?
Mr. Takegi just gave me an earful
before the last recording.
No can do.
It's already locked with another key.
Oh, right.
They're still doing that tedious method?
Then why doesn't Takegi just pack the fruit himself
and lock it?
He says he wants to be surprised too,
seeing the ingredients during the show.
Well, he's getting old.
Actually,
we've already got someone lined up to replace him.
How about it?
I look a bit more girlish, don't I?
Um...
What part of you is different from usual?
I'm wearing cute flower-patterned underwear.
It was a little embarrassing, though.
What's the point if no one can see it?
Anyway, where's Yoko? She's not here.
If she's a judge,
isn't she waiting in another room
for the sweets to be brought in?
Huh?
Don't worry,
she'll be on that monitor.
Then it's no different from watching TV at home!
Um...
Ah, sorry. We'll be quiet.
Excuse me,
but aren't you the famous detective,
Kogoro Mouri?
Uh... yes.
There's something I'd like to discuss with you.
Yes?
We'll start recording now!
Five seconds to air!
Four, three...
Welcome to my Cooking Arena!
Please enjoy this sweet evening.
Before announcing tonight's fruit,
I'd like to introduce two guests
we've invited to the arena.
Returning for her second appearance...
Yoko Okino!
Ms. Yoko Okino!
And the other guest is...
the famous detective...
The great Kogoro Mouri!
This turned into a big deal.
He's subbing for Mr. Takegi,
but he doesn't seem nervous at all.
Go get 'em, Dad!
Hmm?
Nah, the ones who need to do their best
are the chefs.
Detective Mouri, do you eat a lot of sweets?
Yes! I have a weakness for sweet things.
Oh, really?
So your wife makes sweets for you often?
My wife?
No way. Her stuff's not even edible.
Mom was really looking forward to this show.
Just don't show it to her.
It's not live anyway.
Hey...
Is it true that Takegi's gone missing?
Yeah. The staff said
they can't get in touch with him at all.
He hasn't come to the studio,
or even to the TV station.
Ah, look, they're opening the box.
Now then,
challenger, Patissier Kuria Enokido,
and champion, Patissier Shuhei Kurimura.
We will announce the fruit
for tonight's battle!
We will use the key
that Producer Taruoka
has kept in the Tohto Bank
safety deposit box as always...
to open this forbidden fruit box!
A padlock like that,
anyone light-fingered
could probably pry it open easily.
But despite how it looks,
it's actually a special lock
with an electronic chip embedded.
If you try to pry it
and stick something in the keyhole,
a buzzer goes off.
I heard you can't easily make a spare key either.
Well, I guess for Kid-sama,
it'd be child's play.
Sera...
I have something to ask you later.
What? Just ask me now.
Okay, then...
Let me show you!
Today's fruit is...
Sera... are you...
like me...
No way.
Isn't that the judge, Mr. Takegi?
Hey, Conan!
You stay here.
From here on,
it's our territory.
"Us"?
Hey, kid.
No good.
He's already cold.
Looks that way.
Cause of death
is probably this wound on the back of his head.
Judging from rigor mortis,
he's been dead for over half a day.
Huh?
On the edge of the box,
there are traces of blood wiped off.
And these marks...
They're on the inside too.
That means...
He hit his head on the box
when the lid was open and died,
and was packed into the box
with the apples.
Is Mr. Takegi really dead?
Yeah. Call the police right away.
And you should have the audience
wait in another room too.
They might have seen something.
Then...
let's have Detective Mouri, who's in another room,
come here too.
That'd be better, right, Conan?
You know him?
That's Kenzaki-san. He plays Detective Samonji.
We worked together on a case before.
Oh, that goofy detective.
Goofy?
I see.
So inside this box,
which held the fruit for the cooking competition,
was the body of the head judge,
Mr. Takegi.
We couldn't reach Mr. Takegi for a while,
but I never thought he'd be inside the box.
You started the recording
without the head judge?
I happened to be in the audience,
and they chose me as his substitute, Inspector.
Why you?
You're not even a food connoisseur.
I asked the producer to do me a favor.
Since I heard that the recording deadline was approaching,
I thought Mr. Mouri would come forth.
I knew he was going to be at the studio
through the text mail.
Mr. Kenzaki also said that if it were Mr. Mouri,
he would have it easy too,
because he is also an acquaintance.
Isn't that right, Producer Taruoka?
Yeah.
I thought that if it were the great detective Mouri,
it would settle in nicely as part of the program, you see.
But, is that rumor about the box keys true?
That they use two locks?
Yes.
First of all,
the food coordinator Mr. Kasuga
packs the box with the fruit
that is the theme for the day.
He locks it with a padlock
and sends it to Nichiuri TV.
Then after I receive that box,
I lock it with a different padlock
and send it back to Mr. Kasuga's residence.
Then again Mr. Kasuga unlocks the padlock
that he had used at his residence,
and sends it back once again to the TV station.
The MC Kenzaki, at the beginning of the show,
uses the key that he receives from me
to open my padlock.
Here for the first time,
everybody finds out what the theme fruit is.
Well, this method is one that Mr. Takegi had proposed
to make sure that the fruit inside the box
would not be leaked beforehand.
Which means...
that the one who could've put the corpse into the box
would be Mr. Kasuga who first locked the box,
or you, who had the last key.
No way...
I do give the key to the MC,
but I do it while the program is being aired, you know?
Until then, the key is stored
in the safety deposit box of Tohto Bank,
and is not in my hands.
The padlock is kept in the drawer of my desk,
and the assistant director (AD) locks the drawer.
Who is that assistant director?
Mr. Furuya right there.
He always locks the drawer
and is also in charge of taking care of the box.
Which means that he's the one who carries it around too?
Although I do take care of the box,
it's not like I watch it 24/7.
Carrying the box around is left to the young assistant directors.
I just accompany them.
Well, there are times that I go alone
to the storage room where the box is kept
to check whether the lock had been pried open or not.
Then if at that time,
you sniff the box carefully, wouldn't you be able to tell what's inside the box?
No way!
Because to fill the space between the lid and the box,
a rubber packing like the ones used for refrigerators is attached.
Then the only one left would be Mr. Kasuga,
the first one to lock the box.
Come to think of it,
last night another staff member said that
Mr. Takegi asked for Mr. Kasuga's address.
Then, maybe he went to Mr. Kasuga's home.
Yes.
It's true that Mr. Takegi came over
to my house last night.
Just after I finished packing the box.
Before the staff came to pick up the box.
Mr. Kasuga, what brings you here?
I came because Mr. Takegi called me.
He said that he was going to nab the perp who is leaking information about the contents of the box.
He said that he'd expose the perp while the program is being aired,
so to come and watch.
Then, Mr. Takegi went to your house to...
To check the padlock that I locked
and to make sure that I wasn't doing anything
I wasn't supposed to do.
After all, I'm the only one who knows what's in the box.
He seems to have suspected me
for leaking information about the contents.
And, what did Mr. Takegi do after that?
He left as soon as the staff came
to pick up the box.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
No doubt about it
because two young assistant directors were watching.
Hey...
There's no time to put the corpse in the box then.
Moreover, what bothers me more
is Mr. Takegi's actions.
Why was he going that far to check the box?
Yeah. It sounds like he already knew that
the contents of the box was being leaked outside.
Maybe he just thought it was being leaked
to Mr. Kurimura, the champion,
who won for six consecutive weeks?
Huh?
It seems that he always brought ingredients
that went along well with the theme fruit.
So, maybe he suspected
that Kurimura knew the contents of the box.
Is... is that so?
Yes.
At the start Mr. Takegi used to say,
luck was also a talent.
What bothers me even more
is that Mr. Takegi didn't come to this studio,
much less the TV station.
Really?
I know that after the arrangement meeting,
he left the TV station.
If so, where on earth was the corpse
put into the box?
Inspector Megure!
Huh?
It seems that last night Mr. Takegi
secretly came to the TV station
and mingled among the extras of a samurai show.
What?
The director of the samurai show knew Mr. Takegi
who asked him to do a favor.
Saying something to the effect that
he wanted to catch his enemy off guard.
I see.
He wanted to make it look
as if he wasn't at the TV station
and wanted to try catching the perp in the act.
Mr. Takegi always wore a kimono,
so it probably would've been easy for him
to mingle among the extras.
If so...
It's very likely that Mr. Takegi was hiding
in the storeroom where the box was stored,
ambushing the perp.
Why?
There were traces of blood being wiped off
by the area where the lid and box match.
That means that the box
was at the scene of the crime, no?
True.
I see.
That's where Mr. Takegi was killed.
By the perp...
Who secretly opened the box.
♪~♪
So we've narrowed the suspects down to three.
But who's the culprit?
First off, how they opened the lock is a mystery.
Ah.
I see. So that's it.
Then we should get started soon.
Huh? Get started with what?
What? A little...
magic show.
Next Conan...
"A Treasure Box Full of Fruits (Part 2)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"apples"
We're stumped.
Is it because of the apples?
We're up to our apples... I mean, hands.