Whoa, that's awesome!
Poirot really made it into the magazine!
That's right.
A reporter came by the other day and
said we'd be in a book,
but I never imagined we'd get
such a big feature.
You're in it too, Azusa-san.
Look, right here.
"With this shop's regular customer,
the calico cat Taii-kun..."
"and the beautiful waitress Azusa-san."
It's true! She's holding Dai-chan.
Oh come on, "beautiful"
is laying it on too thick.
These things tend to be written
a bit over the top.
R-Right.
How come Amuro-niichan isn't in it?
Ah, I happened to be off sick that day.
That's a real shame.
And you're so handsome too.
Well, a man dressed all in black
wouldn't go showing his face...
in some lightweight gourmet
magazine, now would he?
More importantly, weren't there
one more of you kids?
Ai-chan already went home.
We invited her to come to Poirot
with us to see the cat,
but she said...
that she suddenly remembered
she had something to do.
N-Now that you mention it,
where's the cat?
Did he already come by
for his food?
No, actually...
Since last week, Taii-kun has
become my house cat.
Huh?
Are you sure that's okay?
Taii is a stray, but he was
wearing a collar,
so wasn't he someone's
pet originally?
Well, the other day he got into
a fight with a neighborhood cat,
and showed up covered in wounds,
so I got worried.
And besides, his photo
ended up in the magazine.
If his owner is really
looking for him...
I figured they'd see the article
and come forward.
But still, Dai-chan, keeping him all
to yourself isn't fair!
Besides, there's no way an owner would
turn up from such a tiny photo.
Unless it was going around online,
that'd be different.
That's what you'd think, right?
But guess what...
- Excuse me.
- Hm?
Is this the place from the magazine,
the shop called Poirot?
Oh, yes.
It said in the article, right?
That come evening, there's a stray
cat that shows up...
begging for food.
- With a photo and all.
- Yes.
Truth is, that's my cat.
- Shogo Amezawa (36), Freeter.
I've been searching for him
for about half a year.
- Huh?
- H-Hey.
What are you talking about?
That's without a doubt my house cat.
- Teishi Masuko (56), company president.
Don't go spouting nonsense.
Huh?
Amazing! An owner actually
showed up!
A-And two of them, no less!
A-Actually, it's not two.
There's one more person inside the shop right now.
Huh?
A refreshing autumn breeze blows through
The gaiety of summer for a stylish and dashing display of deduction.
Three owners came forward?
Kogoro and Bourbon, a deduction tag-team.
Seeing through to the
one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"Lucky Calico Cat Case (Part 1)"
Honestly, don't make me say it over and over.
This cat belongs to my granddaughter,
- Mutsumi Shagawa (61), housewife.
her pet cat, Mugi-chan.
Where's Mugi-chan?
Weren't you going to bring her here?
O-Oh, yes.
I stepped outside to go fetch her,
but while I was talking
with these children...
these people showed up saying
they were the owners.
No, the real owner is me...
Wrong! I keep telling you, it's me!
Are you people trying to steal
my granddaughter's cat?
Amazing! Dai-chan's super popular.
But why all three of them?
He's just an ordinary calico cat
you'd find anywhere.
That's the thing, he isn't
ordinary.
Huh?
He's certainly a clever cat,
I'll give you that.
When he got trapped in that
shady delivery truck,
he delivered Conan-kun's
message here, after all.
Dai-chan really saved the day
back then.
But even though he delivered it,
the wind blew it away, right?
Y-Yeah.
Anyways Azusa-san, head back home...
- and bring Taii here.
- O-Okay.
While we wait, let's hear out
these three individually.
- With a mystery-solving expert joining us.
- Huh?
A mystery-solving expert... don't tell me...
What? Searching for a cat's owner?
Do that somewhere else. I'm busy right now.
Honestly...
(cat meows)
- Goro-chan?
- Why's it here?
Isn't this that scary lady's cat?
"Scary lady"...
Mom's away in Fukuoka for work,
so she told me to look after him
just for tonight.
Huh.
Go home, go home.
It's not like anyone's going
to pay me a fee, right?
Then I'll hire you.
For the fee, premier seat tickets to...
Yoko Okino's summer live concert.
What?!
Now then, the first owner is...
- Shagawa-san, you're a housewife?
- Yes.
This old man is really easy to win over.
So, when did the cat disappear?
About two months ago.
We were going on a family trip,
so we left him with an acquaintance,
but the moment they took their eyes
off him, he apparently vanished.
This is a photo of the cat's owner,
my granddaughter.
It was taken five years ago.
I see. He's still a kitten here,
but the pattern of the markings
does look similar.
Right? You think so too,
don't you, detective?
Sure.
So, do you like cats too, ma'am?
Yes, of course.
Come here, come here.
Come on.
(cat meows)
My, what a shy cat.
He seems to really like you, sir.
He's not my cat, though.
The calico in question had marks
from a neutering surgery.
Ah, that was such an ordeal.
He stayed overnight at the clinic
and came back,
but the bandages just wouldn't come off.
It took about a week before
the stitches came out.
Masuko-san, IT company president.
You'd be the second candidate owner,
so when did the cat go missing?
Exactly four months ago, during my move.
My wife of 30 years passed away,
so I decided to sell the house
and move into a condominium.
I'm sure I put him in a carrier and
loaded him onto the moving truck,
but when it was time to unload...
- he was gone from the carrier.
- Hoh.
Do you have a photo or anything?
I have one I took on my phone.
The one with the cat is my wife.
I took the picture.
Well now, this is the spitting
image of Poirot's cat.
Of course it is.
Because it's the same cat.
So, do you like cats too, mister?
- Yeah.
- Want to try holding him?
(sneezes)
Hm? Do you have a cold?
A-Ah, m-maybe so.
By the way, did your cat get neutered?
Yes, but I left that sort of thing
to my wife, so I'm not sure of the details.
But I do remember that even after
the surgery, he didn't wear bandages.
For some reason he had something
like a satellite dish...
attached around his neck.
That much I recall.
Like I said, if you'd just
let me meet the cat...
I'd know right away,
that's what I'm telling you.
That I'm the owner.
Well, let me hear you out first.
Amesawa-san, the freelancer.
When did he go missing?
About half a year ago.
I love freedom, so I let
my cat roam free too.
Then one day, he just
stopped coming home.
Do you have any photos?
No way I'd take any,
when I let him roam free.
So, you like cats too, right, mister?
Yeah, naturally.
- Come here.
- (cat meows)
No way! Goro's actually
pretty shy around people.
Guess I've just got the kind of
body animals take a liking to.
So, do you remember the cat
getting neutered?
Well, I got him after he'd already...
gotten pretty big, so I'm not sure.
By the way, about that calico cat...
he was written up as "Taii-kun,"
but it's a female cat.
Huh? A-Ah, well, in that case
maybe it's not mine.
- What are you saying?
- Taii's a male!
- He had a pair down there!
- Oh, was that right?
D-Don't scare me like that.
Of course it's a male.
(cat meows)
Hmm...
So in the end, which of those
three was the owner?
Gotta be that guy, right?
Goro was super attached to him too.
But the photo on the mister's phone
looked exactly like Taii.
Yeah, but he himself wasn't in the photo.
Then what about the photo the lady showed us?
But that was a photo from
when he was a kitten.
Conan-kun, did you come up with something?
Not quite yet.
- (horse racing broadcast)
- Hm? There it is, go!
Turn the volume down!
We're all trying to think here.
Sound?
That's right! Let's tell Ai-chan too.
Huh, three owners for Dai-chan.
So, how's it going?
Everyone's stumped.
Wondering who the owner is.
- Not everyone, I mean Edogawa-kun.
- Huh?
What kind of face is he making?
Um...
He's grinning, with this
mischievous look on his face.
Then it's fine.
Looks like he's found the owner.
Hey, hey, what's the meaning of this?
Didn't you gather us here because
you figured out who the owner is?
That's why Azusa-chan from Poirot
will be here soon...
bringing that calico cat.
What? Then you should've said so sooner.
Once we meet him, we'll know who the owner is.
But in my case, it's my
granddaughter who's the owner.
- Sorry for the wait.
- (cat meows)
Dai-chan!
(meowing)
See that? He's my cat after all!
Now then, I'll be taking
this cat home with me.
But you know, when a cat sees
three people standing together,
it has a habit of being drawn
to the person in the middle.
So maybe he just jumped at you
because you happened to be...
standing in the middle, mister.
- What?
- Is that true, Conan-kun?
Yeah, they showed it on TV the other day.
That must be exactly it.
Otherwise, our cat wouldn't go to
a shady man like this.
Then let's try it again.
I don't care whether I'm on
the right or left.
Actually, there's an even
clearer way to do this.
An experiment that'll tell us
the owner in one shot.
Azusa-san, are you ready?
Yeah. Taii-kun is eating his food
quietly in front of the office door.
Okay, one at a time, approach
the door and open it.
If it's one-on-one...
the cat should be able to tell
if you're his owner or not.
First up, Shagawa-san.
O-Okay.
Come on, Mugi-chan, it's me.
Don't you recognize me?
Mugi-chan.
I-I guess it really has to be
the owner's granddaughter.
No, it'd be the same even with
your granddaughter.
Because the cat you're looking for,
unlike this one, is female.
- Wha...
- Isn't that right?
Amuro-niichan.
Right. Shagawa-san, you said it yourself,
that for the neutering surgery,
the cat stayed overnight,
and it took a week before
the stitches came out.
Y-Yes.
That isn't a male neutering, that's
a female spaying procedure.
Spaying is a major operation that opens
the abdomen to remove the ovaries,
but neutering only involves making
a small cut in the scrotum...
and removing the testes. It's a simple
procedure, so it's done same-day as a rule.
And as Masuko-san said,
to keep the cat from licking
the wound,
all that's needed is a collar
around the neck.
And besides, ma'am,
you talked as if you kept the cat
together with your granddaughter,
but the truth is, your granddaughter
only brought him over once in a while, right?
Because you're not used to
handling cats.
Owner aside, cats dislike
being stared at.
That's why, back then, rather than going
to you, ma'am, who kept calling him over,
he went to someone
with no interest...
in cats, Kogoro-ojisan.
Probably your granddaughter had
something she had to leave home for,
and asked you to look after the cat,
but he wandered off somewhere, didn't he?
You're exactly right, boy.
My granddaughter is on a school trip,
and her parents took the chance
to go abroad.
I was asked to look after the cat,
but he just wouldn't warm
up to me.
The moment I took my eyes off him,
he was nowhere to be seen.
I was at a complete loss for what to do,
when that magazine photo of
the cat caught my eye.
So in place of the cat that vanished,
you went for Poirot's cat.
But a male and a female would
differ in build and such.
B-But my granddaughter comes back
from her school trip tonight.
If I don't sort it out by then, I won't
be able to face my granddaughter.
- When did he go missing?
- After he ate last night.
I searched everywhere a cat might
slip into, gaps in furniture,
any place a door was open,
but he was nowhere.
Then try looking in places
where doors are closed.
The bathroom, inside the washing
machine, the closet.
Cats sometimes slip right inside the
moment a person opens a door.
I-I'll go look one more time.
Sheesh, what an outrageous old lady.
Okay, next, Amesawa-san, you try it,
just like Shagawa-san did.
Sure, bring it on.
Though the result's obvious
before I even start.
That's right, Conan-kun.
He'll just leap at him. like before...
and start purring, won't he?
Heh. Hm?
H-Hey, what's the matter?
Come to me like before.
I said come here.
- (cat meows)
- Ah!
- Don't you know?
- Huh?
Catnip only works for about
five to ten minutes.
Once that passes, to the cat
you're just some...
scary guy who yells in a loud voice.
The proof is that Goro, who was
clinging to you at first,
is now scared and won't even go near you.
- A-Ah...
- Well, a real owner wouldn't...
come to pick up his cat by
dusting catnip powder...
all over his own body, now would he?
A-Ah, no, this is, um...
Besides, when Conan-kun told you
the cat was female,
you tried to back off right away.
- Huh?
- If you'd seen the magazine photo,
become certain it was your cat,
and gone out of your way to come get him,
you'd have pressed harder.
You knew, didn't you?
That if the cat were female,
it'd have no value.
Value? It's just a mutt, isn't it?
A female calico, sure.
But due to a chromosomal anomaly, males are
born at a rate of only one in a thousand,
and because of that rarity, they're said to be
the model for the so-called "lucky cat."
At least one million yen,
and I've heard they've even gone
for as much as 20 million yen.
- T-Twenty million yen?
- No way!
Amazing, Dai-chan!
On par with a white lion!
W-With that much, that's,
um, how many eel bowls...
You clearly knew its value,
so there's no way you'd let it roam
free in this city, is there?
I-I...
Excuse me!
Now then, lastly,
Masuko-san, you try.
A-Ah.
But I haven't seen him in four months,
and it was mostly my wife who fed him.
I might get the same result
as those other two.
Ah...
- S-Soseki.
- (cat meows)
You remembered me, didn't you, Soseki?
(cat meows)
But why?
It was almost as if he was waiting
in front of the door before it opened...
It's the sound.
Cats have incredibly good ears,
and they remember their...
owner's footsteps perfectly.
They showed it on TV.
Hey, you said the cat went missing...
during your move, right?
Did you happen to use
Cheetah Moving Center?
A-Ah, yes. But how did you
know that?
Because that cat once climbed
into a delivery truck...
container from the same company before.
I see, so that was...
He wanted to get back to his owner.
He thought he could go home if
he got on a truck with the same logo.
Good for you, Dai-chan.
(cat meows and sneezes)
Well then, thank you all for everything.
Bye-bye, Dai-chan.
- Take care.
- Don't run off again, okay?
Haha. Hm?
This is my address and email.
If it works out, come visit him.
Really? Thank you!
(sneezes)
But I had no idea.
That cats are drawn to the
person in the middle.
Ah, that was a lie.
- Huh?
- If I hadn't said something like that,
we wouldn't have been able to
do that footstep experiment.
You set up a fake, didn't you?
With that innocent smile,
playing it coy like a cat.
Huh?
- Ah, you know, fitting for a cat case.
- A pun, really?
♪~
~♪
But still, from that mister...
I never thought we'd hear from him.
"If you want to see the cat,
come today."
An email came to the detective
agency, right?
- Yeah.
- It hasn't even been...
- that many days since then.
- I wonder why?
Maybe he decided to let
him go after all?
That guy seemed to have a cat allergy.
A c-cat allergy?
And yet he was keeping a cat?
(elevator arrival chime)
Well, sometimes people keep cats
without knowing they're allergic,
and sometimes they develop
the allergy while keeping one.
But still, in that case, is he
going to sell him after all?
- Huh?
- It's 20 million yen, after all.
This is the room, right?
Masuko-san's place.
Just open the door,
please!
There was a strange sound!
Masuko-san, it's the building
manager. Are you all right?
- Hm?
- (cat meows)
Huh? What's with this cat?
Mister, is something wrong?
- Hm?
- Ah, no, this cat...
It doesn't seem to be hurt,
but there's blood on its paws.
Which means... don't tell me,
Masuko-san...
Don't tell me...
There's blood on its paws.
Something happened inside.
You guys.
- Do you have any string?
- Huh?
The back room, huh.
This is no time for you two
to be flirting...
- with each other.
- Wha...
There's tape and scissors, and yet...
The trash can nearby is empty too.
Why isn't it here? That thing.
Next Conan,
"Lucky Calico Cat Case (Part 2)".
Next Conan's Hint:
"Wrapping".
Next week is the second half!
Tune in, Yeah!
- That's a rapper.
- It's suppose to be wrapping.