At Sonoko's invitation, we visited the set of a TV show—
me, Ran, Sera, and Uncle Kogoro.
But when the recording began and we opened the locked box containing fruit—
which would determine the fate of the pastry chefs' victory or defeat—
inside was the body of the head judge,
Mr. Shoutoku Takegi.
What doesn't sit right with us
is Takegi-san's behavior.
Why was he so obsessively checking the box?
Don't you think he thought he'd been found out?
The champion who's been winning for six consecutive weeks—
Kurimura-san. Huh?
That champion always brought ingredients
that matched the theme fruit,
so maybe he knew what was inside the box.
Chief Megure! Hmm?
It seems Takegi-san—
last night, mixed in with the extras for a period drama,
sneaked into the TV station.
I see.
He wanted to make it seem like he wasn't at the TV station
to make it easier for the culprit to show their hand.
Takegi-san was hiding in the warehouse where that box was stored,
so it's highly likely he was lying in wait for the culprit.
On the seams of the box's lid and inside it,
there were traces of blood that had been wiped away.
That means the place where the box was kept is the crime scene, right?
Takegi-san was murdered there.
By the culprit who secretly opened the box.
By the culprit.
♪~♪
The blackness of shadows, the density of darkness—
the light of reasoning cuts right through them.
What is the trick hidden in the box,
and what is the key to the evidence pointing to the culprit?
See through the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~♪
"A Treasure Box Full of Fruits (Part 2)"
Ah, here he comes. Oh...
Isn't this Takegi-san?
See, while looking around, into the warehouse...
The question is, who will come next?
Like I said, it's probably him.
No, it's... Hmm?
Producer Taruoka?
Wh... why you?
Well... as the producer,
I came to check that the box was delivered properly.
Takegi-san also warned me,
"If the contents were leaked,
it would be your responsibility."
He had firmly warned me.
Hmm?
Still, you were in there a long time—
about 30 minutes.
No, no, I forgot where the box was placed,
so I was searching for it.
The warehouse is big and cluttered.
Hmm? Next is... Ah.
Assistant Director Furuya, and he's brought two young ADs.
You were inside quite a long time too.
Ah. Hmm?
Actually, I finished checking the box quickly
and was smoking.
The station is mostly non-smoking,
and ADs are so busy they don't have time to smoke.
I was checking my email for 3 to 4 minutes.
Well, the warehouse is non-smoking too, though.
Oh, he's out.
You were inside for about 30 minutes too, huh?
If no one went in after this,
then the suspects are you two...
Eh? Ah, actually—
I also went into the warehouse.
Eh? Kasuga-san too?
Yes. I was worried about something Takegi-san told me,
so—
I was confident in the lock I had put on,
but I hadn't checked the TV station's lock properly.
I hadn't checked it.
Ah, that's right.
Kasuga-san, you came too.
I think I was inside for about 30 minutes,
just like the previous two.
After all, I carefully and thoroughly examined it,
and took several photos to show Takegi-san later.
And what were the results?
The lock was completely secured,
so I went home after that.
Hmm... after Kasuga-san left,
until several staff members took the box the next day,
it seems no one else entered the warehouse.
In other words—
Among the three—Producer Taruoka,
AD Furuya-san,
and food coordinator Kasuga-san—
is the culprit who murdered Takegi-san.
So, the suspects have been narrowed down to three,
but who is the culprit?
More importantly, the method used to open the lock is a mystery.
Unless we figure that out—
Hmm?
But still, why are there so many packed in there?
Even if you combine the champion and challenger,
they wouldn't use 10 of them during the show.
You don't even understand that?
Huh?
A box full of fruit looks better on screen.
The leftover fruit
is given away to the audience by lottery after each recording.
Well, they use a false bottom so the box isn't too heavy.
And because they're rare fruits that are hard to get,
there are apparently a lot of people who apply to the audience
just for that.
Hmm.
So? Have you figured out who the culprit is?
Not at all.
I don't even have a clue about how the lock was opened.
Well, that's trivial compared to that mystery.
That mystery? Huh?
What is it?
Hey, hey, you really haven't noticed?
Yeah. Guh...
How could you not notice something this important?
Listen carefully.
It's about Yoko-chan's hair in the back.
In the last live show, it was quite short,
but today it's long.
That growth rate isn't normal.
Ah, that's probably extensions.
Huh? Exten...
Short for hair extensions. Fake hair.
Fake hair?
In Yoko-chan's case,
she probably hid them well at the hair clip.
Is that so?
Ah.
I see. So that's it.
If that's the case, then the culprit can only be that person...
Ah, you just thought the same thing as me, didn't you?
Huh? Hmm? Hmm?
These buck teeth that show up when she smiles...
But the problem is the evidence.
I knew it. I've—
met this girl somewhere before...
Hmm?
What? What is it?
Is there something on my face?
Ah, no. It's nothing.
We've taken photos,
so shall we take the box back and examine it thoroughly?
Yeah.
Hey. Huh?
Are those all the apples that were in the box?
Ah... yeah.
I think there were a lot of apples that spilled out of the box
and got squeezed inside the lid.
We put them all inside.
They probably just spilled out when the box was opened.
Hey, you always said that box was packed full of the theme fruit, right?
Yeah, so packed that 2 or 3 apples would spill out.
Because the host Kenzaki-san's catchphrase is,
"Look at this!"
"These overflowing fruits!"
If that's the case...
That becomes evidence.
Ah, hey!
That little brat.
It's just like when he's with Hattori-kun.
Hmm? What's wrong, Ran?
Wave... Huh?
Whenever I see Sera-san running away,
I always hear it in the back of my ear.
(Sound of waves)
The sound of ripples...
as if by magic.
Ran? Ah... oh!
What? Don't tell me you've fallen for that kid.
It's nothing like that.
Hmph. It's just because that boastful kid is a returnee.
That's why I feel that way.
Huh? How does that make sense?
See, because she came from overseas, "outside the sea."
That's why.
Uh...
A dad joke.
Why won't you let me in?
Just for a little bit, okay?
No way. This warehouse is where the box was kept,
and it's also the murder scene.
Then, did you find anything inside the warehouse?
So far, nothing related to the case...
Then, did anything unusual happen inside?
Ah, come to think of it, when we went in to investigate,
a young AD was getting scolded
because the props used for the drama's kitchen set
hadn't been washed properly.
The kitchen's...
props.
Well, it probably has nothing to do with the case.
Hey. Hmm?
Those three suspects are still here, right?
Yeah, they're waiting in another room.
All three are asking to be released soon.
Ah...
The producer, Taruoka-san, said
there's a press conference about the case...
AD Furuya-san said he hasn't eaten anything since morning,
so please let him go eat.
The food coordinator, Kasuga-san, said
he wants to go home to feed his pet dog.
Then we should start quickly.
Eh? Start what?
What? A little...
magic show.
Hah? A magic show?
Did you call us and the suspects here just to see something like that?
And the one performing is that boastful kid?
Now, now.
I think if you see it, you'll be surprised.
Hmm...
Hey, Conan-kun isn't here.
Isn't he with Sera-san?
Here he is.
Whoa!
Welcome to Sera Masumi's House of Magic!
Ah... Wait, don't tell me...
The box you're sitting in... is that the one the victim was put in?
Well, yeah.
And I also have this box's padlock
and the key to open it.
Hey, hey.
We asked the prop master to prepare a similar box.
The key is real, though.
So? What's about to start?
First of all...
please make sure there's nothing inside the box.
Hmm. Hmph.
Hmm... Hmm...
It seems empty.
Eh... yes.
Okay, now...
Close the lid, pass the iron bar of the padlock
through the holes at the seams of the box,
and click it locked.
See? Without the padlock key,
the box shouldn't open, right?
Huh? Yeah.
So take this key and go outside the room for a bit.
Huh? We have to go out?
Heh heh. After Takagi-keiji finishes talking,
you can come back in.
Ta... Takagi's?
Ah, hey... hey, Conan-kun...
Hmm? Oh, that's right.
(Clears throat)
Now, let me explain.
The key to this case is—
the locked box.
Food coordinator Kasuga-san
packed the box with fruit, locked it with a padlock,
and sent it to the TV station.
Producer Taruoka, who received it,
instructed AD Furuya-san to put another padlock on it
and send it back to Kasuga-san.
Then Kasuga-san removed his own padlock,
sent it back to the TV station again,
and it was stored in the warehouse until the recording began.
Why was Takegi-san's body inside that box?
That's the question.
Of course, when Kasuga-san first locked the box,
AD Furuya-san, who came from the TV station to pick up the box,
confirmed that Takegi-san was not inside.
Furthermore, the key is a special key with no duplicates,
so it's not easy to force it open.
And of course, there's no hidden door on the box.
Given this situation—
How did the culprit... Hmm...
Enough with the preamble! Just tell us the answer!
Tell us, Takagi-keiji!
Huh? Dahahaha!
It's faster to show you than to explain.
The answer is exactly this.
Ah!
Co... Conan-kun!
Wh... where were you?
I was hiding behind the box.
More importantly, where's Sera-san?
Hehehehe. Where do you think?
Hey, don't tell me... Inside the box?
Don't be stupid. It's properly locked, isn't it?
Then why don't you open it?
Ta-da! Huh? Uh...
Huh? Heh heh.
No way.
Why?
I used this.
Hmm?
A rubber tube?
It's painted gold to match the padlock.
I had the prop master make it.
But how did you use it?
Yeah, yeah.
Then I'll show you using this.
Lend me that padlock too.
Ah... yeah.
When putting on the padlock,
fit the tube onto the tip of the bar,
and forcefully jam it into the padlock's hole.
See? If you do it like this,
it looks like it's locked, right?
Wow! You're right.
Ah...
I... indeed.
With this, you can easily remove the padlock
just by twisting the lock...
And moreover, the seam where the tube is attached
is hidden by the part of the box's seam
that the padlock bar goes through, so you can't see it.
That means I pretended to lock it with that tube,
then removed the padlock, got into the box,
and Conan-kun, who was hiding behind the box, pulled out the tube,
and then locked it properly with the padlock.
Hmm. Right.
The key point of this trick is the padlock—
the fact that it can be locked without the key.
Kasuga-san, who knew the contents of the box from the beginning,
would have no need to go to the trouble of rigging it to open the lid...
And Producer Taruoka, who instructed that the padlock be put on,
had no opportunity to use this trick.
Which leaves—
AD Wataru Furuya, who was instructed by Taruoka
to put on the lock and send it back.
AD Wataru Furuya.
Ah...
I think it can only be you.
Ah. Huh?
I'm sure you were opening the box in the warehouse
to tell the champion the theme fruit inside, in exchange for a reward.
(Sound) Ah.
Last night, Takegi-san was hiding there,
and when he caught you, you got into a struggle...
Ah!
Ugh... ngh...
You killed him by accident,
and in a panic, you hid him inside the box, right?
Wh... where is the evidence for that?
There is evidence. Huh?
It's inside your stomach, AD-san.
Huh? AD-san.
After you put that old man in the box,
you blended up about 10 apples that wouldn't fit and drank them, right?
You put them in the mixer prop that was in the warehouse.
The AD caught on the security camera
wasn't carrying anything when he came out of the warehouse.
E... even if that's true, they've already been digested in my stomach...
You didn't know? Huh?
Apple seeds contain
components that are poisonous.
Eating a lot of them is dangerous.
Huh...
AD-san, when you put the apples in the mixer,
you didn't take out the seeds, did you?
Ugh...
Well, it's okay.
With only the seeds from about 10 apples, it won't be dangerous.
Ugh...
But since you haven't eaten anything since morning,
the "big one" should still be there.
It'll come out eventually, won't it?
The rare apple seeds that the mixer failed to crush.
Ugh... ugh...
Heh heh.
Once that comes out, Case Closed.
Talk about running out of luck.
♪~♪
~♪
Oh, it's on the online news!
Just like Sera-san said,
seeds came out of the AD and matched the theme apples.
It seems the champion, Kurimura-san, also confessed.
That he had asked about the theme fruit in advance.
But Conan-kun surprises me again.
I didn't know apple seeds are toxic.
I just happened to remember hearing it from Shinichi-niichan.
You and Shinichi-kun are really close.
Ah, th... that reminds me. Hmm?
There's something I want to ask Sera-neechan.
Ah, you did say that.
Sera-neechan... don't tell me...
Have we met somewhere before?
Huh?
Who knows? Huh?
Sorry, but I can't tell you that.
Until the time comes.
These are things my late husband collected.
I see.
Ah... whoa!
Hey, Dad, be careful.
I know!
What is the meaning of this?
What's all this noise?
Why did you cancel my passing of the audition?
The lady's room is... Mama.
Next Conan...
"The Diamond, the Painting, and the Great Actress"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Sunlight"
Speaking of light, it's time for this star, Kogoro, to appear.
You're pretty energetic today.
Because I'm not doing any deducing.