Koshien ball grounds, the dream and goal of all high school ball players.
The Japan summer high school ball game will start this morning.
This year, 4,146 schools have participated in the nationwide competition,
and 160,000 players have played.
Chosen from among the winners are 49 schools.
In the indoor training grounds on the side of the first base,
the players are waiting for the game to start.
Let's take a look at the regional champions.
Representing Okinawa, Okinawa Central High.
Representing Kagoshima Prefecture, Sakurajima High.
Representing Miyazaki Prefecture, Tadohara High.
Representing Oita Prefecture, Meihou High.
Representing Kumamoto Prefecture, Kumamoto High.
Representing Nagasaki Prefecture...
We will commence the Japan High School Baseball Tournament!
The players will make entry.
Following Tadohara High School is Oita's Meihou High.
This makes the third time Meihou has gotten this far in the tournament.
Representing Osaka. Here's Ogane High School.
They're getting a big cheer from the stands.
Now, we will move on to the player dedication.
Representing all players from Toyama Minami Vocational High School,
Captain Kawakami.
I pledge!
That we the players have come here with joy and admiration in our hearts
upon this great stage and will compete fair and square.
We will give it our best and display the results
of the of the training we went through
with the sportsmanship of fair play.
Representing all the players here, Toyama prefecture,
Toyama Minami Vocational High School Baseball Club,
Captain Tomoya Kawakami.
Koshien Stadium.
It's the place where the chosen high school ball players gather
from throughout the nation to compete using their skills and strength.
It is the pinnacle of one's goal.
It is a sanctuary where the goddess smiles on the champions,
as well as a fighting arena where the ball game is settled.
Yes.
Koshien Stadium sometimes entices the bewitched into unbelievable fate.
Here's a hot passionate suspense in this cold winter season.
Today's episode is a two hour special. Heiji also appears.
A difficult case on a grand stage.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"High School Ball Game, Invisible Summer Devil"
On the same day of summer vacation,
the ball game finals and Takarazuka show were to take place.
In order to decide which we'd go to
Hattori and Kazuha will have a deduction match.
The case is one that Pops was asked to help out with.
The clue on hand are wooden blocks that the president
of the toy manufacturing company had left behind as a dying message.
Thanks to Hattori's subtle hint,
Kazuha solves the message.
However, it turns out that Heiji figures out who the real killer is
and wins the deduction match.
We can finally go to the Koshien Stadium.
Congratulations, Heiji.
Oh, shoot! I forgot.
Now, I have to practice the boola boola.
Kazuha, wait.
Kazuha, I can ask Hattori for you to go to the Takarazuka show.
You are the one who solved the mystery of the dying message.
You are actually half the winner, right?
Forget it.
What I really wanted to see
wasn't the Takarazuka show or the baseball game.
It was Heiji's smile that he shows when he solves a case.
It's the Koshien Stadium!
I'm sure that here, there and everywhere...
Yoko.
Yoko?
Konan High School is where the idol Yoko Okino used to go to.
Hey, we're not there yet?
Are you all right, Kudo?
I give up.
By the way, why do they call this Koshien Stadium?
Why not Hyogo Stadium or Kansai Stadium?
I think it would've been way better.
The year that Koshien Stadium was completed
was the first year of both ten signs zodiac and the Chinese zodiac.
It was the meeting of the monkey and the mouse
which comes around every 60 years.
So they thought it was a lucky year.
You sure know a lot. Don't you, Conan?
He knows nothing about baseball
and yet he's knowledgeable when it comes to things like these.
Well, I'm so sorry.
That's not all there is about Koshien Stadium.
The number of the stumps of the famous ivies growing here total 430,
and the dimension of the leaves total 8,000 mats.
Although it's an old stadium,
it has the capacity to hold a total of 53,000 people,
which is virtually equal to that of a large stadium
that the major leagues play at.
How about it? Fantastic, don't you think?
You're just as bad as I am.
It's going to start.
Let's do our best...
Top of the 1st inning,
position number 1 short, player Inoue is the first batter
for Ohgane High School.
Play ball!
Strike!
Strike two!
Strike three, batter out!
The starting pitcher, Sakuraba, struck out the first batter.
One out. The stands are cheering.
Sakuraba is a senior at Konan High School.
Here comes the windup and the second pitch.
-Strike! -Strike.
Ohgane High School's pitcher, Inao, with another fastball.
Here comes the second pitch.
Another strike.
Three strikes for Konan High School's batter.
Now...
Here comes the third pitch.
-Strike, batter out! -Three swings and an out.
Inao presses relentlessly with his trademark style.
Konan High School's third batter, Kikuchi is a senior.
The crowd is on their feet.
This being the Koushien finals, we'll see three matched consecutively.
And now, Kikuchi faces off against Inao.
And here comes the pitch.
-Strike! -Strike.
The pitcher and the catcher exchange signs.
And now, the second pitch.
-Strike two! -Strike.
Now, it's two strikes. Thanks to a mean curveball.
The next batter, Nagashima is on deck.
Strike, batter out!
Ohgane High School's Inao holds off Konan High School
with some aggressive pitching.
That's the end of the 1st,
as Ohgane High School and Konan High School switch up.
Konan High School's Sakuraba now takes the mound.
It is the top of the 2nd inning,
and center number 6 of Ohgane High School,
player Matsuda is the batter.
Strike!
Foul ball!
The finals are amazing.
Strike, batter out!
Number seven, third player Morita.
Sakuraba gets three strikes against Morita,
bringing us to two outs.
Number eight catcher, Watanabe.
The catcher, Watanabe steps into the batter's box.
The pitcher Sakuraba, with the delivery.
He pops it up.
-It's going right... -Foul ball!
Foul.
Strike!
Strike, batter out!
End of the bottom of the 2nd inning,
as Sakuraba from Ohgane High School
prevents Konan High School from breaking the no-run tie.
Bottom of the 2nd. Hitting for Konan High School.
Third baseman, Nagashima.
And the batter we've been waiting for takes the box.
Konan High School's Nagashima.
Listen to this.
The roar of the cheer of the people loud enough to erase the announcement.
By some strange coincidence, it turns out that the same players
get to compete against each other three times in a row
at the finals of Koshien.
Will the victor be the winner of last year, Konan High School?
Or will it be Ohgane High School that is aiming
to win the spring and summer games successively?
The pitcher flings his arms up high
and prepares to throw his first pitch.
There goes the ball!
Strike!
Talk about strike indeed!
Strike. Strike.
Hey, Pops.
What have you been looking at all this time?
Dad. The game's over that side.
I bet he's watching the cheerleaders in those stand.
Pervert.
We came all the way out here.
So watch the game, will you?
But...
Sitting in right stand like this,
it's so far that you can't really watch the game anyway.
I thought we were going to have better seats because you invited us.
I'm so sorry.
I asked an acquaintance of mine who lives here
to line up and get the tickets,
but he seems to have overslept.
Inspector Ohtaki.
Besides, the game between Ohgane and Konan is super popular.
So, unless you come really early in the morning,
it seems to be impossible to get an infield seat.
That's why you should buy advance tickets.
Nagashima faces off against the pitcher, Inao.
Here comes the second ball.
He pops it up!
It clears the field and goes just foul.
Here, have some ice candy. Ice candy.
I bought one for each one of you.
Cold!
Thank you.
You're welcome.
But are you sure it's okay, Inspector Ohtaki?
What about you work?
No problem. He took time off anyway.
Right?
Yes.
I've been watching the game for three days since the semi-finals.
You like Koshien, don't you?
Of course he does.
Mr. Ohtaki may not look it, but he used to play high school baseball.
Right?
Come on, Kazuha. It's no big deal.
Oh, really?
How embarrassing.
Have you played on this Koshien field, too?
No.
Making it to the best eight for the preliminary district match
was as far as I ever went.
But coming here and watching them play brings back memories.
The days when we struggled while covered with sweat and dirt
just to after that one ball.
And just by giving the game everything you have.
Just what do you think you're doing, Ohtaki?
There!
What's the matter? Missing a ball like that, Ohtaki?
I guess I don't have the knack for playing baseball.
That's not true. Don't give up.
All you need to do is practice a little more.
Right. I'll practice even more and get better.
Hey! Freshman Ohtaki.
Yes, sir?
You'll be the number seven catcher for the practice game
against Yakushiji High School that's coming up.
Yes, sir!
Hey, fantastic. Let's give it our best shot.
Yes.
I wonder if I don't have the knack for baseball?
It's not that.
Don't give up and practice more and more.
If you give up before doing anything, that's it.
I was really hopeless when I started off, too.
But I stayed after school everyday and practiced.
Then one day, I realized that I had become captain of my team.
You weren't a good player?
No. I was really bad.
Are you serious?
Yes. So don't give up, okay?
Hey, what's with that look of yours?
All the underclass men don't know what to do since you look so depressed.
Ohtaki, you're the one who lead the weak team to where it is now.
The underclass men are the ones who are going to Koshien.
Encourage them and make them feel that can do it.
I have one last thing I'd like to say to all of you.
No matter what...
No matter what, don't ever give up!
Yes, sir...
So I really think,
that the effort I put in back then was worth it.
I feel that one should never give up.
Really? Koshien is really a good place.
What a worthless place this is.
Don't you think so, Hiroshi?
Bottom of the 2nd inning, Konan High School batting,
Nagashima in the batter's box.
Pitcher Inao is on the mound.
Here it comes!
He hit towards third base.
It's a long ball.
Fast! The one who hit the ball is fast.
The left fielder sure is taking his time.
I think the runner's going to make it to third base, don't you?
Go! Go!
Left! Left! Just what do you think you're doing?
Nagashima rounds second and heads for third.
The left fielder throws it to the infiled, a fast one to third base.
It's a good throw.
Nagashima is almost to third, he dives.
The third baseman catches...
-Safe! -Safe!
The fleet-footed Nagashima gets a three base hit.
No out third base.
I guess them scoring a point can't be helped.
No, you can't tell yet.
That pitcher sure got guts.
It's the first round of the spring preliminaries
We are now in the 18th inning of overtime.
This match between Teitou High School and Ohgane High School
has had its share of ups and downs.
At the bottom of the 18th with two outs,
Teitou High School is hitting with a runner on first.
In the batter's box is number four, Yamamoto.
Inao faces off against Yamamoto.
Here's the pitch.
A cell phone?
Was it there from before?
Maybe the man who passed by here a while ago dropped it.
Let me see.
Hello? Are you the one who dropped this cell phone?
Yes.
Then come to the right stand.
Having fun?
What?
I'm asking you if this place is such an enjoyable place?
Who are you?
If it's okay with you, let's play an even more enjoyable game.
It's way more fun
-than this baseball game. -Strike!
An exchange of lives that will make your blood stir.
Well, it is an exchange of lives, but the one who's going to die is me.
You idiot! If you want to die, go and die on your own.
Yes, I'll do that.
But I can't die alone.
Being alone is much too lonely.
What?
The rule is simple.
Each time the third, sixth, and ninth innings end,
I'll call the cell phone that I've left somewhere on this baseball ground.
Ball!
I will ring my cell phone that will be the clue to where I am.
I will be near the phone that will ring after the game ends.
Strike!
I will ring only three times.
If you don't answer by then,
it's three out and game set.
Of course if you gather all the cell phones
before they ring and find me before the game ends,
it's your win.
Hey, you got to be kidding. Cut out your stupid talk!
I'm hanging up.
You'll find out whether I'm kidding or not
after the end of the bottom of the second inning.
Hey, just what do you mean by that?
So your first clue is written in the mail of the cell phone.
Yes, tell that to the police detective sitting next to you
that I'm looking forward to seeing him, too.
Okay, then. I'll talk to you later.
Wait up.
At least tell me your name.
Me? I'm...
The Demon of Koshien.
You can call me that.
-The Demon of Koshien? -The Demon of Koshien?
Hey, you!
Strike! Batter out!
-Okay! -Okay!
Is the bottom of the second inning finished?
It's still one out.
What's with you, Heiji? Aren't you watching the game?
The strike out ball just now was a very fast ball.
I found it!
This is it.
96, 7, 13.
What's that?
The telephone number of the whereabouts of the owner of this telephone.
What's that? Why doesn't he come get it himself?
I wonder what it is though?
96, 7, 13.
It doesn't seem like a seat number.
Could it be some kind of code again?
Enough of codes!
Thanks to an odd code,
we ended up not being able to go to Takarazuka.
If it's 8, 1 and 2, it's the Alps stand.
-Alps stand? -Alps stand?
Why?
Because 8 (hachi), 1 (ichi) and 2 (ni) is pronounced as "Heidi".
And Heidi is connected with the Alps, right?
So lame.
Please, Dad.
Oh, well.
Mr. Ohtaki, please help us find him.
But this is the best part.
Don't worry. We'll be done right away
if you come with us, Mr. Ohtaki.
Are you going too, Conan?
Because it sounds like fun.
Well, don't worry. We'll give it to the owner
and come right back.
What's with him?
He's the one who wanted to come here with us.
Seriously.
What? Suicide?
Really? Heiji?
Yes! He saying that if we don't find it
before the end of the game, he's going to die.
He says he'll kill someone along with himself, too.
But maybe it's just a prank.
I think it's most likely not a prank.
The one who called didn't change his voice,
and the manufacture number seal was pasted on the cell phone, too.
It means that he doesn't mind his identity being revealed later, right?
Moreover, he's doing something like this
knowing that you're an inspector, Mr. Ohtaki,
which means that this man must really be desperate.
At any rate, please use your police badge, Mr. Ohtaki.
And let us in behind the back net.
What? Why behind the back net?
On the phone a while ago, I heard the referee call out strike.
He could still be there.
Right.
No.
Oh, no. Heiji,
he's not going to die until the game ends, right?
The man says he'll show proof after the bottom of the second inning.
What?
We're going in, Mr. Ohtaki.
If the cheers that we heard just now was for the third out...
Maybe he's already done something.
No good. Just as I thought.
The bottom of the second inning is over.
You go down.
I'll go up. Mr. Ohtaki, please search the center.
He's a suspicious looking man wearing a cap.
Okay.
Darn it! He's not here after all.
But nothing is happening.
Nothing.
The third inning, batter for Ohgane High School
is number nine. Right fielder, Seki.
Sakuraba, with the pitch.
Here it is.
Hit!
Straight down the third baseline, the third baseman picks it up.
And a fast one to first!
And he's...
Out!
A picture-perfect play by Konan High School's third baseman, Nagashima.
Seki makes one out here at the top of the third for Ohgane High School.
Hey, Heiji.
What's going on?
There's nothing happened, right?
Strange.
The guy who called said that he'd show evidence
after the bottom of the second inning ends.
Maybe it's a prank after all?
Who'd do a thing like that at the finals of Koshien?
Hey.
I wonder what that is?
There. On the other side of the freeway.
What is it?
Smoke is rising.
It looks like fire.
It seems to be around Tekiryokumachi.
Mr. Ohtaki, you once told me
that you have a superior working at the Hyogo Prefectural Police, right?
Yes.
Won't you please call and ask him?
Okay.
What?
A bomb?
Is that true, Mr. Kazuhisa?
As for the details, I can't say for sure
until I see the report of the fire-fighters after they put out the fire,
but it seems to be so.
A company called Takano Transport seems to have caught fire.
According to what the neighbours are saying,
before that place caught fire, a loud boom seems to have been heard.
I see.
Fortunately, that company was off today.
So there seems to have been no casualties.
They think a bomb went off because the sound
came from a building that was supposedly empty.
And do you know when the building caught fire?
Well...
Hey, Numata.
Yes, sir?
You know that fire that's being put out now?
Do you know what time it started?
I think it was about 2:40 in the afternoon?
Just around when...
Around when the bottom of the second inning ended.
This looks bad, Hattori.
If the evidence that the guy warned us about over the phone
was that explosion that caused the fire,
maybe the way he's going to commit suicide is...
Moron.
If he commits suicide with a bomb in a place like this with so many people,
it would cause a grave disaster!
Hey, Ohtaki.
Come to think of it, aren't you at Koshien today?
How do you know about the fire?
Oh, well...
Heiji, what do you want to do?
Do you want to tell the police about this?
No!
The guy who called is saying
that he's going to commit suicide when the ball game ends.
We don't want to start a useless commotion here and end the game.
Because the minute it ends, we will all be blown up.
I think it would be better to listen to what the man has to say for now
and solve the codes one after the other.
Trace the three cell phones
and arrest the man.
Either way, we'll have to solve the codes
before the bottom of the third inning ends
and find the first cell phone
that is hidden somewhere in the stands of Koshien,
or we're finished.
The top of the third inning,
one out and runners on first and second base.
There is a map of the stands
right behind the back net of gate number eight here.
I guess I'll go outside,
look at the map, and use my head and decipher the code.
The meaning of these numbers 96, 7, 13!
I'll go borrow the radio from Pops then.
We need to know how the game is progressing, or we'll be in trouble, right?
Do so, will you?
Position number three, Pitcher Inao.
All right! Clean up time.
I guess this game is going to be a long one.
Let's go, Heiji.
Okay.
-Ball! -Ball!
It's clean up, but the pitcher is not quite in control of the ball.
If the runner gets to walk, then it'll be one out with the bases loaded.
And then comes the fourth batter.
Heiji and the others sure are late.
Maybe they can't find the owner of the cell phone yet.
If so, why don't give up already and hurry on come back here?
The man who dropped it is to blame, and not us.
True.
Don't worry!
We'll find that man for sure,
so wait a while longer.
Conan.
Pops, will you please lend me your radio?
Huh?
Searching for that man,
we won't be able to tell how the game is progressing.
Okay? You'll lend it to me, right?
Gosh.
Don't break it.
Here you go.
Thank you.
And if you see a suspicious man wearing a white cap,
call Heiji on the cell phone, okay?
Hey, Conan!
They look so much alike.
Conan's face just now...
looked so much like him back then.
He hit the ball! This is a big one!
Right back! Right back!
What? It's coming this way!
I think the ball will make it.
Thrust forward by the beach wind, the ball flies into the right stand...
He caught the ball!
The runner on second base starts!
The ball goes pass second base.
-Safe! -Safe!
From that fly ball to the right field to touch up
makes for two outs with runners on first and third base.
Although the hit looked to be a homerun,
the ball was blocked by the beach wind
and both wings spreading out wide over this vast Koshien of 96 meters!
Both wings are 96 meters?
96, 7, 13.
Where is it? Where is it?
I'm sure that it's indicating the seats somewhere here.
Heiji, we'd better hurry or we'll run out of time.
Darn it.
Where is it?
Heiji!
I borrowed the radio!
How's the game going?
The top of the third inning just finished,
and the score's still zero-zero.
Three outs left.
Hey. Do you know that is there such a wing in this ball field?
Wing?
Because I heard them say,
Koshien have both wings with 96 meters on the radio.
You really don't know a thing about baseball, do you?
Well, they don't say both wings in other games
so I guess it can't be helped, but...
Kid, both wings with 96 meters
means that the distance from the home base to the pole is 96 meters.
Don't tell me that the first 96 code
means the seats by the end of the pole?
But which way, Heiji?
There are poles on both sides, the right and left.
Then maybe the next number seven in parenthesis means something?
-Seven... -Seven...
Hey, this looks bad!
It's three balls three strikes and one out!
Kid, turn your back on me!
Huh?
Like this?
I see!
You see what, Heiji?
The number of the outfit the boy's wearing is 55, not 7.
Right the number on the back of the outfit!
In high school baseball, where is the player wearing number seven?
Number seven is left field.
Which means, Heiji...
In other words, it's the seat at the end of the left pole!
Then, what about the last 13?
Probably the seat on the 13th aisle!
The first cell phone is there!
It's the bottom of the third inning. The two batters of Konan High School
struck out three times in a row and now with two outs.
The next batter is number one left, Iwata.
The pitcher flings his arms high in order to throw his first ball.
Strike!
Straight in high.
The pitcher throws his second ball in good rhythm.
Strike two.
Outlaw, another straight!
27, 26, 25.
The pitcher flings up his arms.
21, 20, 19.
The third pitch...
15, 14.
He has thrown the ball!
13!
Over here!
Strike three!
Don't answer it! Give it to me!
Hello? Hello?
Hey, you! What's so funny?
It's really interesting.
You kids sure are interesting.
Hang in there a while longer and entertain me, will you?
I love to see people making futile effort.
Hold it, you!
Hey! Hello? Hello?
Darn it! He hung up.
Hey, look!
The next code is on the display.
47, 3 and 4.
Yes, futile effort.
There is no such thing as a victory
that can be won through effort.
It doesn't exist.
It is the top of the fourth inning,
the batter for Ohgane High School
is number five, left fielder, Shigeta.
Shigeta versus Sakuraba.
The first pitch.
He hit the ball!
It's up! The left line.
He caught it! He caught the ball!
Great play!
That third is really fantastic!
Yes. He sure is.
At any rate, let's get with this code.
Before the end of the bottom of the sixth inning,
we've got to locate where this number 47,3, 4 indicates
and find the second cell phone!
Before that man wearing the white cap
uses the bomb to commit suicide.
But these numbers are hard to figure out again.
Not really. I've figured out half of it.
What?
Because we figured out that the first code 96, 7, 13,
indicated that the first cell phone was on the 13th aisle
at the edge of the left pole.
96 is the distance from the home base to the pole.
The seven in parenthesis is the number on the back of the uniform
and left of high school baseball.
The final 13 means the seat on the 13th aisle!
Which means that the number 3 in the parenthesis of the numbers 47, 3, 4
is the number on back of the uniform
and the last number four means the fourth aisle of a seat somewhere, right?
But we've got to find out where that somewhere is.
Number four is probably the one that indicates that.
There's no doubt that it's a seat by the first base.
In high school baseball, the player with number three is at first base.
But Heiji, the one wearing number three at Konan High School
is the third base.
Out!
He's special so you shouldn't be concerned about him.
But if the guy made the code in accordance
to this final game between Konan and Ohgane,
maybe it would be of some concern.
Okay, tell you what?
I'll go check the fourth aisle of the infield stand by first base,
so you go check the third base side.
Okay.
What about me?
After you get us into the infield stand,
wait for us at the map of the Koshien outside that we saw a while ago.
That place is right in the centre of the infield stand
of the first and third base,
so whether I find the cell phone or the kid does,
it'll be easy for us to join up.
Okay. While I'm waiting,
I'll call and ask my superior at Hyogo Prefectural Station
if the Takano Transport company that was bombed and set on fire
by the guy wearing the white cap had been hated by someone recently.
Do that will you, Mr. Ohtaki?
Strike!
Three strikes.
Eight strike outs in a row!
The droning ball shows no signs of weakening at all even at the finals.
Hey, what's with you, kid?
I'm just looking for something.
Okay, they're really going for it!
Will the ninth player strike out in a row?
Idiot! Use more balls and slow down the progress of the game.
What? Is that true?
Last month the truck of Takano Transport...
Huh?
It's a homerun!
In the bottom of the fourth inning,
thanks to the hit of the big slugger of Konan High School,
they've taken a one point lead.
No, no. I can't be watching the game.
-I got to find it quick. -Super batting just as expected.
Moreover,
-he's using a wooden bat and not a metal one. -47, 3 and 4.
-Incredible. -47, 3 and 4. What is it?
Metal?
Metal...
Metal.
Strike! Batter out!
Kubota gets three strikes and is out!
But in this inning,
Konan High School scored a run from Nagashima's home run.
Ohgane High School are trying to make up for it now.
In the batter box is number eight, Watanabe.
Sakuraba throws against Watanabe.
A hit.
Right down to the middle.
Out!
Konan High School third baseman,
Nagashima is really showing his skills in this game.
Strike!
Inao's third pitch against Sakuraba.
Here it comes!
Strike! Batter out!
A swing and a strike out.
Konan High School with no runs in this inning.
As the fifth inning comes to a close, the score is 0-1.
Konan High School is still with a one run lead
from Nagashima's home run in the fourth.
Out!
Top of the sixth inning, hitting for Konan High School
is number nine, second baseman, Michishita.
Kudo?
How about it? Did you find it?
No. I searched all through the fourth aisle,
but it's nowhere.
And how about you?
Same here.
I guess we'll just have to decipher
the meaning of the figure 47.
Hey, Hattori.
What is it, Kudo?
At Koshien,
there's nothing that is gold, is there?
Well, at Koshien the gold would be...
"Ginsan".
Huh? You mean there is something called that?
You can see it, can't you?
The big roof hooked onto the ceiling behind the back net,
that's it.
Then, there's no doubt about it.
The second cell phone is there!
Huh? Why?
You know, don't you?
47 is gold.
That's right!
47 is the atomic number for gold!
Let's go outside and go in behind the back net
and check the seats in the fourth aisle.
But I wonder if we'll make it in time?
The seats under the "ginsan" behind the back net
has 100 seats an aisle.
If we try checking every seat from now,
three outs and that's it!
Then maybe it's first base or third base?
Because there's a 3 under 47.
Idiot!
You just checked there.
There's got to be something else.
Number three on the back of the uniform
that would indicate a seat under "ginsan".
I got it.
There is one, Kudo!
Another number three, on the back of the uniform!
Mr. Ohtaki!
Heiji.
Did you figure out the code?
Yes.
The first 47 stands for "ginsan",
and the next three in the parenthesis is...
the one wearing the number three on the back of his uniform,
the Bay Bruce monument!
Which means that the location of the 2nd cell phone is...
The location of this monument
is slightly left from the centre.
In other words,
under "ginsan", slightly left from the center behind the back net
and a seat in the fourth aisle!
What is it?
What's up?
The player made first base because the catcher fumbled.
But we've got to hurry.
It's two outs already.
There's only one more out to go!
-Ball! -Ball!
Two three!
It's the bottom of the sixth inning.
It's two out with a runner on first base because of a fumble.
Count two three.
If this batter walks,
next in line is Konan's big slugger, who scored a homerun.
Okay, the pitcher gets a hold of himself
and from set position, throws his sixth ball.
The ball's been hit.
It's a foul fly.
But the ball flies in front of the Konan bench by first base.
The catcher stops going after the ball.
The pitcher.
The pitcher goes after the ball and dashes into the Konan bench!
Is the pitcher all right?
He caught the ball! He caught it!
The fantastic play of the pitcher and it's three out change!
Amazing!
Talk about being reckless.
I wonder if all boys are that way.
Huh?
This is indeed the finals of the Koshien.
The passion that the players display towards the ball can't help
but has touched the hearts of all who are watching!
Hey, you stupid idiot!
Listen, I'm going to find the third cell phone right away
and get a hold of where you are
so you can look forward to me getting to you real soon, you fool!
Darn it! He hung up without saying anything.
Come to think of it, Heiji.
You know the Takano Transport case?
According to what my superior told me,
the truck of that company ran over a person a month ago in Tokyo,
and it seemed one person died.
Maybe that accident has something to do with this?
But what does that have to do with Koshien?
I still don't know but...
Well, never mind.
Let's just nab the guy and ask him directly.
We already know how to decipher the code, so...
What's this?
Only the number of aisle is written here.
No hint.
Hiroshi.
Why?
Why is only the aisle number of the seats written?
Maybe it's because you shouted at him furiously on the phone a while ago?
I'm going to find the 3rd cell phone right away
and get a hold of where you are,
so you can look forward to me getting to you real soon, you fool!
Darn it! He hung up without saying anything.
If the guy's saying that he's going to commit suicide using a bomb,
it's not surprising that he'd get pissed at what you said
and decided not to give you any clue!
Idiot!
If he was one to get pissed over something like that,
he would've pushed the switch for the bomb long ago
and the stand somewhere here would be in bad trouble!
There's some kind of meaning to it.
The blank in this code.
It's indicating some stand of Koshien here.
But what an odd guy.
If he really wants to commit suicide,
why would he give out complicated clues
and make people look for where he is?
Maybe he wants somebody to stop him?
-Huh? -Huh?
I'm sure that person
is hoping deep down in his heart that somebody will stop him.
And maybe he doesn't even realize it himself.
He wants somebody to stop him?
Because the code that he thought up
cannot be made unless he is interested in Koshien or baseball.
It's hard to believe that such a person
would want to do something like that at Koshien,
much less use a bomb to commit suicide, right?
I guess so.
Mr. Ohtaki.
Huh?
Please call the Hyogo Prefectural police once more
and ask them for more detailed information
about the traffic accident a month ago,
that Takano Transport the man set fire with a bomb that was involved in.
I also want to know what the motive of a baseball fan
who would do something like this at Koshien is, too.
Okay.
Then, shall we think about this code
and look through the seats in the 13th row?
Just look at each and every seat
until the time limit when the bottom of the ninth inning ends.
Let's do so.
Who know whether there'll be a bottom of the ninth inning or not though.
I see!
Unless Ohgane who is batting first, catches up or wins the score,
the top of the ninth inning will be the end of the game.
The game is at the top of eight,
one out, runner on third.
Ohgane High School has a chance to even the score.
The pitcher gets into set position.
The third runner has dashed off!
It's a squeeze!
It's a short fly in front of the pitcher!
He caught the ball! He caught it!
It's a direct catch by the third!
The ball goes to third base and it's a double play!
Home base is far for Ohgane High School!
It's the top of the eighth inning
and though they've establish opportunities,
they haven't scored a point yet!
The score is still 0-1. It is the bottom of the eighth inning
and Konan High School will be batting.
Yes.
Huh?
Huh? A high school student?
Are you sure that the one who was run over by the truck
was a high school student?
Yes.
I was in charge of that accident together with a colleague
who was appointed to the Metropolitan police in Tokyo.
I asked for all kinds of details.
Here it is.
I'm sure that you would know since you like high school baseball, right?
The name Hiroshi Torimitsu.
Yes.
In the first game during the spring selection,
the left hander of Teito Jitsugyo High school,
who threw 18 extended games along with Ohgane's ace,
but lost by a close game.
Don't tell me it was that boy?
Right.
He seems to have dashed out into the road after baseball club practice
and was run over.
Well, it seems that the boy's bicycle was moving unsteadily to begin with.
Something about he had been over practicing baseball.
Come to think of it, since the accident,
the whereabouts of the boy's father have been unknown,
so they were having problems not being able to ask questions.
Don't tell me that...
Father.
Strike!
I'm going to give it my best shot.
I'm going to do even better
during the summer Koshien,
become a professional,
and make money
so that you won't have to work that hard.
You can count on me.
Father.
Hiroshi.
Hey, Kudo. Did you find it?
No, it's nowhere.
It seems that it's nowhere in the seats of this back net.
Darn it!
Why is everything else besides 13 blank?
The least he could do
is write the number on back of the uniform in parenthesis!
Hey, Hattori.
Maybe it's that...
There's a player with no number on the back of his uniform near the bench.
Right.
The ball boy, right?
I thought so, too.
I've checked the seats on the 13th aisle behind both benches,
but found nothing.
Then all that's left are the Alps stand or outfield seats.
Strike! Batter out!
Called out on strike, two out!
Ohgane High School's tie runner
cannot budge an inch from second base.
Konan High School is only one player away from winning the championship.
No good! If the game ends the man's going to blow himself up!
Darn it!
We don't have time to go around the Alps stands nor the outfield seats!
What is this?
Why is there nothing written?
That fact that nothing is written...
A zero? Nothing? White?
He hit the ball!
An interesting ball that goes up left!
Can he catch it?
Can he pull through?
Will the scores be reversed?
Will the game end?
Don't catch the ball, you idiot!
Konan High School is only one player away from winning the championship.
No good! If the game ends the man's going to blow himself up!
Darn it!
We don't have time to go around the Alps stands nor the outfield seats!
What is this?
Why is there nothing written?
That fact that nothing is written...
A zero? Nothing? White?
He hit the ball!
An interesting ball that goes up left!
Can he catch it?
Can he pull through?
Will the scores be reversed?
Will the game end?
Don't catch the ball, you idiot!
He missed the ball, he missed!
Okay! It's a tie!
Missed?
Wait a second. If I'm not mistaken...
While the ball goes travelling outfield,
the batter runners go from second to third base.
Hey, Kudo? What's up?
The runner dashes out from third base!
The ball goes from hook-up to back home!
Safe!
A running homerun.
Fantastic!
They reversed the score!
Heiji, what's up?
Did you find out about something?
Ask this kid here.
Huh?
See, look at this map.
As to the entrance of the stadium, there are entrance from number 1 to 24,
but the numbers 17 and 22 are missing.
Missing? Number of the entrance.
Number 17 and...
number 22.
That's true.
The reason there's no code number is probably because of this.
Now that you mentioned it,
I heard that they blocked off gate number 12 and 22
to make some kind of facility.
But which one is it? 17 or 22?
Where do we look?
We've no choice. Let's start from number 17.
Wait!
We don't seem to have that much time.
Now for the grand finale.
This is the bottom of the ninth inning with two out no runner!
Ohgane High School leads by one point.
The next batter is the one known for his three hits,
three base hits and one homer.
Number four, third, Nagashima.
They're going to pick on the weak point and make him walk.
He's the only one who's had hits, too.
They don't want to risk him striking a hit
and lose the game after all this.
Strike!
Right in the centre? Straight!
Hey, hey. Is this the end of the game?
Those two are just like Shinichi after all.
Just like?
Just like Shinichi back in junior high school
during the soccer championship game.
It was lost time with the other team leading by 1 point.
With less than a minute to go, the other team scored another point,
so it seemed to be over.
Wanting to see what kind of look Shinichi was wearing
when returning the ball to the centre.
I looked through the opera glass.
Then I saw him laughing.
Laughing?
Yes. I asked the other boys of the soccer club later
and you know what he was saying while laughing?
What? What?
I tell you, that guy...
Cool. If we win, we'll be legend.
Awesome.
And? How'd the game turn out?
Right, right!
They lost after all.
Life's not that easy, you see!
During the Penalty Kick.
Which means...
Right. With a minute left,
and Shinichi's goal and assistance,
they somehow made it to penalty kick.
But in the end it was Shinichi who didn't make the penalty kick, too.
But his rear view after that looked a bit cool.
Just a bit now, just a bit.
And Shinichi back then...
Those two kind of resembled him.
I mean, they refuse to give up.
The childish character of not wanting to lose.
I wonder if Heiji is that way, too.
Yes. I'm sure he is.
Strike two!
He swung at air! Two nothing!
Oh, no! They've been cornered!
It's no good, we won't make it.
Mr. Ohtaki,
in baseball, you never can tell until the very last minute!
If you have time thinking of something useless like that,
hurry and think of the meaning of the code, will you?
Right, but I mean really...
Big slugger of Konan is cornered!
Will he be able to pull the game out of the fire?
Nagashima?
Right! The missing number!
What?
There was no number in the parenthesis
because it's a retired number!
Retired number?
Between gates 21 and 23,
there is a booth for a professional team whose home ground is Koshien!
And there's a reference library where that retired number is displayed!
But Heiji,
isn't the area between 21 and 23 the place
where we were to begin with, the right stand?
Ran.
Darn it!
You mean she can't hear the phone because of the applause?
Pitcher Inao!
This is his 100th ball. There it goes!
He hit the ball!
Did it go up too high?
You idiot!
The centre spreads his arms out wide
and is waiting for the ball to come his way.
Konan High School, is it over for them?
Don't catch, don't catch.
Here goes, Hiroshi.
Don't catch it! Don't catch it!
I'm going over to where you are.
Don't catch the ball! Don't catch it!
Pitcher Inao!
This is his 100th ball. There it goes!
He hit the ball!
Did it go up too high?
You idiot!
The centre spreads his hands out wide
and is waiting for the ball to come his way.
Konan High School, is it over for them?
Don't catch it! Don't catch it!
Here goes, Hiroshi.
I'm going over to where you are.
The Ohgane nine are overjoyed because victory seems near!
The centre is still in position to catch the ball
and backs off slowly.
He still backs off.
He made it! He did it! It's a homerun!
It's a tie! A tie!
Konan High School, the bottom of the ninth inning at the very last minute
with two outs, thanks to their big slugger Nagashima
ties their opponent with a score of 2-2!
That high fly...
Made it.
Amazing.
What's this?
What is going on?
Dead ball!
Dead ball.
Two players in a row!
Ohgane's ace Inao suddenly pitches out of control!
Is the homerun a while ago affecting him after all?
That's why they should've let number four walk.
He puts on airs,
gets hit and goes out of control, talk about getting worked up.
This is going to be a walk-off homer.
Struck out swinging!
All right!
What's with that pitcher?
The game is 2-2 and will be extended!
What's this sound?
Behind your feet, Kazuha.
Huh?
The cell phone again.
Gosh.
Shall we answer it?
Hey! I found the last cell phone!
Come on and show yourself!
Heiji?
The game's not over yet.
It's an extended game.
An extended game?
Yes.
The Demon of Koshien favours showing itself just before game sets.
Hey?
He says it's an extended game
but the next code is nowhere!
Darn it!
Mr. Ohtaki, please look for him!
I'm sure he's still somewhere around here!
Okay!
Mail?
I'll look to the right. So please take care of the left, Mr. Ohtaki!
Okay!
Wait!
It seems we don't need to look for him anymore.
Just as expected of the finals of Koshien!
It's a great game!
Nonsense.
This isn't such a great place.
Right.
If you guys didn't root, encourage and cheer him on like that...
If this place didn't exist...
my son wouldn't have...
He dropped the ball, he dropped it!
He dropped an ordinary catcher's fly!
Ohgane High School is playing the bottom of the 10th inning
as if possessed by the Demon of Koshien!
Faced up against an irregular hit,
fielder's choice and error along with two outs and bases loaded,
they are in a pinch!
Moreover, the next batter
is number four,
Nagashima!
They're really up against the wall.
The Ohgane nine gather on the mound!
The disappointed catcher who had dropped the ball cannot lift his head.
Of course he can't.
He made a blooper in front of a large crowd like this.
The other nine members of the team will hold a grudge against him,
and the player as well as his parents, siblings and even his relatives
will face embarrassment.
Just for something like this.
They're laughing.
That pitcher's laughing.
Really?
They split running to their positions with smiles on their faces,
the nine members of Ohgane!
It can't be.
How can they keep laughing?
Why at this stage?
Because this is baseball.
You can't play baseball unless all nine members are there.
I'm sure that the pitcher of Ohgane
is thinking for himself as well as for the team
and for the catcher who made an error,
that he's going to slug this ball even if his arms break!
He hit the ball!
But the ball veered slightly to the left and is a foul!
Well, the number number that follows
probably wants to send the runner to home, so he's stepping out
and pitching the ball the way he is, even if the ball may hit him.
Although no one knows which team will win yet!
Absurd.
If they go out of their way and get hurt, they can't become professionals.
They could be throwing their whole life away, you know?
What is it anyway?
What is there to this Koshien?
Devastating! It's a right this time!
The ball has enough distance! Will it make it?
It's a foul! Another big foul!
There's nothing.
Of course, I think there are many kids here who want to stand out
and become professionals.
But that's all before the game.
Once you set foot on the field
and hear the voice play ball,
for those kids out there,
it's a battlefield of whether you win or lose.
-Strike! -Strike three!
With three players left on base, no points have been scored!
All they want to do is win,
and win the championship.
They have no feelings of profit or loss at this time.
It's just a very simple feeling.
And since you've been involved with baseball,
you should already know of things like this.
Isn't that right?
Teito Jitsugyou High School's advisor for their baseball club,
Mr. Yukio Torimitsu.
Your son was run over,
not because of the truck nor because of Koshien.
Your son tried too hard during club practice,
was pooped and braked too late.
Yeah, that's right.
I knew that.
I knew it, but unless I blamed it on somebody,
I couldn't stand it.
I had to do so to calm my heart
that had been torn apart from losing my beloved son.
But you wouldn't let me push the bomb button after all.
You, as well as both those teams.
Of course not.
This is a place where all the ones in Japan who hate to lose are gathered!
He's right!
Shall we go, then?
The top of the 11th inning top,
Ohgane High School will be batting.
Yes, that's right.
Yes.
Okay, thank you.
Somebody from this jurisdiction will be coming to pick you up.
It's amazing how you deciphered that code
that I thought up at the spur of the moment.
We figured out that 8, 1 and 2 was the Alps seat right away...
Thanks to the greatest man in Japan who likes to crack jokes.
What's up?
A cold?
Idiot! I'd never catch cold!
This seat is in the outfield, you know?
It's not the Alps seat, you know?
Such a great joke!
Sure, sure.
Next Conan's Hint:
"Service Coupon"
It's almost time for long awaited Christmas.
I wonder what I'll get for Christmas this year?
-What a kid! -I look to be in elementary school, you see.