Look at this. These amazing figures.
And these beautiful dioramas.
This is amazing!
Right? Right? The creator is Masahiro Kitajima.
He's the modeler who's getting the most attention right now.
Hmm... It's all so tiny, I don't really get it.
Ah, how unfortunate. Not understanding this technique...
What do you think, Conan-kun?
I don't know much about the trains,
but the dioramas are definitely amazing.
Every single branch is reproduced perfectly.
As expected of Conan-kun.
Kitajima-san is called a genius when it comes to natural forms.
On top of that, he's been selected to exhibit at this year's world championship...
Ah, Kitajima-san!
You're Masahiro Kitajima-san, right?
How do you make such amazing figures?
Well... I guess it's imagination.
The richer your imagination,
the better figures you can make.
I see. Imagination...
Masahiro-san.
Ah, Reika, you came.
Of course. This is your big day.
Cut it out. People are watching.
Hey, hey, you kids. Ah...
Come take a look at my figure too.
Wow, it's beautiful!
The colors are so pretty.
Haha... yeah, I guess.
I'm sure you all know this too,
but this is from the most popular robot anime right now.
Huh?
I made it working all night. Pretty amazing, right?
A grown adult doing this... Huh?
Yes. On this day, at this convention hall,
the Figure Model Festival was being held,
and we had come to see it.
♪~♪
The blackness of shadows, the density of darkness—
the light of reasoning cuts right through them.
An incident occurs at the event hall.
The secret hidden in the figures.
See through the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~♪
"A Much Too Perfect Figurine"
Hey, Mitsuhiko, let's go home already.
I'm hungry.
Wait a minute.
What color would match the Kamen Yaiba I'm making now...
(Female staff screams) Whoa...
Someone!
Conan-kun?
Ah...
Whoa!
H-hey, Conan.
One stab in the chest with a blade, huh?
Hmm? This person...
Kitajima-san? Ah.
(Hiroto Kenji panting) (Female staff screams)
Stop! Move!
Ah!
Ugh... ah...
Ah, ah, ahhh...
Are you okay, Haibara? Ayumi?
Yeah, I'm okay. Ai-chan saved me.
...Geez, get it together.
Sorry, sorry.
We heard the staff member's scream,
and when we rushed over, this Kitajima-san was collapsed on the ground.
...is that right?
Yeah, we found him.
The victim is Masahiro Kitajima-san.
That's right.
He's one of Japan's top modelers.
Hmm... Top modeler?
A professional who makes plastic models.
Hmm... Ahahaha...
Ah, okay, okay.
You kids should go home now.
That's not fair. We even caught the culprit, you know?
Ai-chan did, right?
Chief Megure. Hmm?
We've brought Hiroto-san.
Yes.
Ah! It's this man.
There's no doubt he's the culprit.
Hmm... Ah, whoa!
His name is Kenji Hiroto.
He's apparently an editor for a plastic model magazine.
There's no mistake about it.
That's right. I've been saying it from the start.
I just came to interview Kitajima.
Then why did you run away?
Ah, I... was just surprised.
I mean, Kitajima was in that state...
Um... is this man not the culprit?
No, he wasn't carrying any weapon.
Huh? More importantly, Agasa-hakase,
it's probably best not to bring the children to places like this...
Ah, I understand. Come on, everyone, let's go home.
Huh? Come on, let's go.
But it's just getting started! What a bummer.
Sorry about this, everyone.
Hey, Takagi-keiji.
From when Kitajima-san died until we found him,
how much time had passed?
Ah... a few minutes.
The weapon was definitely a sharp blade?
Yeah, some kind of knife.
But you still haven't found it?
Yeah, we've been searching.
What about the staff member who came to bring tea?
She didn't have anything like that.
The weapon hasn't been found...
He's definitely the culprit. No question about it.
I wonder. Huh?
From when Kitajima-san was killed until he was found,
only a few minutes passed.
If that man is the culprit, there's a high chance he still has the weapon.
Or he hid it somewhere nearby.
But there's no sign of it anywhere...
I see.
Where did the weapon go?
Um, detective... what should I do?
Ah, sorry.
The inspector wants to speak with you,
so please wait a little longer.
Huh? It's the robot guy.
Ah, you kids were here too.
What's wrong, mister?
Well, I was in the waiting room over there the whole time.
Then I heard a commotion,
and when I went outside, there was a staff member,
and they told me something terrible had happened to Kitajima-san...
And you've been with that staff member ever since?
Huh? Uh...
Ah, yes. This man was with that staff member the whole time.
Was there a knife near Morishita-san?
No, neither he nor the waiting room had one.
So this man isn't the culprit either.
Ah, if it isn't Morishita.
Hiroto-san.
Did you kill Kitajima-san? Wasn't it Hiroto-san?
Huh? Huh?
Wha... what?
You do some harsh interviews, you know.
Taking figures without permission, touching them even when told not to.
Kitajima-san told all the other modelers
to never agree to be interviewed by you.
Hmph. Look who's talking, Morishita.
You're suspicious too.
I heard you borrowed quite a bit of money from Kitajima.
And you couldn't pay it back for years, so he was putting pressure on you.
Shut up! Be quiet!
(Footsteps) Hmm?
Masahiro-san, is it true? Was Masahiro-san killed?
Ah, hey, you...
Masahiro-san, Masahiro-san!
Masahiro-san... ugh, why...?
Here comes the main suspect. Hmm?
I wondered who it was, but it's Hiroto-san. And Morishita-san too.
You two are the culprits, aren't you? Huh?
Give me a break.
I heard you were having a rough time with a breakup recently too.
A breakup? That's...
Masahiro-san and I even promised to get married.
I doubt it.
Morishita, you've heard about it too, right?
Huh? Ah... well...
You kids.
Hakase, please take the children...
Ah, sorry.
Come on, let's go. (Detective Boys chatter)
Come on, hurry up. We're going home.
Ah... and we were just getting started.
I thought we were finally about to corner the culprit.
Huh? Where's Conan-kun?
Huh? ...What?
Reika Kameyama-san.
Where were you when the incident occurred?
I was outside.
After we met at the venue, Masahiro-san contacted me by email.
He said, "Wait for me at the river plaza next to the hall."
But Masahiro-san never came, no matter how long I waited,
so I came to the waiting room, and...
this...
Indeed, an email was sent from Kitajima-san's phone
addressed to Reika-san.
11:25 AM. Ten minutes before the incident occurred.
That means...
after sending this email,
Kitajima-san was killed.
Hmm? Hey, Conan.
The police officers?
Yeah, they're making a fuss over there.
Can you reach it? No.
Officer, what's wrong? Huh?
Ah, something fell between the vending machine and the wall,
and we can't reach it.
I'm small, so I think I can reach it. Leave it to me.
Ugh... grr...
That's it, right?
Genta, a handkerchief.
Oh? Oh... yeah.
Okay, here we go... ugh...
Okay, nice, Genta.
Okay, got it.
Oh!
This is...
Bloodstains?
Kameyama-san.
Do you recognize this brooch?
Huh? Ah... yes, it's mine.
There were faint bloodstains on it.
According to forensics, it's definitely Kitajima-san's blood.
Ah, no way. That brooch, since yesterday...
Yes, I couldn't find it since yesterday...
When yesterday?
At night. I brought a celebration bouquet.
From that time on...
Um... I just remembered something.
Actually... I saw it.
No! I'm never breaking up with you!
I'm going to...
go out into the world as a modeler from now on.
You're in the way.
That's...
Was that your plan from the beginning?
Hmph.
How cruel.
I'll never forgive you. I'll kill you.
Is that true, Kameyama-san?
Ah... y-yes, I said that.
But I didn't do it.
Hahaha... Ah.
So you're the culprit after all. Is that how it went?
You received the email. You were afraid of being broken up with,
so you went to the waiting room.
But in the end, you got into an argument...
After that, you
immediately went outside and pretended to be waiting for Kitajima,
and threw the weapon into the river. I see.
Kameyama-san, we'll need to hear more details from you.
It seems necessary.
But... I didn't do it.
Ah.
Ah... so that woman is the culprit.
But it's a little frustrating.
Yeah. They treated us like children until the very end.
Damn it. I'll take out this anger on dinner.
A brooch... blood spatter...
It's still strange.
Hey, kids. Ah.
Nice footwork, little lady.
Oh, thank you.
What, did you come to get revenge?
Stop it.
I don't feel like fighting.
Believe it or not, I'm actually feeling down.
I missed out on a scandal.
Scandal? Do you mean about Kitajima-san?
Mister, what is this scandal?
Whoa, that's none of you kids' business. See ya.
Ah...
Ah... I see, I see.
Wait a minute, please.
What?
To these kids, Kitajima-san was a hero.
If that man had any hidden secrets,
won't you tell us?
Hmph. Dreams are best kept as dreams, you know?
No, I think knowing the truth
would be much better for these kids.
Well, I guess it's fine. The guy's dead anyway.
The truth is, there were rumors
that Kitajima had someone making figures for him.
Huh? Making figures for him?
Yeah. His natural forms
were outstanding, even among modelers.
But originally, he wasn't that skilled
of a modeler.
But then, in the past few years, suddenly...
On top of that,
he's never let anyone watch him make a figure.
I see. So that's why you snuck into the waiting room
to confirm it?
Yeah.
That's right. I've been bothered by something
from the moment we arrived at this venue.
Hmm?
Conan-kun, what's wrong?
Is it this?
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
Doesn't this color look like the one in Kitajima-san's diorama?
Huh? Ah, it's Kamen Yaiba.
I'm using the same color for the Yaiba I'm making now.
So the finish is also...
Yes, no doubt about it. It's the same color.
I see. So that's how it is.
Hmm? Ah... huh? You kids are still here?
Go home already... wait?
No, I mean, Agasa-hakase.
What is this? Why did you suddenly gather everyone?
Sorry to suddenly call you all together.
Regarding this case,
there are several things that bother me.
First, Reika-san's brooch that was found in the hallway.
The brooch had Kitajima-san's blood on it.
But take a close look at her clothes.
There's no blood anywhere on them.
Would blood spatter from stabbing someone
only get on the brooch and nowhere else?
Then someone put blood on the brooch
to frame her?
But that's...
And there's another strange thing.
Huh?
Regarding you, Morishita-san.
Huh? Me?
Yes. When I first met you,
you said it was from a popular robot anime,
and that you made it working all night. Your clothes were
stained with paint.
Yes, that outfit. However...
(Footsteps) Hmm?
Take a look at that robot.
It was made by Morishita-san. The colors are vivid.
They're completely different from the colors on his clothes.
Why is that?
Inside Morishita-san's paint case,
there was paint the same color as the stains on his clothes.
This is it.
And for some reason, this color is the same
as the color used in Kitajima-san's dioramas.
There were rumors that Kitajima-san
had someone making figures for him.
Morishita-san, wasn't it you?
The one making them for him.
Y-yes, that's right. I was forced to make them.
My mother was sick, so I borrowed money from Kitajima.
But the interest was outrageous, and the debt grew until I couldn't pay it back.
Then that guy...
In that case, Morishita,
make my share too, okay?
And on top of that, Kitajima-san was planning
to enter the world championship with your figures.
That must have made you hate him.
So you killed Kitajima-san.
No! That has nothing to do with this incident.
But if that's the case,
everything fits together perfectly.
Last night,
you happened to see Kitajima-san and Reika-san arguing.
At that time, you picked up the brooch
that Reika-san dropped as she left.
Then today, you killed Kitajima-san,
got his blood on the brooch,
and threw it behind the vending machine in the hallway
to frame Reika-san.
Of course, you didn't forget to call Reika-san by email
to eliminate her alibi.
Ha, hahaha...
Haha, hahaha... Huh?
Give me a break.
You're not seriously buying this nonsense, are you?
I didn't do it.
That's right. The weapon. Where is the weapon?
I didn't have anything like that on me.
When it comes to natural forms,
Kitajima-san was said to be a genius.
But the truth is, that was you,
the one making them for him.
Inside your paint case, there was a color like this.
Natural Light Green.
I know it because it's used on Kamen Yaiba too.
There's one natural thing of the same color in this room.
Everyone, which one is it?
That one! That one!
Ah, ah...
I'll never forgive you. I'll kill you.
Kitajima-san said
that the important thing for making figures
is to have a rich imagination.
So you imagined it too, didn't you, Morishita-san?
Seeing these flowers that Reika-san brought.
(Metal sound) Ah.
Ah.
I see.
You painted the blade in advance and then committed the crime...
It's all Kitajima's fault.
He told me to make them for him, so I...
I'm not the bad one!
(Crying)
♪~♪
Everyone praised us like crazy.
And they even gave us these plastic models.
That's great.
But still...
Okay.
Conan-kun, please.
Huh? Me too.
I'm making Yaiba right now.
Once I make it, I'll get hungry.
Haha. Food, food!
H-hey, wait a minute. Make them yourselves.
Whether it's four or five,
it's the same, right? Huh?
Ah, ah, ah... Haah... Food, food!
H-hey, you guys!
Well then, casually, a sixth one too.
Hey... come on!
Take this. Huh?
Please don't open it until you have all seven.
Huh? Someone died?
This is clearly a suicide.
No. Hmm?
It might be murder. Huh?
So you prepared one outfit... is that what you're saying?
That's... if I remember correctly...
Next Conan,
"The Neighbor at the Site is an Ex-Boyfriend (Part 1)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Will".
Four suicide notes? Heave-ho.
The Professor's quiz is interesting. Heave-ho...
I slipped...