"Murderer Shinichi Kudo"
Hey, are you all right, Conan?
I'm fine.
I drank the cold medicine that Dr. Agasa gave me.
But, your voice sounds terrible.
I think it's better we head back
and I take care of you at home.
He'll be just fine.
That wonder drug that was given to the brat a while ago,
will soon cure him.
What wonder drug?
Hey, don't tell me it's that Chinese liquor called Baikaru
that you brought with you
when you first visited my detective agency?
No, no.
It's medicine that's way more effective than liquor.
Right, boy?
I wonder if the person
that we're going to see is really okay.
"Mr. Heiji Hattori" -Because it said in the letter
that he wanted to talk to Shinichi.
Isn't the person going to be disappointed
if he finds that Shinichi's not with us?
Really?
Yes, something about that person
finding that Shinichi made a mistake in deducing
a murder case that he solved a year ago.
So the person wants to meet him and talk about it.
That's why, in consideration of that mistake in deduction,
we're going to reinvestigate the case and reveal the truth.
Well, I mailed Shinichi.
So he just might decide to show up.
Shinichi might come?
But, why would the guy send the letter to you?
Of course because I'm Shinichi's best friend.
Well, even if he did try to contact me by mail or phone,
I'm not living here now anyway.
So, he probably got impatient
and decided send mail to high school detective Heiji Hattori,
since he's in the same profession.
But, what's this about a mistake in deduction?
If I'm not mistaken the sender was...
It's a letter from a man called Makoto Okuda
who lives in a place called East Okuho Village
on the outskirts of Okuho-cho.
You know him, don't you?
Yes. I think it's the young man who helped us
when we investigated the murder case
that occurred in that village.
Do you have a cold?
Well, I'll take the letter that's addressed to you
that's enclosed together with mine when I go over,
so read it well, okay?
"Shinichi Kudo" -I'll bet it's filled with foul remarks
about your deduction,
but it'll be great stimulus to get rid of that cold of yours.
The only case I can recall
that occurred in East Okuho Village is...
A mistake in deduction?
It sure bugs me.
A crisis is gracefully revived.
The table is turned and the mystery solved.
Shinichi loses his memory and is not himself.
He cannot deduce the case together with Heiji.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
"Murderer Shinichi Kudo"
What? His whereabouts is unknown?
Are you serious?
"Residents Division" -Yes.
A missing persons search was out for him six months ago.
Well, Makoto always wanted to go to the city anyway.
"Makoto Okuda (19)" -The villagers say
that he probably left home for the city
and is part-timing or something there.
And? What do you want with Makoto Okuda?
I got a letter from him last week.
It said that he wants to talk
about the deduction mistake that was made by Shinichi Kudo
when he solved a murder case
that occurred in this village a year ago.
Who?
He asked me to bring Shinichi Kudo.
What this?
Liar!
You're friends of that liar, right?
Liar?
Hey, Sonny.
At any rate,
if you want to know about the case, go to the village police box.
We have nothing to tell you people.
What the heck did that high school brat detective do anyway?
Ran, haven't you heard anything from Shinichi?
No.
Where's Conan?
That brat said that he'd head off for the inn ahead of us.
I guess his cold got worse.
I'm going back to the inn too then.
I don't want to leave him there alone.
Well, I guess the truth is he didn't want to go there
and have to face me pointing out his deduction mistake.
Dear Mr. Shinichi Kudo,
I've found evidence that there was a mistake in your deduction.
I suggest that we should talk things out just the two of us,
so you can save face as a detective.
I'd like to see you at the mountain hut
where we both first ran into each other.
Makoto Okuda.
Excuse me.
The cold medicine that doctor got me
isn't making me feel better at all.
Are you Shinichi Kudo?
His voice is changed.
Who is it?
The door is locked.
Hey, wait! Hey!
Darn, my throat...
I've lost my voice because of this cold.
The window...
and door as well...
I've got to find an escape route.
This thing I'm feeling...
It can't be...
Doctor, did you see the bottle of medicine
that I had way inside the drawer?
You mean that cold medicine.
The container was that of cold medicine,
but the content is the medicine that I made.
What?
Don't tell me you drank it?
No. Well...
Bummers.
I've got to get out of here fast.
What? It was a prototype anecdote for APTX 4869?
Yes, that's right.
I made it thinking to secretly try it on him
when he comes to spend the night here next time.
That medicine was the miracle drug
that could maybe change his body that had become that of a child
to the body of a high school student that it used to be.
You've got to call him quick.
If he transforms into his original body in front of everyone,
we can't afford that to happen.
Conan is not back at the inn yet?
No. I asked a villager
and was told that he saw a boy wearing glasses
go into the forest alone.
Then, why don't you call him on his cell phone?
"Out of service"
No good.
This place is out of service range.
What the heck is he doing?
And Conan has a cold too.
That troublemaker.
Sorry, officer.
We'll go to the site of the murder later.
Okay, see you later then.
Conan!
Where are you?
Come on out!
Don't tell me that he...
that something was written on that letter addressed to him,
and he was summoned to go to some strange place?
Hey, did you hear about it?
What's up?
A stark naked man was afloat in the lake.
Yes. I heard.
My mom just took a blanket over.
Hey.
It wasn't an elementary school kid, was it?
No.
It was a young man,
probably a high school student or something.
-High... -High school student?
Over there, over there.
It's that man wrapped in a blanket.
Shinichi?
Shinichi!
Why? Why are you here, Shinichi?
Shinichi...
Is that my name?
Shinichi?
What kind of nonsense are you saying?
You're the high school detective of the East, Shinichi Kudo.
Talking funny like that isn't making anybody laugh.
Detective?
Don't tell me that Shinichi...
Lost his memory?
I don't know
who I am or where I am.
Shinichi?
Hey, isn't this the guy, Shinichi Kudo?
If so, we shouldn't have rescued him.
Hey, watch your mouth.
Could you lend me something to wear?
I don't seem to have any clothes on.
Okay. I'll lend you my clothes.
Talk about a voice hoarse from a cold.
Just like Conan.
That's right, we've got to find Conan quick.
No, I don't think we need to worry about him.
Well, the thing is...
What?
He took the train and left for home?
All by himself?
Yes.
I'd completely forgotten that he told me so
before we went to the town office.
He said he didn't want his cold to get worse,
so he wanted to go on home.
But, there's nobody back at the office.
I'm sure that he told me
that he was going to stay over at old man Agasa's place
or something.
What's your problem talking like that?
I said I just simply forgot.
At any rate, this place is out of service range,
so if we want to check on the whereabouts of that brat,
we've got to go back to the inn where there's a phone.
We're taking this troublesome detective brat
that forgot everything with us too.
Forget about trying to put sense back into him.
I'm sure he met the you know what in the forest.
-You know what of the forest? -What a scare, scare...
Hey, hold it you!
What do you know about the forest?
You look pretty good in Heiji's clothes.
Don't you think so, Ran?
Where's Ran?
It seems that Ran's more worried about the glasses brat
than that high school detective.
What? You gave me the wrong medicine?
Don't tell me you gave me the medicine
that the little lady made at the school festival?
Yes, that's right.
It's the antidote for APTX 4869
that shrunk Shinichi's body.
In other words, it's a drug that will return his body
to that of a high school student that he originally was.
I mistook that drug that Ai made for cold medicine
and carelessly gave it to you.
I mean gramps, careless is not the word for it.
By the way,
is it true that Shinichi has lost his memory?
Yes, it seems he doesn't remember anything.
Well, I guess it's better for him that way, though.
I mean with his original body from here on now,
it'll be more convenient for him and all I guess.
Stupid.
That drug is only a prototype.
There may be a slight discrepancy
but the longest the effect will continue is more or less 24 hours.
Twenty four hours?
You've got to make sure he regains his memory by then
or else we're in big trouble.
Why? If it's his memory,
we can work on it slowly after he becomes small again.
What are you saying?
If two people get amnesia at the same time,
no matter how dense, it'll be more than obvious
that the two are one and the same.
Especially her.
True.
If that should happen,
I'm sure she'll find out
what's going on no matter what.
About who made him drink the drug and for what.
I wonder if she'd be able to hold the truth
that she finds out about all within herself?
Well, in order not to corner her
into a dangerous predicament like we're in,
will you please bring him back here
before he turns back into a child again?
I'll take care of everything else here.
Okay, you can count on me.
Heiji, what's all the whispering about?
Please put me on the phone.
They hung up.
What?
Well, I was told that he drank medicine
and is fast asleep so not to worry.
Okay.
Okay then, let's eat dinner too and hit the sack right away.
After all, we've got to back to Beika-cho tomorrow.
I thought we were going to take it easy
and stay for 2 nights and three days?
The schedules been changed.
We've got to get Kudo to a doctor as soon as possible, right?
Let's take Shinichi to that murder site too then.
He may just remember something.
What the heck are you talking about?
Wait.
Maybe she's got a point there.
My god, what a mess!
The entire house is messed up.
"Officer Shiroyama (46)" -The room was left as is, since the incident,
in keeping with his wishes.
His?
Daiki who was staying over at a relative's house
and escaped disaster on the night of the incident a year ago.
He's the brat that we ran into at the town office.
Then, the two people who are in the picture on both sides of him are...
Daiki's parents who died because of that incident.
He's Mr. Takinori Hinohara, who was the village head back then
and his wife, Shoko.
Mr. Hinohara was a very cheerful person
"East Okuho Village Office" -and was liked by all the villagers.
He served as village head for more or less 20 years or so.
Therefore, that disaster that struck a year ago
really broke the hearts of the villagers.
And this is the aftermath of the incident?
These black footprints.
Yes. This is...
the blood of Mrs. Hinohara who was stabbed part way down the stairs
and stepped on by the murderer
which after he seems to have walked around the room
with his shoes on, leaving footprints behind.
How terrible.
These shoe prints continue on quite a long way
over to that veranda.
It sure is a spacious veranda.
The shoe prints return back from here.
I see.
So, the village head was made to fall over from here.
And? What about the murder weapon,
or was anything taken?
The knife that was the murder weapon wasn't found in the house,
but the jewelry and antiques were gone.
The only thing left behind were the bloody shoe prints.
The same shoe prints were found going from the back door
to the asphalt outside and then back.
Are you sure that those were the only shoe prints?
Yes.
It was raining until the day before the incident
and the ground was muddy, you see.
Which means that the armed robber after killing Mr. and Mrs. Hinohara,
made off with the jewel and valuables in the house
and fled by car.
And? Who did Kudo say the murderer was?
Don't tell me that he branded an innocent citizen
to be the armed robber.
No, well the thing is...
Double suicide.
Shinichi Kudo there deduced this case to be
a forced double suicide that Mr. Hinohara committed.
Forced double suicide?
By the way, who are you, young lady?
I'm the classmate of Makoto
who was staying over at this house after his parents passed away.
See, he's in that picture over there too,
behind the village head.
Hold it.
Makoto, you mean Makoto Okuda?
"Moegi Hikawa (19)" -Yes, that's right.
He, Makoto Okuda, discovered the corpses
and was the first to be suspected of being the murderer.
Well, on the day the murder was committed,
Makoto was staying over at a hotel in the city
to take the entrance exam for a university,
so he was cleared immediately.
And let me ask you,
where's that Makoto now?
He's the one who sent a letter asking for me to bring Kudo here
because he found that Kudo had made a mistake in deduction.
Yet his whereabouts are unknown?
What the heck is going on?
His whereabouts are not unknown.
He's probably been killed.
What?
Just what do you mean?
The people of this village say that Makoto is part-timing in the city,
but since he was adopted by this family,
he probably inherited a huge.
So, you're saying that somebody who wanted to take that money from him.
Yes. It's unthinkable
that Makoto would not get in touch with anyone for half a year.
Besides, the one who killed him
is probably that thing in the forest.
That thing in the forest?
If so, who for what reason sent me a letter like that?
What the heck is Kudo's deduction blooper?
The motive for Mr. Hinohara committing forced double suicide
was because his doctor declared that he had cancer
and he was full of despair.
The problem arose
when Mr. Kudo publicized the truth a year ago.
Who are you?
"Misato Kawauchi (36)" -I'm a reporter for Tohto News,
Misato Kawauchi.
I'm sorry,
I helped myself in because the door wasn't locked.
And? So, what was the problem?
Some days later,
a nurse at the hospital let it out with a slip of her tongue.
She told him that although he did have cancer, the tumor was benign
and it would be completely cured with surgery.
Hearing this, the he seemed very happy.
What?
Hey, Kudo. What the heck is going on?
Explain.
Kudo.
I don't know... I don't know anything.
I don't know what's going on.
Kudo.
I see.
I finally got it.
I understand now why the villagers don't like this detective kid.
Yes.
He's a horrendous villain who disgraced the village head
who was loved by everyone.
But, how frightening.
If that's true it means that the murderer
is still out there somewhere, right?
There's a rumor going around among the villagers
saying it's that you know who in the forest that's done it.
Hey, I heard that just a while ago.
But what the heck is it about?
Is there something in the forest?
It's folklore that's been relayed for generations in this village.
Folklore?
I remember frequently being told the folklore
when I was a child too.
I was told not to look at its eyes if I run into in the forest.
That if you don't look away, you'll be cursed
and become prey to Death.
Death?
What is it, Ran?
It's nothing.
I just felt a bit weird.
That stuff is just fairy tale.
True. The story about Death
is a story of the god of the district who protects the land
from those who dare mess around with it.
A folklore that is often heard of in rural areas.
That is until a young woman died in this lake...
9 years ago.
Oh no.
You mean something's really inside this forest?
Yes.
At sundown of the 3rd day
after the villagers went all out searching
for the young woman that never came back from the forest.
A rumor started going around among the tired villagers
that she'd been punished for breaking the rule
that had been set from ancient times
by entering the forest at night and angered Death,
the guardian of the forest.
The father of the young lady who heard this rumor
ignored all those who tried to stop him,
went into the forest just around sundown
to look for her and never came back.
It was two days later
that the people found the corpse of the young lady
who had slipped into the lake and drowned.
If I'm not mistaken her name was...
Tamako Okuda.
Okuda?
Right.
She was the younger sister of Makoto Okuda
who you said sent you a letter.
Then, the father who you mentioned
went into the forest to search for her was...
Yes. Makoto's father.
He hasn't been found to this day.
Maybe Makoto's father was also fell prey to Death.
But I wonder if it's credible to conclude
that an imaginary figure committed the crime,
just by the information that we have now.
I didn't believe the story at first either.
But...
I saw it.
I saw the white haired monster hiding on top of a tree
inside the crimson forest at sundown,
with its teeth showing and sneering.
What?
Maybe you mistook a monkey or something for it.
It wasn't a monkey.
A person from the town office said that he saw it just last week.
But, it's strange?
Why would the village and his wife be killed by that monster?
Did he go into the forest at night?
The redevelopment of the village.
Mr. Hinohara was planning to build
a large tourist facility in the forest.
I see.
That's why he angered Death.
Yes, therefore, the plan went down the drain.
As for the hero of this village, Hinohara,
all he was trying to do was do something
about the rural exodus that was occurring in this village.
Hero?
You don't know?
During his younger days,
he was a track runner nominated as candidate
for track in the Olympics representing Japan.
I forgot what exactly he competed in.
But, if you'd like to, do you want to go and see
upstairs to his room on the 2nd floor?
Really.
He seems to have competed in many contests.
It doesn't say what contest it was.
How come only the medals are here?
I wonder if he took all the strings off?
It's the statue of the Deva Kings.
Let's see.
It's pretty heavy.
It's exquisitely well made.
But why is there only one?
The Deva Kings are a pair of two wrath-filled
and muscular guardians of the Buddha.
Since that's the Unzo with its mouth closed,
there would usually be an Azo with its mouth open too, right?
The Azo of the Nioh statue,
on the night the incident occurred,
disappeared from this house together with the jewelry of Mrs. Hinohara.
I see. The culprit stole it?
Is this expensive?
Yes, it's the masterpiece of a famous wood carver of the Edo Era,
and at present its probably no less than 5 million yen.
Five... five million?
Hold it. Isn't it funny?
Why'd the culprit take only one of it?
It's worth more if they're a pair, right?
I wonder...
That seems to have bothered Mr. Shinichi Kudo,
who came here a year ago too.
Kudo, can't you remember anything yet?
Kudo.
Ran.
-Where? -Over this way.
Come over to this room over here.
You'd be surprised.
Shinichi's picture?
This is a picture of when Shinichi first did an interview for a magazine.
How nostalgic.
It's been enlarged.
It sure is big.
All the cases that Shinichi solved are filed.
Whose room is this?
It's Makoto's room.
Makoto worshipped this high school detective you see,
that's why when he heard that Shinichi Kudo
was going to come help solve the case,
Makoto was really happy
saying that he was sure Shinichi would solve the case.
But, the conclusion he came to was that,
the village head committed a double suicide.
Makoto was really depressed too
because he lost his mother
who fell sick when he was little.
And now Mr. Hinohara who adopted him as his son,
when he thought that he'd be alone for life was.
They were a typical blood type O family.
He told me that Mr. and Mrs. Hinohara,
as well as their son, Daiki were all very pleasant,
so he felt very comfortable and that he couldn't be happier.
So, it's hard to believe
that the village head would do anything to hurt his wife.
But, I told myself over and over again
that I had no choice but to accept it
because Makoto believed that you're a renown detective.
But it turns out that the truth of the case
is not what that renown detective concluded.
The detective was wrong
when he said that the Mr. Hinohara
was told by the doctor that he had cancer
and committed double suicide in despair.
Right. Makoto tried to get in touch you
by writing letters and calling you repeatedly,
but he was disappointed because he couldn't get a hold of you at all.
He said that he even personally went to see you
to ask you to reinvestigate the case, but you weren't in.
Well, yes...
Because he shrunk and wasn't at home.
But, only now you come
and have amnesia to make things worse?
You got to be kidding.
I want to be alone.
Would you please let me stay in this room alone for a while?
I feel as if I can maybe remember something.
Okay.
Well leave you alone for a while then.
Take your time and try to remember, okay?
Which means that the village head's son, Daiki
is staying with you Mr. Shiroyama?
Yes, Makoto was doing likewise till six months ago too.
You know, it's been bothering me from a while ago but...
Why is his name still Makoto Okuda?
If he was adopted by Mr. Hinohara,
wouldn't his name have been changed to Makoto Hinohara?
Yes. That's what's written on the family register.
But, he felt that it would be too audacious for him
to take after the village heads name,
so he used to go by his previous last name, Okuda.
Shinichi's come out.
And were you able to remember something?
Well, no need to be depressed.
I'm sure that you'll regain your memory in time.
I was wondering what kind of trick you had up sleeve,
but I guess you haven't come up with anything yet.
Trick?
Yes.
Mr. Kudo, I know what you're up to.
Oh, my. What's with that look of yours?
Don't tell me that you thought I didn't realize either?
Well, if you decide to give in and confess to everything,
come to the Kotoh Inn where I'm staying.
If you do,
I'll write a very nice article about you in the papers
about the truth that you're trying to hide
the fact that you cannot speak of.
Don't tell anyone, all right.
A truth that he cannot speak of.
Gee, that newspaper reporter lady wasn't very likable.
What did she mean by know what Shinichi is up to?
Well, what we know for now is...
that this detective kid made a mistake deducing this case
which can be none other than armed robbery case
as forced double suicide,
as well as totally mistaking the motive for murder.
And one more thing.
Within this forest,
an unidentifiable creature or something is still here hiding.
Kazuha.
What if...
Just what if... This is just what if okay?
Yes.
The person you've been wanting to see and love
suddenly appears in front of you
and turns out to be amnesic.
What would you do, Kazuha?
Well...
I'd just break down and cry.
I'd be so happy to see him
and at the same time be so sad that he had forgotten all about me.
I'd be overwhelmed with emotion.
If you can't feel this way,
I'd say you don't love that person.
He'd be no more than a friend.
I thought so too.
No, no.
I was just talking about stupid me just now.
I don't feel a thing.
Only...
All I feel is that Shinichi has gone far away.
Don't worry.
Once he regains his memory, everything will return to normal.
Yes.
I wonder what's gotten into me?
Oh no. Rain.
This is bad.
Let's run to the inn.
Hurry, hurry.
"Okuho Inn" -What? Shinichi is not in the room?
Yes, when I got up in the morning
his side of the bed was empty.
Oh, no.
Hey.
I asked a villager just now
and he told me he saw Shinichi go into Mr. Hinohara's residence
early in the morning.
Don't tell me that he got his memory back?
Hey, Kudo!
Kudo's shoes and a woman's shoes?
Are you in there, Kudo?
There he is.
You got your memory back, right?
That's why you came here, right, Kudo?
Blood?
What's up?
You're bleeding profusely.
Hey, Kudo.
What's going on?
What happened?
I don't know.
My mind just went blank.
When I snapped back to myself, I was here.
Did I do it?
Did I... kill her?
She's still alive.
So you were here after all, detective kid.
Isn't she the newspaper reporter?
What happened?
She's bleeding badly.
Explain later.
Hurry call an ambulance and the police.
No, all you need to call is the ambulance.
Why?
Somebody did this to her, right?
How can you be so dense?
If we call the police with things the way they are,
the police will deem Shinichi the culprit.
Oh no...
Don't tell me that you...
Idiot. Kudo would never stab anyone.
This is a trap.
Somebody set it up to look as if Kudo did it.
After all there seems to be many who hate Kudo in this village.
Besides, if Kudo's taken to the police now...
No matter if he's innocent,
he'll have to be interrogated for a long period of time.
If the drug that will return his body back to a child's takes effect,
it'll be more than I can handle.
Call the ambulance, Kazuha.
Pops, bring the car here and hide Kudo, will you?
Okay.
Yes.
That's the siren of an ambulance...
There are the sounds of police cars too.
It's getting closer.
Who called them?
I see.
You had doubts about a solved murder case
that occurred here a year ago,
despite having come here last night,
came back here again and found
newspaper reporter Ms. Misato Kawauchi,
stabbed in the stomach and lying here.
Yes, Detective Kogoro Mouri?
Yes, well I guess.
And when you came, are you sure that no one else
other than the victim was here?
Yes. Right?
Yes.
Well, the murder weapon is here,
so if we conduct investigation of the hardware at the entrance,
well probably come up with the culprit right away.
Hardware?
In police jargon, it means footprints.
But, how can you figure it out?
The ground is muddy from the rain all night yesterday,
so shoe prints are left on the ground.
The prints of the victim
and the culprit are left clear on the ground.
But, officer. They could be our shoe prints.
No. You all came here after the sun rose
and the ground more or less dried,
so your shoe prints are shallow.
We already matched your prints with those of your shoes at the entrance,
so there's no doubt.
What bothers me are the shoes prints of the culprit
who came here at the break of day when the ground while still wet.
Why did the culprit go outside from the backdoor of this house
after the ground dried?
Moreover, the number of people who came here
after the ground dried is supposed to be four,
but there are only three here.
What's more, the owner of the fourth shoes print also went outside
for some reason from the backdoor.
I wonder if you, Mr. Sleeping Kogoro can solve this mystery?
Oh, well...
I can't say anything yet.
Listen, Kudo.
I know it's sort of cramped in there,
but hang in there, okay?
Hold up for a while
until I find the real culprit and let you out of here.
The effect of the drug according to the little lady will keep
keep for 24 hours.
I've got to solve the case completely before sundown at all cost.
Heiji.
I can't take lying any longer.
She's right, Heiji.
I think we should tell the truth
and cooperate with the police in their investigation.
It's easy for them to say because they don't know anything.
Well, the situation looks really bad, though.
It seems that today the people who went to that house
before the police came, were we four,
the victim, Mrs. Kawauchi
and that detective kid, but no one else.
Is that true?
Yes.
The surroundings of the house was investigated with great care,
but only the shoes prints of the six, were found, I heard.
Shinichi's shoes are those that you bought for him
at the store of this village.
No matter how much we try to hide Shinichi,
I'm sure they'll find him right away.
A trick.
Somebody summoned the two,
drugged Shinichi putting him to sleep
wore his clothes
and stabbed Mrs. Kawauchi in the stomach.
But, if so...
That somebody's shoes prints should be left here, shouldn't it?
That's why I'm saying a tricks been used.
There's got to be a way.
Wait a second.
The house should've been locked.
How'd the culprit make it inside?
Neither Kudo nor Mrs. Kawauchi have the key to the house, do they?
Right.
When we went there last night
the police officer called Mr. Shiroyama opened the door for us.
That's right.
Why'd that police officer have the key to the house?
I got it from Daiki.
Did anybody besides you have the key to the house?
I have the keys that the head of the house
and his wife had also.
If anyone else were to have the key,
it would be their foster son, Makoto.
But, his whereabouts are unknown.
Now that you mentioned it...
During the time that Makoto left for the city
to take his university exam,
they key was temporarily given to his classmate, Ms. Hikawa,
so she could help around the house.
If I remember correctly,
on the day of Makoto's university exam is when the incident occurred.
Yes.
If so, that young lady called Hikawa may be a suspect.
Well, if she had the key,
she could've made a spare.
Maybe that young lady's the one responsible
for the incident a year ago, that Kudo deduced wrongly,
as well as for the incident that occurred this morning.
What did he deduce wrongly?
It's true that the house was totally messed up.
But it could have been that just as Shinichi said
Mr. Hinohara killed his wife and after that messed the room up
to make it look like it was armed robbery.
Idiot. It seems that when the incident happened a year ago,
the ground was also muddy from rain,
but the only thing they found around the house
were the shoe prints of one person going to the road
from the backdoor and back.
The culprit also walked around inside the house wearing shoes.
If Mr. Hinohara wanted to make it look like armed robbery,
and went outside with those shoes on,
then came back to the house again,
those shoes should be somewhere in the house, right?
True.
If he threw his shoes out of the house
the police are sure to have found them already, right?
The house of the veranda is about 30 m from the lake,
so there's no way the shoes would've made it inside.
But, I'm sure that Shinichi knew of that too, no?
Yes. That's why I've been thinking all night from last night...
No, wrong.
Even if we were to assume that the culprit who had the key
was ambushing them inside.
Unless you can find a way to go in and out of the house
without leaving shoes prints behind,
the murder would be impossible to commit.
An impossible crime.
Impossible crime.
A mysterious murder trick, but...
Shinichi would...
I'm sure that Shinichi would find a way.
Darn.
If Shinichi were his usual self,
we would've been able to think it out together
and solve it in no time.
Maybe we've got to go see Death after all.
Why Death?
Because the villager said yesterday, remember.
That he lost his memory after seeing Death in the forest.
And, last night
before going to bed
I heard from the clerk at the inn together with Ran
on what to do if Death's curse fell upon a person.
The clerk told us to go into the forest while the sun is still high.
When you see Death shout with all your might and call him.
And continue to pray with a heart that isn't tarnished.
Then, the curse will be lifted.
That is what's being said in this village.
But, there's virtually no one who actually tried it.
But, the clerk told us that the newspaper reporter lady did it.
Is that for real?
Yes. The clerk said that her daughter that she brought along with her
when she came to interview the people about the incident a year ago,
her daughter went into the forest and never came back so.
Hey.
Ran's not here.
What?
Don't tell me that she took that story seriously
and went into the forest?
Death...
Death.
Please.
Return Shinichi back to normal.
If you don't mind my tarnished heart and all,
I'll give it to you.
That's why please return Shinichi
back to the real Shinichi.
Please, Death.
There... there he is.
He's really there.
Wait...
No good. I'm so scared that I've lost my voice.
Hey, wasn't that...
Wasn't that Ran's voice?
Something must've happened.
-Ran! -Ran...
-Where are you? -Ran!
No good.
My whole body hurts and I can't move.
What am I doing anyway?
I come into the forest of my own initiative,
then fall on my own.
How stupid can I get.
Death.
Please... please return Shinichi...
Please return Shinichi to normal.
Next Conan's Hint:
"The Curse of Death".
In the next episode Shinichi's memory...
And, the truth of the case is...
Don't miss it.