A year ago,
I, Shinichi Kudo solved a murder case at East Okuho Village.
A letter saying that a deduction miss that I made
was found was delivered to me via Heiji Hattori.
"Makoto Okuda (19)" -We went over to East Okuho Village
to meet with the sender Mr. Makoto Okuda, but...
Makoto's whereabouts was presently unknown.
And, for some reason,
the villagers seemed to have feelings of enmity against Shinichi Kudo.
I went alone to the mountain cabin
where Makoto had arranged to meet me.
Excuse me.
This thing I'm feeling...
It can't be...
I made it thinking to secretly try it on him
when he comes to spend the night here next time.
That medicine is the miracle drug
that could maybe change his body
that had become that of a child due to APTX 4869
to the body of the high school student that it used to be.
Shinichi?
Shinichi!
Shinichi...
Is that my name?
Don't tell me that Shinichi...
Lost his memory?
That drug is only a prototype.
There may be a slight discrepancy
but the longest the effect will continue is more or less 24 hours.
Twenty four hours?
You've got to make sure he regains his memory by then
or else we're in big trouble.
Let's take Shinichi to that murder site too then.
He just may remember something.
Shinichi Kudo there deduced this case to be
a forced double suicide that Mr. Hinohara committed.
What the heck is Kudo's deduction blooper?
The motive for the Mr. Hinohara committing forced double suicide
was because his doctor declared that he had cancer
and he was full of despair.
"Misato Kawauchi (36)" -The problem arose when Mr. Kudo
publicized the truth a year ago.
She told him that although he did have cancer, the tumor was benign,
and it would be completely cured with surgery.
Hearing this, the former he seemed very happy.
What?
Hey, Kudo. What the heck is going on?
Mr. Kudo, I know what you're up to.
The truth that you're trying to hide
the fact that you cannot speak of.
Did I do it?
Did I... kill her?
Hold up for a while,
until I find the real culprit and let you out of here.
I've got to solve the case completely before sundown at all cost.
Impossible crime.
A mysterious murder trick, but...
Shinichi would...
I'm sure that Shinichi would find a way.
Death...
Please.
Return Shinichi back to normal.
Death.
A crisis is gracefully revived.
The table is turned and the mystery solved.
The unbelievable truth that Heiji discloses.
Ran's tears doesn't stop as she watches Shinichi.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
Sorry, Ran.
Go on home ahead.
Oh, hey.
I'll catch up with you right away!
Shinichi!
He's going away.
Shinichi's...
Shinichi's going away.
No. Don't go.
Shinichi!
"Shinichi's True Colors and Ran's Tears"
Where am I?
I remember.
I found Death in the forest and I went after him
then I slipped.
My wounds are treated.
Who on earth?
Ran!
I found Ran!
-What? -Kazuha.
Are you all right?
What's with the bandages?
I fell in the forest and passed out.
It seems that someone brought me here and treated my wounds.
I'm sure it was the owner of this hut
so we've got to thank him when he gets back.
No, the owner of this hut doesn't seem to be a nice person.
What?
The transceiver?
Heiji, where are you?
In the next room.
Come over here, will you? The place is a mess.
Come over you say,
but the door is closed off with a wooden board.
Go outside once and come in through the window.
Yes, I guess so.
Hey, what's this?
This place is full of the pictures
and articles of the detective kid.
Yes. It seems that whoever it is, is really infatuated with Kudo.
To the point of wanting to kill him.
His picture is slashed up.
Ran, didn't you really see the person who carried you here?
No, all I saw was Death in the forest.
Death?
Are you serious?
It seems that the owner of this hut is that what you may call "Death".
Look at this.
It's gray hair made of polyester used to make wigs.
The hair of Death that you saw was also white, wasn't it?
Yes, but he didn't look like such a bad person,
although I was scared.
I guess so.
After all he seems to have treated Ran's wounds for her too.
Maybe he's up to no good after feigning to be kind
and getting everyone off guard.
Well, but it's true that he's a dangerous character for sure.
There's an empty box for bullets.
Shattered pieces of glass of cracked mirrors.
There are at least 5 to 6 cracked mirrors.
And to top everything off...
The nasty words that are carved on this desk say.
"Failure means death".
Hey, if there's an empty box for bullets, it means...
Yes. It means that Death may be carrying around a dangerous weapon.
Does that mean that the one who stabbed
the newspaper reporter lady
and made it look like Shinichi did it, is Death's doing?
Yes, most likely.
Since he seems to hate Kudo too.
But if so, he would've had to call the lady and Kudo
over to that house and wait for them.
But the shoe prints of the culprit
weren't found anywhere around the house.
It rained all night and the ground was damp,
and yet nothing was found.
Maybe he was already in the house before it started raining?
Idiot!
If so, the culprit could've never made it out of the house
without leaving any footprints behind.
I checked around the house last night
because of the case that happened a year ago
and found that in order to go in and out of the house,
you have to walk on the ground somewhere around the house
no matter how you do it.
Besides, before the police and ambulance came this morning,
we searched through the house,
but found nobody there, right?
True.
Right. Who called the police and ambulance?
Did you hear anything on it?
Yes.
Both calls seem to have been made
by the same young man who sounded like he had a bad cold.
What?
Couldn't that have been Shinichi?
In fact, the person who called the newspaper reporter,
Mrs. Kawauchi at the inn she was staying at,
was also said to have been a young man who sounded like he had a bad cold.
The man who called them said that his name was Shinichi Kudo.
You mean Kudo called that lady
and called the ambulance and police as well?
Could it be that he's pretending to have amnesia,
but actually thinking of something?
Mrs. Kawauchi said something similar to what you just said too.
What?
That remark that Mrs. Kawauchi made last night still bothers me.
Oh, my. What's with that look of yours?
Don't tell me that you thought I didn't realize either?
After that, I went to Mrs. Kawauchi's inn to ask her about it,
and she answered me.
She said that Mr. Kudo is just faking he has amnesia.
And that he has something up his sleeve.
I see.
The lady said what she did last night
hoping to get more information on Kudo.
At any rate, there's no mistake
that this is the house of a dangerous character.
We've got to call the police over here right away.
Yes, sir.
I know we can somehow get out of the forest,
but I'm not sure if we'll be able to make it back here again.
Then, we'll make a bonfire again
and use the smoke to guide us.
Bonfire?
Yes.
You saw the bonfire near the stone
that looked like a tombstone, didn't you?
That's what was burning.
He was just probably getting dinner ready,
when we showed up. So, he probably got up and fled.
Could it be that the culprit fled from the little window
by the ceiling of the next room?
You mean that window.
But, isn't it a bit too small for an adult to make it out of there?
The shoe prints of a child's shoes.
It's Kudo.
I'm sure he was summoned here by that letter
"Mr. Shinichi Kudo" -and confined here.
So, he escaped from that window.
But who on earth confined him?
The whereabouts of Makoto Okuda's been unknown for the past six months.
I'm sure Makoto's been killed.
Is Makoto Okuda dead or alive?
Hold it, hold it.
Let me think it over from the start once more.
The slashed up pictures of Kudo.
It seems that the culprit really hates him.
And the words on the desk.
The culprit is trying to do something
even if it means taking his own life.
Is he planning to take revenge on Kudo?
There was an empty box for bullets in the next room.
The culprit most likely is armed with a gun.
I'm sure he had many chances to shoot Kudo if he wanted to.
Why didn't he do anything?
The lady called Kawauchi was stabbed with a knife.
How on earth is he planning to use the gun?
And, another thing that's bothering me is...
the mirror that was shattered to pieces.
Why did he have to crack so many mirrors like that?
Don't tell me that...
Don't tell me that he...
While you go out and call the police,
I'd like you to check on something for me.
But, how on earth am I going to check on something like that?
Don't worry.
This will do it, I guarantee.
Will this be enough?
I guess so.
That'll be enough for us to see the smoke from far away too.
And we won't have to go around in circles getting lost in the forest.
I wonder what sport consists of going around in circles,
you know, that Mr. Hinohara used to do?
I think it's some kind of field and track sports.
Remember, I told you that we asked the person
at the inn about Death, right?
We asked that person what sport Mr. Hinohara was into,
and was told that although he wasn't sure of what it was called
but said it was something that spun round and round.
Spin round and round?
Field sports that would include spinning something
would either be hammer throwing or discus.
Oh, right, he also mentioned that Mr. Hinohara was good at quoits.
Quoits?
It seems that his son, Daiki was bragging about it to everyone.
He goes around saying that his father was really good at quoits
an always got a perfect score.
Perfect score?
-It's that police officer. -Darn!
Hey!
What's up? What's wrong?
Death...
Death suddenly appeared before my eyes then...
I suddenly passed out.
Hey, the mouth of the holster of the gun is open!
Don't worry.
Your gun hasn't been taken.
But, why only the gun?
You mean he bought the bullets but didn't own a gun?
I wonder... I can't say for now yet.
But, I more or less have an idea of the case.
Later for the hut.
Let's get everybody together at Mr. Hinohara's house
and solve the mystery, shall we?
A High School Detective from Osaka?
Heiji Hattori?
Are you saying that you're going to solve the mystery
of how Mrs. Kawauchi was stabbed here this morning?
Yes, exactly.
Before that...
If possible, I'd like you to bring along the owner
of the of the mysterious footprints that left
from the backdoor over here with you.
Of course, I brought him along
the owner of the footprints.
Shinichi Kudo, it's you.
What's with the blood on your clothes?
Hey, hey...
Don't tell me that Shinichi's the culprit?
Of all the footprints left in front of this house,
if you exclude the footprints of us
who have an alibi because we were back at the inn
and those of Mrs. Kawauchi,
the only footprints left would be his.
Blood of the victim is splattered on his clothes,
his fingerprints are on the murder weapon...
No matter how you look at it, he's the murderer.
That's true.
Because he is the killer.
In other words,
no trick was used in committing the crime.
What?
Heiji.
What are you up to?
Is this some kind of strategy?
It's not a strategy.
I'm saying that this guy called Mrs. Kawauchi out by phone
and stabbed her.
Hold it.
You insisted this morning that he'd never stab anybody.
I... I was scared.
That newspaper reporter said that
she'd expose the blunder that I made a year ago.
She threatened me saying that she'd shatter the fame
and pride that I'd established up to now.
I didn't know what it was about, but...
I was so scared that I inadvertently...
Who is he?
No. He's not Shinichi.
The Shinichi that I've be waiting for is...
The person that's been filling my heart.
The Shinichi that I've been longing for is...
It's just as you say, Kazuha.
I can't...
I can't stop my tears from falling.
Did you really call the newspaper reporter, Mrs. Kawauchi here and stab her?
Yes. I did it.
I just can't believe it.
Your deduction a year ago was fantastic.
You saw through the trick in the wink of an eye
and paved the way to solving the case with lightning speed.
Why would a person like you, do something like this?
You're over evaluating me.
I'm not God.
I hate people and make mistakes too.
It seems that a year ago
I wrongly made a culprit out of Mr. Hinohara
who was innocent.
Maybe you don't remember because you've lost your memory.
But as far as that incident is concerned, there was legitimate evidence.
Excuse me.
The test results have been reached
so I thought I'd report it.
Test results?
That boy from Osaka asked me to get it.
He asked me to check if the murder weapon knife
and the piece of chain inside the lucky charm pouch that the boy had
matched or not.
And, what about the result?
Just as you said, they didn't match.
All right! It's just as I deduced!
You mean that lucky charm, right?
What does it have to with the knife?
What on earth didn't match?
It's what all humans are bestowed with
from the heavens when they are born,
an emblem that stays with you till the end of your lifetime.
Since there is no one with the same,
when it comes to criminal investigation,
it is considered to be one of the most reliable evidence.
Fingerprints, isn't it?
Yes.
Who is he?
Death?
Stand back.
A gun?
No use.
Cut it out.
Enough with the costume party already.
Costume party?
What're you talking about?
Yes. If any trick was involved in this case
it's his face.
I mean it's unthinkable that the high school detective Shinichi Kudo
would ever stab anybody.
The first thing that bothered me was
the attitude that Mouri's daughter took.
Despite the Kudo she'd been waiting for all this time
appearing before her,
she acted as if she didn't know him and displayed a cold attitude.
Normally, she would've clung to him and not let go, right?
And the more so, if he has amnesia,
at first I thought she was just hiding her embarrassment,
but after I checked the hut of the culprit in the forest, I found out why!
Culprit's hut?
Yes, the pictures of Kudo that are pinned up on the wall
were all slashed to pieces,
and a great number of mirrors were cracked
with the shattered pieces scattered over the floor.
There could be only one reason that the guy who hates Kudo to the point
of slashing his pictures would crack mirrors to pieces.
He couldn't stand seeing the face of Kudo
that was reflected in the mirror.
Don't tell me that...
Yes, he underwent plastic surgery
and changed his face to that of this green-horn detective...
stupid high school detective.
Hey, this is...
He's a perfect double.
But, why would you change your face to Shinichi's?
He called me out to that hut,
confined me there and after becoming me,
he was probably scheming to commit some sort of crime.
His intention was to probably annihilate I, Shinichi Kudo...
as a person, and from society too.
Annihilate you?
He pretended to have amnesia
so that he wouldn't have to answer anything
that my friends who he supposed would come along with me may ask.
He went into the lake naked and had a hoarse voice
as if having a cold for the same reason.
Although he could make himself look like me,
he couldn't copy my voice.
Neither did he know what kind of clothes I would be wearing.
Well, I too, when escaping from that hut fell into the lake,
and have a bit of a hoarse voice with a cold.
Then, the one who called the ambulance and police this morning
-right after the incident was... -Me.
I saw Mrs. Kawauchi and he come into this house,
so I prepared for the worse.
Then, why didn't you yourself rush inside and stop him?
I couldn't even if I wanted to.
Because when he came out of the house last night,
from the protrusion in the back of his clothes,
I was sure that he was armed with a gun.
I guess it can't be helped.
After all, "Failure means death"
was carved on the desk too.
Yes.
If he was ready to shoot a specific person,
maybe I could've stopped him.
If he had his mind made up to kill himself
as soon as he found out that his scheme didn't work,
the time I had to stop him was limited.
That's why I took the bullets out of Officer Shiroyama's gun
and scattered it before his eyes
to make him hesitate and putting him off guard.
Because he was probably planning to carry out his scheme
as soon as I appeared before him.
Isn't that right, Okuda?
Rather, Makoto Hinohara?
Makoto? You mean you're Makoto?
He sure is.
To do this much with plastic surgery
would cost a lot of time and money.
But, Makoto could do it because he got a lot of estate
and his whereabouts were unknown for six months.
If so, he would've hidden the gun in his own room in this house.
He assumed beforehand that they would bring him back here
to help him regain his memory.
He then tells everyone that he wants to be alone,
and that's when he retrieves the gun.
But, why, why did he have to stab the newspaper reporter?
He probably thought that she found out about everything
because of her remark last night.
Oh, my. What's with that look of yours?
Don't tell me that you thought I didn't realize either?
That you underwent plastic surgery to make yourself look like Kudo.
But, I don't understand.
When I came over to the house this morning,
why didn't you say that you stabbed Mrs. Kawauchi?
If you wanted to frame Kudo for the murder,
wouldn't that have been faster?
I was testing you detectives out.
I wanted to see what kind of deduction
you'd come up with after the evidence all pointed
to Shinichi Kudo being the murderer.
Well, it seems they saw you through completely.
Then, what about the incident that occurred a year ago?
What's with Shinichi Kudo who made a stupid deduction
saying that Mr. Hinohara committed forced double suicide
when a robber made away with the valuables and murdered them?
What about him?
Kudo didn't make a mistake.
That was a forced double suicide.
What?
The murder weapon of the killer,
Mrs. Hinohara's jewelry,
as well as her valuable Nioh statue were taken, you know?
It's more than obvious that the killer took it with him.
The lake...
After Mr. Hinohara stabbed his wife,
he sunk the murder weapon together with the jewelry into the lake.
What're you talking about?
It's close to 30 meters from this house to the lake.
How would the culprit be able to take all that
to the lake without leaving footprints behind?
Not only the murder weapon and the jewelry,
but the strings for the gold medals
and the loops for quoits are also gone.
Quoits?
Mr. Hinohara's son Daiki was saying, remember?
That his father was good at quoits
and always played a perfect game, right?
The scores that are written on the target of quoits
are 10 points, 5 points, 2 points.
So, if he wants to play a perfect game scoring 100 points,
he needs 10 quoits, but there were only 9.
Besides, one pair of the Nioh statue was left untouched
and taking into consideration
that Mr. Hinohara used to be a player of field sports,
the answer is obvious.
Hammer throwing.
He packed the Nioh statue that he used for weight together
with the murder weapon, shoes and jewelry into a bag,
and used the quoit as a handle
by tying on the string of medal onto the package.
He did this all to throw the bag into the lake from the veranda
as he would do when hammer throwing.
I see.
He left one Nion statue behind
because putting both in the bag would make it too heavy
and the bag wouldn't reach the lake.
Ridiculous.
The bag would've never made it because of resistance from the wind.
No, the bag made it.
The bag, string and quoits
have already been retrieved from the lake.
Of course on the blade of the murder weapon knife,
Mrs. Hinohara's blood was found and on the handle of the knife,
Mr. Hinohara's fingerprints were found.
There's no mistake that it was a forced double suicide
committed by Mr. Hinohara.
Not true.
He probably made it look like the doings of an armed robber
so that his son, Daiki wouldn't realize what happened.
That's a lie! Mr. Hinohara who was cheerful and kind man
would never commit forced double suicide with his wife.
Besides the Mr. Hinohara's cancer was found to be benign
and it turned out that the motive for his murderous act
which was because he was depressed over it was also a lie.
After the doctor told him about his cancer.
Another problem came into the light.
After the physical exam,
it turned out that Mr. Hinohara's blood type was...
in fact, AB.
Hey, wait!
I thought I heard that Mr. Hinohara's family
was a cheerful blood type O family.
Yes.
According to Mendel's Law of Heredity,
a child with blood type O is not born
from parents whose blood type is AB and O.
In other words,
Daiki is not Mr. Hinohara's son.
Oh no.
My god.
Don't lie.
I see.
If that was his motive for committing the murder,
it's something that people would want to keep secret.
Yes. That's why it was announced
that the motive for him committing the murder
was because he was told he had cancer.
But if so, why didn't he tell me about it?
I was a part of the family and yet!
I already told you why.
Because Mr. Kudo told me to.
Don't dare tell anybody.
But, please do tell Makoto about this.
When? Where did you tell me this?
Here, the night after Mr. Kudo finished investigating the case and left.
But, come to think of it.
The truth about Mr. Hinohara having committed forced double suicide
that I told you about first was so shocking
that you may not have been listening to what I was saying.
No.
It's not possible.
What the heck is wrong with me?
What the heck did I go and change my face for?
What the heck?
A tragedy brought about by a much too unfortunate coincidence.
Seeing my face breaking out in tears before me,
I thought that...
I can't ever forget this face.
That I should engraved it deep inside of me.
So that guy called Makoto was Death.
Yes. He was the 2nd one though.
The second one?
The first was his father.
In order to prevent the children of the village
from going through the same misfortune as his daughter
who had died in the forest.
He built a hut in the forest
and lived in it as Death,
to scare and keep people from entering the forest.
He did so until he fell ill and died 3 years ago.
So the stone that was placed near the hut was...
Yes. It's Makoto's father's grave.
How come you know so much?
When I came here a year ago,
there was another incident other than this case happening.
Mrs. Kawauchi's daughter who had come here on an interview
went into the forest and never came back.
I heard about it from the person at the inn.
That Mrs. Kawauchi also went inside the forest to look for her.
Yes, just when I was about to go to look for her too,
her daughter came out of the forest on her own.
She said that Death found her in the forest
and she was chased around.
She was so scared that she kept running around
until she found herself outside the forest.
I figured I had to solve this mystery
before taking care of the murder case,
so I went into the forest.
I found Death, went after him and found that hut.
Then, I ran into Makoto who was dressed as Death.
I see.
So, you borrowed the outfit that you found in that hut this time.
Yes.
I did so because I had no choice after I fell into the lake
and my clothes got wet.
Besides, with these clothes on everybody fled from me too,
so it turned out to be a great way to hide my face.
But I feel sorry for Makoto.
He'll be fine.
It seems that Mrs. Kawauchi wasn't that badly hurt
as we thought she was at first either.
When she finds out who had saved her daughter's life a year ago,
she will be grateful to Death.
Shinichi?
What's the matter, Shinichi?
This is?
Shinichi? What's the wrong?
Oh no, it's come.
Oh no. It's almost 24 hours.
I've got to take Shinichi away from everybody quick.
I almost forgot.
The Inspector had asked Kudo and I to come
and tell him more in detail about the case.
So you guys go on ahead by car and...
No.
I'll go with you too.
I have things that...
I want to ask you too, Shinichi.
Lots and lots of things too!
Ran...
Shinichi?
Kudo?
Are you all right?
My body's... my body's hot...
Oh no. He's really hot.
If things go as is, I'm going to return to a kid.
I'll transform back to Conan again.
I can't afford to go back
to how was in front of her.
It's his cold, his cold.
Remember he said he fell into the lake?
The cold he had back then got worse.
I guess so, but...
He seems to be suffering abnormally.
What?
You want to go to the john and let out what you have to?
I see! I see!
Okay, I'll go take Shinichi to the toilet at the inn,
so Kazuha would you bring my bag and come along.
Why do I have to take your bag?
Change of clothes, I need change of clothes!
Kudo is sweating profusely
so we can't keep him in Death's outfit forever, can we?
So, okay? Bring it for me, will you?
"Okuho Inn"
Twenty four hours?
Are you serious?
Yes. The little lady at doctor's place said so.
The drug only stays effective for 24 hours.
She told me to bring you back to her before the time is up.
Isn't it almost time?
If you do get small again,
go inside this bag.
Then, I'll somehow get you out of here safely.
You can count on me.
Yes.
Heiji?
Kazuha?
What're you sneaking around about?
Stupid, don't come in.
This is the men's room.
But, we're worried about Shinichi.
We brought a doctor that we found in the neighborhood along.
He's fine. He's fine.
Besides, I just gave him some cold medicine now.
What kind of medicine did you give him?
Well, it's a secret potion
that has been handed down in my family for generations.
Darn it.
It always turns out like this.
It always turns out like this!
I always go back being Conan
without being able to say anything to her.
Am I going to have to start all over again?
Shoots.
I'm Conan again.
Shinichi? What's wrong?
Hey, don't!
Shinichi?
Hey, Shinichi?
I've to hide in the bag quick.
Shinichi.
Well, so you see...
Or, Ran will find out about me.
Shinichi.
Shinichi!
Oh no.
The toilet next door?
Who is it?
Shinichi, please answer me.
I'm telling you he's okay.
How can he be okay screaming like that?
Get out of my way.
Please, Heiji!
No... Don't...
You idiot.
Kudo?
Shinichi...
What is it? Stop bugging me.
The least you can do is give me peace using the toilet.
How're you feeling?
Yes, since I let everything out,
I'm feeling much better.
It looks like your fever came down too.
See?
I'm glad. I was really worried.
Shall we head on home then.
Don't we have to go to the police
and give them the details of the case?
Well, we can do that after we get home.
True. And just to be on the safe side,
you'd better go to the hospital too.
Yes.
Okay, let's head home then.
I'm very sorry, after you came all this way.
Not at all.
Kudo, what the heck is going on?
I'll tell you later.
Wait, Kudo.
We seem to have somehow made it through.
He seems to have regained his memory too.
Yes. What a life saver.
Thank god you remembered the name of the inn they were staying at.
Good gracious, too, that we were able to assume
that if he was cornered,
he would flee into the toilet of the inn.
Ai?
How'd you get here?
I've no time to explain.
Just drink this right away.
This is, don't tell me...
Yes, it's the prototype of the antidote of the APTX 4869
that shrunk your body.
It's the same medicine you drank yesterday.
Then, it'll keep for 24 hours?
Don't be silly.
Just as when you frequently keep drinking the same medicine,
the effectiveness wears off.
Your body builds up resistance to the medicine,
and by taking it repeatedly,
the length of time the drug remains effective shortens too.
If you want to continue hiding your true identity,
you'll have get out of their sight
before the effect of the drug wears off
and go back to being Conan Edogawa.
And?
What is it that you want to ask me?
I just wanted to say thank you for treating my wounds.
You're the one who treated them, right?
Yes. Since there just happened to be a first aid kit in that mountain.
You didn't look, did you?
You know when you were treating me...
When I was wrapping the bandage around your thighs,
I saw the white stuff.
So you did look after all!
How dare you!
You idiot!
I didn't look at it because I wanted to,
I just happened to see it, you get?
Well, I'm so sorry!
That I showed you what you didn't want to see!
Ran.
Would you like to change seats with me?
I think it'll make it easier for both of you to talk.
It's okay, Kazuha, stay right there.
I'm going to throw that guy over my shoulder after we get home.
Give me a break.
No. This isn't how it's suppose to turn out.
The thing I wanted to ask Shinichi about was...
The thing I really wanted to confirm was...
Ran.
Officer Sato and Takagi. What's up?
I went to the Kanagawa Prefectural Police Department!
And, since I finished doing what I had to do,
I'm having my driver drive me home.
I'm no more than a driver.
What about you people?
Did you have any case to solve or something, Mr. Sleeping Kogoro?
Yes. Well, sort of.
Really? Well, excuse us, since we're in a rush.
Tell us about the case some other day then!
Since that incident is big news,
as long as they read tomorrow's papers they'll find out about it
without us telling them about it.
No, I don't think it'll be in the papers.
Nobody died as a result, and besides,
the culprit is still a juvenile.
Neither his name nor picture will be publicized.
It seems that the newspaper reporter lady who was stabbed,
also said that she won't write about it.
You were sure lucky, Kudo.
What's with that car?
It's moving along scraping its body against the guardrail.
Maybe he's sleeping at the wheels?
If we leave it as is, there's sure to be a big accident.
Hey, get up!
Hey, you!
Hey, something's not right.
Get this car in front of that car.
Hey! In front, don't tell me that...
When you go up front slow down little by little.
Idiot! If I do that, the rental car will...
Never mind, just hurry.
Gunpei? Gunpei?
Hey, wait. Don't touch him.
Please step back.
Who're you people?
-No good. -He's not breathing anymore.
Look, Kudo.
There's hemorrhaging under his eyes.
Don't tell me that this is...
a rope mark.
Kudo, this is...
Hey!
What's wrong?
Ran. There's a toll gate a kilometer from here.
Call Officer Sato and have them block it off.
Why?
The driver of this car is dead.
He was strangled.
Strangled?
Yes.
In this moving car that's locked.