Yeah, it's the watermelon, right? I didn't forget.
Then go buy a nice-looking one!
Alright, alright... Sheesh.
Ran's at the Professor's house... Huh?
So, in other words, you, Ms. Kaori Kitazaka...
are an alumna of Jonan University's Mystery Research Society, and a party celebrating the marriage of a fellow alumnus of that same society...
is being held...
starting at 4 o'clock today, but...
you don't know the location of the venue.
The reason being, the party host...
in keeping with the Mystery Research Society name...
sent out invitations drawn as rebus puzzles.
...Is that about right?
Yes. I just couldn't solve the rebus puzzle, no matter what...
and so, by chance, I happened to be passing by...
and I thought perhaps the famous Detective Mori could help...
Ah, I see. Leave it to me.
I, the great detective Kogoro Mori...
will solve this rebus puzzle for you in no time.
Hey, hey, are you sure about this?
...So, what is this rebus puzzle?
Here.
It's this.
Hmm...
Hm? What's this...?
I see. Yeah, this isn't an easy one to crack.
♪~
Cutting through the blackness of shadows and the depth of darkness, the light of deduction!
With the Belfry Tower area as the stage, solve the mystery of the secretive venue!
Seeing through the one and only truth!
Looks like a kid, mind is an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
~♪
"A Coded Invitation"
I've always been bad with deductions and codes, you see...
Even when I joined the club, the only code I could crack was the "tanuki code."
The "tanuki code"?
It's a basic cipher where you read the text while omitting the character "ta."
Oh!
But if that's the case, why did you join a mystery research society?
Well, that's...
I've got it!
These four fingers, from the pinky to the index finger...
represent train lines.
Huh? Train lines...?
Huh?
You see, train lines have what they call "line colors"...
This yellow pinky is the Sobu Line.
The yellow-green ring finger is the Yamanote Line.
The light blue middle finger is the Keihin-Tohoku Line.
The red index finger represents the Chuo Line.
In other words, the party venue is at the location of the thumbnail, in a place where these four train lines run parallel.
The party venue is at the location of the thumbnail.
Oh, I see! I never would have thought of that.
Hmm... But is there really a place like that?
Unfortunately, no.
But, if you twist your head a little...
The numbers written on this guide map mean...
"Look at a 1:25,000 scale map,"
You place the pinky, the Sobu Line, over this point, Akihabara...
and place the ring finger, the Yamanote Line, and the middle finger, the Keihin-Tohoku Line...
on this line between Akihabara and Kanda.
Then place the index finger, the Chuo Line...
on this line between Ochanomizu and Kanda.
If you do that, the place this thumbnail points to is...
Kanda-Ogawamachi.
Kanda-Ogawamachi? Ah... Then...
this drawing of a river means "Ogawa" (small river), right?
But the fingers on the guide map are stretched out straight.
Your hand, though, is all curled up.
Don't sweat the small stuff!
Oh, brother...
Hm?
Well? Does that location ring any bells?
Yes, it does!
There's a Jonan University hall in the 2-chome district of Kanda-Ogawamachi.
Seriously?
Just as I thought.
That hall must be the party venue, without a doubt.
Amazing, Dad!
Na-ha-ha-ha!
No way...
Thank you very much! Now I can attend the party.
Um, what about your fee...?
Ah, no, no, no, no.
I couldn't possibly accept money for such a simple request.
What? But...
No charge is necessary.
I'm so sorry about that. Well then, if you insist...
(Bump)
Thank you so very much.
If anything else comes up, please feel free to contact us.
Yes, excuse me.
Hm...
(Door closes)
But since we're all making it together...
we should do something on a huge scale, right?
How about making lots of different insects out of paper...
and calling it the "Insect Forest"?
What about an aquarium with lots of fish swimming around?
An airfield would be cool too!
As I suspected, you just can't accept Mori's deduction, can you?
Yeah. To be precise, the Chuo Line's color...
isn't red, it's vermilion, and...
Even if I try swapping in other red, blue, yellow, and green line colored trains
I just can't find a spot that fits.
No matter how I rearrange them...
the location just doesn't match up.
Could it be the subway?
I thought about that too, but...
in the first place, there's no line with a yellow line color.
Huh... A bridge?
Oh... Right.
That left hand, it's...
Oh no, I have to let her know, fast!
Sorry, handle the rest!
Conan?
It seems he's solved it.
Looks like it.
What?! It's not Kanda-Ogawamachi?
Yeah. Look at this map.
The river drawn on that rebus is this Sumida River...
and the colors of the bridges spanning it are...
Kuramae Bridge is yellow.
Umaya Bridge is a yellowish-green.
Komagata Bridge is blue.
Azuma Bridge is red.
In other words, those fingernail colors were pointing to these four bridges!
Wow, Conan!
Mmmph...
You have the copy of the rebus, right?
Hm? Ah, yeah...
If you match the hand's fingernails on this invitation...
to the positions of each of these bridges...
the thumb's position is...
Belfry Tower! Then that's the party venue?
But still, there's a university hall in Kanda-Ogawamachi...
There's no doubt. I called Belfry Tower just a bit ago...
and confirmed it.
They've specially rented out the pre-opening restaurant...
and from 4 o'clock today, Jonan University's Mystery Research Society...
is holding a wedding party there.
Dad, you have to call Ms. Kaori right away and tell her!
Alright, alright.
The number you have dialed is not currently in service...
That's odd.
You got the number wrong.
Dad, you have to call her cell phone, not her home phone.
Ms. Kaori should still be out and about.
Ah, right.
Wait a second.
Why would Ms. Kaori write down a wrong number for her home phone?
Well, she probably just made a careless mistake...
But it's her own home phone number.
Who gets that wrong...?
In that case, she wrote a fake number on purpose.
It happens sometimes.
Some people write down lies because they don't want their family to know they visited a detective agency.
Some people write down lies for that reason.
But Ms. Kaori just wanted to find the location of a wedding party, right?
It's not something bad for her family to know about...
How should I know? Quit your yapping.
(Phone ringing)
Hello?
Ah, hello, is this Ms. Kaori?
It's Mori. Actually...
Oh, I see! I'm here at the university hall in Ogawamachi right now...
and was at a loss because it wasn't the venue.
Belfry Tower, right? Thank you very much!
No problem at all. Take care.
That's good. Looks like she'll make it to the party.
Still, why would Ms. Kaori write her real cell number...
but a fake number for her home phone?
And in the first place, just to find a party venue...
even if she was passing by...
would you normally visit a detective agency?
Hey, did you hear anything about Ms. Kaori's family?
Ah, yeah. Ms. Kaori is single...
and lives with her parents, it seems.
When she wrote her home phone number, did she act strange at all?
Huh? Not at all... Sheesh, you're such a pest.
Ah, wait, now that you mention it, Ms. Kaori...
after writing her cell number...
"Um, should I write my home number, too?"
Yes, if you don't mind.
...which means...
Could it be she only faked the last digit...?
(Phone ringing)
Hello, this is the Kitazaka residence.
Ah! I got so caught up in verifying the number, I didn't think about what to say...
I got so caught up in verifying the number...
Hello?
Ah, um...
My name is Conan Edogawa.
Conan Edogawa?
Wait, Conan?!
Excuse me, just a moment...
Ah, yes.
Hello, Conan? It's Sato from the Metropolitan Police.
Officer Sato?!
What?
I'm here at the Kitazaka house with Officer Takagi right now...
Why are you calling this number, Conan?
Why are you there, Officer Sato?
What are you doing at that house? Did something happen?
Huh? Well, that's...
Hang on, I'll put Kogoro on.
This is Mori. Did something happen at the Kitazaka household?
Mr. Mori...
What's wrong? I'm happy to help if I can.
Actually, a handgun has gone missing.
What? A handgun...?
Yes. The missing weapon is...
an old Imperial Japanese Army Type 14 automatic pistol...
that the homeowner, Michio Kitazaka's father...
Nobuyoshi, had passed away last year...
and they found it while going through his belongings.
Of course, military handguns...
must be reported to the police as soon as they are found, but...
Mr. Michio, as a keepsake of his father...
had carefully stored it away, along with five bullets.
I see. And that's what's gone missing, right?
Yes.
There's no sign of a break-in.
So if someone took it...
the only possibility is their daughter, Kaori.
What?!
Ms. Kaori said today...
she was going to attend a university senior's wedding party...
and left the house late this morning, but...
apparently, the way she was acting then...
seemed deeply troubled.
What?
When we spoke with the family, it seems this senior, a male...
was two-timing Kaori and the person he's marrying, and in the end...
Kaori was apparently dumped.
H-Hey, then that means...
Yes. Her father, Michio, noticed the missing gun...
and tried calling Kaori's cell phone several times, but couldn't get through...
so that's why he contacted the police.
We were just about to start looking into where the wedding party venue is...
We know where the party is.
It's Belfry Tower.
But I wonder if it really was Ms. Kaori who took the gun.
When she came to the office...
she was carrying a big clutch bag, remember?
Huh? Yeah.
Well, when she left...
(Bump)
The gun was probably inside that bag.
What?!
And also, Ms. Kaori...
did you notice she was wearing low-heeled shoes?
Ah, yeah. For a party...
I thought it'd be better to wear higher heels.
She wore shoes like that...
to stabilize her body.
So she wouldn't miss her target when firing a gun.
What? Then, as I thought...
Ms. Kaori, who's bad at deductions and codes...
probably joined the Mystery Research Society...
because she liked that senior.
Damn... We're not gonna make it.
What do I do? What do I do?!
Ah...
Conan?
Somehow, with this... Please, don't go through with it.
Huh...!
Ahem, well, thank you all so much for joining us today in such a lively gathering...
thank you so much for coming in such large numbers.
Did you find the party venue easily?
Like we ever could!
Yonekura isn't here yet.
Alright, alright, we'll hear your feedback later...
Now, without further ado, let's call up the bride and groom!
(Applause)
(Party poppers)
(Cheers)
Hah...
First, a greeting from the blissfully happy groom!
Has Ms. Kaori not arrived yet?
No, coming from Kanda-Ogawamachi, she should have been here ages ago.
Ah! Ms. Kaori...!
Ms. Kaori!
Ah... Hah...
Hm?
No good.
Don't do it, Ms. Kaori!
What were your words for the proposal?
You're really gonna make me say it?
Ah...
K-Kaori?
Ms. Kaori...
Ms. Kaori... Ah!
(Cheers)
Congratulations, Mr. Nagai.
Ah... Thanks, Kaori.
Thank goodness... You didn't go through with it.
Hey, kid.
The old man Kogoro, he went downstairs with the detectives.
Seems they mistook someone else for Ms. Kaori.
When I was about to head to the party venue just now...
(Message received)
Ah!
Ah...
"It's good that you were distinguished as a hairy caterpillar and a smooth caterpillar."
At first, I didn't understand what it said.
But then...
I ignored the "ke" characters, and the "i" characters, and read it.
"It's good you broke up with that kind of man."
In that moment, my surging emotions...
just suddenly vanished, like a tide going out...
I figured, if you could read the "tanuki code," Ms. Kaori...
you would definitely understand.
Huh? So, the person who sent this wasn't Mr. Mori...?
Heh heh.
Conan...
Ms. Kaori!
Hey, Ms. Kaori.
You said you happened to be passing by the office...
but the truth is, you planned from the start to have Kogoro solve it...
and you came to the office with that plan in mind, right?
Yes. I used the famous Detective Mori.
I'm very sorry.
No, no, please don't worry about it.
Ms. Kaori Kitazaka?
Yes.
I'm Sato from the Metropolitan Police, First Investigation Division.
And I'm Takagi.
Ms. Kitazaka, please come with us to headquarters.
Alright.
Hey, kid, your name's Conan, right?
Yeah. Conan Edogawa, detective.
Thank you, little detective.
♪~
~♪
After that, Ms. Kaori and her father, Michio...
were sent to prosecutors for violation of the Firearms and Swords Control Law, but the case was dropped...
and the phantom shooting incident was resolved without incident.
Speaking of which, we were invited by Sonoko tomorrow to...
the Toto Belfry Tower. I'm looking forward to it.
Me too!
I hope the weather's nice.
I'm gonna make a "teru teru bozu" doll.
Ah, man... I have to chaperone these guys again?
I hear there are great restaurants near Belfry Tower...
No one could have imagined...
that a new shooting incident would be waiting for us at that Belfry Tower...
No one had any idea at the time.
Ha ha ha ha...!
Mwa ha ha ha! As expected of the great detective!
To see through the hiding place of this Kaito Kid!
So you've finally shown yourself, Kaito Kid!
Hm? Ah!
Damn it! Where the hell are you?!
Next Conan,
"The Secret of the Kogoro Mouri Statue"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Basketball"
The movie will be released from today.
The theme song is great!
I love the singer too!