There!
Got it!
Nice catch!
Wow, Shinpei-san, you're amazing!
Alright, next up...
Conan-kun!
Here goes! There!
Huh? Whoa...
Ah...
Huh?
Huh? Whoa, whoa!
H-Hey, come on...
Cut it out!
Huh... Matsunosuke?
Matsunosuke?
Stop that, Matsunosuke!
(Matsunosuke barks)
Good morning, Granny!
Granny?
Shinpei... You..
Are you messing around again instead of working?
First thing in the morning?
Messing around? I wasn't really...
He isn't messing around.
He teaches us frisbee here every week!
He's super nice!
Heheh...
That's the same as messing around.
A grown man like you...
Thanks to that, now even Matsunosuke...
Tries to catch anything that looks like a frisbee.
(Matsunosuke barks)
That dog's name is Matsunosuke?
So cute!
Oh dear, you're all covered in mud...
Hm?
Ah...
Let me clean this up properly...
Huh?
Here, I'll give it back.
Oh, it's fine... This is no big deal.
No, I can't let it be.
These things need to be done properly.
I don't want your parents
complaining at me later.
Granny, you're about to have breakfast, right?
Let me eat too!
Once you do some proper work
and pay back the money I lent you.
Ugh... Fine... Sigh...
♪~
Black shadows and pitch-black darkness...
The light of deduction cuts right through.
Same morning walk with the beloved dog, day after day...
A tiny difference sparks the beginning of a case.
Seeing through the one and only truth...
A child's appearance, an adult's mind...
His name is Detective Conan!
~♪
"Suspicious Promenade"
(doorbell rings)
Is Granny home?
We came to pick up Conan's clothes!
Looks like she's not here.
Probably walking the dog, right?
Yeah... We'll come back later.
But it looks like Matsunosuke
is sleeping over there.
You're right.
Sleeping so peacefully...
Not moving at all.
Oh my, is he sleeping? Matsunosuke!
And here I was,
about to give him a treat...
Um, who's that lady?
She's Kanae-san's dog friend.
- Hirota Tomoko (52), Kanae's dog friend.
She owns one of Matsunosuke's
siblings.
What?! Matsunosuke has siblings?
Do they look alike?
Of course. They're identical.
Hey... Don't tell me...
Hm?
Conan-kun?
Is it unlocked?
Ah... Ugh...
Kyaa!
K-Kanae-san!
What on earth is all this racket?!
I can't concentrate with all this noise...
Ugh... Ahh!
So when we came to get Conan's clothes...
Matsunosuke was asleep.
No matter how much we called, he wouldn't wake up.
Huh? M-Matsunosuke?
He's a dog. Sleeping in the doghouse outside.
Ah... Forensics says it looks like
he was put to sleep with some kind of drug.
Drug?
Now then... You're Hirota-san,
the fellow dog owner, correct?
Yes. I came to share
some dog treats, but...
And then this...
...And you are the neighbor, Kitazawa-san.
Yeah. The doorbell next door kept ringing over and over...
- Kitazawa Soukichi (54), Kanae's neighbor.
So I came to see what was going on,
and found this.
Are the two of you acquainted?
We know each other.
Hirota-san...
Didn't you borrow quite a bit of money
from Kanae-san?
She was always complaining about it.
Saying you never paid her back at all.
Maybe you're the culprit, hmm?
I heard you were always
complaining too.
That the dog's yapping
was too noisy.
What... Are you saying I'm the culprit?
Don't be ridiculous!
Right back at you!
Now, now, calm down.
Inspector Megure. Between 8 AM
and 8:15 AM...
Several people in the shopping district
and the park...
Reportedly saw Asakawa-san
walking her dog.
Hmm... Do you happen to know
Asakawa-san's walking route?
If I recall, she leaves the house,
goes through the shopping district...
Then heads to the park.
After that, she said she comes back
along the main road.
Yes. She always said
about an hour long walk...
Was the best routine for them.
Which means...
She left the house a little before 8 AM...
Finished the walk, and returned home
around 9 AM.
So she was killed after that.
What were you two doing during that time?
I was at home, playing shogi
with an acquaintance.
I was at home too.
I had flowers delivered
from the florist...
And asked them to arrange them
on the spot.
My jacket came back
from the cleaners.
Hm?
Hmm... Ah!
A beige
spring coat.
The coat she was wearing
when she died, huh... Hm?
A pack of prepared food...
Her breakfast?
Huh? But Shinpei-san, back then...
Inspector, come here!
Hm...
What is it?
Look at this.
A bandana, huh?
Oh! Is that stain blood?
Hey, isn't that...
Yeah.
Shinpei-san's bandana.
Shinpei-san?
He's Kanae-san's grandson.
Inspector Megure!
Hm?
This person says she saw a man
running out of this house...
What?
Sorry...
Could you tell us
what you just said once more?
Yes.
I think it was just past 9 AM...
A young man
came out of this house.
His face was deathly pale,
like he was running away.
I'm pretty sure that person was
Kanae-san's grandson...
Hmm. Do you know
where he lives?
I heard he lives alone
in an apartment nearby.
Right. Let's bring him in for questioning
immediately.
R-Right.
No way...
There's no way Shinpei-san
would commit murder.
It has to be some kind of mistake!
This is awful...
Shinpei-san, a murderer?
Even though he teaches us frisbee
so enthusiastically...
No way... Absolutely not.
(stomach growls)
Hey, Genta-kun!
What's wrong with you, at a time like this?
I-It wasn't me!
(stomach growls)
Sigh... Huh?
Shinpei-san!
Ah, Conan-kun!
Hey, you...
The police are looking for you.
This is about Granny, right?
Yeah. They're saying Shinpei-san
is the culprit.
No... I didn't do it.
But Shinpei-san,
you ran away from the scene, right?
Th-That's... Granny called me over
with a text...
And when I got there, she was already...
I ran outside in a panic
and bumped into someone...
After that, I just...
I didn't know what was happening...
Shinpei-san... You said your grandmother
has breakfast...
After walking Matsunosuke, right?
Huh? Ah... Yeah.
She always said eating after a little exercise
felt better.
There he is!
No! It wasn't me!
(police siren)
They arrested Shinpei-san...
Hey, Conan-kun...
Why are you just letting this happen?!
There's nothing we can do.
Shinpei-san's bandana
was found at the scene...
And there's even an eyewitness.
No way...
Conan-kun, you think
Shinpei-san is the culprit too?
I misjudged you.
But...
Hm?
There's more to what you're saying,
isn't there? Edogawa-kun.
Well, yeah.
First, the bandana found at the scene
isn't that rare of an item...
If someone wanted one,
they could get one easily.
I see... So the real culprit
might have prepared it...
To pin the crime on Shinpei-san.
But that alone isn't enough...
Inside the trash can at the scene...
There was a plastic bag
with a dry cleaning tag on it.
On that tag...
It said "Women's beige spring coat."
A beige spring coat?
Ah! The coat Granny was wearing
when she died!
Right. And then,
underneath that plastic bag...
A breakfast prepared food pack
had been thrown away.
The breakfast pack was under the plastic bag...
Which means the breakfast pack
was thrown away first.
So she ate breakfast,
then went to walk Matsunosuke.
Ah, that's backwards!
Yes, it's reversed!
Exactly. According to Shinpei-san,
the old lady always...
Had breakfast after coming back
from walking Matsunosuke...
But the scene showed
the opposite.
In other words, the scene
may have been staged.
But what if Shinpei-san
is the one lying?
No chance of that.
He talked about his grandmother's breakfast
last week too, remember?
Granny, you're about to have breakfast, right?
Let me eat too!
If he'd been lying
since back then...
That'd be pretty premeditated.
A guy that calculating wouldn't
drop a bloodstained bandana, right?
Good point.
Then who on earth...
As far as suspects go right now...
There's the dog friend Hirota-san
and the neighbor Kitazawa-san.
But they both
have alibis...
Then let's tear those alibis
to shreds ourselves!
Right! If we do that...
Shinpei-san might be able
to come back.
Time for the Detective Boys to shine!
Yes!
Yeah!
First up, Kitazawa-san's place.
Then we'll ask around
the shopping district.
Yeah!
Hmm...
No take-backs.
Shut up... I know that.
Here goes, Conan! There!
Ahh!
Sorry!
Our frisbee went in there...
Could you get it for us?
Good grief...
Sorry!
Alright, alright.
Go around to the front door.
Hmm...
Sorry about that, mister.
Our frisbee...
Oh, shogi!
Hmm, looks like a close match.
How long have you been playing?
Heh... Since this morning.
Wow, that's amazing.
99 wins, 99 losses over 10 years.
Today's the day we settle it once and for all.
We've been battling since 6 AM
without a single break, but...
Looks like you're losing.
Ugh...
Shut up! Don't interrupt the match!
S-Sorry...
Hmph!
Yes, 8:30.
At that time, Hirota-san...
Asked me to deliver the flowers,
so I went over.
And the arrangement as well?
Yes.
There were so many flowers...
In the end, it took me
until past noon.
Is that so...
In the end, we couldn't
break the alibis.
What do we do now, Conan?
Shinpei-san's going to be framed for this.
Hmm...
Maybe our original premise
was wrong.
Huh? original premise?
We've been thinking the victim,
the old lady...
Was killed after returning
from walking Matsunosuke, but...
Huh?
What do you mean?
The old lady walked the same route
at nearly the same time every morning.
So... maybe...
I see... The witnesses...
Just assumed they saw her
this morning as well.
Yeah.
An old lady in a beige coat
walking a dog, right?
I saw her this morning too.
Was it really this morning?
Yeah, a little past 8, I think.
I always pass her
when I'm walking this guy.
That dog always
marks his territory right there...
But this morning, that person
seemed to be in a hurry...
She just dragged the dog
right past.
Ah, the lady who walks her dog
every morning, right?
I saw her. This morning
was especially bad.
Especially bad?
That dog always gets in a fight
with a cat in front of my shop.
This morning it was really awful.
Lately, that person...
Had been keeping the dog
away from the cat, but...
Seems like she got careless.
So far, that's exactly 15 minutes
from the house.
Everyone said
she passed by this morning.
Hmm... So that means
it wasn't just an assumption.
Hmm... Huh?
Excuse me, ma'am.
Yes? What is it?
Did you see a woman walking a dog
around here this morning?
Oh, the police asked me
the same thing.
I saw her. Definitely.
Was that person
dragging the dog along?
Dragging? Yes...
Something like that.
When that person leaves the park,
she always goes left.
But this morning...
She pulled the dog and went right.
Pulled the dog... to the right?
H-Hey, Conan-kun!
This is the opposite direction
from the walking route!
We won't find any witnesses
this way!
(dog barks)
Ah!
Th-This is...
Oh? You kids...
Hm?
Still looking for witnesses?
Ah! That guy from earlier!
Didn't recognize you
without your dog.
Ha...
I see... So that's how it is.
Everyone was mistaken.
The witnesses... and even the culprit.
If that's the case, the culprit
will definitely show up there.
To destroy the crucial evidence.
Good evening.
What's the matter? At this hour...
You children...
Lady, we've figured out
who the real culprit is...
The one who killed Kanae-san.
What...
The culprit killed Kanae-san
well before 8 AM this morning...
Right after she'd finished
preparing breakfast.
After that, they cleaned up
the breakfast that had been set out...
Dressed the body in the coat
that had just come back from the cleaners...
And made it look like she was killed
after returning from her walk.
Then, they placed Shinpei-san's bandana,
which they'd prepared beforehand...
At the entrance...
Disguised themselves as Kanae-san,
and went out walking with Matsunosuke.
To create witnesses who saw
Kanae-san walking Matsunosuke...
And to establish
their own alibi.
Of course, it was an amateur disguise...
So if someone looked closely,
they might have been found out, but...
Having Matsunosuke with them
fooled everyone.
Marking territory in the usual spot...
Picking a fight with a cat in the usual spot.
Everyone thought, "Oh, it's the same old lady
with Matsunosuke, as always."
But when the culprit
left the park...
They went to the right.
Even though she always goes left.
Makes sense. If they completed
the entire walking route...
It would ruin the alibi setup.
After leaving the park, the culprit
returned home with Matsunosuke...
Met with the person they'd called over,
and completed their alibi.
Wait a minute... The dog?
What about Matsunosuke?
Back then, Matsunosuke
was sleeping here, wasn't he?
So the culprit couldn't have taken him...
It was a fake.
Ha!
The one put to sleep with drugs
back then...
Was a fake Matsunosuke
prepared by the culprit.
...Which means the culprit...
Owns a dog
that looks exactly like Matsunosuke.
Lady, you said you own
one of Matsunosuke's siblings.
Identical to Matsunosuke.
In other words, the culprit
can only be you.
Hirota Tomoko-san.
Conan-kun!
What?!
D-Detective! Please help me!
These children suddenly started
saying the strangest things!
Mouri-kun contacted me,
so I came over, but...
Yeah. Kogoro-san...
Had something urgent come up
and couldn't make it, so...
He asked us to tell you
in his place, Inspector.
I see...
...So, you have evidence, I take it?
Th-That's right! Evidence!
Show me your evidence!
The evidence is right there.
What?
The real Matsunosuke...
That you swapped with your own dog.
What do you have to say,
Hirota-san?
N-No... You're wrong!
This is my dog!
Matsunosuke is
tied up over there...
Hey, Matsunosuke! Let's go!
(dog barks)
Got it!
Ah... Ahh...
We did it!
Hey, lady.
You think the dog is the reason
you got caught, don't you?
Because that's true, isn't it?
If that stupid dog hadn't
gotten lured by a frisbee...
Wrong.
After you killed Kanae-san...
You cleaned up the breakfast,
dressed her in the coat...
And staged it to look like she was killed
after returning from her walk...
But you made
a huge mistake.
Kanae-san always...
Had her breakfast after
coming back from the walk.
What?
So if she'd been killed
right after coming home...
The breakfast setup should have been
left as it was...
And if she'd been killed
after eating breakfast...
It makes no sense for her to be
wearing her walking coat.
In other words, that scene...
Was full of inconsistencies
that didn't add up at all.
♪~
~♪
Still, I'm glad...
They found the real culprit.
Now Shinpei-san can
teach us frisbee again.
Yeah... I can't wait.
And your clothes came back
all clean too.
Ah... Matsunosuke's paw prints
got cleaned off...
Nice and clean, good as new...
(Matsunosuke barks)
Gwah!
Ahh...
Ah... Sorry, Conan-kun!
I'll get it cleaned again!
No... that's quite alright.
Here, Detective.
For now, please take this.
He lost the ability to distinguish reality
and became a shut-in...
And in the end,
he went and hanged himself.
Ah... Ahh...
Th-The chief... He won't wake up...
He looks dead!
This one really is dead.
Next Conan,
"Kogoro is at the Bar (Part 1)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Champagne"
What's
champagne?
Champagne is something
you drink to celebrate.
Way too fancy
for the old man.