Evacuation of residents in a three-block radius has been completed.
Defusal at Location One is now in progress.
Defusal at Location One has been completed.
The helmet is equipped with a duct for cooling
for respiration that alternates as the mist remover for the lens.
And we are heading to Location Two with Officer Matsuda with us.
To protect against the hot air of explosion,
the structure of the protective gear does not allow any openings.
The pockets all over the wear have metal protective plates in them.
The gear is so complex that you cannot put it on by yourself.
It weighs 40 kilograms.
In the protective gear, it's a sauna even in cold winter.
You can't keep wearing it for more than five minutes.
I'd say it's impossible.
All police units, all police units.
Disperse from area 1.
Proceed to secure area 2...
All units in city limits,
watch out for suspicious vehicles.
That is all.
DC unit 80, roger that.
AV unit, roger that.
Keep cool and collected.
No baggage, please. Evacuate quickly and quietly.
Please be careful not to push others.
There is no need to rush.
Evacuation of the residents of this building is completed.
Roger.
"Kenji Hagiwara" -Well, let's start...
working on it.
"Jimpei Matsuda, MPD Riot Squad Bomb Disposal Unit"
You've done a good job, Matsuda.
How's Hagiwara?
Well, analysis shows a photosensitive trigger.
A white cord from a mercury tilt switch.
From the LCD panel...
Matsuda. What's up?
Hagiwara! What's taking you so long?
Go, tear it apart fast.
You're too loud, man.
You're making my fingers shake.
Have you finished already?
Yeah.
I opened it and found out it's rather simple clockwork.
It's so simple.
Three minutes was long enough?
How about yours?
Takes more than 3 minutes for sure.
It looks simple, but there're so many traps around it.
I suppose this is the real one.
Right.
By the way, you're in protective gear, aren't you?
In that hot torturing thing? No way.
Moron! You want to get killed, man?
Well, you can get the guy for me.
Are you trying to get on my nerves?
Can't take a joke?
I'm not a klutz.
Anyway, finish ASAP and get on back here.
I'll buy you a drink tonight.
Lucky me!
You lured me into full throttle.
I'm gonna work at full speed.
What's that?
What's up, Hagiwara?
Run, everybody!
Get out of here!
The timer started counting again!
Hagiwara?
Hey! Hagiwara!
Hagiwara...
Hagiwara!
Why? How did you find out?
I asked that boy wearing glasses.
So, that's why.
By the way, Shinichi,
what're you going to do about the all-country sim-test?
All-country sim-test?
You can't make it, can you?
I'll bet you're going to say you're tied up with a new case or something.
Wait! What's this?
"I have stolen your sleeping face." -How did you do that?
Gotcha!
Gosh.
Dad, Conan!
Don't be late. Breakfast is ready!
Dad.
What's all the commotion about from so early in the morning?
It's noon already.
I'm going to prepare for tomorrow test.
Sonoko and I are going to work on it today.
Will you finish up quickly?
That's your problem, not mine.
You're taking your report to a client, aren't you?
And, Conan, you promised Ayumi and the others
that you'll go to Haido Shopping Mall with them.
Yeah.
Haido Shopping Mall?
Oh, the mall with that huge Ferris Wheel.
Yeah.
January 6th, Monday.
The Winter holidays were almost over.
That first day started very peacefully
but the following two days were turned out to be a nightmare.
"Unsettled Metropolitan Police Department, 12 million hostages"
Sato, what do you think of this disguise of mine?
It's cool, isn't it?
Sato?
What's the matter with you? Anything wrong?
Miwako?
Hey, Miwako.
Miwako!
Yumi.
What's the matter with you? In a coma or something?
I'm all right.
Just a little tired, I guess.
I'm going out for a while.
I thought you said you were going to do paperwork all day today.
I just remembered something. I have to go out, and take a look.
Don't forget the karaoke tonight.
Oh, yeah. What time was it?
Nine o'clock.
I sent mail to your cell. You can look at it.
Huh?
Well...
Sorry. I've deleted it already.
Gosh. Stop deleting mails right after you finish reading them.
That's one of your bad habits.
If I don't delete them, I'll soon get a mailbox full of junk mails
and lose track of important mails.
So, you mean mine is not important.
That's not what I meant.
You better not.
Okay. Nine o'clock.
Don't be late!
Roger and out.
Mail that you can't delete...
"Haido Shopping Mall"
It's so high!
Really. Great!
This Ferris Wheel is 125 meter high.
It's the highest in Japan.
It takes 18 minutes to make one round.
I could make six cups of ramen!
The diameter of the circle is 105 meters
and it takes 18 minutes to go once around.
That means the speed of this car
is about 30 centimeters per second.
Come on. Can't you think of anything else?
Oh? Such as the power necessary to make one round?
Cut it out.
It's been three years now.
Everybody. Let me introduce...
Mr. Jimpei Matsuda.
He will start working with us as of today
in the Criminal Investigation Section.
He has been in the Security Department, Special Task Force,
and I'd say that he is a bit of a stranger here.
We can do without that kind of introduction, Inspector.
I'm not exactly a new kid from the country.
And I don't think this show and tell about me
would be of any use to anybody.
I was stationed where I don't want to be
and I'm upset about it.
Well then, Officer Sato!
You help him out and...
Me, sir?
Don't shy away!
He is here for certain reasons,
and they asked me in person to play along.
Will you take care of him?
Yes, sir.
Hey, what kind of questioning was that supposed to be?
Questioning people like a mobster like that,
nobody will answer you.
Gosh. You have been with us for 6 days now.
Why don't you listen to me and do as I say?
Oh, you got mail?
You're pretty fast.
Yeah.
I just happen to be clever with my fingers.
Are you mailing your girlfriend?
No. I'm sending my best friend mail,
though I know he's not going to write back to me
because he blew up 4 years ago.
What?
Pass? Pass what? Are you crazy?
I have to wait here today.
I'm sure you guys can bring the old suspect
from the local police up here without me.
Now, you listen to me.
I am.
You said you receive it on January 6th every year. Today is the day.
Yes. Every year for three years,
you mean the fax with just one large number on it, right?
Number 3 was written on it three years ago;
number 2, two years ago,
and number 1, a year ago.
I'm sure
it's the time bomb count down.
If the guy's making any moves, today is the day.
Inspector! We got one this year, too.
That fax with a number on it, you mean.
And? What is the number this time?
It's not a number this time.
"I am a knight of the round table.
Let the foolish, cunning police know that
today at noon, at the 14th hour,
we will bury the head our fellow knight,
and in his memory, we will set off fireworks.
If you want to stop it, come to us.
We prepared the 72nd seat for you and we are ready."
What does it mean?
I don't know.
Hey! Just where do you think you're going?
Where else?
The knight of the round table says there are 72 seats.
If it's round and has 72 seats,
it's the big Ferris Wheel...
in the Haido Shopping Mall.
Please, go ahead.
Gosh! We are too late.
But it's 30 minutes to noon.
Police. What happened?
The control room of the Ferris Wheel suddenly blew up.
We can't stop the wheel.
We'd like to get the people out of cars, but...
Where is the 72nd car right now?
What?
It's coming down soon.
-Matsuda! -Stop right there!
The knight was not waiting for us,
but there's something beneath the seat.
You don't say... a bomb?
Wait, Matsuda!
I'm all right.
Let a pro handle work like this.
Wait a second, Matsuda!
What does he mean by pro?
He was at the explosives disposal team until last year,
in the Security Task Force.
Then the pal he was talking about that he said had passed away...
That's probably his pal Hagiwara of the same team,
who was killed on duty while he was disposing a bomb,
four years ago, on January 6th.
In that case, there were two bombs in separate places.
Matsuda disposed of one bomb.
But Hagiwara didn't have enough time.
The bomber has not yet been identified.
Matsuda requested transfer to the special team
that is investigating on the bomber.
He kept requesting the transfer, but was turned down.
Since they thought he wanted to do things for his pal,
they chose to transfer him, so he could cool off,
and sent him to our section.
Inspector, what shall we do?
It's six minutes to noon.
It'll take the car 10 more minutes to make a round and return.
We have no choice but to leave it to Matsuda.
What's that?
It stopped.
Put out the fire quick!
We've got trouble.
Hello! Matsuda? Are you all right?
Yeah.
But with the shock just now, and odd switch was turned on.
What?
The mercury lever.
Mercury lever?
A slight shake can make the mercury-drop roll,
and if the drop touches the wire, that's it.
If you don't want to see me blow up,
keep the car still until I dispose of this bomb.
But we have less than five minutes until the blow-up.
Three minutes would be more than enough for this kind of device.
"To the brave police officer..."
"To the brave police officer.
In praise of your courage, we will give you a prize."
Wait, what are you talking about?
"A clue to another bigger firework will be displayed
at 3 seconds before the explosion.
With best wishes."
These are the words displayed on the LCD panel right now.
I suppose if we stop the bomb and turn off the power,
we will never be able to read the clue again.
That is, the guy intended to put someone into this car
and show these words to him.
Then, that blow-up was turned on
because the guy saw you enter the car.
In other words, the bomber is somewhere close by.
It's very difficult to identify him out of this crowd of people.
But I can guess where he set the other bomb.
You can?
The fax says, "the head of our fellow knight."
The knights of the round table were from medieval Europe.
And those medieval knights wore helmets designed with a cross in front.
It's obvious now, isn't it?
A diagram sign of a hospital?
You guessed right.
I'll tell you which hospital it is after I read the clue.
You'll tell me after you read it?
But the clue comes up just 3 seconds before.
Well, the battery is almost out.
Bye now.
Matsuda...
Allow me for today, will you?
Hell, no. There's only one minute left.
Everybody! Get out of here!
What?
Matsuda!
Don't, Sato! It's too late!
But...
Too dangerous! Back off, please!
But he's still there!
He's inside!
"Sending mail"
Sorry, Hagiwara.
I guess I couldn't keep my word.
What?
What are we going to do? The fax says there's another bomb.
I know there is!
Beika Central Hospital.
What?
The other bomb is there!
Dispatch the bomb disposal squad on the double!
He was like a puff of wind.
"Jimpei Matsuda: Beika Central Hospital."
"I kinda liked you."
He vanished in an instant.
All he left behind is the sad sound.
Officer Sato!
Hey.
I didn't know such a thing took place three years ago.
Yes.
If Sato still has lingering memories about the incident,
we don't have a chance.
I suppose so.
If you want to be like him, you can die on duty.
Hey! Don't say things like that.
Unlucky things may come true, you know.
Wait! It's Sato.
Takagi and Shiratori.
What's the matter?
Conan and the kids are here too.
I just happened to run into them.
Because I am grateful to them for helping out in the case,
I'm going to get them sweets or something.
-All the cake we can eat. -Yes.
And, what brings you here?
We sort of got a squeal.
We looked through inside this restaurant,
but nothing showed up.
It's very likely to be a false lead.
Okay, then, I am going to karaoke with Yumi this evening.
Would you guys care to join us?
What? Sure we do.
Well, then, you go ahead, Takagi.
I'm not in the mood for singing today.
And I guess I'd rather not.
Hey, let's hurry up and go.
-Yeah. -Yes.
What kind of squeal was it?
Yeah. It was a phone call, a warning,
that a bomb is set up in this restaurant.
Today is January 6th.
The same day as the bombing of 7 years ago and 3 years ago.
So, we came and checked.
A bomb threat warning, a false lead...
"I am a Major Leaguer, a strong pitcher as well as batter."
"Now, this is the beginning of an extended game."
Don't tell me...
Shiratori!
What's that?
Bombing, again?
Shiratori!
It's dangerous.
Get out of here, quickly.
Are you all right, Shiratori?
Yeah. I couldn't run as you did.
Takagi! Block off this road and get an ambulance.
I will.
But he can speak, that means he's okay.
No. He's bleeding at the side of his head,
with paralysis in the left limbs.
This could be...
Accute subdural hemorrhage.
We'd better take him ASAP to the hospital.
He's in critical condition.
Oh, no.
Anyway, if the gas catches fire,
it might cause secondary explosion.
Let's move Inspector Shiratori away from the car
until the ambulance gets here.
Yes, let's do that.
This is terrible. Really terrible.
Yeah. Who on earth would do such a thing?
I don't know the bomber,
but I'm sure that he's after a police officer.
What?
He gave false lead saying that he set up a bomb in the restaurant,
and lured the police into the restaurant.
While the officers were looking for the bomb,
he planted the real bomb into the car,
hiding himself among the customers
who were lead out of the restaurant.
From what I saw,
the trigger mechanism seems to work
in a way that the safety pin goes off when the door is first opened.
And when the door is opened again in order to exit,
then it explodes.
The question is,
why did Inspector Shiratori try to get out immediately?
This...
What's that?
I wanted to show this to you as soon as possible.
The memory that you harbor within you and cannot erase...
This is a chance to get rid of it.
"I am a Major Leaguer, a strong pitcher as well as batter.
Now, this is the beginning of an extended game.
The game starts at noon tomorrow.
It ends at three in the afternoon.
No use getting ready a good stopper.
Because I will win in the end.
And if you want to stop the game, come to me.
I will be waiting for you
to climb up the bloody mound in the steel batter's box."
What?
It's...
Hey.
Could it be...
This is...
I am a knight of the round table.
Let the foolish, cunning police know that...
Let a pro handle work like this.
It's him.
It's him again.
Really?
Did Shiratori get involved in an explosion?
Yes, sir.
He was taken by an ambulance to a nearby hospital just now.
He has been seriously injured.
What is the situation over there, sir?
The same fax with the same words you just told me.
The same faxes have been sent to
all the police stations in the metropolitan district.
They are all upset over the fax.
There's a possibility that it is the same one
responsible for the bombings 7 years ago and 3 years ago.
No doubt about it. It's from the bomber.
Please tell Director Matsumoto about it, sir.
In the incident of three years ago,
only the first portion of the warning notice
was released to the public.
An imitator couldn't have made up such a detailed warning notice.
Sato, I brought your car here.
Thanks, Chiba.
Now, I will go join the investigation team, sir.
Hey, Sato! Sato!
He's not getting away. Not this time.
I'll take him in myself.
Emergency, emergency.
From MPD to all stations.
We haven't specified where yet,
but we received a bomb threat warning.
There are two bombs.
Time of explosion is at noon tomorrow and at 15:00 the same day.
As the past incidents show, this warning is very credible.
Keep strict watch and be on the alert.
Continue investigation and don't let the suspect get away.
Extended game?
He's toying with us.
-Megure! -Yes, sir.
No extension is allowed.
Settle the case once and for all, understand?
I'll do my best, sir.
It's your chance to...
The memory that you harbor within you and cannot erase...
This is a chance to get rid of it.
Yes. I have to get rid of.
I've got to arrest the bomber and forget about the past.
Forget?
Keepsakes of your father who died on duty,
and you wear it as a charm.
Give it back to me!
I know what you want to say to me,
throw it away to go on forward, forget about it.
No. You don't have to forget.
What?
Whether you move on forward or not depends on you.
If you forget him completely, your father will be really gone.
Matsuda.
Will you tell me something?
Why does this bomber hold a grudge against the police?
Conan!
When did you get in the car?
Tell me, please.
In the bombing incident of 7 years ago,
there were two bombers.
They planted the bombs in two separate condominiums.
They demanded a billion yen,
and said that they will blow the bomb up
if even one resident escapes from the condo.
We disposed of one bomb in time
but failed with the other.
We had to accept their demand.
They stopped the time counter
for triggering the bomb through their remote controller.
All the residents evacuated
and it seemed as if all was over.
But 30 minutes later, one of the bombers calls the police.
He said, "The timer is still counting down, what's going on?"
He probably made the mistake of watching the TV news
and reviewing what happened through VCR.
The police thought it a good chance to secure the bomber.
They talked him into conversation and succeeded in tracing his phone call.
We found the bomber in a telephone booth.
But unfortunately...
The bomber fled and was run over by a car and killed.
Then, how did you figure out there was the other bomber?
It's because...
Later, the timer that was supposed to stop counting
started counting again and the bomb blew up.
Run, everybody!
The timer started counting again!
We found the address of the bomber who was killed.
But all we found out was that he was living there with another guy.
The other bomber probably thought
the police gave false information through TV
and set a trap, which killed his pal.
They're blaming their faults on the wrong people.
It's their fault, because they set the bomb
and tried to get the money in the first place.
That's right.
You heard me, it's time to get off now.
We're going to help you.
The more the merrier.
Well, but if they find out
I'm making investigations with kids in my car...
Well, kids have more advantage
in solving this kind of childish codes.
Or, is it that you're not satisfied having just us
and Conan not around?
Not satisfied?
No, that's not it.
But, why did the bomber go out of his way
to send the coded note to the police?
If he didn't do anything, he wouldn't be caught.
Suppose you hide a treasure
and somebody comes trying to find it, what would you do?
I'll be watching him with my heart beating fast.
Suppose you hide the treasure in a pitfall with a trap?
Then of course, we will...
We'll give them clues little by little.
That's it! That's why he's started to give clues.
You're right. The bomber's acting like a child,
playing with a toy called the bomb.
He's a wicked brat with a wicked toy in his hands.
Hey, Ran! Telephone!
Gosh. Dad, answer the phone, will you?
Both my hands are full, so I can't pick up the phone.
Gosh.
Hello. This is Mouri.
It's me.
Dr. Agasa!
Ran, it's about Conan.
He insists on staying here tonight.
What? At your place, Dr. Agasa?
Yes. The kids really liked the game I made
and they just can't quit.
Are Ayumi and the others there, too?
That's right.
The Winter holidays will be over,
so they will be back by tomorrow evening.
But...
Well then, goodbye.
Ayumi's home next.
Please, Doc.
We want to get back at the bomber for what he did to Inspector Shiratori.
Right, right!
Please, Dr. Agasa.
I'll make sure to keep them out of danger, Doctor.
Gosh. I'll be in trouble if anyone finds out.
And I cooked Conan's favorite dish.
That's good, you know.
You're taking the national test tomorrow, aren't you?
You don't have to take care of the kids,
so you can prepare yourself for the test.
By the way, Ran, I'd like another bottle, please.
What? You are going to drink more?
It won't hurt, will it?
It's more of hassle taking care of a drunkard.
What does this note mean?
The only thing we're sure of is the time.
Anyway, the guy's a foreigner.
He's a major league baseball player.
Not exactly a foreigner.
There are Japanese major league players too now a days.
That's right.
But he set bomb to a baseball ground somewhere, I'm sure.
Yeah. It says "mound" and "Batter's box".
It's South Haido station.
You mean, South Haido station?
Of Toto Central Line?
That's right.
What are you talking about?
There's no baseball ground near South Haido Station.
It's a code.
It isn't literally referring to a mound or batter's box.
So, you mean you deciphered the code?
Yes.
Three years ago, bombs were set to
the Big Ferris Wheel of the Haido Shopping Mall
and the Beika Central Hospital.
South Haido Station of the Touto Chuo Line
is located where the roads facing the two places.
But that's just a play on words extended game and extended lines.
Slow, aren't you?
If a station is located where the roads intersect,
there would most naturally be a stopper there, right?
A stopper?
Stopper?
What's that?
I see! I got it!
What?
The crossing bar of a railroad crossing, isn't it?
Then, the steel batter's box could be...
Box of steel, or the car of the train.
And, to go climb the bloody mound,
could mean a red colored train that goes up to the center of the city.
Good heavens! I have to let Sato know about this.
It's all right. I heard you.
We virtually agree.
One bomb will be set up on the Toto Central Line train
that goes from South Haido Station to Tokyo.
I will contact the Inspector to dispatch investigators.
And Takagi, you arrange for the bomb disposal squad.
-Hurry! -Yes, right away.
What? South Haido Station?
Really?
Yes. And then?
Okay, I see.
We will arrange for it immediately.
Everybody, please evacuate calmly!
What? It's just trash.
What's this?
This... this is...
A bomb?
Get off, everybody. It's a bomb!
What?
What the heck is this?
What? False?
It wasn't a real bomb, you say?
And then?
I guess the bomber expected
the investigators go there to search.
Right. He is a smart-aleck mischievous brat, I guess.
-Besides, he's not after money. -Yes.
Yeah. The guy probably just has a grudge against the police,
and is holding hostage 12 million people who live in the city of Tokyo.
"Tohto Line, South Haido Station"
"Fail"
What? False bomb again?
Did you check all of them?
Is there no real bomb?
No, sir.
We have checked all the red trains that go through the city,
but all the suspicious ones have been false or pranks.
I see.
The bomber's probably trying to throw off our investigation.
Anyway, be patient and continue your investigations.
Yes, sir.
Director Matsumoto.
What is it?
Report from the Ozaki team, sir. They are at the ballparks.
-And, what did you get? -Yes, sir.
They have finished checking all the major ballparks in the city
but nothing came up so far.
They say they will continue investigation covering smaller ballparks.
We don't have to check the ballpark anymore, I guess.
All right. Stop all the red trains in the city.
Get all the investigators out of the ballparks
and dispatch them to all the stations to conduct investigations.
We still have five more hours
till the first explosion expected to go off at noon.
He can outfox us and try setting up a bomb from now.
Yes, sir!
Five more hours, huh?
I wanted to say we have only five hours left for us.
Yes.
I'm sleepy.
Isn't it strange?
From this note, you would think that
he expected somebody to come kooking for it to the ballpark,
but nothing happened.
He thought nobody would come.
It's off-season and no big game is scheduled.
Oh, yeah?
If he wanted to play pranks on the police,
he could have set a false trap or two.
At any rate, we can't keep those kids with us anymore.
You're right.
By the way, how is Shiratori? Did you ask how he is?
Yes, I did.
Yumi is taking care of Shiratori,
and she told me that the operation was successful.
They are waiting for him to regain consciousness.
That's good. I'm relieved.
Listen here, Takagi.
Make sure Miwako stays out of dangerous situations.
If the bomber is the same bomber
that killed Matsuda with a bomb,
who knows what she might do
and there will be no one but you who will be able to save her.
What? Why me?
You're so much like Mr. Matsuda.
But that's only because I happened to be disguised like him.
Of course, he's five to ten times better in looks or attitude.
Ten times, is it?
But something about you reminds me of him.
It may be your heart, feelings or whatever...
Something resembles Matsuda.
I guess Miwako came to realize that lately.
Hey, Takagi.
Takagi!
What were you thinking over so seriously?
Did you find out where the bomb is?
No, I didn't.
Then, what?
It's nothing important.
Okay, for now.
I'll continue the investigation.
You send the kids home.
Then you return to the MPD to get some sleep
and stay there to help Inspector Megure.
But I can keep investigating.
Don't be silly. An officer who is unsteady from lack of sleep
will only get in the way of the investigation. Got it?
Yes.
No.
I won't let you take him from me.
Not anymore.
Never.
Taking a test right after new year holidays
makes me feel like I'm living a gray life of a prep.
Yeah.
New year days are meant for everyone to enjoy!
So, you enjoyed yourself, didn't you?
Sure. I didn't want to regret not doing what I wanted to do.
Well, only thing I can depend on is this.
What? Isn't it... Could that be...
No.
Look!
Gosh. It's the photo of Kyogoku.
Yeah. This photo gives me energy when I look at it.
Even if my test results aren't good,
I won't get depressed.
As long as I have Makoto's love,
I don't need to score 100 on my test.
Oh, I'm so ashamed of myself for being so bold!
Sure, sure.
"I have stolen your sleeping face."
Okay, kids. I'll take you home.
Tell me where you live, will you?
What?
Are you taking us back home?
We may be able to solve this code in a moment.
You haven't slept for a long time.
I can't keep you, school kids, with me any longer.
What?
Say! Where's Officer Sato?
She's investigating on the case.
I see. Officer Sato told you to send us home.
You do everything she tells you to do, don't you?
I have to. She's two years older and my senior as well.
And you think you'll do fine after marrying her, too?
Marry her?
I won't be. Because she just dumped me the other day.
Sato.
Yes?
You said you have something to say to me.
Oh, that.
Sato.
Let's forget about the date. The date we were gonna have.
What?
I'm cursed.
Cursed?
All the people that I care dearly for,
seem to disappear from me.
My father, the P.E. teacher in school,
my senior in the baseball club,
and...
him too.
I don't want to have to go through that kind of pain anymore.
Sato.
We have been good friends and police officers,
and I want us to stay that way right through.
Sato.
Takagi.
Yes...
You're right. We are not well-matched in the first place.
Yeah, you deserve a prettier cuter girl.
Really?
See? I'm not getting married.
So you gave her up?
What a chicken!
No guts at all.
I don't want to give her up, but...
But what?
But...
Officer Matsuda risked his life to save the people in the hospital,
but I can't be his equal. Right?
Where did you learn that?
Officer Takagi. Ahead! Look ahead!
We heard about it from the lady on the mini-patrol car.
You mean Yumi?
She told us in detail.
Then, Officer Matsuda decided at that time
to risk his life to tell us where the other bomb was planted.
Yes, yes.
Well, time's up. I have to hang up now.
Wait, Matsuda!
Matsuda...
You can't listen to it or tell it without tears.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah?
I wouldn't blame you for giving up.
The memory of one who's gone is sealed
and will be kept in the heart for a life time.
Like someone I know.
Hey! I'm not dead yet.
How did you do on the math test?
Bummers.
Unlike you, I have nobody to help me in my difficulties.
Help me?
You can't fool me, Ran.
You were often looking at Shinichi's desk for the right answers.
"Help, Shinichi!
I have trouble solving this derivative, integral problem."
Be honest about it.
No, you're wrong! I looked at Shinichi's desk because...
Because? Keep on!
Because...
You're blushing crimson.
Red is a sinister color during test time.
Speaking of red,
there has been so many police sirens since this morning.
True. You're right.
What's happened?
Red, red...
What's the matter with red?
Something does not fit.
This "climb up the bloody mound" means.
You mean that it's not a red train?
It's kind of... not right.
Now, wait. If it's like the case 3 years before,
the first bomb is set in a place
that's rather easy for the police to find.
I have to think more simply.
The simpler the better.
Something that reminds you of red?
Mailboxes, fire engines...
Red demon, little red riding hood...
Tomato, strawberries, watermelon, apple,
cherries, hot chili pepper, red salmon and red lobsters...
Red... climb... steel... box...
Genta, you only think about food.
I've used up my brain, now I'm hungry.
I'm kinda thirsty.
Well, then we can go and stop at some parking area.
Red, you say. There's another red over there.
Look, you can see it over there.
Yeah.
I see.
Red, climb up, box of steel...
"Toto Tower"
Is something already happening?
What is it?
There's smoke coming out.
I wonder if a bomb was set up here after all.
I'll go ask what happened,
so you kids wait in the car.
Okay?
We were scheduled to bring you
a special on Toto Towers mascot Toto today,
but due to an accident,
we have inevitably changed the schedule.
Excuse me. What on earth has happened?
You see, the thing is...
What? The bomb is inside Toto Tower?
Yes, I'm pretty sure.
Just what do you mean? Tell me about it in detail, will you?
Yes. Just before I got here, there was a small explosion,
and the elevator seems to have stopped.
-What? -It's most likely that
the suspect thinking that the police located the bomb,
used a remote control to set off the explosion.
The control room of the Ferris Wheel suddenly blew up.
We can't stop the wheel.
It's the same as back then.
I'll go over to the elevator that had stopped and check things out.
No!
That bomb has been set to lure officers there. It's a trap!
What? A trap?
I'll be there in 5 minutes, so wait there until I get there.
Understand?
Okay.
Hey, we've got trouble!
It seems that a girl's been trapped in the elevator that stopped
because of the explosion a while ago.
What?
Officer Sato, a child is in the elevator.
Calm down.
We've still got two hours to go before the predicted time of bombing.
But I'd better go and check things out as soon as possible.
Don't worry.
I'll work something out, so you just stay there.
But...
Listen here, Takagi.
Make sure Miwako stays out of dangerous situations.
I'll rescue that girl. I promise!
But...
Who knows what she might do later.
Understand? This is an order!
You stay there until I get there.
Understand, Officer Takagi?
Hey, Officer Takagi. Can you hear me?
Officer Takagi, answer me!
Hey, Officer Takagi!
Officer Takagi!
Please, Officer Takagi! Don't go!
I'm going.
I'm going to check how things are inside.
Officer Takagi!
All of you!
I'm going to go inside the tower now,
so you all stay still and wait here, okay?
What?
Understand?
Yes, sir.
I'll be right back!
I wonder if Officer Takagi is going to be okay.
-Ai, take care of everybody, okay? -What?
-Hey, Conan! -Conan!
What? Are you going too, Conan?
I'm just going to go check how things are.
You guys keep watch and make sure nobody suspicious
comes near this car.
But...
We'll be in big trouble if a bomb is set up on this car again, right?
But I know you guys, the Youth Detective Squad,
will be able to take care of things even if I'm not around, right?
Well, I guess.
Leave it to us.
See you!
Be careful, Conan!
According to the report from Officer Takagi,
about 15 minutes ago,
there was a small explosion near the special observatory area.
It seems that one elevator of this observatory is stalled.
Only it hasn't been confirmed whether this explosion
was due to a bomb or an accident.
It much too resembles the case of 3 years ago to be an accident.
True.
There's probably no doubt about it.
Emergency, emergency!
From MPD to all stations.
There is a high possibility that
a bomb has been set at Toto Towers in Minato Ward.
Head to the site on the double
and block off the entrance to Toto Tower.
Secure an evacuation site for the citizens in the vicinity.
Officer Takagi.
Emergency announcement to all visitors.
We are very sorry to announce that we will be closing for the day.
Please follow the instructions of the guide
and leave the tower immediately.
Please remain calm, and move along without rushing.
Excuse me, police. Please let me through!
Please don't panic.
Police! Where's the elevator that stopped?
It's the one at the very end.
Thanks.
Akemi, you'll be fine. Don't be afraid. Come on out.
Police.
This is the elevator that the girl is trap in?
Yes, sir.
-It came down from the top floor... -Akemi...
and stopped just before reaching the observatory.
Akemi. What are you doing, Akemi?
Hurry and come out! Come over here!
Akemi!
Only one child was in the elevator
but she's so scared that she won't listen to her mother
telling her to come out.
This space is too small for an adult to get through.
Will you carry me up then?
What?
I can make it inside, can't I?
Conan.
We continue to bring you live broadcast news from Toto Tower.
Today, at approximately 9:45 a.m.,
there was an explosion inside Toto Tower.
The cause of the explosion is still unknown.
Fortunately, no casualties have been reported,
but due to the impact of the explosion,
one of the elevators have stopped.
A four years old girl who happened to be on the elevator
is trapped inside.
Presently, while trying to find the cause of the explosion...
Conan, are you all right?
Yes.
Hello, Akemi.
I'm going to go over to you now, so hold on, okay?
Akemi, what a cute teddy bear.
What's its name?
Jam.
What a cute name! Is he a boy?
Yes.
I want to go over and say hello to Jam.
Is it okay?
Yes, it's okay.
I'm going over there, okay?
We just got a report that
a police officer went into the elevator
to rescue the girl that is trapped inside.
What? A child went into the elevator?
It can't be!
And mommy bought me Jam for my birthday.
I see. Since mommy's waiting outside, shall we go?
Yes.
Okay, come. Good girl.
-Mommy! -Akemi!
Mommy!
-Akemi! -Mommy!
Akemi!
-Okay, Conan, now you. -Yes!
Conan!
Gosh!
And? You went off wanting to look cool,
and now you're trapped in the elevator with Conan.
I'm sorry.
By the way, are you sure there's no bomb in that elevator?
No, there's nothing that looks like a bomb here in the elevator.
I'm going check the top of the elevator now.
Do you know about where you are now?
Probably...
All the wires seem to have been severed,
so I think with the emergency stop
we are in the middle of the observatory and roof of the tower building.
Is that right?
I guess I'll have to climb to the ceiling
and wait for the rescue squad.
No, don't climb up to the ceiling!
The mercury lever will operate!
The mercury lever?
Mercury lever?
A slight shake can make the mercury-drop roll,
and if the drop touches the wire, that's it.
Conan, what's a mercury lever?
It's a part of the trigger device of the bomb.
It's a bomb big enough that is capable of
not only blowing up this elevator
but the entire Toto Tower as well.
A bomb?
On the ceiling of this elevator?
Are you sure about that, Conan?
Yes. I saw bombs that looks just like this one on TV.
I heard that if it's just one type of liquid it's okay,
but when it mixes with the other liquid,
it turns into a very strong bomb.
Then, wouldn't it be more the reason
to have the rescue squad come here?
I just said that the mercury lever is set, didn't I?
It's most likely that the switch went on
with the impact of the elevator stopping just a while ago.
The switch of the trigger device
that will go off with the slightest shake.
So if you climb up to this roof
or if the rescue squad comes down here with a rope,
the minute they set foot on the ground
and even if it shakes just a little bit, it's boom!
Is it that strong?
The mercury lever.
Mercury lever...
Just as I thought.
I'm sure that the one who set this up
is the same bomber as three years ago.
Then, don't tell me that...
Then, why don't we have them lower a rope from the elevator door above
and we both climb and escape?
I don't think that will work either.
What?
There's wire tap near the bomb.
So, I'm sure that as soon as the bomber
is listening to our conversation from somewhere.
And the minute we leave here and he stops hearing our conversation,
he's planning to turn on the switch and set the bomb off.
Which means we're trapped either way.
No, we still have one way out.
I have to disassemble this bomb.
I need them to lower the bomb disposal tool from above though.
I repeat.
All citizens within the vicinity of Toto Tower,
please follow the instructions of the police and evacuate to safety.
-What? -Are we running away?
Conan and Officer Takagi are still in there.
No need to worry,
because those two are probably heading this way already.
Officer Chiba, please take the children to a safe place.
Okay.
The two are going to dispose of the bomb.
What?
The bomb disposal squad is not even going into the tower
and are waiting for communication,
so that's what it means, right?
They'll be okay.
The composition of the bomb is virtually the same as
the one that was set up in Beika Central Hospital 3 years ago,
so those two will somehow work something out.
Yes, I guess so.
As long as they don't lend an ear
to the voice of the devil, like 3 years ago...
Let it down slowly.
Easy now, easy.
All right...
Are you all right?
Okay, I got it!
Roger!
We've completed giving the equipment.
Okay.
Okay, Officer Takagi, let's start.
Yes, sir.
You idiot!
Shape up and stop panicking!
The one who's going to do the actual work is the boy that is with you!
If you get flustered, you may make the boy anxious
and that may call for careless mistakes!
Yes, sir.
Don't worry.
If you take it easy and follow our instructions,
it'll finish in no time at all.
Calm down!
I understand.
Okay. First of all,
let's start by removing the photosensitive trigger device.
Yes, sir.
We will turn off the elevator lights in a minute from now,
so put on the infrared night scope.
When it gets dark, remove the mercury lever's right side cover.
Be careful not to touch the mercury lever.
First, we remove the cover, right?
Right. We'll turn off the lights now.
Did you get that, Conan?
Conan?
Here it is. The light sensitive tube.
If I cut the cord...
What a relief.
Conan, can you hear me?
Yes! I can hear you, so keep on going.
Yeah.
Let's see.
If you take off the cover, you can see a lot of machines, right?
Just above those machines, you should see a device that moves
when it detects light called a light sensitive tube.
First of all, cut the cord
that is sticking out of the light sensitive tube.
Then, I turn this...
Electricity's flowing!
Watch out, watch out.
Okay, then. I'll place the plastic plate in this space
and use it as a stopper.
Stopper?
Come to think of it, that code...
"No use getting ready a good stopper", that's what it said.
Good stopper probably means earned run average.
But, why a major leaguer?
This is Japan.
He could've just written pro baseball player.
Wait a sec.
Extended game... earned run average...
Turn over... Major Leaguer...
Don't tell me that the other bomb is located at...
There's still a lot of time,
but unless I figure out where it is...
Now listen, Conan.
When you're finished what you're doing, next...
Hey, Officer Takagi.
What is it, Conan?
I have something I want to discuss with you.
Hey, what's going on?
Now, it's the helicopters of the TV stations!
I wonder if something's happened after all.
Hey!
Crap!
We're having a test now. Be quiet.
The time now is 11:40.
There is less than 20 minutes to go before the bomb is to go off.
The boy and the police officer who are trapped together with the bom
have not been rescued yet.
Time is definitely ticking away.
What will become of the boy and police officer?
Will they perish together with the symbol of Tokyo?
What? He can't cut the cord?
There are only three more left!
First, the yellow cord to switch off the liquid crystal panel.
Next, the white cord that is connected to the mercury lever.
And the black telephone cord that is set there
for remote control manipulation.
If you cut it in that order, the bomb will stop completely.
How come you can't do that when you've already gone that far?
Give me that!
Officer Takagi! Just what are you doing?
Hurry! Hurry and cut it!
No. We can't cut it.
What are you talking about? You've only got 10 minutes left.
"To the brave police officer."
What?
"In praise of your courage, we will give you a prize.
A clue to another bigger firework will be displayed
at 3 seconds before the explosion.
With best wishes."
Conan says these are the words that are displayed on the LCD panel.
I would at least like to get Conan to evacuate somehow,
but in order to specify the other place where the bomb is set
and to avoid a large number of casualties,
there seems to be no other choice
than for Conan to look at the hint
and for me to relay the location by phone.
I'm sorry.
Officer Takagi.
But you understand, don't you?
Stupid.
4 minutes to go!
There's only 4 more minutes till the bomb goes off.
The timer has not been stopped yet.
Mr. Bomber. If you are watching this broadcast,
please stop the timer, please!
If you have a tinge of conscience left in you.
Heck with conscience...
I still can't believe that it's all working out so well.
Then, why don't you pick the broadcast of the TV on radio
and listen to our heroic story?
The timer of the bomb is still moving.
-What? -Mr. Bomber, are you watching?
Don't tell me the remote control didn't work right!
Let them be. We got the money already besides.
I'm going to go tell the police how to...
Hey!
Stop the bomb!
Hey! Wait!
The police...
Those cops took advantage of his conscience
and killed him.
I feel sorry for the brat.
But if the bomb goes off, the police will be blamed
for not being able to save the kid.
If they go chicken and stop the bomb before it explodes,
they lose the hint and a greater number of casualties is inevitable.
I'm going to make this public to the media
and colossal blunder of the police will be exposed in broad daylight.
Either way, the cops are done for.
I see. That code had such a meaning.
If you talk too loud, the bomber will hear us.
But there are more than 400 places in Tokyo
that fit into that category.
Yes. It would be impossible to check all the places from now
without the bomber noticing.
If we try to evacuate all the people
that are at the more than 400 locations...
Judging from the bomber's character,
he will probably turn the switch on using remote control.
In other words, to definitely save everybody...
We've no other choice
but to look at the hint pinpoint the location
and look for the bomb.
Just like Officer Matsuda did, right?
Yes.
And besides,
the person that I don't want to let die no matter what,
one who is very precious to me may be there.
I'm sorry, Officer Takagi.
It's okay.
Hey, Conan.
While you're at it, tell me one more thing, will you?
Who on earth are you?
If you want to know...
I'll tell you...
In the world beyond.
The two have not been rescued yet.
There is only a minute left.
The seconds are ticking away!
Hey! What's going on?
Conan and Officer Takagi are still inside!
Oh, well...
It seems that the members of the riot task force
has also been ordered to evacuate!
-What? -Take the car back to Toto Tower!
Hey, it's dangerous, dangerous!
Take the car back! Hey, Chiba!
Take the car back! Take it back!
They listened to it.
The same words of the devil, as 3 years ago...
But I know you guys, the Youth Detective Squad,
will be able to take care of things even if I'm not around, right?
Conan!
15 seconds to go.
Are you ready, Officer Takagi?
Yeah.
I wrote all your deductions in the mail.
All I have left to do now is to punch in the hint you're going to read
and send it out.
It's going to be coming out soon.
The first letter is...
The letter...
E...
V...
I...
T...
No!
Get out of there...
Get out of there, Ran!
Shinichi?
Ran!
Takagi!
Conan! Hurry, what's next?
What? What the...
The slightest shake will set the bomb off!
Huh?
I was too scared to die after all,
so I cut the rest of the cord and stopped the bomb.
What?
I'm sorry.
Then, you stopped partway through the hint.
Yes. With only the letters "EVIT",
we can't tell where the other bomb is.
Well, it can't be helped.
Let's call the rescue squad and have them come rescue us.
So, they went chicken after all.
The kid's the one who stopped the bomb,
but the people will think the police made him stop it.
They'll think that the police sacrificed the lives of a lot of people
just to save their own skin.
Please listen to the people cheer!
The bomb has safely been stopped!
Moreover, the one who disassembled the bomb
was boy who was trapped in the elevator!
Let's ask the boy some questions then.
I'll bet you were scared, sonny?
"The Hero! A Primary Schooler" -Yes!
Shinichi?
But the police taught me how to do it really well,
so I had an easy time taking it apart.
Officer Takagi.
Officer Sato.
Stupid. Don't blame yourself.
Two hours and a half left to go.
Let's go look for the other bomb!
But the thing is...
I'm glad you're okay!
I knew you'd do it, Conan!
Just as would be expected of my following!
Well, you did right to stop the bomb.
It's a silly thing to sacrifice your life
for people you don't even know.
Yeah, I guess so.
I'm sure that's what the bomber thought, too.
Finally, only one more subject to go!
What's the matter, Ran? You look depressed.
The next subject is your best subject, Japanese.
Yes.
I was just thinking that there sure are
a lot of cars going in and out today.
It's probably because they loading the ping-pong table
into the warehouse of the gym in the basement.
It seems that the next ping-pong tournament
is going to be held at our school.
While they're at it, they should take the space-consuming drum cans
that are inside the warehouse with them, too.
What are you talking about?
Don't you know?
Because of those 5 big cans.
It's so hard to take out the tennis net.
So, they couldn't find it after all.
Well, even if they were to find it now,
they wouldn't be able to evacuate.
There's only 5 seconds left to go.
4, 3, 2, 1...
0...
Boom!
Why? Why isn't it exploding?
Gosh! It can't be helped.
I'll have to set the bomb off with remote control.
I'm sorry to say that your partner can't talk to you anymore.
The bomb disposal squad secretly went into school quietly taking care
not to leave any voices on the wiretap that you set up
and took apart all 5 of the bombs
that you set up in the drum cans.
You look as if you're wondering how we located the bombs.
We deciphered the code you sent of Toto Tower
and the time of bombing as follows.
"I am a Major Leaguer, a strong pitcher as well as batter.
Now, this is the beginning of an extended game.
No use getting ready a good stopper.
Because I will win in the end."
The phrase "Major Leaguer" means
to change everything into English.
A good stopper means
a pitcher with good earned run average.
Extended game in English
is called Extra inning game.
The abbreviation of earned run average is ERA.
If you remove the no use words "ERA" from the word "EXTRA",
you get "XT".
XT is written vertically and when it is "turned over",
it becomes the Japanese Kanji character, "Bun".
That's the map symbol that stands for school.
And the hint that was displayed on the LCD panel of the first bomb,
"EVIT" is the English spelling of "Detective",
that is, a part of it, spelled reverse.
And if the Japanese for "Detective" is reversed,
it becomes "Teitan".
The school with the name Teitan has a grade school,
intermediate school, high school and university,
but the only school where a lot of students gather during winter vacation
is only Teitan High School
that is holding national trial exams.
You didn't plant a fake bomb at the baseball park
is because you wanted to keep everyone's attention away
from the schools with baseball grounds.
Well, but I guess you took us lightly
looking through your binoculars from a conspicuous place like this,
keeping watch over Teitan High School. You lose this time.
Look out!
Gosh!
-Sato... -Officer Sato!
No!
Officer Sato!
Wait!
I'm not the one...
It's one of those things that occur frequently.
I heard it in my head, a child's voice.
It told me to kill the police.
No, it told me to kill anybody.
Yeah.
That's why it's not my fault.
To think that he was killed by a guy like this...
A guy like this!
Officer Sato!
What do you think you're doing? Don't bother me!
No, Officer Sato!
Let me go! Let me go, I said!
To think that he had to die for a guy like that!
So, let me go!
Just what do you think you're doing, Officer Sato?
Wasn't it you who always said
to contribute to the nation and the citizens
with pride and a sense of mission,
never to cringe in fear and hate
and at all times to respect the rights of people,
and perform our duties as police officers with justice.
That's what you always said, right?
But...
Acting the way you are now,
I'm sure that Officer Matsuda will scold you.
Stupid...
I want to forget him, but you...
Let me forget him!
You idiot!
You shouldn't forget him.
If it's a precious memory, you shouldn't forget it.
Once a person dies,
that person can only live within one's memory.
Officer Takagi.
Hey! What was that gun shot just now?
Well...
I fired one warning shot.
Don't tell me you wounded him or something?
We weren't kissing!
But it's really amazing that you stopped it.
You had less than 3 seconds to cut the cord, didn't you?
I had the wire cutter in hand
in case I figured out the clue midway.
Besides, I couldn't afford to let Officer Takagi die.
But you're really something to figure out that
just by seeing "EVIT" it's the reverse of "Detective".
You can say that again!
Idiot. Of course I'd figure it out.
I've been hoping that it wouldn't be there.
I've been hoping from the very start that it wouldn't be there.
Hey, Sato.
We're going to visit Shiratori at the hospital.
Yes, I'm coming!
"Erase message?"
"Deleted"
Goodbye, Officer Matsuda.
But...
But I won't forget you.
Next Conan's Hint:
"Door glass"