(seagulls crying)
Wow, amazing!
So many yachts!
I wonder how far
those things can go?
They can go all the way
to foreign countries.
The oceans are all connected,
after all.
I'd love to ride one.
Me too.
Never mind all that.
I'm getting hungry, so let's hurry
back and eat our lunches.
Sigh... I guess for you, Genta,
it's appetite over romance.
Huh?
That looks delicious!
Hey... where are you going?
This is the place.
Mr. Takiguchi?
I'm from the Shirakabe Hotel.
I've brought the food you ordered.
A hotel, he says.
No wonder it looks
so delicious.
Hey, no matter how long you stare,
there's none for you. Get lost.
Don't be so mean
to them.
Thanks for your trouble. That was quick.
- Takiguchi Nao (34), president's wife.
(dog barking)
A cute little doggy!
His name is Koro.
Woof!
And what a pretty necklace.
Thank you. But it's just
a cheap acrylic one.
Ma'am, where should I
put the food?
Oh, sorry. Could you carry it
onto the boat for me?
You kids, come along too.
Oh... but...
We couldn't, with strangers...
This hotel's food is delicious.
You'll have some, won't you?
But if we eat, there won't be
enough left for you.
Don't hold back, kids.
We ordered with dinner in mind too...
- Takiguchi Kotaro (55), company president.
so there's more than
we can possibly eat.
Huh?
Then we can really
eat some?
Yes. Just the two of us
felt a bit lonely.
We'd be glad to have you.
Well, if you put it that way,
don't mind if we do...
We'll gladly accept!
Hahaha!
Ufufu!
Blazing sun,
undefeated by the heat,
a slick and stylish
deduction show.
We're all witnesses...
a tycoon dives into the sea.
Seeing through to
the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid,
mind of an adult.
His name is
Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"The Man Betrayed by the Sea"
Where the heck
did those guys go?
We came all the way to the beach
and you slept the whole time.
Let's look a little more,
and if we can't find them...
let's just eat our lunches.
Do that and they'll
hold a grudge.
They say grudges over
food are the scariest.
Yeah, I guess.
Mm! Can you believe Conan and Ai
are missing out...
on such delicious food?
What a shame.
Don't worry about it. It's their own
fault for sleeping at the beach.
Are your other friends
here too?
Yeah. We're all
really close.
But today Ai said she
didn't want to get a tan.
Oh? An elementary schooler
caring that much about her skin.
I look forward to seeing
what a beauty she'll become.
And Conan, even though
he's just a kid...
he reads mystery novels
until morning.
He's a bit too
grown-up for a child.
He's just not cute.
Well, excuse me
for not being cute.
Conan!
So then, that cute girl
must be Ai?
Yes. Sorry I'm not
a beauty yet.
Hahaha! You're plenty
beautiful as you are.
For an elementary schooler,
that is. Ahahaha!
What are you two
doing here?
That's our line.
We came looking for you
to finally eat our lunches.
I feel bad for the mother
who made it for you...
but you can just eat your
lunch on the way home.
You two come over here
and eat with us.
Do it. It's delicious...
this roast beef.
This lobster is amazing too!
Mm.
Oh... okay.
Mitsuhiko, you're eating
too much lobster.
This is a spiny lobster,
I keep telling you.
(everyone laughing)
Huh? It's different?
Dear.
Hm?
The children are
laughing at you.
You two are like newlyweds.
Ha! Well, we did just get
married six months ago.
Whaaat?
And it was my first
marriage too.
I was so busy growing
my company...
that I forgot to get married
until this age. Haha!
That's so nice.
Going out to sea
on a boat like this...
and swimming in the beautiful
ocean would be wonderful.
That's impossible.
You can't really swim
yet, Ayumi.
If I had a boat like this at home,
I'd learn to swim in no time.
That's the spirit, Ayumi.
No need to be discouraged.
I couldn't swim either
until this age...
but with special training
I learned how.
Where there's a will,
there's a way.
So you joined a
sports club?
No, I built a new house, so I added
a pool while I was at it.
Oh, let me show you
something nice.
Hm?
You were filming all that?
Stop it. This is
embarrassing.
But by the end,
look...
You're right!
You can really swim now.
All right! Let's race to that
breakwater and see who's fastest!
Ayumi, you can use
a float ring.
All right, let's do it.
Oh no you don't.
You just drank wine.
And your blood pressure
is high enough as it is.
You need to rest
a bit first.
Tch. And I was sure
I'd win, too.
(dog barking)
Hm?
How old is Koro?
He just turned one.
Huh? The metal clasp on his
collar is rusted.
Oh, maybe because we walk
him even on rainy days.
Oh! Hey, we should
get going soon.
Oh! I forgot!
Going off and getting yourselves
a feast all on your own...
In times like that, someone
should come let me know.
I was so worried I almost
called the police.
Eating while you're angry
is bad for digestion.
All right!
Kyahaha!
Here goes!
Nice shot!
Haha!
Whoa!
Take that!
Huh?
Isn't that boat heading out
Nao and her husband's?
You're right.
Yeah, Nao came out too.
Are they going to swim?
Thanks for earlier, mister!
Let's swim too!
Sure.
Then I'll go get
the float ring...
What is this... that's
not right.
Somebody help... somebody!
This is bad, he's drowning!
Dear!
(ambulance siren)
I'm worried.
I'm not really in the
mood to play anymore.
Yeah.
The sun's still high, but
let's head home today.
We can call the fire department later
to ask about Mr. Takiguchi...
You kids were with
Mr. Takiguchi earlier, right?
I went to collect the dishes,
but no one's on the boat.
Do you know anything?
Oh, then we'll go
get the dishes for you.
(barking)
I see... you couldn't
ride in the ambulance, huh?
We should probably
bring Nao and her husband...
their clothes and things,
shouldn't we?
Yeah, you're right. Hm?
Was it really an accident?
The detailed investigation
is still ahead of us...
but according to witnesses, there's
no doubt he jumped in himself.
I can't believe it.
- Katagiri Ryoichi (48), Takiguchi's secretary.
Isn't it possible someone pushed him in?
The only people on the boat...
- Nagai Keiji (38), Detective.
were him and his wife, just the two of them.
Are you saying...
his wife pushed him in?
That's not what
I'm saying...
The president told us. He nearly drowned
in a river as a child...
and ever since, he was afraid
of water and couldn't swim.
He recently did special training
and learned to swim.
Huh?
And who are you?
Oh... excuse us.
The children got acquainted with
the Takiguchis at the beach.
They said the couple was very kind
to them, so we came by.
We brought their clothes too.
And Koro got left
behind as well.
(barking)
How is Mr. Takiguchi's
condition?
Ah... that's...
this is hard to say...
but he was pronounced
dead a short while ago.
What?
No way... such a nice man,
gone just like that.
I can't believe it.
(crying)
In any case, detective...
please investigate properly
whether it was really an accident.
Even before they married, we kept
telling the president she was...
clearly after his money.
But the president was completely
deceived by that woman...
and it came to this in the end.
Are you saying Nao
did something wrong?
There's no way someone
that nice would do something bad!
H-hey, hey!
I apologize.
Are you with Mr. Takiguchi's
company?
Yes. I'm Katagiri,
head of the secretarial office.
You children witnessed
the accident?
Yeah, we saw it!
Mr. Takiguchi drowned
right in front of us.
He waved at us and then
jumped into the sea.
I see. Then sorry to
trouble you, but...
would you come to the station
and tell us...
about what happened in detail?
Sure.
Yes.
Okay.
When Mr. Takiguchi
jumped in...
do you know where
his wife was?
She was doing something
a little ways off.
Probably clearing away
the lunch dishes.
I see. So that's why she was
slow to notice he was drowning.
(knock)
Come in.
Nao!
Ayumi, thank you for
bringing the clothes.
Oh, Nao, your necklace...
Oh, the chain must have
broken when I...
was saving him, and it
sank into the sea.
I've heard the account
from these children...
and it seems certain your husband
jumped into the sea himself.
It does appear to be safe
to treat this as a tragic accident.
It was my fault.
No matter how well he'd
learned to swim...
if only I'd watched
him a little more carefully.
There's just one more
thing I wanted to ask...
It's that very thing.
Mr. Takiguchi told
his colleagues...
that he couldn't swim,
apparently.
Had he really
learned to swim?
Oh, just show them
that, why don't you.
The practice video.
Oh... right.
This was filmed when he first
practiced at the pool.
The ones I'm in were
filmed by...
our housekeeper.
Ha.
And this was filmed
last week.
That's good, keep it up.
Don't stop, now turn.
Mm... mmh...
I see.
He really had learned
to swim.
Huh?
Come here a sec.
What is it, Conan?
Can you let me
see the video camera?
Sure, that's fine.
Is there something important
captured in this footage?
You're right.
Yeah, Nao came out too.
Good, the audio's recorded too.
The problem is what comes next.
Let's swim too!
Sure.
Then I'll go get
the float ring...
What is this... that's
not right.
Somebody help... somebody!
Here, right here.
Can you zoom in
more on this?
Sure, but the image
will get grainy.
Somebody help... somebody!
Aah... agh...
Dear!
What's going on here?
From when Nao noticed Kotaro
was drowning...
to when she dove in to save him,
there's a slight gap.
And that cruiser had
a life ring on board...
so why didn't she use it?
And one more thing... what was that
in the practice footage?
Kotaro was actually...
(dog barking)
What are you two
whispering about?
Oh, uh...
Woof!
Huh? The metal clasp on his
collar is rusted.
Oh, maybe because we walk
him even on rainy days.
So that's it.
Well then, everyone...
sorry for the trouble, but
you're free to go home.
We'll see the wife
to the hospital.
Thank you for your time.
Could you wait
a moment?
Huh? Is there something
you'd like to say?
Oh, no, no, haha.
This was no
mere accident.
It was a carefully
planned murder.
Huh? What did you say?
Ha!
Huh?
But Mr. Takiguchi jumped
into the sea himself.
Yes. However...
if he had known he
couldn't swim...
Mr. Takiguchi never would
have jumped in, would he?
Mr. Takiguchi was made to believe
he could swim when he couldn't...
and was suddenly taken
out on the cruiser...
to open water where
his feet couldn't touch.
Isn't that a clear-cut
murder?
Don't you agree,
Nao Takiguchi?
My husband could swim
just fine. You saw it too.
Are you saying there's some
trick in that footage?
No, that footage
is genuine.
Mr. Takiguchi
could swim.
Th-then what on earth
are you saying...
But only in
his home pool.
Conan.
Coming!
Here, let me borrow that.
The part from when he was...
practicing his kicks. Look
at Nao's necklace here.
See, it's sunk
in the water, right?
But on the last day...
look, it's floating in the water!
Huh? W-wait a minute.
Y-you're right, the necklace that
was sunk is now floating.
Could you explain what this
means in plain terms?
(throat clearing)
Why did the necklace float?
Koro is what told me.
Koro, who supposedly
just turned one...
yet the metal clasp on his
collar has somehow rusted.
The wife put a large amount
of bath salts in the pool water...
to make the body float
more easily.
The necklace in the footage
is made of acrylic.
Acrylic has a specific density of
about 1.17 to 1.2...
so last week's pool water must
have had a higher density than that.
Isn't that right, ma'am?
You're wrong.
If I'd put in that many bath salts,
even my oblivious husband would notice.
Then what did you put in?
The necklace that sank in the sea
floats in the footage.
Either way, this footage...
proves the pool water's
density was high.
Shall we head to your
home now and check?
Even if you go,
there's no water.
I've already drained
the pool.
Don't underestimate
the police.
If there's even a bit
of residue in the pool...
we'll know exactly what
was dissolved in it.
Ma'am, is what
this man is saying true?
Well?
Nao, it's not
true, right?
It's true...
Huh...?
Just as he says, at first
I put in bath salts...
but when I increased the amount,
he noticed.
So after that I switched to
a water-soluble polymer.
A harmless substance used
in medicine and food.
Last week's pool water
probably had a density...
over 1.3, I'd guess.
1.3, you say...
that's about the same as the Dead Sea,
where you can float and read a book.
No wonder Mr. Takiguchi
mistakenly believed...
that he could swim.
You filmed the video thinking
it would help you...
when the police came
asking questions.
But that footage turned out
to be your undoing.
That man...
all he ever thought about
was growing his company.
For that, he'd use any dirty
trick without a second thought.
Never knowing how many people
he'd ruined because of it.
So I thought this time
I'd make him suffer...
but living with a man with no
common sense or refinement...
was unbearable agony.
I was at the end
of my patience.
It's true that Mr. Takiguchi was
desperate to make money...
and may have lacked common
sense and refinement.
But compared to you, who killed
a man for revenge...
wasn't he far more
human?
♪~
~♪
And I believed she
was such a kind person.
When she treated us to the feast,
I really thought she was nice.
I'm never gonna
trust adults again.
There are all kinds of
adults, you know. All kinds.
That's right. I still have
a pure heart.
Hahaha!
What?
Did you just laugh
purely at me?
Come to think of it, didn't we
still have our lunches?
That's right!
We got treated to lunch, so
our boxes are still here!
Let's hurry and eat!
Now that you mention it,
I'm getting hungry.
I wonder what's in
today's lunch.
Hey, hey, what happened to all
that gloom from just a moment ago?
He's right! Tai-chan's
holding something.
This cat belongs to
my granddaughter.
When these people showed up,
each claimed to be the owner.
No, the real owner
is me, and...
Wrong! I keep telling you,
it's mine!
That's just not
normal.
With a mystery-solving
expert joining in.
Next Conan,
"Lucky Calico Cat Case (Part 1)".
Next Conan's Hint:
"Taii"
The detective team has nothing left to fear.
Or is that really true?
I'm sure there is something.