What lies in one's heart is a mystery to us all.
Star and snow glitter on the two.
Naniwa is the stage for a tag team match of Conan and Heiji.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"Osaka Double Mystery:"
"The Naniwa Swordsman And Hideyoshi Toyotomi's Castle"
"Naniwa Chuo Gymnasium"
Strike to the mask!
Match is over!
Nice going! That's 3 wins and 1 draw,
he qualifies for the preliminaries!
Right. All the members on Kaiho High School's team this year is strong.
They're undefeated so far in the group competition.
Mrs. Hattori. Don't get all worked up
until you're seen our captain.
Heiji's gotten stronger than a demon.
Oh, is Heiji Kaiho High's captain?
He doesn't tell us anything at home.
Kaiho High School team captain, come forward!
Yes, sir.
Huh? That's not Heiji.
Isn't that him over there?
Over there, surrounded by all those girls and talking up a storm.
Hey, Heiji!
What the heck are you doing, goofing off over here for?
The match has already started! You've got to hurry!
Huh? You're pale.
Hello.
I know you. You're a sophomore, aren't you?
Heiji asked me to cover for him.
He said that we probably wouldn't need him until the semi-finals
so he told me to put his gear on
and just intimidate the other team.
But Heiji's so popular so all the girls flock around me
when they see his name on the uniform.
So where did Heiji go?
I think he went to the toilet.
I saw him heading toward the other building.
"Annex" -Listen up.
I'm going to tell you one more time.
To get to the Naniwa Chuo Gymnasium,
take the bus headed for Tojiri
and get off at the 7th stop.
If you don't know which bus, ask the driver.
Ask them which gymnasium is holding the Kinki Kendo Competition
that Heiji Hattori's competing in, they'll know!
Okay, I got it.
I'm not a little kid. You don't have to keep reminding me.
Sorry. You look like a little kid, so I forget.
Never mind, just don't call me anymore.
I'm having a hard time getting away from Ran and the old man.
And another thing. We're going to Osaka
because you invited us to a tetchiri dinner
since we didn't get to eat it the last time
or the time before that at your place.
The only reason we're going to watch you compete is,
it's on the same day.
You always give me the cold treatment.
By the way, this bullet train just left the station,
so it'll be past 2:00 when we get there.
Won't your match be over by then?
Don't worry about it.
The semi-finals don't start until 2 pm.
You'll make it in time for the finals.
Oh, okay.
So I'll be waiting to see you.
Kazuha?
What are you doing in there?
That's what I'd like to ask you!
This is the men's toilet, you know!
Really? I didn't notice that.
I thought it was a hiding place
for cowards who didn't want to compete.
I'm planning my moves.
So that I can beat that guy in the finals.
By that guy, are you talking about
that guy that looks just like Kudo?
That's right. Okita from Senshin High School in Kyoto.
Last year, he got me with jabs to the neck.
I'm going to pay him back for this scar behind my ear.
Just because he beat you before,
don't you think you're being kind of sneaky?
Don't be stupid! He didn't beat me.
I got cut on the neck when I dodged the jab,
and when it wouldn't stop bleeding,
the doctor stopped the match.
Besides, the guy skipped the first and second match,
he was sleeping behind the gym
and then he took me on.
You don't have to worry about him, you can beat him.
You brought your lucky charm, didn't you?
That's not the only reason
I skipped the first and second matches though.
The truth is, it's my right hand
remember what happened on Bikuni Island.
It's so itchy, it's driving me crazy!
I can't concentrate on the match!
Is that so? Fine then!
I'm going to have a talk with your mother.
And have her beat some heart and soul into you.
What? Mom's here?
Hey, Kazuha, wait!
What's the matter with you? You idiot!
-Idiot? -No, that wasn't me.
Did you say you can't compete because you have a hangover?
I couldn't help it.
The company that informally promised to hire me went bankrupt.
I was so floored. I had to have a drink.
You blockhead! You should have thought about the consequences!
Let's all settle down.
There's still over an hour left in the competition.
He's right.
Let's all calm down and come up with a plan.
You know, I could tell everybody about that.
What did you say?
Unlike the rest of you who all have jobs waiting,
I've got nothing to lose.
I don't know what you're talking about,
but if you don't want to compete,
then we'll just have to send in one of the seniors
although they aren't as good as you.
We can't have the whole team be embarrassed
just because of you.
For a guy who stole another guy's girlfriend, you sure talk big.
You're a fool. She made up her own mind to leave you.
I didn't steal her away.
Listen, I think you'd better sober up and start thinking about
how to get rid of that chip on your shoulder,
and what you're going to do with the rest of your life.
Kill...
I'm going to kill you.
What're you doing, Heiji? Come on, hurry!
Yeah, okay.
Chest jab, point!
Yes! Good move!
Hey, I can't find Tarumi anywhere.
Maybe he went home?
Good grief. You guys go look around there.
Okay.
Hey! Why aren't you paying attention to the match?
Go and score those points fast.
Make it to the best four!
"Annex" -Did you find him?
No, he wasn't in the toilet or the fencing hall.
Did you look in the storage room?
No, not yet.
But he wouldn't be here in the middle of the competition.
Ta... Tarumi?
How horrible!
Somebody, get an ambulance!
Okay, I'll go call for the ambulance!
Omotani, you go to the police box and get the police!
All right, then I'll go back to the gym
and tell Hakamata about this.
Okay! Go quick and bring him back here!
Okay!
Yahoo! We're in the best 4!
I think we can win the championship!
Tarumi's dead? Are you sure?
Pretty sure. I couldn't tell if he was breathing
but he was covered with blood!
Where is he?
Who the heck are you?
I asked you where he is!
What is this? There's nothing in here.
That's strange.
We found him here, leaning against this vaulting horse.
What kind of doll is this?
I think it's a doll you use to practice life saving techniques on.
You know, like mouth to mouth resuscitation.
Are you sure you didn't mistake this doll for your friend?
That's ridiculous!
Hey! Police is here!
The ambulance will be here in about 10 minutes.
Thing is, we can't find Tarumi.
What did you say?
You don't think Tarumi pulled a fast one on us, do you?
What?
Come on, let's split up and look for Tarumi!
If this is some kind of joke, I'm going to teach him a lesson!
Excuse me.
Are you from Shinnai University?
Yeah, that's right. What is it?
A call just came in to the reception desk from a strange man.
He said to tell the guys from Shinnai University
who are in the storage room now
to go to the locker room beside the pool.
It's got to be Tarumi!
That sneak! What a stinker!
Let's go and check it out.
"Shower room"
Ta... Tarumi!
Is this for real?
He's really dead.
I don't believe it.
The body in the storage room
is moved to the locker room beside the pool while no one is watching.
Dees that mean someone moved it?
But if you were carrying a body as bloody as that,
someone's bound to notice.
There's a team from some school
sitting around the doorway in the annex having their lunch.
Why go to such lengths?
Hey, Heiji!
What're you doing? You haven't even eaten your lunch!
There's less than an hour left before the semi-finals.
Shut up. I'm on a case!
There's been a murder in the locker room over there.
What? Are you serious?
But I don't understand something
so I can't concentrate on the match.
Then maybe you should ask Kudo for advice.
Are they coming here, aren't they?
That's right, Kudo! I'll just give him a call.
Kudo would be able to solve the case in no time.
You don't have to lose any sleep over it.
Let Kudo handle the investigation,
you get back to the match, come on!
Listen, Kazuha.
Don't you dare tell Kudo about the murder.
-What? -Don't forget what I said!
Heiji!
Kudo won't get here for another hour and a half.
I've got to solve this case by then!
You've got rice on yourself again.
What? Did you say murder?
Then you mean, Hattori's...
That's right. He said he doesn't have time to compete.
He's running around looking for clues.
What're we going to do?
The semi-finals are going to start already.
We don't have a choice.
We've got to take the championship without Heiji.
Then we'll break that darn mystery fool's nose in half!
Excuse me. We're the ones who're going to be in the match.
You're positive he's one of your team mates?
Yes, that's right.
His name's Tarumi. We're classmates at the same university.
The killer must have put him under the hot shower
to mask the time of death.
Well, it's plain to see
that the murder weapon is this sword.
As soon as we find out who it belongs to,
we'll have the killer...
You're wrong about that, Inspector Otaki.
The "fast draw" instructor brought it to the competition
because he was going to put on a demonstration using a real sword.
Somebody probably saw it left in the dressing room,
stole it and used it to commit the murder.
Heiji, what're you doing here?
Can't you tell by looking at me? I'm competing.
Oh, I remember now! Today's the day of the big competition
between Kinki's high school and college teams.
So do you have any idea who stole this sword?
Sort of.
The killer's somebody who comes to this competition a lot
and knows about the fast draw demonstration.
That person also knows the layout of the place,
the gym, the annex and the locker room.
Which means, the killer is somebody just like you guys.
I understand the part about having to know
about the demonstration and stealing the sword
but what does knowing about the gym and annex and locker room
have to do with anything?
Because if the killer didn't know the locations of these places,
it wouldn't be possible to move Mr. Tarumi
from the annex to this locker room without being seen.
What bothers me is, not why he was moved but how.
Because when it happened, there was a group of people
sitting in front of the annex eating their lunch.
It would've been impossible for them not to notice
a man covered with blood being carried out.
Unless of course,
after you guys found Mr. Tarumi in the storage room,
the last one to leave the place
very cleverly managed to carry him out.
Do you guys remember what happened?
The first one to leave was Kotegawa here.
He said he was going to call an ambulance.
Then I left.
Kotegawa told me to go to the police box and get the police.
So that means, Mr. Doguchi,
you were the last to leave, weren't you?
But I left right away to get Hakamata who was in the gym.
How do I know you're not lying?
I... I said I was going, didn't I?
Yeah.
Besides, Doguchi wasn't the last one to leave, it was me.
What?
I knew we needed the ambulance as soon as possible
so when I saw a group of high school students
hanging around the entrance,
I borrowed their cell phone.
But the person I was talking to
asked me to describe the injured person's condition
so I went back and described Tarumi's condition.
Of course, there was nobody else around.
As soon as I was finished,
I went back to return the cellphone
then I headed for the police box.
Is that the truth?
Yes, he came to the police box.
I'm not good at explaining things, so I was relieved he came.
And how long did it take to go from the annex
to the police box then back again?
There's a big intersection in front of the police box
and we got stuck at the light...
I think it took about 14 to 15 minutes.
Did you say 14 to 15 minutes?
Don't you think that's strange. Mr. Doguchi?
Mr. Omotani and Mr. Kotegawa
came back with the police right after we arrived.
The gym is right by the annex,
don't you think it took an unusually long time to get Mr. Hakamata?
He probably had a hard time finding me.
The place was filled with guys wearing the same kind of outfits.
This means, you also had some unaccounted time.
I don't care if you suspect us,
but can you tell me one thing first?
Explain how you can get Tarumi, who was in that condition,
out of the storage room in the annex
into the locker room without being seen?
Yeah, that's right!
If you can't explain that,
then you can't prove we're guilty!
Don't make up stories.
Well, Detective, we're going to see Tarumi's mother
and tell her what happened today.
Hakamata, you're the only one without a sash. Why's that?
I thought I brought it with me, but I guess I lost it.
Well, it looks like we're going to forfeit the match
so I guess I won't be needing it anyway.
Speaking of match, Heiji, how did you do today?
Did you win? Or did you lose?
Heiji?
Hit on the forearm, 1 point!
Way to go! We scored!
All we've got to do is hang in there until it's time
and then we're in the finals!
That's right!
We don't need Heiji to win the championship!
Thrust to the neck, 1 point!
4 to 1, the match goes to Kyoto Senshin High School!
Kyoto Senshin High School?
It's Okita, just like Heiji said.
This is not good!
Without Heiji, we don't stand a chance.
The windows behind the annex don't open
and the ones in the front are too noticeable.
The front door is only way.
But to carry him to the locker room beside the pool,
I'd have to pass the front of the gym
where there were a lot of people.
It's impossible.
Somebody's bound to notice a man covered with blood
being carried past them.
Gosh!
Kudo's going to be here in less than 10 minutes.
Hey, you! Wait up!
You just came out of the annex, didn't you?
What were you doing?
I only went to the toilet.
Sorry, but there's something I want to ask you.
What is it?
Before Mr. Tarumi was killed, I heard him say,
"You know, I could tell everybody about that".
What was that about?
How would I know? I don't know anything!
All right then, is the girl Mr. Tarumi and Mr. Hakamata
were fighting about here today?
Of course not!
After that incident, Haori quit managing the kendo team!
That incident? What do you mean?
Did you see Okita's thrust?
Yeah. You can kill somebody with that one.
Hey, come back!
Huh? That's the guy.
He's running again like he was when we were eating lunch.
What?
Where you guys eating lunch around the door to the annex?
Yeah, that was us.
There were three weird college students.
They asked to borrow a cell phone,
and then they brought the police and other people, it was a circus.
All right then, after those three left the annex,
did any suspicious person go in there?
Yeah, there was one guy!
You!
Dummy! Before me!
There was one suspicious guy that came out of the annex.
What?
He was carrying somebody else's gear in a bag.
How could you tell it wasn't his?
That was easy.
He was carrying the bag
while he was wearing his mask and protective gear.
So that's how he did it! A gear bag!
If you put the body in there and carried it out,
nobody would get suspicious.
Mr. Hakamata's the only one would could've done it.
He killed Mr. Tarumi beforehand
and hid the body in the storage room.
And while he has the others looking for Mr. Tarumi,
he goes back to the storage room
and after the other three find the body and go for help,
he puts Mr. Tarumi in the gear bag
and sneaks toward the locker room.
No, that's not possible.
Even if you were hiding in that storage room,
there's no guarantee somebody would look in there.
Besides, it was just coincidence
that all three of them left the storage room.
If someone decided to remain,
then he wouldn't be able to come out.
Hey!
You better watch yourself kid
or you're going to be in a whole lot of trouble.
I hear you've been asking about Haori too.
You already told him?
Of course he did!
Doguchi and me go way back.
Whenever he is in trouble, he always comes to tell me.
We made a pact when we were little kids.
You're way off course suspecting him though.
He's a coward. He can't stand the sight of blood.
What?
Listen carefully! Don't be a pest!
Hello?
Hattori, it's me.
Kudo, it's you.
Where are you? On the bus?
No. Pops didn't want to wait for the bus
so we got on a cab.
All right, take your time!
In fact, why don't you get off and have a bowl of noodles?
Maybe even walk around and do some sightseeing.
Don't be stupid. We already told the driver where to go.
We're on our way there.
What?
By the way, you're in the finals, aren't you?
Hey, Hattori. You there?
Hey, guys.
Do you know about the life saving dolls in the storage room?
Sure, because we came here a lot to practice.
How many dolls do they have in there?
Two. One skinny one and one big one.
That's it!
Isn't he Hattori from Kaiho High?
What's he doing here? The finals are starting already.
If my theory's right, it should be here.
It should still be here in this storage room.
I knew it!
This is what the killer used to move the body.
Heiji! Heiji, where are you?
That fool! Where the heck is he?
Kazuha!
We're here to root for Heiji!
Ran!
Is Hattori's team in the finals'?
Yes! And it's starting soon
-but Heiji's gone off somewhere. -What?
I just know he's running around
trying to solve the murder that just happened.
Murder?
The question is,
who the killer is and how Mr. Tarumi was moved.
We know how.
One of my men just questioned some of the kids
that were hanging around the entrance to the annex
and it seems they saw the killer.
A suspicious character came out of here
wearing a mask and protective gear carrying a gear bag.
A mask, protective gear and a gear bag?
I see! The killer put Mr. Tarumi inside the gear bag
and wore a mask to cover his face
so no one would recognize him when he walked out.
When did that guy wearing the mask come out?
It seems it was after the three
left the annex after finding the body.
So it means that the person who moved the body
was not one of the three who found it.
That's right.
The killer was probably hiding in the storage room
when the three came in and found Mr. Tarumi's body.
He didn't think the body would be found so soon,
so he moved it here.
Excuse me, Inspector Otaki.
Did Heiji come here?
Yes, he was here for awhile
but he rushed off for someplace.
It's no use.
No matter what you do,
you can't make it look like Mr. Tarumi
was killed in this storage room.
Mr. Kotegawa.
That's right. This isn't where Mr. Tarumi was killed.
He was killed in the locker room beside the pool.
After you fellows found Mr. Tarumi's body,
Mr. Omotani and Mr. Doguchi left.
You alone came back
and told him to go to the locker room,
that's where you killed him.
Isn't that right?
How stupid.
It was pure coincidence that they left the storage room.
If someone had stayed behind,
I wouldn't have been able to come back
and do what you claim I did, now would I?
No, it was no coincidence.
All you had to do was tell Mr. Omotani to go get the police
to guarantee no one would be left.
You knew Mr. Doguchi's personality.
Whenever something happened,
he always reported it to Mr. Hakamata.
Besides, he can't stand the sight of blood.
You knew he wouldn't touch the body,
that he'd immediately go to find Mr. Hakamata.
You gave Mr. Tarumi liquor laced with sleep inducers
then you put red paint on him to make him appear dead,
so no one would think he was alive.
This storage room is dark,
so the red paint would look like real blood.
There were a lot of people in front of the annex.
If somebody covered with red paint came out of here,
don't you think someone was bound to notice?
Yes, they did.
They saw a suspicious character wearing a mask
and protective gear come out of the annex carrying a gear bag.
Come on, I hope you're not saying that that was Tarumi?
What makes you think he'd dress himself up like that
to go to the locker room just because I told him to?
It wasn't just what you said.
If you were shown something like this while you were groggy,
you could be talked into doing anything.
He said "I'm going to kill you"?
Mr. Tarumi was always saying that?
Yes. It seems he had a grudge against Mr. Hakamata,
the other team members told me that.
So that means there's a possibility
Mr. Hakamata killed Mr. Tarumi instead.
No, that's wrong.
The killer probably took advantage of Mr. Tarumi's anger.
That's right. When you came back here alone,
you put the Japanese sword in Mr. Tarumi's hand.
Woke him up and showed him
the doll you'd hidden inside the vaulting horse beforehand.
Then you probably said this to him.
"What in the world have you done?"
Mr. Tarumi hated Mr. Hakamata
and he was still in a groggy state of mind.
So he didn't notice that it was just the doll
used to teach life saving techniques
wearing Mr. Hakamata's uniform.
That's why he thought the red paint on his chest guard
was Mr. Hakamata's blood
and that he'd killed him while he was drunk.
That's when you probably told him
that you'd let him get away
before the police arrived so he should put the mask on
and sneak into the locker room beside the pool and hide there.
And you also suggested he change out of his bloody clothes,
put on the protective gear
and put the sword into the bag for the bamboo sword.
Then told him to take them with him, didn't you?
You put the extra clothes and protective gear in the gear bag
and had it hidden it in the storage room.
That's so it would appear like someone else besides you
carried the body out of the storage room wearing a mask.
Then you took a shortcut to the locker room
and waited for Mr. Tarumi to arrive
and then you killed him for real.
After that, you washed the paint off of his body in the shower,
put the mask and protective gear in the gear bag.
And after you hid them somewhere,
you went to the police box where you'd sent Mr. Omotani.
That's when you did it, right?
That's when you got Mr. Tarumi's blood
on the towel you're holding now.
When you went to get the doll from inside the vaulting horse,
you decided to smear his blood on it
so that it'd look like he really was killed here, right?
That bloody towel in your hand
proves that you killed him!
If you know so much,
then you probably know why I did it.
Yes. I called the college you go to and checked up on you.
I found out that last year,
one of the new members of your kendo team
lost consciousness during practice and died.
The college claimed it was an accident,
but the truth is...
That's right. We were initiating the new members,
Tarumi didn't know his own strength, he overdid it.
Hakamata was officiator, but he was absent that day.
This is what Tarumi said.
"Sure I'm the one who did it
but everyone present here today and the manager is just as guilty.
If anyone talks, I'm taking everybody down with me."
So you decided to shut him up
so he couldn't ruin it for all of you
since you've got your new career.
I guess you know everything,
but seeing as you aren't armed,
you didn't know about this, did you?
The fast draw demonstrator had a partner.
Naturally, when I went into
the demonstrator's dressing room to steal the sword,
I'd already...
taken a few practice swings with it!
Huh?
A strange man called and told you come to the locker room?
Really?
Yes. When they all arrived,
they found Mr. Tarumi had been moved here.
The reason the killer called to give Mr. Tarumi's location was
he didn't want the storage room to be searched.
Which means, there's something he doesn't want found still inside.
Hey. Where is the storage room?
It's in the annex next to the gym. Why?
-Show me! -Wait, slow down!
Conan, where are you going?
Don't be a fool!
You won't be able to get away with it this time
if you kill me here!
I'm not worried.
The police will assume it's the same killer
and since they've already decided
I couldn't have moved Tarumi's body,
they won't even suspect me.
I've already figured everything out!
You picked the wrong guy to fight with.
What the?
Hattori?
Don't tell me...
you're that high school kid that shocked everybody
by beating the entire Osaka Police Department's team,
and they're all well trained.
That's right, but you realized it too late.
Yuranosuke!
Yo! Good to see you!
Heiji?
Well, Otaki, I'll let you take it from here.
You can count on me. Best of luck to you too, Heiji.
I almost forgot! The match!
We can't waste our time standing around here!
Are you okay?
Oh, no. I think it's already over.
Well, it couldn't be helped.
We lost the championship but solved the case.
Right?
Huh?
When's Heiji's turn?
This is delicious!
It's the best!
Of course it is.
No one makes better "tetchiri" than my mom.
Look at her. She fell asleep without taking a single bite.
It's all your fault!
She was running all over the place looking for you!
Well, it couldn't be helped.
I had to solve that murder, didn't I?
You can tell he's the son of the Chief of Police.
He solved the case in no time.
Thank you.
This kid solves cases purely on intuition.
He's just playing detective.
He doesn't even come close
to being a real detective like you, Mr. Mouri.
So what's that supposed to mean?
That Kudo's better than me too?
But Heizo, he's just like how you used to be
when you where his age.
I hate to see what he'll be like when he's older.
Hey, Toyama. Lay off the liquor.
You're driving, aren't you?
Don't worry. I'm going to let you drive me home.
What did you want to talk about?
Isn't that why you wanted me to drive you home?
Yeah.
It's about Heiji and my daughter Kazuha.
What do you think about their relationship?
Kazuha's already 17.
She'll be leaving for college soon.
And when she comes back, she'll be 20.
Some good for nothing's going to take her away from me one day anyway
so I figured it might as well be that no account son of yours.
Toyama, get to the point.
You still can't take a joke, can you?
So you were just kidding?
Do you remember what happened at Osaka Castle 13 years ago?
You mean the unidentified burnt body found in the inner moat?
This piece of pottery the victim had
hidden in his pocket.
That piece of pottery used to be
the main topic of our conversation back then.
We made up a lot of stories.
Well, turns out maybe they weren't just stories.
We found another piece.
It was on the burnt body we found in the east moat not too long ago.
It looks just like this one.
The lab is checking it out
but they're almost certain it was made in the same period.
Another thing. On the piece we just found,
you can make out the word "848" on it.
Things could turn out like we figured 13 years ago.
It could still be lying around somewhere.
Yeah. The huge fortune that great man left.
That round one's Osaka Hall.
And Osaka Business Park's over there
where all those buildings are.
And you can't see it from here because it's behind the building
but Osaka's most exciting television station is behind it!
And there's the city's symbol, Osaka Castle.
So? Now you know how great Osaka is!
That's the same thing you said
that last time we took them around.
-What? -Besides, we showed them
the view of the city from up high from Tsutenkaku last time.
I shouldn't have let you be tour guide.
I know, but the Tenjin Festival and the Gion Festival
and even the Danjiri Festival in Kishiwada are all over,
only Osaka Castle was left.
So if it was up to you, where'd you take us?
Let's see. If it was me,
it's right in front of this castle.
I'd give you the grand tour of Osaka's police headquarters.
And I'd take you inside the new building
which is almost finished.
That is so stupid.
You're the only one who'd enjoy something like that.
That sounds like fun.
Osaka Castle is much prettier
than when you see it on television or in pictures.
You noticed? They've just finished repairing it,
so it's been cleaned up nice.
They hadn't done any work on it
since they restored the tower about 60 years ago.
It was 70 years ago.
Huh?
Hideyoshi Toyotomi first built it in 1599.
Tokugawa rebuilt it in 1629.
And the people of Osaka restored it 70 years ago, in 1931,
this is the third tower.
You sure know your stuff.
Of course I do. Hideyoshi Toyotomi's my hero.
So you say, but that badge you've got on
looks like the Tokugawa crest, the 3 leafed mallow.
Well, you see it's like this.
Hey, Ieyasu. What're you doing?
The Lord is waiting.
Sorry, Mitsuhide.
-Ieyasu? -Mitsuhide?
Lord?
"8 days research tour of Hideyoshi Toyotomi"?
That's right. That's the name of our tour.
All the tour members are Hideyoshi fans,
we got together through the internet.
We went from Nagoya to Kyoto visiting places he's known for
and now we're in Osaka.
So what about the names you call each other and those badges?
It's sort of like a penalty in a game.
Every day, after breakfast,
we draw lots to decide which roles we'll be playing
and we put the badges on
with the crests of Nobunaga, Hideyoshi, Ieyasu and Mitsuhide.
And for the entire day,
whoever picks Hideyoshi, Ieyasu and Mitsuhide
has to play the role
and cater to whoever Nobunaga is.
For instance, we take souvenir pictures of that person
or go run errands, things like that.
On the other hand...
Nobunaga has to give Hideyoshi and Ieyasu
money for dinner.
-Isn't that right? -Yes, that's right, Nene.
You mean you have someone playing "Nene", too?
That's right. Whoever picks the blank lot has to be "Nene".
That person has to watch everyone else
and pass things off with a smile.
But I feel sorry for whoever has to be Mitsuhide.
He has to pay for his own dinner
even though he works hard all day, right?
But playing Mitsuhide also has its rewards.
He gets to play Nobunaga for 3 minutes
and he gets to pick the time.
I see. Rather than Lord for 3 days,
it's Lord for 3 minutes.
Sounds stupid.
It sounds like fun.
It is.
So this is where everybody is.
I couldn't find you, so I'd been looking all over the place.
Lord Nobunaga, please forgive us.
Here is the oolong tea you requested.
And this is the post card of Osaka Castle.
Thank you. That was very thoughtful of you.
He's a very humble Nobunaga.
Something's not right though.
The main character Hideyoshi is missing.
That's right. I thought he was with you.
He was with me until just a little while ago,
but then he got a call on his cellular
and he ran off somewhere.
Do you know where he went to?
No. But he did say we were to have lunch without him.
Then he must have gone off to have lunch on his own.
Come on, don't bother with them.
They're kind of strange.
Why don't we go get some lunch too?
Finally! I can finally take a look at it.
I gave up 13 years ago,
but this radiant treasure's finally in my hands.
"Dragon"
How can you be so dumb?
We have to go back to Osaka Castle again.
Besides, how can you lose your wallet
when you put it in your bag?
You kept saying "Hurry up, hurry up"
so I must have left it somewhere.
How much did you have inside?
5,000 yen.
Just forget about it then. Besides, it's getting dark already.
No! I have my favorite amulet inside it!
It's nothing to cry about!
I'm not crying.
It's raining.
It doesn't look like it's going to let up so soon.
Here, I have an umbrella.
-This is the pits. -What'll we do?
Hey, maybe you left your wallet in that store.
Remember? Kazuha, you bought a disposable camera there.
I think you're right.
All right then, we'll go and ask.
Gosh.
I think we should look over there.
We already did.
Is something wrong?
Yes. We can't find our friend who's playing Hideyoshi.
We looked for him at Osaka Castle and the shops around here,
even in the toilets...
He's nowhere to be found.
I wonder where he could've gone.
What's that?
Look! What's that?
Somebody's burning!
Mr. Mouri, call for an ambulance!
Okay!
Hey, can you hear me? What happened to you?
Huh?
Hey, hang in there! You hear me?
Yes! That's it! This is my wallet!
You're very lucky.
I figured you might be coming back right away
so I kept it here instead of giving it to the police.
It's a very precious wallet, isn't it?
It was filled with amulets.
It sure is! Thank you so much, madam!
You mean you had more than one amulet in there?
I bought a charm to chase away evil, too.
So that we wouldn't be involved in another case
and have it ruin your visit to Osaka like last time.
How sweet!
What? A burning man fell from the tower?
Are you sure about that?
Yeah. The police are there and everything's going crazy!
It didn't work, none of them.
I guess not.
Inspector Otaki, you sure are busy.
Two murders two days straight.
Well, it's my job.
It's amazing though.
How did you know the victim's name was Yuji Kato?
I looked on his badge.
His badge?
You mean the crest on his chest?
That's Hideyoshi's crest, the Goshichi paulownia.
As soon as I saw it,
I knew he was the Hideyoshi character from their group
so I had them come and identify the body.
What do you mean about Hideyoshi character?
As part of the tours entertainment,
we have each member act as
a famous person from the Warring States period
and also have a penalty game.
For instance, I'm Mitsuhide and Kasuya is Ieyasu.
Wakisaka is Nobunaga and Katagiri is Nene.
And Kato over there was Hideyoshi.
I see. That sure sounds like a lot of fun.
But I don't understand how you could lose track of
one of your tour members and let him end up like this.
Well...
He disappeared so suddenly
and we were looking for him all this time.
He was wearing a flashy fleece outfit
so we figured we could spot him right away.
Who'd have thought he'd fall from there in a ball of fire.
By the way, can you think of a reason
why Mr. Kato would commit suicide?
No. I don't have the slightest idea.
How do you know it was suicide?
First off, it's raining so hard.
No one would go out there on the roof.
And then, he was wearing clothes made of fleece,
which is very flammable.
That proves he went out on the roof himself
and set himself on fire.
But you sure do come across a lot of murders, don't you?
Maybe you're cursed or something?
Not really.
The Chief of Police's son comes across them more often.
What? Is Heiji here, too?
Yes. He and Conan went inside the castle just a little while ago.
Hey, Kudo.
Be careful, it's slippery up there because of the rain.
How embarrassing. I feel like a trained monkey.
Did you find something?
There's a lot of teeny tiny pieces of something up here.
It's a lighter.
Could this be the lighter he used?
It doesn't make sense though. Why is it here?
What's this mark?
I just don't believe it.
Why would Kato commit suicide?
I don't believe it either.
He was really looking forward to coming to Osaka.
I guess you never know what people are really thinking about.
Maybe he'd planned all along
to commit suicide here in the land of Hideyoshi Toyotomu.
All we have to do is find what he used to set himself on fire with.
Right. That's all we need to find.
We found it!
It was on the roof of the tower. It's a lighter.
Why isn't that the lighter Kato had?
Yes, I think it is.
That settles it! It was a suicide!
I wouldn't be too sure about that.
What?
The cover on this lighter was closed.
Do you think someone committing suicide
would take the time to close the cover?
But Heiji, maybe the cover closed when he dropped it.
If that were the case,
we should have found it further down the roof.
Besides, it looked like something else was there
before the lighter was put down.
What do you mean, something else?
When we found the lighter,
there was a dry spot in a strange shape under it.
Not a rectangle shape like this lighter,
it was a nice fan shape.
I'm pretty sure something round was put there
before it started to rain.
After the rain started,
that round thing was replaced with the lighter.
-Isn't that right, kid? -Yes.
But Heiji, what do you think that round thing was?
Beats me. I haven't figured that out yet.
But I think it has something to do
with the little chips all over the place.
Inspector Otaki.
We've laid out all of the victim's personal belongings out.
Wallet, watch, cellular phone,
keys, cigarettes and a piece of something.
Huh? A scroll.
What is this?
Only the word "dragon" is on this thing.
And what is this from?
It looks like piece of pottery.
Huh? That piece...
Isn't it possible that piece is the same
as the ones they found on the other burned bodies?
My dad and your father were talking about it in the car last night.
One was found in the inner moat 13 years ago
and the other was found just recently in the outer moat.
Both victims had pieces of pottery that looked the same.
And I heard them say that
the one they found recently had "848" written on it.
848? What does that mean?
No one was really sure
but it seems that those pieces are a part of some kind of treasure.
Treasure?
I'm not making it up!
They were whispering like it was a secret!
They said something about huge fortune the great man left behind.
Did you say huge fortune?
Are you sure you're not making all of this up?
Hey, Hattori.
Look at this piece of pottery.
There's shiny stuff stuck on the inside of it.
Hey. Isn't that gold?
I think so, but it's not much
so I don't think it's much of a treasure.
Gosh. I just don't understand this case.
It's a mysterious enough that Mr. Kato left the tour
and went up the roof
but it's even harder to explain why he suddenly burst into flames.
And the biggest question...
Why Mr. Kato grabbed the umbrella...
just before he died.
Umbrella could refer to rain.
And rain makes me think of
the Ryuko rock right here at Osaka Castle.
What's that?
You mean you don't know?
Here at Osaka Castle,
standing on both sides of the Sakura Gate, protecting the tower
we have rocks called Ryuko Rocks.
That's what they've been called since long ago
because it's said that when it rains,
the figures of a dragon and tiger appear on them.
Rain.
Let me borrow that for awhile!
-What's going on? -That's evidence!
Her story might just be true.
Yeah.
There's still a possibility it could be hidden somewhere.
The treasure of Hideyoshi, the man called "Lord of Gold"...
It's somewhere in Osaka Castle.
Which means, Hideyoshi's treasure...
Yeah, it's me.
Don't make a move yet.
It doesn't look like the cops will be leaving soon.
Don't worry about it.
The thing we want is right in front of me.
Make sure you've got everything ready.
What? You know what the treasure Hideyoshi left is?
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm pretty sure about it.
The clue is the piece of pottery Mr. Kato had.
Take a good look at it.
There's just a little bit here and there,
but you can see that there's gold stuck on the inside.
You're right.
But how do you knew there's a lot of treasure
just by looking at this piece?
Now, put it together with this scroll that Mr. Kato had
and look again carefully.
But this scroll only has the word, "dragon"
on the upper right hand written on it.
What is this?
Several sheets of paper
were pasted over the word that was written there.
It's just like the Ryuko Rocks at Osaka Castle,
when you wet the paper, the word underneath appears.
But most of the words have been burnt
and you can't read them.
And what about this? What's this drawing on the left?
Isn't that a gourd?
The gourd is the symbol on Hideyoshi's flag. It's his standard.
-What? -So, is that mean
that piece might have come from pottery shaped like a gourd?
And are you saying that it was filled with gold?
But according to this diagram,
it was about one shaku high,
which is only about 30 centimeters.
No matter how much money you stuffed in it,
it's so small, it wouldn't add up to much.
Did you forget?
It's been said that whenever General Hideyoshi won a battle,
he added a small gourd
and that's how his golden standard was created.
The bottle gourds!
Bottle gourds, you mean?
Don't tell me...
That's right. If there were 1,000 of the same thing,
that would be some treasure!
And if you were to consider the history behind it,
it would be priceless.
The burnt body 13 years ago had a piece,
so did the other recent body
and now Mr. Kato, it could mean that
maybe they were after the treasure
but they were killed by someone who wanted it all for themselves.
I don't understand though.
How did the Chief of Police and your father know
that it meant a huge treasure just by looking at the two pieces?
They hadn't seen the scroll yet.
They probably knew by looking at the shape.
The piece my father was looking at in the car
looked like it came from the top of the gourd
and he said the words "848" was written on it.
I get it. 848 is a number between 1 and 1,000.
If both of the pieces had gold stuck to them on the inside,
that theory might be correct.
But that sounds like a fairy tale.
But it isn't entirely impossible.
It's been said that even after Hideyoshi died,
Ieyasu was intimidated by him
because of all the gold and silver he'd stored in Osaka Castle.
There's a legend that when Hideyoshi wanted
to purify the water in the well,
he put a huge amount of gold in the Kinmeisui
directly in front of the tower.
Even if that's true,
what makes you think this is refers to hidden treasure?
For all you know, this scroll could just be a blueprint.
Stupid. Hiding gold in pottery
and layering sheets of paper over the scroll
is the proof someone deliberately wanted to hide something.
That scroll's the dragons chapter.
Which means, it's so obvious...
About the tiger.
If that scroll with the dragon is like the Ryuko Rock
and the drawing of a gourd appeared when it got wet,
then there should be a scroll with a tiger somewhere too.
And what's more,
there's two high possibility that scroll will show us
where the gourds are hidden.
Isn't that right, Heiji?
Mr. Toyama!
What brings you here?
I gave him a call.
The prefectural police's main headquarters is fight over there.
Huh?
It seemed to be linked to a case dad was involved in before.
Besides, if I didn't do something like this,
you'd never tear yourself away from this place, would you?
She's gone and butted in again.
Kazuha's right. Let us take care of this.
Yes, listen to him.
I know a real nice place in the Shimbashi direction of Osaka Castle.
Let's have dinner there!
Be quiet! Someone died right in front of our eyes!
How can you stuff your face...
I mean, have dinner. It wouldn't feel right, would it?
So, you should just forget about me
and have dinner with Ran. I won't mind, Kazuha.
Forget you, then!
Let's go, Ran! We'll just go without them!
Wait a minute, Kazuha!
Come on, let's go!
It's a super delicious Italian restaurant!
Excuse me, would it be all right if we got something to eat too?
We haven't had anything to eat since lunch.
My clothes got wet from the rain
so I'm going to the hotel first and change.
-Wait! -We'll be right back.
The hotel we're staying in is close by.
All right then, but don't be long!
That voice... Could it be...
-Hey, Otaki. -Yes, sir!
Listen.
Yes, sir. I'll tell my men right away.
-Be careful. -Yes, sir!
Heizo, it's me.
You did it for Heiji, didn't you?
Calling your father like that.
You knew your father was deeply involved in that case
so you figured if you called him in
he'd fill Heiji in with all the information he'd be dying to know.
But you didn't want him to catch on
so you used that tone with him.
So, what if I did? I love seeing it.
I love seeing how his face glows
whenever he solves a case.
I'm such a fool, aren't I?
Yes, a major fool!
A major fool?
And so am I.
It's so frustrating,
but there's something so wonderful about Shinichi
when he gets like that.
But only when he gets like that though.
Isn't that right, Conan? You agree, don't you?
Oh, no! I forgot to bring Conan along!
You're right.
Hey, Hattori.
Take a look at this.
I found something strange in a strange place.
A battery?
Wait a minute.
If that came from when Mr. Kato burned up...
Right. It was no suicide.
It was murder.
Don't worry about it.
Heiji and your father are with him.
Besides, there are a lot of police around here.
Nothing's going to happen.
The victim's name is Maho Katagiri, a member of that tour.
According to Kazuha, her coat caught on fire
and she fell into the moat as if she were collapsing.
But the cause of death is a blow to the back of her dead.
She probably got it when she fell.
I think she hit her head n the girder over there.
Was it suicide?
It looks that way, at least for now.
Kazuha, are you sure she wasn't holding anything else
beside the lighter?
Yes. I'm sure, that's how it looked to me.
Was there anybody near her?
No, not near her,
but there was somebody near the bridge's entrance, right?
-Yes. -That's it!
That's who set her on fire!
I don't think it was possible though.
That person was on the same side as we were.
I definitely think it was suicide though.
Don't be stupid! No way it was suicide!
There's got to be something here!
Something to prove it was murder! There has to be!
Stop that, Heiji!
Dad?
Heiji, stop acting like you know everything!
Don't you understand?
Do you know how much trouble you cause
every time you meddle in police matters?
Calm down, sir!
Heiji's just trying to solve the crime in his own way.
Sorry.
Mr. Mouri, that may be how you see it.
But when it comes to this kid,
you don't call his methods police work.
He's a pest.
People flatter him by calling him a high school detective
and that's given him a swollen ego.
He interferes with our investigations by handling the evidence
and the victim's bodies all because it's his hobby.
He's nothing more than a crime scene assaulter.
To prove my point, look around two people
have died right in front of his eyes
and he hasn't done anything to stop it.
He was so sure that nothing else would happen
because the police had the area covered.
Actually, you could say we were just as much at fault.
At any rate.
Meddlesome amateurs should leave.
Get out of my sight immediately!
Sir!
You're being too hard on him.
Otaki.
Did you forget? I told you to follow that guy, didn't I?
That's right! No wonder the Chief's so...
Yes. That's his way of showing he cares about his son.
Otaki, are these both murders?
No.
Regarding Mr. Kato's case,
he fell from the tower as he burned
and we found a lighter on the roof
with the victim's fingerprints on it.
As for Ms. Katagiri,
she lit the fire on herself and fell into the moat.
Kazuha herself witnessed this.
There are several things we can't explain,
but I'm almost certain there were both suicides.
If that's the case, then 2 or 3 men
should be enough of cover the work here.
Huh?
-Toyama, let's go. -Huh?
The police have more important work to do.
We can't spend so much time on a case as minor as this.
Chief!
Heizo.
What are you planning?
Don't look so disappointed, Heiji.
The Chief's probably angry
because two people died so close to headquarters.
Still, he didn't have to hit him.
Maybe it's all the killer's fault.
Remember the story?
About Heiji's dad driving us home
and they were talking about some pottery.
Well, there's a continuation to that.
They said it was possible
that when the burnt body was found 13 years ago
there was a rash of armed burglaries
and that the burglar might unexpectedly be discovered.
Armed burglaries?
Yes, there were five consecutive incidents.
Seven people were killed
and the vicious killer is still on the loose.
Are you saying that Hattori's father thinks
the killer in these recent cases is the same person?
Now I get it.
Heizo didn't want to put his son in danger
so he acted coldly to distance him from the case.
That's so touching. It makes me want to cry.
Yeah. It makes me want to cry, too.
Who'd have thought my old man would go soft like that?
Heiji.
I don't take orders very well.
If I get pushed, I push back.
I'm going to solve the case
and shove the killer right up my father's nose!
What he's saying is he's more stupid than obedient.
But that's strange.
You'd think that being his father,
he would know that his son wouldn't give up so easily.
You know, Heiji.
You keep talking about a killer,
but this doesn't look like anything else except suicide.
All right, take a look at this.
Look on Ms. Katagiri's right side.
It's faint because it's wet, but you can still see it.
There are 2 or 3 strange marks.
You're right! There is strange marks here.
And there're all the same.
Isn't that blood?
Yes, probably from the victim.
From the victim?
That's right. Ms. Katagiri died from a blow to the head,
but she didn't get it when she fell
and hit her head on the bridge girder.
Someone might have hit her on the head with something hard.
Causing blood to splatter onto the killer
and the blood got on her when the killer picked her up.
What I'm saying is
when Kazuha and Ran saw her on the bridge,
she was already dead.
Another thing. The figure you saw
suddenly burst into flames and fell into the moat,
that's why you came to the wrong conclusion
and assumed it was a suicide.
But when she burst into flames,
it looked like she was struggling in pain.
Yes, that's right. She was definitely alive.
That's what you thought you saw.
It was very dark, you didn't get a good look, did you?
Yes, but...
Well anyway, those guys seem suspicious to me.
I've got to find those three guys who were on the same tour
as the two deceased people and question them.
Are you talking about us?
We came back right away just like you told us to
and noticed the big commotion.
It looks like the crowd's getting bigger.
What happened here?
What? I don't believe it!
Ms. Katagiri fell from the bridge while burning up?
From this Gokuraku Bridge?
Yes.
But why would she commit suicide by setting herself on fire?
It hasn't been officially declared a suicide yet.
That's why we need you to answer few questions.
First off, you fellows and Ms. Katagiri left this area,
where did you go
and what were you doing before coming back.
I went to get something to eat at a small restaurant near here.
I did the same.
Only I went to a different restaurant.
I went back to the hotel in Nanayari
where we're all staying and changed my clothes.
So you were with Ms. Katagiri, weren't you?
Yes, until we got back to the hotel.
If I'd known something like would happen,
I should have stayed with her the whole time.
But why did Mr. Kato and Ms. Katagiri choose fire?
It's almost as if someone ordered them to do.
Ordered?
That reminds me, Mr. Wakisaka.
You were playing the role of Nobunaga, weren't you?
Yes.
That means, if you ordered them to do something,
they'd have to obey, wouldn't they?
Well, in that case,
Fukushima who could assume Nobunaga's role for 3 minutes
-could also have done it, too. -What?
I played Ieyasu, so that leaves me out of the picture.
So one of you must have done it.
Their duty was to entertain Nobunaga,
not to take orders!
Besides, no one would obey an order
to set themselves on fire.
And another thing. Ms. Katagiri played Nene,
that was just a supervisory role.
Also, when the first member of our party died,
we wouldn't be so callous as to continue our role playing game!
Yes, I see what you mean.
Inspector Otaki.
We've found another piece of pottery on Ms. Katagiri's body.
What, again?
I wonder why they all had pieces of pottery like this.
And we found this photo, too.
The young couple in the right corner...
Isn't that Mr. Kato and Ms. Katagiri?
You're right. So they knew each other from before.
But who are the other three people?
Oh, that's Hirano.
Here, that's him.
You're right.
He looks really young, but I think that it's him.
And who's this Hirano character?
He planned this tour.
We got all together because of Hirano's home page.
He suggested we all go on a trip.
He came up with the idea of the role playing game, too.
Unfortunately, just before we were leaving on the trip,
something important came up and he couldn't make it.
I see.
So the man planned this trip
resulting in strange deaths, isn't in attendance?
Are you absolutely sure Ms. Katagiri didn't commit suicide?
Yes. Well, we can't say for sure just yet.
Well, if the killer is using this tour to commit murders,
the first thing we should do is talk to Mr. Hirano.
All you have to do is
access "Legend of the Lord of Gold" home page.
-That's him. -Huh?
When Ms. Katagiri burned and fell from the bridge,
that's who the suspicious person behind Ran and Kazuha was.
Yes, I thought so too,
but there's something I don't understand.
The killer called Ms. Katagiri out to the bridge, killed her
then tied a rope around her and propped her against the railing
and waited in the distance for someone to come by
when the moment was right, the killer pulled the rope
and she fell into the moat, that set up is easy.
But to set her on fire at just the right time
make it look like she was writhing in pain as she fell,
that's not as easy thing to do.
Another thing bothers me, too.
That strange blood stain on her side.
I'm pretty sure that's from blood that was on a zipper.
But none of those three wore clothes with a zipper.
There has to be a reason the killer would
go to the trouble of changing into that kind of outfit
then calling Ms. Katagiri out to the bridge.
I know what it is.
Yeah.
Now we know why the killer wore a special outfit that has a zipper.
The question now is, who used that trick.
Well, anyone of those three could have.
Hey, Heiji. Let's go already.
It's getting windier, too!
My umbrella!
Hey, Hattori.
I think we...
I think we made a big mistake.
Oh, my umbrella's ruined.
Well, you can always buy a cheap one from that store nearby.
Huh? Where's Heiji?
He took Conan and went off somewhere.
They probably figured out who the killer is.
Huh?
He was positively glowing.
Gosh. They couldn't have gone so far,
but I don't see them.
It's no use! Only one of them is at the hotel.
The other two haven't returned yet.
There might be another murder.
After the first and second cases are investigated thoroughly,
the trick is bound to be exposed.
So the killer's got to finish the job by tonight.
Where could they have gone?
Over there! That's Mr. Kasuya!
It doesn't look like he's heading back to the hotel.
It looks like he's going to finish things.
Okay! I'll let the police know.
Stop. If the police come,
there's bound to be a commotion and he might get away.
Let's you and me open this one up on our own.
I'm talking about the door to the truth.
Wait, Hattori!
That old man went into a suspicious looking warehouse.
Hattori, don't you feel something?
I get this weird feeling we're being watched.
Hey, what're you doing? We're going in!
Okay.
It's so dark here, I can't see a thing.
He's over there.
It looks like he's going up.
Kudo, that tranquilizer you've got in your watch,
-get it ready. -Yeah, I know.
Hey, Kudo. What's wrong?
You need to go to the toilet?
Oh, no. I'm going to lose sight of him if I don't get moving.
Listen, Kudo. When you finish using the toilet,
catch up with me right away.
Hey, sorry to make you wait.
Wakisaka.
No problem.
Did you bring it with you?
It's over there. Inside that box.
I see, good!
But there's so much stuff in here
and it's so dark, I can't make anything out.
I put a flashlight on the side of the box.
Why don't you use it?
Here it is!
Use that and you'll be able to find what you're looking for.
The tiger scroll.
I wouldn't turn it on if I were you.
You'll be burnt to a crisp if you do.
Just like Mr. Kato on Osaka Castle's tower.
Isn't that right, Mr. Wakisaka?
You mean both Ms. Katagiri and Mr. Kato were...
That's right. Mr. Wakisaka killed them.
He used the same trick he used on you.
He lured the three of you out
by saying that he'd found the tiger scroll.
It was easy with Mr. Kato.
All he had to do was tell him that
he hid the scroll under one of the tiles on the roof of the tower.
in order to climb out on the roof,
you'd avoid going in the afternoon
when a lot of people would be around and wait until night.
Going out there at night is fine, but without a light,
you wouldn't be able to tell which tile it was under.
Mr. Kato had no other choice,
so he took the lighter he had out
and lit it so he could look around.
He saw a flashlight just lying there as if waiting to be found.
Mr. Wakisaka had left it there earlier.
It was rigged to explode when it was switched on.
I see.
So you're saying Mr. Kato chose to use the flashlight
which was handier,
but when he turned it on, it exploded.
That's right.
The flashlight exploded into tiny pieces
and the lighter with his fingerprints on was left on the roof,
making it look like he set himself on fire.
That would explain the dry mark
that was left under the lighter.
You wouldn't get that kind of mark
unless you put a lighter on a round shaped mark.
Besides, we found a burnt battery
on the ground near the castle.
But how did he kill Ms. Katagiri?
According to the girls who witnessed it,
when she set herself on fire,
there was no one else around.
And she was writhing in pain,
as she fell into the moat.
And all she had in her hand as a lighter.
Suicide is the only conclusion.
I don't blame you for thinking like that.
But it wasn't her that set herself on fire
and fell into the moat.
It was Mr. Wakisaka.
What?
After the crowd that was gathered near the tower left
and people walking around thinned out around the bridge,
he called her out after making her change into a coat.
Then he killed her by striking her with a hard object,
then he threw her into the moat.
Her body floated on the water
and he poured kerosene on her, setting the stage.
All he had to do was wait for someone to pass the bridge
then set fire to his coat,
and pretend to writhe in pain
dropping the lighter into the moat,
the lighter would set fire to Ms. Katagiri's body floating in the moat.
After that, he jumped into the moat
and dove underwater.
The only thing visible would be
Ms. Katagiri's body burning in the water.
What you're saying is, even when her body
was lifted out of the water and examined,
the injury on her head which was the actual cause of her death,
would appear to have been a result of her hitting her head on the girder
because the witnesses would testify
that she set fire to herself and fell from the bridge.
That's right.
But it only went as smoothly as it did
because those girls happened to pass by at just the right moment.
If a lot of time had passed before anyone had walked by,
the time of death would be off, wouldn't it?
Not really.
Because Mr. Wakisaka had already prepared a witness.
It was mere coincidence
that Kazuha and Ran saw what happened first,
it appears the intended witness ran away from the scene though.
Don't tell me that it was...
It was Mr. Fukushima.
He didn't know anything about the incident,
but when he heard a burning body fell into the moat,
he immediately said it was suicide.
Think about it.
If someone were going to commit suicide
by setting themselves on fire,
they wouldn't jump into water. It would put the fire out.
It would be natural to assume that you'd jump into the water
only if someone else set fire to you, isn't that right?
What he said proves that he witnessed her
jumping into the moat after setting herself on fire.
Judging by the events of the day,
all a person would have to do is disguise their voice
pretending to be the police and call him out to the bridge,
he would have gone there right away.
But it's awfully strange.
After what happened,
Mr. Wakisaka's hair and clothes weren't all that wet.
And if by chance something went wrong,
he could have been seriously burned.
He was wearing a dry suit
under his coat over his clothes.
If he wear to put the hood on before setting fire to himself,
he wouldn't get burned,
and neither his hair or his clothes would get wet
so he could swim underwater.
Until he got far away from the bridge
then climb up the stone wall,
and after he hid the dry suit and coat somewhere,
he went and joined the crowd
so as not to draw suspicion to himself.
Incidentally, both the flammable fleece Mr. Kato wore,
and Ms. Katagiri's coat were given to them by you, right?
You probably told them that it would be easy for them
to spot each other when they snuck off to meet in secret.
Did you know there was blood on Ms. Katagiri's coat?
Her blood splattered on your clothes
and then you got it on her.
It got on her when you carried her.
They were shaped like the zipper on a dry suit
and the edge of that badge you have on your chest.
Which means that
if we were to check that Nobunaga badge you're wearing,
we'll have the proof to nail you.
But why did he want to kill me and the other two?
You three weren't the only ones.
He killed the man who planned this trip, Mr. Hirano too.
I asked a professor I know to access Mr. Hirano's home page,
he found that Mr. Hirano had been putting new entries on a daily basis
but he stopped 3 weeks ago.
Remember that burnt body they found in the outer moat recently?
That was probably...
Yeah, that's right.
I killed Hirano, Kato and Katagiri
in dedication to my grandfather Masakiyo
who loved Hideyoshi and was killed for it.
Your grandfather?
You saw the picture, didn't you?
The old man in the middle holding the scroll open
was my grandfather.
He always used to tell me
about the scroll he'd found
and about the clues to Hideyoshi's treasure.
He told me he wanted to give up looking for the treasure
and donate the scroll to the country.
But the others didn't agree
and they began to argue about it.
Then 13 years ago, he told us he was going to Osaka
to try and convince the others to agree with him,
and he never came back.
You mean the burnt body they found in the moat 13 years ago...
Was my grandfather. He was killed by his partners.
Grandfather found that piece of pottery along with the scroll
but he didn't tell the others about it.
That photo was the only clue I had
as to who his partners were,
so I had a hard time finding them.
And I never imagined that one of them
would change how they looked.
You mean that old man on the left is...
That's me.
Something happened, and I had to change my appearance.
Ms. Katagiri seemed to suspect
that I was a member of their former group.
I don't care what happens to me,
but are you going to kill Mr. Wakisaka too?
You'll never find out where the treasure is.
I assume you haven't brought the tiger scroll with you.
I've already found out where Mr. Wakisaka lives
I'll just tear his house apart.
Both of you move to the back, quickly!
Pick up that flashlight and turn it on.
I'm going to have you two fall to the ground.
It's going to look like the killer and the teenage detective
fell to their deaths while engulfed in flames.
By the way, before you die, answer my question.
How did you figure out Mr. Wakisaka was the killer?
Anyone could have used that trick you just explained.
What tipped you off?
Why should I tell you?
It was the umbrella.
In Mr. Kato's last moment, he grabbed hold of an umbrella,
it was his dying message.
He was indicating Nobunaga's standard, the golden umbrella.
That's how he knew Mr. Wakisaka was the killer.
You little brat! When'd you get up there?
Get down here!
Or I'll fill your friend here with holes!
No! Don't come down there!
I guess I don't have a choice.
You idiot!
What a good little boy.
You're Heizo Hattori!
Dad?
You may have changed how you looked 13 years ago
but it seems like you can't change
that sick voice or that warped personality.
You're under arrest for possession of an illegal weapon
and for attempted murder!
Also for the five robbery murders you committed
because you failed to find the treasure.
You're going to pay for what you did!
Robbery murders?
I don't know what you're talking about!
No use pretending!
We've get your voice on tape, on the spur of the moment,
the victim recorded it on his answering machine,
and we've also got your handprint on the telephone
when you hung it up!
There's no sympathy for those who turn against their friends.
If you don't want to get hurt...
Come along quiet like and let us put these cuffs on you!
So the case that spanned 13 years
was personally solved by the head of Osaka's prefectural police
while we watched in wonder,
it all happened in a blink of an eye.
You must feel good about this.
You sent each of us a piece of that pottery
and baited us with all that talk of the tiger scroll,
you knew that would make us join the tour.
You succeeded in avenging your grandfather with one blow.
And on top of that,
your family's got Hideyoshi's treasure all to themselves.
That was no treasure map.
What do you mean?
This is what was written on the tiger scroll.
"This is to certify that I have received
the 1,000 items depicted on the dragon scroll.
From Kajisuke."
Kajisuke? Isn't he the thief who was after Hideyoshi's gold,
the one who went down into the Kinmeisui well?
That's right.
Kajisuke left that letter intending it be a joke.
Then why didn't that grandfather of yours tell us?
He couldn't.
Not to his friends who were so excited
about finding the treasure,
especially not to you who had invested so much money in the project.
That's ridiculous.
What? We were bait?
Yes. This is what your father said.
Sorry, Conan.
But his men are all pros, they can spot a cop a mile away.
In order to solve this case as quickly as possible,
I thought it'd be best just to have Heiji followed
because he always takes chances.
So now you know.
So he hit me to get me mad
because he knew I'd take the risks?
Yeah.
He said he knew a lot of Mr. Kasuya's accomplices were coming here.
Because you need a lot of men
to transport 1,000 golden gourds.
But before I was got into trouble,
Inspector Otaki, who was staking things out,
took me into protective custody.
Hold it a second! You said stake out,
does that mean dad knew Mr. Wakisaka was the killer?
Yeah. When he questioned the people on the scene
and found out Mr. Kato had grabbed the umbrella,
he had someone follow Mr. Wakisaka.
That beady eyed sneak of a father.
If he ever tries something like this again,
I'm going to stick my finger in his ear
and rattle it around so he can't talk!
Ouch!
Shizu, can't you be do it a little gently?
Don't complain.
I'm paying you back for putting Heiji through so much.
Next Conan's Hint:
"Cellphone"