Um... uh, Sato-san?
Th... this important talk you wanted...
what's it about?
Just get in.
Y-yes!
Huh? Wait a second...
this feels familiar somehow.
That's right, that one time
when I opened the car door...
Whoa! Aah...
Ahahaha! Gotcha!
Gotcha! Ahahaha!
That time, Sato-san
got a real kick out of it.
Whew.
Well then, guess I'll let her
prank me good and proper today too.
Whoa, please don't,
not one of these pranks!
Huh...? Wait, what?
What are you doing?
Huh?
Oh... no, I just figured
this was another prank.
I told you, it's something important.
But last time you said it was
important too, and you got me.
Hey.
Yes?
Can't you tell just by looking?
Uh, well, even if you tell me to look...
all I can really say is
you're as beautiful as ever.
What kind of nonsense is that? Honestly.
S-so... what is it, then?
It hasn't come. That.
Huh. So "that" hasn't come.
Hm? W-w-wait...
"hasn't come"... you don't mean...
This is embarrassing,
so don't tell anyone, okay?
Y-yes, of course.
Ahh, but what do we do?
This is a matter of responsibility, isn't it?
R-responsibility...
I'll properly take...
Takagi-kun.
Wait. A marriage between two
police officers...
and in the same department,
no less...
Right, when a married couple works together,
to avoid potential complications...
one of them gets
transferred, doesn't it?
Sato-san is the flower of
Division One, and if she got transferred...
who knows what the senior
detectives would do to me.
Which means I'd be the one
transferred to some other precinct.
No, no, the noble thing would be
for me to quit and become a stay-at-home dad...
Yes, understood.
Huh?
We'll head over right away.
A sighting of the suspect
we've been searching for, in Beika-cho.
We're heading straight to the scene.
Ah... y-yes!
M-Miwako's having a baby!
Congratulations are in order!
The sun blazing down,
undaunted by the heat...
a stylish and dashing
mystery show.
Sato finally confesses to Takagi?
A perfect alibi and the riddle of flower meanings.
Seeing through to the one and only truth...
Looks like a kid, mind of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"Detective Love Story at MPD Headquarters (Confession)"
(cicadas chirping)
(three of them yawning)
Hey, hey, all three of you
yawning at once?
You're not Haibara, you know.
Well, excuse me for being the yawning girl.
But...
That new game
"Titan Hunter" is just so much fun...
I couldn't help getting hooked on it.
Sheesh. You're gonna waste
your whole summer break on a game?
Ehehe.
Oh yeah, Ayumi got her dad
to help, and I'm at rank five!
Seriously?
I keep getting eaten
by the blue giant over and over...
What kind of game is that?
Apparently it's a role-playing game
where you defend your own castle...
from a race of giants
that come attacking you.
Huh.
Come to think of it, the strategy guide
comes out today, doesn't it?
That's right.
Hey, you think they're selling it
at the convenience store over there?
Let's go check!
Hey, you guys, weren't we
supposed to play soccer at the park?
Nothing for it, I guess.
Sheesh, honestly... hm?
Was there an accident over there or something?
But for that, those flowers...
If I remember right, that's an obedient plant.
The flower meaning is...
Hey, Edogawa-kun?
Ah!
What are you doing?
We're leaving you behind.
O-okay.
Man, what a surprise that was.
To think there'd be a complete
stranger who looks so much like him.
Yeah, you're right.
We're running a little late, but...
want to grab lunch around here?
Ah, sure.
Oh! Then maybe something sour?
Huh? Why?
Whoa, that's amazing, the Overlord Blade!
So cool!
"Attack power over 10,000..."
"the one and only holy sword
feared by the giants," it says here!
(Haibara yawning)
But it's a black-and-white photo,
so we can't tell the colors.
You can't get it unless you beat the
super-huge red giant at rank eight, you know.
Sounds like it'll take a while yet.
I've got that sword.
Huh?!
The hilt is shiny gold...
and the pattern on the blade is red.
After this you have to keep...
collecting lots of...
upgrade items...
to forge the sword,
apparently, though.
Wow, so that means
you reached rank eight!
Yeah.
Hey, aren't you that kid
from the class next door...
You're not showing off
and lying, are you?
It's not a lie.
Hey, Toshinari nii-chan.
Yeah.
You worked hard, Noriya.
Huh? This guy from earlier...
If you really got the Overlord Blade,
I'd love to see it.
Me too!
Then do you all want to come
to Toshinari nii-chan's place?
Hey, that's okay, right?
Toshinari nii-chan?
Hmm...
All right, go on ahead
and get in the car.
I'll go pay for this.
That comes to 1,350 yen.
Card, please.
Sure. How would you like to pay?
One payment.
Understood.
Foreign car keys and a platinum card.
Some rich kid, maybe?
Ugh.
What a run-down apartment.
Hey, Genta-kun!
Hahaha, it looks shabby,
but home is where you make it.
Well, I'll go park the car...
so head on into the room.
Yeah.
Whoa!
It really is the Overlord Blade!
The grip really is all shiny.
Wow!
That's great!
Sheesh, the trash bag is...
full of snacks, cup noodles,
and convenience store bento containers.
You can really see his diet.
Hey, Haibara.
What?
Didn't you smell something?
Not really. Doesn't seem
like there's any food garbage in here.
No, I mean out in the hallway,
before we came into this room.
Hm, I didn't notice anything.
I see. Hm?
Hey, what are you doing,
rummaging through someone's house?
Hey, Noriya-kun.
Hm?
Did your big brother just
move into this place?
No, it was about a month ago.
Before summer break he lived in
the same building as me.
Huh.
And Toshinari nii-chan isn't
my brother, he's my cousin.
He's my mom's older sister's kid.
Right now my dad's away
on a business trip overseas...
and my mom went to take care of him
for a week...
so just for that time I'm staying over
at Toshinari nii-chan's place.
A whole week here?
Yeah.
Besides, my mom asked me to.
Toshinari nii-chan's big sister
died in a car accident half a year ago...
and he was really down about it...
so she told me to stay with him
and cheer him up.
Then those flowers from earlier...
were at the site of that sister's accident.
Oh yeah, he showed me a
photo of that sister before.
She was a kind sister who
often took us camping.
Huh? Were there
this many photos before?
Hey, let me see that.
U-uh, sure.
That's strange, these last few photos...
in every single one,
her eyes aren't looking this way.
And what's this?
There's a tiny hole
near the top of the photos.
Ah!
Th-that's Toshinari nii-chan's voice.
The hallway... don't tell me...
Room four next door, huh.
It's for sure that smell from before.
C-Conan-kun...
What on earth happened?
You guys, don't come in.
Haibara, call the police.
Tell them someone's died here.
Huh?!
Right, got it.
What's that?
The photos pinned to this board...
the sun-fade marks and the photos
are slightly out of alignment.
And it's not just one or two of them.
Why would this be...
In every single one,
her eyes aren't looking this way.
There's a tiny hole
near the top of the photos.
Don't tell me.
The one who did this...
don't tell me...
Still, man...
to think those two
had gotten that far.
That settles it, they're tying the knot!
But man, this is bad, Takagi-kun.
Huh? Bad how?
I mean, just imagine if the
other detectives found out about this.
Ah, true.
Sato-san sure has
a lot of fans.
It's bad, seriously bad.
It really is.
Seriously, this is bad.
Hm? Whoa!
U-um, Yumi-san?
Hm?
Your words and your expression
don't match at all.
Huh?
The victim was...
Yasutomi Hiroto, 31, a freelancer.
According to the coroner's assessment,
the estimated time of death...
was between 7 and 9 last night.
Stabbed repeatedly in the chest and abdomen.
And the one who first discovered the body
was the resident next door to this room...
Shiga Toshinari-san, correct?
Yes.
After I parked my car in the lot
and was heading back to my room...
there was a strange smell
coming from this room.
The door was unlocked, so when
I opened it, I found this scene.
I was surprised when this kid who's a friend of my cousin Noriya,
just went into the room without asking.
It's Conan-kun.
Then the girl who called it in...
That was me.
Today everyone came to visit...
the room of Noriya-kun's cousin.
But you're quite the Grim Reaper,
right up there with Mouri-san.
A murder scene every single time.
Ehehehe.
B-but you detectives
got here pretty fast too, didn't you?
Yeah, we got a tip that a clerk
at a flower shop fairly close to here...
resembled the suspect
we've been looking for.
Turned out to be a total stranger, though.
We happened to be in the neighborhood...
so we got called in to this scene.
Well, if Takagi-kun
hadn't been off...
whispering about flowers with that clerk,
we could've left right away.
No, the reason we lingered around here
was because we were having lunch, right?
You were talking about flowers?
Are you giving them to someone?
But you wouldn't have to whisper
if it were Detective Sato, right?
An affair.
Oh! You think so too?
N-no, that's not it!
Hey, never mind all that...
if the victim died between
7 and 9 last night...
why not ask Noriya-kun
or Toshinari-san?
If they were in the room next door...
they might have heard
some suspicious sounds.
Around that time last night, I was
watching TV with Toshinari nii-chan.
The "Kamen Yaiba" movie was on.
Oh! Ayumi watched that too!
Me too! It was super fun, right?
If I recall, it ran from 7 to 9,
its TV premiere.
And while you were watching it,
did you hear any strange sounds...
like a groan, anything?
Yeah.
Partway through, that man next door
banged on the door...
and yelled at us to keep it down.
What time was that, around?
I think it was probably around 7:30.
I apologized through the door
and turned the volume down, though.
So at that point, Yasutomi-san
was still alive, then.
Any odd sounds after that?
Not that I noticed.
"Kamen Yaiba" is a hero show...
so there were people screaming
and explosions going off constantly...
so even if there'd been a suspicious sound,
I might not have noticed.
Besides...
the neighbor's body is at
the kitchen sink...
two rooms away from where
we were watching TV.
Come to think of it, I saw the neighbor
at the convenience store yesterday evening.
What time was that, around?
Hmm, it was while I was
buying a bento for dinner.
I was worried about
the bento's expiration date...
so I remember asking Noriya
what day it was.
You asked a child the date?
Yeah, I was holding the shopping basket...
and the newspaper he bought at the
store that day was in it...
so I told him it said "August 13th" on it.
I said, "It's the day the Yaiba
movie's on TV."
If it was the 13th, then yes,
that was yesterday.
At that time, was Yasutomi-san
with anyone?
No, I believe he was alone.
Hey, Noriya-kun, while you were
watching the Yaiba movie...
did Toshinari-san get up
to use the bathroom or anything?
No. I was leaning against
Toshinari nii-chan the whole time we watched.
What did you do after it ended?
That movie ended a little
before 9, right?
Yeah. As soon as it ended
I went to pee...
and then went back to the game.
"Back to" it means
you were playing before that too?
Yeah, the whole time from when we got back
from the store until the movie started.
Then Toshinari nii-chan
looked at his watch...
and said, "Uh-oh, it's already 7,
the movie's starting, let's save."
So I hurried up, saved the game,
and switched back to the TV...
and it was just barely in time,
right as the movie was starting.
Then after the movie ended,
while you were in the bathroom...
did Toshinari-san leave the room at all?
No, from outside the bathroom...
he was asking me what snacks
I wanted to eat.
And after that, you two
just kept playing the game?
That's right.
We played pretty late into the night...
woke up early and played some more...
then went to the store with Toshinari
nii-chan to buy breakfast...
and after that we played
until around noon...
but I got sleepy, so I took a nap...
and after I woke up I played again...
and then I got hungry, so we went
to the store again just now...
and that's where we ran into you guys.
N-nothing but games, huh.
No wonder your rank was so high.
I'm jealous!
...So, what did you
do about lunch?
Oh, I was eating snacks,
so I didn't get hungry at all.
Eating snacks and playing
games the whole time...
Lucky.
Sounds like heaven.
Don't go imitating him.
So today too, were you with
Toshinari-san the whole time?
Hmm, after we ate breakfast,
he said he had something to take care of...
told me to be good and play games,
and went out.
He said it'd be bad if the man next door
got mad at us again...
so he told me to wear headphones
while I played.
What time was that, around?
Um, let's see...
We went to the store to buy
breakfast...
at around 6 in the morning...
and he left right after we got home and ate,
so I think it was around 7.
The clock behind the
store clerk...
said it was a little past 6, too.
What?
Don't tell me you suspect that man?
Hm...
U-um...
Is it about time I head
back to my own room?
I don't want the children
near the body any longer.
You're right.
Just to be safe, I'd like
to check the contents...
of your trash bag, if that's okay?
Sure, I don't mind.
Ah, from behind like that...
Huh?
Weren't you the one who was
at the flower shop earlier?
Ah, yes. I did buy some flowers.
I knew it. At that flower shop,
when I asked the clerk...
what would be a good flower to give
when a wish comes true...
she suggested the obedient plant...
that the customer just before me
had bought.
And that's when I spotted you
leaving the shop.
So, Detective Takagi,
something good happened to you?
Did you win a prize on an ice cream stick?
Hey, hey, tell us!
Ah, no... please help me out here.
Huh? Why?
I told you I'd take
proper responsibility, didn't I?
Oh, that?
Well, you do bear part of
the responsibility...
so it's only natural for you to take it.
R-right.
Hey, mister, you bought
those flowers too, right?
Yeah.
In that case...
did a wish of yours come true too, mister?
Ah... yeah, something like that.
All right, Shiga-san, shall we
head to your room?
S-sure.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
Huh? What is it, Conan-kun?
There's something
I'd like you to look into.
Huh?
Toshinari-san was laying flowers
on the road in front of the flower shop...
so I wondered if there'd been
an accident or something.
I-I see.
Come on, Takagi-kun, stop dawdling.
Ah, right.
Hurry up.
Wait, are you okay?
Sato-san, you need to take it easy...
The one who killed
Yasutomi-san is most likely him.
It's got to be Shiga Toshinari-san.
And I've probably got
the motive figured out too.
But the problem is his alibi.
During the time of the crime, the night of
August 13th, between 7 and 9...
he has an alibi that he was
with Noriya-kun the whole time.
Damn it. Just how exactly
did he kill Yasutomi-san?
So? Takagi-kun,
did something good happen to you?
Huh?
♪~
~♪
Wh-what's with
this ominous atmosphere?
Actually...
Sato-san's developed the awareness of a mother.
Hey, that Yaiba movie
you watched last night...
Yeah, that's right.
I had to hold it in even though
I felt like I'd pee my pants.
Just as I thought.
Next Conan,
"Detective Love Story at MPD Headquarters (Truth)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Newspaper".
Summer break is...
games...
snacks... naps...
Go play outside!