Four hundred matches, undefeated?
In the world karate championships?
I look forward to seeing
how far that record goes.
Ah, no.
Unfortunately, I couldn't take part
in the last tournament...
so it went down as a forfeit loss.
He skipped the tournament
to come see me, you know.
Oh?
Ah, no...
If not for that, the undefeated legend
would still be going strong.
But in the Suzuki household,
brute force has no use.
Do you have what it takes
to one day carry...
the entire Suzuki Group on your shoulders?
Huh?
Now, now, Tomoko,
it's far too early for talk like that.
The two of them are still in high school.
No. Now that our eldest, Ayako...
- Suzuki Shiro (51), Sonoko's father (Chairman of the Suzuki Financial Group)
- Suzuki Tomoko (43), Sonoko's mother
has been promised
in marriage to the Tomizawa family...
the only path left
for an heir is to have...
Sonoko's future husband
marry into our family.
By rights, I had hoped
to weigh family standing and education...
and select someone truly worthy
of the Suzuki household.
And yet, you're seeing some drifter,
still just a high schooler...
gallivanting off to study abroad
for "warrior's training"?
What are you thinking, Sonoko?
That's my business, isn't it?
I have no intention
of inheriting this house anyway.
Why, you...
Now, now.
Makoto-kun, it's about time
for your return flight.
I'll have a car
take you to the airport.
We'll continue this discussion
another time.
Ah... yes.
And once your next tournament
is decided, let me know.
I may not look it,
but I'm a fan of martial arts.
Yes.
(cell phone ringtone)
Hm?
Oh, it's Ran calling.
Hold on, I'm not finished talking...
Hello?
Huh? Kaito Kid?
(News: Early this morning, a notice arrived for Suzuki Group advisor Jirokichi Suzuki...
Once again targeting a jewel belonging to advisor Jirokichi Suzuki... the alexandrite known
as the Green Emperor... will be stolen at 10 p.m., after the
first day of the exhibition closes. The Metropolitan Police will tighten
security around the Suzuki Grand Museum... while also accounting for the possibility
he disguises himself as a staff member... verifying identities swiftly...)
That's right, Kid... a heist notice from Kaito Kid has been delivered.
It's all over the TV news right now, about the heist notice he sent.
No way. Seriously? For real?
Then I'll call Uncle Jirokichi right away.
Ah, wait... (call disconnects)
Honestly, Kyogoku-san is here today...
I wanted to tell her not to get all
worked up like she always does.
Backfired completely.
(cell phone ringing)
Ah, hello? Uncle?
I heard all about it.
Kid-sama's coming again, isn't he?
"Kid-sama"...
Sun blazing,
heat I won't lose to...
a stylish, dashing
deduction show.
A battle between the two men Sonoko adores?
Jirokichi's all-out ultimate weapon.
Seeing through the one and only truth...
Looks like a kid,
mind of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"Thief Kid vs. Makoto Kyogoku (Part 1)".
One... one hundred matches,
all losses?
You're telling me
every one was breached?
The state-of-the-art security system
we only just completed the other day?
Y-yes.
Of course, this is all
on the computer simulation.
We input Kaito Kid's
behavioral patterns to date...
and the results of the simulation...
Th-they were...
Ungh... hmm.
What do we do?
The notice day is tomorrow.
At this rate, we'll just hand it
right over to that scoundrel.
The alexandrite I finally got my hands on...
after scouring the entire globe...
the verdant emperor,
the Green Emperor.
B-but Kid's disguise skills
let him impersonate anyone...
plus a mind that adapts to any situation
on the fly...
and when you add in physical abilities...
that seem barely human as data points...
the result will be the same
no matter the security system.
If anything, why not lower
Kid's numbers by twenty percent...
and run the simulation again?
He's human too. Surely he has days
when he's not feeling well.
Fool. That man is a master thief
renowned for his swiftness.
And he sharpens his skills
every single time.
Even a twenty percent increase
wouldn't be enough.
Well, a hundred matches,
all losses.
Putting the gem on display knowing
it'll be taken hardly makes sense.
It pains me, but this time
we'll just have to postpone the exhibit...
Advisor Suzuki.
Hm?
There's a... strange man
at the entrance just now...
demanding to be let in to see you.
What?
Gwaah!
Ugh!
Haaah!
Whoa!
Whoa, waah!
Any further sparring would be pointless.
Ugh... ungh...
I humbly request an audience
with advisor Jirokichi Suzuki.
(panting)
What's all this?
A-advisor...
My name is Makoto Kyogoku.
I'm a humble young man...
who has the honor
of dating Sonoko-san.
Oho, oho, oho.
Sonoko's boyfriend.
And what business
brings you here?
I heard that you possess the gem...
that this so-called kaito kid
is targeting.
If so, I beg you...
to allow me, Makoto Kyogoku,
a place among your guards.
Denied.
I-I implore you, reconsider.
Hmm. So young.
I take it you can't stomach
the fact that Sonoko...
is so smitten with that scoundrel?
But rest easy.
That's like a case of the measles.
The... measles?
Once I've captured that rogue...
I'll make her forget him
clean and clear.
Ah, advisor!
Alright, out you go, out you go.
(cell phone ringtone)
Ah, Sonoko? Perfect timing...
Hey, by any chance,
has Makoto-san shown up there?
Advisor, please, let's talk...
I'm at Haneda Airport right now...
but while I was doing his check-in,
he just disappeared.
Apparently he asked our driver
for your address, Uncle...
so I thought maybe
he'd gone over to your place.
What sort of man is he?
I hear he's a karateka.
He's no ordinary karateka.
Four hundred matches in the world championships, undefeated.
The unbeatable prince of kicks,
who has no equal anywhere.
F-four hundred matches, undefeated?
Huh? Keep security out
of the gem's exhibition room?
Why on earth? Kaito Kid
is coming to steal it!
Because it'd interfere with the latest
security system, apparently.
Advisor Suzuki called me
about it just a moment ago.
What's that old man
thinking this time?
And this is the footage
he sent over after the call.
Eh... footage?
Ungh...
A single man,
surrounded by guys aiming pistols at him.
The rounds are BBs, of course,
but at this range and with these numbers...
and the man in the center...
is wearing a gas mask
that blocks his vision.
You'd think there's no way
he could dodge it all, right?
Come at me like you mean
to take me down, all at once, please.
(gunfire)
Whaaat?
His name is Makoto Kyogoku.
According to the advisor...
he's the world's strongest
security system.
Th-the world's strongest?
Come on, you know her, don't you?
The advisor's niece,
young miss Sonoko.
Heh, this is her boyfriend, it seems.
Her... boyfriend?
Hmph. Well now,
isn't this interesting.
(heavy breathing)
Oh my.
Ah...
Don't tell me you intend
to stay the night here in the museum?
Yes.
I'd like to commit the dimensions
of this room to memory.
I have a sleeping bag, too...
and I've brought along
a bit of food as well.
Tell me, young man.
Would you care to make
a wager with me?
A... wager?
Huh?
Kyogoku-san and Kaito Kid
are going to face off?
Really?
That's right.
Apparently Makoto-san pleaded
his case directly to Uncle Jirokichi.
Seems my "Kid-sama" remark
really lit a fire under him.
Two handsome guys, throwing sparks
over little old me...
it's just the best.
"Over you," she says.
It's not like Kid has
any interest in Sonoko.
So?
Which one do you want to win?
Kid or Kyogoku-san?
Well, of course I want
Makoto-san to win, but...
I don't really want
Kid-sama to lose, either.
Huh? What's that supposed to mean?
Make up your mind.
I mean, Makoto-san
is my precious darling, and...
(static)
I mean, Makoto-san
is my precious darling, and...
Hey, Sonoko?
The call's...
Hello? Ran? Ran!
(call disconnects)
Ah...
No way, I've got no signal.
A signal-jamming device.
Ah...
Good evening, young miss.
K-Kaito Kid!
H-how did you get in here?
Oh, I just grew weary of flying
and stopped by to rest my wings.
And while I'm here,
if I may...
would you make a wager with me?
A... a wager?
Kaito Kid came last night?
To your room, Sonoko?
That's right.
He was just standing at the window,
like Peter Pan or something.
Our guards spotted him,
so he beat it right away, though.
Didn't you hear about it?
Of course I didn't.
So? What did Kid come for?
Heh, hehehe.
Well, he asked me
to make a wager with him.
As his reward for getting the gem,
he said he'd like to claim my lips.
That's a lie.
So? What did he really say?
Huh?
Ah... well, the truth is...
the alexandrite Uncle Jirokichi
is putting on public display...
this time, the Green Emperor...
if he manages to get
his hands on it successfully...
he wants me to tell Uncle...
that he'll trade the stolen gem
for a single item...
that he gets to choose,
from the Suzuki Group's art collection.
What is it, this one item?
Who knows? He said he'd tell us
after he stole the gem.
So? What did you tell him?
I yelled right back at him,
of course.
Told him I wouldn't accept
a single condition...
from a villain like him.
Really?
Well, I put it
a little more softly than that.
Strange. What Kaito Kid targets...
should only ever be the huge gems
called "Big Jewels."
If the Suzuki Group really
had a gem like that...
that advisor would've used it as bait
to lure Kid out ages ago.
Besides, why tell something
that important to someone like Sonoko?
Oh, so what about Kyogoku-san,
the one protecting the gem?
Ah, Makoto-san...
he's with the gem right now, too.
R-right now? But that gem went
on public display starting today, right?
Yes, at the Suzuki Grand Museum,
where we're headed now.
Don't tell me he's standing next to
the display case with a scary look on his face?
Well, you'll see when we get there.
(visitors murmuring)
Huh? Why is he holding up
the gem like that...
looking so bored?
It's weird, isn't it?
It's fine, it's fine.
See?
Y-yeah, sure enough...
Just like she said.
Well done, Sonoko.
Huh?
To choose such a formidable warrior
for your suitor...
that's my niece for you.
Uncle Jirokichi.
But Kid's predicted time is 10 p.m.,
after the visitors have left.
There's no need to have him do that
this early...
It's his own earnest request.
Huh?
He wants to prevent any scheme...
where Kid makes it look like
he stole it at the appointed time...
when in fact it had already
been swapped for a fake.
But even if he's a karate master,
he's still a high schooler, isn't he?
Leaving him alone
to guard the gem...
Haven't you seen it?
Huh?
The eleven men
I sent to the Metropolitan Police...
he mowed them all down with
lightning-fast, gale-force technique.
That astonishing footage.
But what if Kid pulls his trademark blackout
and plunges the place into darkness?
No need to worry.
He's the prince of kicks,
gifted with the mind's eye.
If it goes dark, it's that scoundrel
who'll be in trouble.
What's more...
Hm?
I have a secret plan
of my own as well.
A-a secret plan?
Kid's specialty is his disguise art,
impersonating someone close to us...
to slip right up to the gem.
Yes, just as he once
disguised himself as my husband.
I just fell for a fake phone call...
that was all...
Hmph.
Both the advisor and Inspector Nakamori
have had that experience as well, haven't you?
Ah, that's why I keep doing this...
pinching my cheek now and then.
That may do just fine
for you gentlemen...
Ow, ow, ow!
but doing something so crude
to a lady is hard to bring oneself to do.
So what I've prepared instead...
special-ordered from a Paris designer
and just delivered...
is this dress, the only one
of its kind in the world.
Oooh!
B-but if Kid knocks you out
and strips a dress like that off you...
That's only when it's a gentleman.
As far as I know, Kid has never once
stripped a woman of her clothes...
to impersonate her.
In other words,
as long as I'm wearing this dress...
it's plain at a glance
that I'm the real me.
I... I see.
Guess Sera doesn't count.
Of course, I've prepared dresses
for Sonoko and her friends as well.
Huh? M-me too?
I only stopped by
on my way home from school.
Do change into it later, won't you.
After we've pinched
each other's cheeks, of course.
Yes.
And also...
Ugh.
Well, I'm sure the advisor wouldn't want
to send this Kid-killer boy...
home either, would he?
Heehee.
Oh, that's right.
When I checked the mailbox this morning,
there was a letter from Kid-sama inside.
Huh?
What?
It's addressed to Makoto-san.
Huh?
What in the world does it say?
Ah...
It's... blank.
Huh?
Don't tell me he means he's calling off
this whole heist notice?
That rogue, has he taken fright
at a karate master?
I don't think it's blank.
Hm?
Isn't this invisible ink?
(sniffing)
It's got a fruity smell to it.
Ah...
Invisible ink?
F-for now,
with my lighter...
Ah, there's some writing!
"Now then, let's have a fair contest.
Kaito Kid."
Whaat? That's all?
Yes. Nothing on the back, either.
Heh, heh.
It's probably some foolish taunt...
along the lines of...
"draw me out if you can."
Now, Sonoko, Ran-chan,
let's go get changed.
Ah... yes.
Ah, um, before that...
Huh?
Ohh!
Whaat?
Ah...
Oooh!
Ah, only once we're grown-ups.
Good luck, Makoto-san.
Ah... yes.
I...
I believe in you.
Yes. I'll protect it to the end.
I stake it on this fist.
Come on, Sonoko.
Yeah.
I believe in you as well.
That you'll keep
that promise of ours.
Yes.
Of course.
♪~
~♪
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Wh-what is all this?
Come on then, any time, Kaito Kid.
Today's the day I'll show you
what's what.
Hey, let me see that letter.
I won't take it out of the bag.
H-hey, you...
Ha.
Next Conan,
"Thief Kid vs. Makoto Kyogoku (Part 2)".
Next Conan's Hint:
"Candle".
Sonoko, whose side are you on?
K-K-Ki...
The ultimate choice, huh.