On our way home from school, we ran into
Yumi Miyamoto and Naeko Miike in their mini-patrol car.
Just then, Naeko received a call about an incident.
When we rushed to the scene,
there was a body hanging from a chandelier.
There was what looked like a suicide note at her feet,
so we thought it was a suicide, but...
I see. Hmm?
So that's what you meant by "the one move you prepared"?
"The one move you prepared."
That's... if I remember correctly...
♪~♪
The blackness of shadows, the density of darkness—
the light of reasoning cuts right through them.
The suspect is Yumi Miyamoto's ex-boyfriend?
A single move of deduction at the clogged scene.
See through the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~♪
"The Neighbor at the Site is an Ex-Boyfriend (Part 2)"
(Door opens) Chief Megure!
Hmm?
We have an eyewitness account of a suspicious person.
What? Hmm?
According to the concierge in the first floor lobby,
a suspicious person with their face hidden by a hat, mask, and glasses
entered and left the condo.
Wow! Chi... Chiba-kun.
When was that?
Apparently it was after the master and housekeeper left.
Why didn't the concierge stop him?
He used a key to enter normally, so he was thought to be a resident.
Also, he said the son came by too.
The son?
Hmm? Yes.
He said it was before the master and housekeeper returned,
but
whether the suspicious person left before or after that,
he couldn't remember.
Huh? Huh?
Could you be... (Heartbeat)
Sakurako-chan? One year below me? Huh?
Ah, Chiba-chi. Long time no see.
What, so the housekeeper is Sakurako-chan?
Why won't you remember me?
Ah, come to think of it, you might not remember,
but I was often with you... (Doorbell)
Chiba-kun, go check that.
Ah, yes.
Hey, what's with this kid?
Let go... Huh?
Like I'd let go! You... ugh...
Wh... what are you kids doing?
What do you mean? We caught a suspicious guy!
It's not like I'm suspicious or anything...
You were peeking inside through the peephole, weren't you?
I was just joking around.
I thought it'd be funny if someone peeked back and got scared.
Besides, even if you peek from outside, you can't see inside.
But your hair is weird too.
Ugh... th-this is...
I just let my dyed hair grow out and it ended up like this.
That's what you say, but
you actually came back because you were worried, didn't you?
They say the culprit returns to the scene.
C-culprit? What are you talking about?
Hey, is it true you were peeking?
Ah... yes. This man rang the doorbell suddenly, and then
That voice... Yasue?
Ah, Dad. Hmm?
...So this guy is the son.
What's wrong?
Weren't you at driving school?
I skipped. I wanted to show you the car catalog as soon as possible.
Car, nothing. Worry about that after you find a job.
What's your problem? You agreed to me getting a license.
With that pudding-head of yours, there's no way you'll pass.
Hey, Dad, why are you so irritated?
There are cops here. Did something happen?
Ah, well...
Huh? Mom committed suicide?
No way... why?
The possibility that she was murdered still remains.
M-murdered?
Come to think of it, I heard you came here once today.
Ah... yes. To show him this catalog.
But when I rang the doorbell, no one answered,
so I thought they went out shopping,
wandered around for a while, and came back.
I see. Can anyone prove that?
H-hey, Inspector.
You're not suspecting me, are you?
(Cell phone vibrates) Huh?
Someone's phone is ringing.
Huh? (Cell phone vibrates)
Ah, sorry. That was my phone.
...Geez.
So all three of you have the same phone?
Ah, yeah. This model is popular.
The covers are different colors, so we don't mix them up.
Hmm.
Speaking of phones, before you found the wife's phone,
you heard the bedroom door close,
didn't you, Sakurako-san?
Uh... yes.
How did you know that sound came from the bedroom?
You can't see it from the entrance.
All the other doors were slightly open.
I thought they were closed before we went shopping.
Then was the bedroom window slightly open too?
Huh? How do you know that?
Were you with her the whole time during shopping?
No, I was in the smoking area until the shopping was done...
Then the master has no alibi either.
Haneda-san, were you at home the whole time?
No, I went out.
Right after I got back, the police officer rang the doorbell.
Where did you go and what did you do?
Well...
Come on, just say it already.
I can't say that.
Huh? Hmm?
Whoa...
What are you saying, Chuukichi?
You're being suspected of murder, you know.
Come on, say it. Otherwise you'll be treated like the culprit.
It's okay, Yumi-tan.
This case has already
been solved.
Listen up, you guys.
It's definitely somewhere in this neighborhood.
When you find it, show the photo I emailed you
to someone nearby to confirm.
Okay. Got it.
Yeah! Yeah, yeah.
Chief Megure, the handwriting analysis results are in.
Oh, is that so?
The handwriting is quite distorted,
but there's no doubt that the note was written by Itami Chiyoko-san herself.
What?
So there's no chance she was forced to write it by the culprit?
No. With it that distorted,
the culprit would have made her rewrite it.
Ah, also, the supermarket's security camera
showed the housekeeper frequently,
so her alibi is confirmed.
The master, Naginobu-san, who went shopping with her,
didn't appear on camera.
That's because I was in the smoking area...
So the suspects are the master,
the son Yasue-san, and me.
The son came once, rang the doorbell, got no answer,
killed some time, then came back.
I was out at the time of the crime,
but I won't say where I went.
Won't say? You're one to talk.
Th-that's why I said I'll tell you where I went later.
What, you can't say it in front of me?
It's a woman. You were meeting some woman, weren't you?
That's not true.
I told you, you're the only one for me, Yumi-tan.
How troublesome.
Inspector, just say this guy is the culprit and cuff him already.
B-but, Yumi-kun.
Ah... there are some unclear points, but
when the master and housekeeper
returned from shopping and entered the front door,
they heard the bedroom door close,
and inside the bedroom, the wife had hanged herself.
And if the note at her feet was written by the wife herself,
then it can only be a suicide...
"The one move you prepared." Hmm?
That's what that note was all about, right?
Haneda-san. Huh?
Come to think of it, Chuukichi, you said something like that.
What was that? What did you mean?
W-well... did I say that?
It's when you anticipate a certain situation
and then, when that situation arrives, you make a brilliant move.
I read online that it's called "the one move you prepared."
It's apparently a shogi term.
Shogi term? Why would Chuukichi know something like that?
More importantly, why is that note "the one move you prepared"?
Didn't you think the contents of that note were strange?
Let's see, it said...
"I'm sorry for injuring you. I pray for your speedy recovery."
"Yasue-san, do your best on your exam. I know you'll pass."
"For Ichiko-chan's Shichi-Go-San, please dress her in my furisode."
"Please forgive me for leaving you so suddenly. Itami Chiyoko."
What about this is...
The part about the exam.
Hmm?
The exam Yasue-san is taking is the written test for a driver's license.
It's not the kind of exam you need to pray so hard for.
M-my wife was a worrier.
In fact, she was quite worried about our son, who hasn't found a job
even though he's graduating from university.
Yes. Yasue-san is currently a university senior.
If that note was written four years ago
to her son who was preparing for his university entrance exams,
wouldn't that make sense?
Th-that's true, but four years ago...
Four years ago,
her niece Ichiko, who is now seven, would have been three,
so Shichi-Go-San. Yes.
I saw that photo recently. The lady showed it to me.
Pointing to a little girl in a furisode, she said,
"You can't tell this kimono is 40 years old, can you?"
Then that note really was from four years ago...
That's ridiculous. You saw this bruise on my eye, didn't you?
It's from an ashtray my wife threw last night.
If that injury is mentioned in the note...
Speaking of injuries,
I believe you also said you broke your leg before.
Ah... yes.
Mom was a beginner skier and crashed into Dad.
Because of that, she had to fly alone
to the annual New Year's party in the countryside,
and she often told me how she nearly lost her life.
So that was also four years ago.
If that plane nearly crashed,
it wouldn't be strange for her to write a suicide note on board,
addressed to her family.
I see. That's why the handwriting was shaky.
Because she wrote it on a plane that was shaking.
I see. And the reason she wrote her full name
was to make it clear whose note it was when found at the crash site.
If the culprit got hold of that note
and used it in this murder four years later,
then it would truly be "the one move he prepared."
But when the master and housekeeper returned,
the bedroom door closing is still a mystery.
Ah. M-maybe
the culprit was still hiding in the bedroom at that time?
I don't think that's possible.
When we returned, I locked the front door.
And when Conan-kun first came, the lock was still on.
So why did the door...
It wouldn't close by itself.
Ah.
Hey, who's that? So rough.
Could it be Chiba-kun? Huh?
Hey, Conan-kun.
Did you just close this door, Conan-kun?
What do you mean? I opened the front door
to check if my friends had come back.
But I did open the bedroom window a little.
The heating was too strong, and it was hot.
The window was slightly open when we found the lady too.
Is that true?
Ah, yes.
The master said it would be sad for her to be cold,
so he closed it immediately.
That's it. Huh?
When the front door was opened,
the warm air inside rushed out the window,
and the bedroom door closed.
So the culprit left the bedroom window and door open
so that would happen.
But if that was the case, when the culprit tried to escape
and opened the front door, it would have closed then too.
That's true...
Come to think of it, the wife's phone
was on the floor in front of the bedroom door.
Ah, yes. Then what if
you wedged the phone in the door gap to keep it open?
Like this.
But then it would just stay open.
I guess it's impossible.
If the phone had legs and could move like a living thing,
then maybe...
Th-that's right! The phone's vibration.
The culprit wedged the phone in the door, left the room,
called the phone from outside,
and the vibration made it fall and dislodge.
But the wife's phone found on the floor
had no call history.
Maybe that's not the wife's phone.
Huh? Hmm?
Because all three of them
have the same phone, just with different colored covers.
It wouldn't be strange if someone took the wife's phone by mistake,
thinking it was their own.
I see. If you remove the wife's phone cover
and put it on your own phone, you can pretend it's the wife's.
Use that phone in the trick,
then put the cover back before handing it over to the police,
and it would seem the wife's phone wasn't used in the crime.
And the only person who could have done that
is the one who had the wife's phone until handing it over to us—
the master, Naginobu-san. It can only be you.
What you likely did was:
You went home while the housekeeper was shopping,
strangled your wife, hung her from the ceiling,
placed the four-year-old suicide note at her feet, opened the bedroom window,
wedged the phone in the door, and left.
Then you called that phone from outside,
the vibration dislodged the phone from the door,
you met up with the housekeeper and returned home again,
and made it look like your wife had committed suicide.
The reason you didn't go into the bedroom immediately after returning
was to hide the fact that
some time had passed since the body was hung.
Then the suspicious person the concierge saw...
was you.
You probably had a change of clothes ready in the supermarket bathroom.
Well, we'll know once we check your phone.
C-come to think of it, while I was in the supermarket smoking area, I got a call...
From who? Ah, th-that was...
it seemed to be a wrong number.
(Cell phone vibrates) Hmm...
We found a public phone!
It's in front of the convenience store nearby.
When we showed the store manager a photo of the master,
he testified that he was "sneakily using the phone."
Well, not many people use public phones these days,
so there might still be fingerprints.
So there.
Ah... ah...
B-but is it true, Dad?
Did Dad really kill Mom?
I thought my luck had finally turned around.
Huh?
To be honest, I was hesitant about carrying out this murder plan.
Until last night.
Hey, Chiyoko.
I told you to quit stocks.
But you know, even though you said no,
don't you want to buy a car for Yasue?
What are you saying? Our debt is already huge.
I've figured it out!
God only smiles on us when we're in a pinch.
That's why I mortgaged this condo and borrowed money.
Huh?
After that, we had a huge fight.
When the ashtray Chiyoko threw hit my eye, I felt a shock run through me.
Now, with things as they are,
the murder plan I thought of
when I found that suicide note before... I can carry it out.
I felt that God was on my side.
Hey, how did you know who the culprit was?
I suspected it from the note,
but I became certain when I heard the father and son talking
at the front door.
"With that pudding-head of yours, there's no way you'll pass."
The only way he could know what was under the hat of his son,
who he hadn't seen in over a year,
was if he saw his son ringing the doorbell
through the peephole while his wife was hanging.
But if the son was wearing his hat, he wouldn't have seen.
Hmph.
The son has a hobby of peeking back through the peephole.
Huh?
Hmph.
If you're wearing a cap with a brim,
you can't look through unless you take it off, right?
♪~♪
Still, he was quite a sharp guy, wasn't he?
He's Yumi-san's ex-boyfriend, right?
From what I heard before,
I imagined someone more host-like.
Well, it's fine. He's sharp,
and he seemed to help solve the case.
Yeah, I got a bit excited too, solving a case with a celebrity.
Celebrity? Huh?
Was there an actor named Shukichi Haneda?
Look, this guy.
Congratulations on winning the Meijin title and four crowns.
Ah!
It's the Meijin, Taiko!
Ayumi's mom is a big fan too.
But what does the Meijin have to do with him?
Look closely.
Hmm? Hmm...
"I guess the sideways rook worked out well today..."
Hmm...
Ah!
That cowlick!
That's that guy!
I see.
The kanji in his name resembles that of Hideyoshi Hashiba,
so that's why he's called Taiko.
Ah, actually, he went to the shogi hall for a qualifying match that day,
but he didn't want Yumi to find out
that he's a shogi player yet.
Why not? Being a Meijin is awesome!
So then, what were the seven things he was collecting?
Well, when it comes to seven in shogi...
Huh?
(Flashback) Haah, haah...
Yumi-tan, I did it!
I finally got the Meijin title I've been longing for!
Yumi-tan!
Ah... you're late, Chuukichi.
Ah, sorry, sorry. The match ran longer than I expected.
Huh? Were you playing a game?
Ah... well, you could call it a game, but...
Actually, today I...
More importantly, look at this news.
Ah... news?
Yokozuna Tenho won the summer tournament,
winning all six tournaments in a row.
That's amazing. Winning for an entire year straight.
If a prince-like man like that were my husband,
I'd feel like a queen.
Heh heh. Don't worry.
I don't expect anything like that from you, Chuukichi.
Kioh, Osho, Oza, Kisei,
Oi, Ryuoh, Meijin.
Seven crowns!
Huh? Chuukichi is a Meijin?
Y-yes, that's right. Actually...
It's probably fishing champion or a game champion or something.
That sounds like him.
Ah, um...
(Bell tolls)
The groom has collapsed!
Ah...
So these two murder cases appear to be the work of the same culprit.
I see. If we use that...
Next Conan,
"The Wedding Reception and Two Gunshots."
Next Conan's Hint:
"Bamboo Forest."