Hahahaha...
Fufufufu... Fuhahaha...
Fuhahaha... As expected of the great detective.
To have seen through
this Kaito K's hideout...
How impressive.
So you've finally shown yourself,
Kaito K.
Master, it's dangerous.
Please come down.
Silence, Sada.
I am not the master... I am Kaito K.
Master...
Umm...
We were invited to dinner
by that person, right?
What's going on?
You didn't know?
My old man is an obsessive detective fan.
And among them all...
Mouri-san is his absolute favorite.
Oh really...
Now that you mention it, there was a statue
of the old man earlier.
So cool...
So sometimes he challenges him to a match
like that.
Pretending to be Kaito K himself.
Get down here,
you bastard!
Haha... What a peculiar hobby.
Honestly...
Oh!
Men really are
such foolish creatures, aren't they?
The time limit is 30 minutes.
Try to catch me, everyone.
If you manage to catch me
before that grand clock strikes six...
I shall present you with a marvelous prize.
Well then, I wish you luck.
Fuh... Hahahaha...
♪~
The darkness of shadows and the depth of night...
The light of deduction cuts right through.
A vast estate filled with tricks...
The shocking reason Kogoro was targeted.
Seeing through the one and only truth...
A child's appearance, an adult's mind...
His name is Detective Conan!
~♪
"The Secret of the Kogoro Mouri Statue"
Still... this garden is incredible as always.
It really is like there's a whole town
inside the garden.
We actually call it the "Town" rather than a garden.
Haha... So it's perfect for a game of tag, huh?
Got him... That should be a dead end.
Huh? Ah!
Ah!
Kataoka-san disappeared?
No way... Huh?
Hmm...
Huh?
This is...
Hmph.
Oh... Did you figure something out, Conan-kun?
Don't you think it's weird? This clock...
It's hung way too low, for one...
And both the hour and minute hands
pointing at six at the same time...
That's strange, right?
Now that you mention it...
Ah... Could it be...
Ah... Yeah.
(electronic sound)
Whoa, whoa whoa...
That's right. This is the entrance to the underground passage.
Ouch...
Whoa! Kaito K!
Fufufu... Hahahaha...
Wait... Whoa!
Ah! Sorry, Dad!
I'll circle around to the exit.
We'll catch him in a pincer attack.
Right.
Ah... This is...
The footprints in the mud are still fresh.
No doubt, he went this way.
Yeah.
Ran-neechan, over there.
Found him.
Whoa!
Master, prepare yourself.
Whoa...
Whoa!
Ahh!
My apologies... How clumsy of me...
Then hurry up and get off!
P-Please excuse me.
Huh? If we go this way...
Yes, it leads to the front
of the main house, the starting point.
It seems he's heading for the back garden.
You two, go around from that side.
This time we'll really trap him.
Understood.
Dammit... This mansion is way too huge.
He went that way! Catch him!
Ah!
Whoa!
Huh?
Conan-kun, let's go!
Right...
Hmph.
(cat meows)
Look out!
(brakes screech)
Using a bicycle... Isn't that cheating?
Well, yeah.
This is just like a maze.
At this rate, we'll have no idea where he went...
(collision sound)
Ahh!
This way!
Ah!
Ouch...
Are you alright?
Yes... We just ran into each other...
I was startled and simply tripped.
What about Kataoka-san?
Most likely headed toward the main house.
Seven minutes left.
Uwaah!
(falling sound)
Yurie-san.
Did you hear that? That voice just now...
Yes... What happened?
I just got here myself, so...
Don't tell me something's happened to the master...
Master!
Ran-neechan, what about over there?
No, nobody here either.
Dammit... Where on earth is he?
What's wrong?
Ah...
I heard a pretty loud voice.
Seiya-san, where were you all this time...
Where? I was in my room listening to music...
Ahh! Master!
Huh?
Sada? It came from the back garden...
Ah!
Master, please... Hold on...
Master!
What happened? Did something happen?
W-Well...
Move.
Whoa!
It's no use... He's dead.
The deceased is the master of this house...
Financier Kataoka Eisuke-san, 54 years old.
He suffered severe impact to the back of his body.
In particular, the damage to the back of the head is extensive...
And that appears to be the fatal injury.
The time of death is without a doubt 5:55 PM.
Everyone present here, at that moment...
Heard Kataoka-san's scream
and the sound of a ladder falling.
I hear Kataoka-san was in the middle of a game
with you all.
Yeah, we were playing tag.
We were "it."
Good grief... At his age,
what was he doing?
Well...
Ah...
So it really was an accident?
Hmm... Well, on the ladder...
Kataoka-san's shoe prints were found, after all.
Most likely, Kataoka-san was climbing the ladder...
He lost his balance and fell.
I believe it's safe to assume that.
The bruise on the victim's cheek...
Was probably caused when he fell from the ladder as well.
He got what he deserved.
Getting so wrapped up in such childish games
all the time...
Hmm?
She's Kataoka-san's wife.
After his first wife passed away,
he remarried three years ago.
Hmm.
Huh? Yurie-san, you're not wearing
a wedding ring?
It's a bother, so I've just been
leaving it off.
But in that case, that ring mark...
...So, the son from the first wife is him?
Yes. When his mother passed away...
He seemed to resent Kataoka-san,
blaming his reckless father for it.
Well, it's a fitting way for my old man to die.
Huh...
Hey, Seiya-san... What happened to your hand?
Huh? Oh, just... my guitar string, a little earlier.
Huh? Why was this person, back then...
What's wrong?
I heard a pretty loud voice.
Seiya-san, where were you all this time...
Where? I was in my room listening to music...
I have caused everyone
a great deal of trouble...
I am terribly sorry.
But... was it truly an accident?
Huh?
Is there something on your mind,
Mouri-kun?
Whenever Kataoka-san faced me in a match...
He always set up some kind of trick.
But this time, he just ran and ran.
Aren't you overthinking it?
He's an amateur. Sometimes that's just how it goes.
Yeah... Well, I suppose you might be right.
Then it's settled as an accidental death.
Yes, I suppose so.
No... The old man is right.
For an accident, there are several
strange points.
First, the body wasn't sweating.
Even though he should've been running
right up until he died.
And also... Ah!
Ha... Don't tell me... It was here?
In that case, it must be over there.
It should be somewhere
around here...
As I thought, this one too... Huh?
Whoa!
What do you mean "Whoa"?
Like I'm some kind of monster.
I've been searching for you, shouting my head off.
Huh? Then why, back then...
(piano playing)
Huh?
It's a piece that the late
Kataoka-san was fond of.
Someone in the main house must be playing it.
In his memory.
Old man, try moving this statue.
Huh? It's a bronze statue.
No way it's gonna move.
But don't you think something's
weird about this statue?
Huh?
The mustache that shouldn't be connected...
Your mustache... is connected.
Almost like it's a fake.
Oh!
Oww...
This one?
What? There's nothing here.
(cat meows and clattering sounds)
That sound...
I see...
Huh?
Let me borrow this.
(cat meows and clattering sounds)
I see... So that's what it was.
Oh?
Huh?
What are you doing in a place like this,
Conan-kun?
Ah, Takagi-keiji.
The old man Mouri asked me to do something...
Huh? But Mouri-san is right over there...
Never mind, never mind.
Huh?
Old man, I brought everyone,
just like you asked.
What on earth is this about, Mouri-kun?
I've finally figured it out.
The truth behind this murder
disguised as an accident.
What?!
But the scene's circumstances
can only be seen as an accident.
Why do you believe it's murder?
The bruise.
The bruise... You mean the one
on the victim's cheek?
That was likely caused when he fell
from the ladder.
I thought so too, at first.
But this statue
told me otherwise.
Take a close look...
The nose is chipped, isn't it?
It certainly is... but...
It's a very fresh wound.
As if something struck it
with great force just moments ago.
No way...
Yes. If you examine the marks,
they should match.
The bruise on the victim's cheek...
Was caused by colliding
with that nose.
However, the body was found...
Yes. If Kataoka-san had truly
fallen from the ladder...
There's no way he could have struck this statue
so far away.
That's right... Kataoka-san did not
fall from that ladder.
First, he was struck by the culprit here
and knocked unconscious...
Then he was carried
to the spot where he was found...
And murdered by having the back of his head
and his entire body slammed against the stone pavement.
After that, the culprit transferred
Kataoka-san's shoe prints onto the ladder...
Placed that ladder
next to the body...
And made it look as if Kataoka-san
had fallen from it.
Who would do such a thing...
Before that, there's something
I want to confirm.
Takagi-keiji.
Regarding Kataoka-san's cape...
Wasn't the edge torn?
It was not torn.
Don't you find that odd, Ran?
Huh? Ah, that's right...
Hmm? What do you mean?
Kataoka-san's cape
should be torn.
Look out!
(brakes screech)
But the cape on the body
was not torn.
But then why...
The answer is simple.
Because the person you were chasing
was not Kataoka-san.
What?!
Of course, the Kaito K
we were initially chasing...
Was Kataoka-san.
But partway through,
he was swapped.
Kataoka-san was replaced by the culprit.
Isn't that right, the other Kaito K...
And the one who murdered
Kataoka-san...
Sada Makoto-san.
But Dad... Sada-san was
with us the whole time...
We were chasing Kataoka-san together.
He had no chance to swap...
No, he wasn't with you the whole time.
There was one moment when you were apart.
Right before we came to this back garden.
Ah...
You two, go around from that side.
This time we'll really trap him.
Understood.
Most likely, the original plan
was Kataoka-san's idea.
He had indeed
prepared this swapping trick...
As expected.
But Sada-san's objective
was to use that trick...
To murder Kataoka-san.
After seeing Ran and the others off,
he took a shortcut through the mansion...
He put on the Kaito K costume and mask
he had prepared beforehand...
And attacked the waiting Kataoka-san
from behind, knocking him unconscious...
He hid him behind this statue...
And appeared before Ran and the others
as Kaito K.
So after that, the one we were chasing was...
Not Kataoka-san, but Sada-san.
I checked with the boy earlier...
The bicycle pedals that should have been dirtied
by the Kaito K shoes...
After running through the underground passage...
Were perfectly clean.
And then, with a straight face,
he put on his one-man act...
And Sada-san returned to his original form.
Mouri-san, you're forgetting
something important.
I heard the master's scream
along with Ran-san and the others...
And the sound of the ladder falling.
Would you be referring to this?
Takagi-keiji.
Right.
Hmm?
Uwaah!
(falling sound)
There's no mistake...
It's the same voice and sound from that moment.
It's a stereo recording.
Sada-san had, beforehand...
Recorded Kataoka-san's scream
and the sound of the ladder falling onto a CD.
He set a timer so it would play
at full volume at that exact time.
He had it all set up.
But the truth is, at that moment...
Kataoka-san was still alive.
Right here, behind this statue.
Then... Don't tell me...
While we were inside the mansion...
Searching for Kataoka-san...
Yes. Sada-san came to the back garden...
Killed Kataoka-san...
And in the time before everyone rushed over,
set up the fake scene.
Holding Kataoka-san's body
was also...
To hide the blood spatter
that had gotten on his clothes.
Isn't that right?
Sada-san... Your mistake was...
Turning the stereo volume up too high.
It reached us, far away,
and even reached Seiya-kun...
Who was listening to music with headphones.
Normally, a human voice
would never carry that far.
But... what does any of that prove?
That alone is not evidence.
Indeed. So allow me to show you.
The conclusive proof
that you are the true culprit.
At the crossroads where my statue stands...
After your one-man act...
You must have hidden the disguise items
somewhere around that area.
In fact, there was a hidden compartment
in the statue's pedestal.
But it was empty.
I suppose it was.
Yes. That was merely...
The place to store something
for hiding the disguise items.
At that time, you placed the disguise items
inside the object...
You took out of that hole.
Ah...
(clattering sounds and cat meows)
Don't you think this ball is strange?
(clattering sounds)
It's a little too big,
and more than anything, it makes a strange sound.
Hmm.
Ah... Ahh...
Th-This is...
Marble fragments...
It's faint, but there's blood on them.
And white hairs on the wig...
What is the meaning of this,
Sada-san?
At that moment, you took that ball
from the pedestal's hidden compartment...
Hid the disguise items inside it...
And tossed it into Ran and the others' blind spot.
You probably intended
to retrieve it later.
But there were two miscalculations.
One, a stray cat wandered in...
And made the ball go missing.
The other... was that the marble nose fragment
you suddenly had to hide...
The marble nose fragment
Made an unnatural sound
inside the ball.
No... I'd say my greatest miscalculation...
Was underestimating your powers of deduction, Mouri-san.
You mean...
Yes... I am the one
who took the master's life.
But...
Why?
I could not forgive him.
As if he had forgotten
his late wife entirely...
The master continued his
unrestrained way of life.
I pitied the mistress so deeply...
That's not true.
What?
The only things that man loved were detectives...
And his late wife... only her.
It seems he married me
to heal his grief, but...
In the end, I could never
fill that void.
Although, I only realized that recently.
So that's why you took off
your wedding ring?
It was meant as a small protest.
That man... he never even noticed.
I see...
In that case, the master also,
regarding the mistress...
♪~
~♪
...So, this is the prize
Kataoka-san had prepared?
Hmph... Going and making something like this.
He really was a colossal fool.
I just... genuinely enjoyed
competing against him.
Dad...
...And?
So what do we do with this?
(Matsunosuke chirps)
Hey, don't tell me...
Conan-kun?
Ah!
Kyaa!
So I told you, when I came to get Conan's clothes...
Matsunosuke was sleeping in there!
Ha...
Everyone was mistaken.
The witnesses... and even the culprit.
I see... So that's how it is.
Next Conan,
"Promenade"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Walking the dog"
Hey, let's get a dog.
Dad's more than enough
for a watchdog.
Arf! Woof!
Good boy.
House.