Alibis, secret codes, tricks and deals.
The mysterious organization of men in black.
Today is a 2-hour special program, of many mysterious being solved.
We also get very close to meeting Gin and Vodka.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
I am Shinichi Kudo, a high school detective.
I went to an amusement park with my childhood friend Ran,
when I happened to witness a suspicious dealing
being carried out by a man in black.
Absorbed in watching the event,
I did not realize that another man in black was sneaking up behind me.
I was knocked down, and forced to drink poison.
When I regained consciousness,
I realized that my body had shrunk to that of a child's.
If they find out that Shinichi Kudo is alive,
danger will fall upon the people around me.
Through Dr. Agasa's advice, I decided to hide my true identity.
When Ran asked for my name, I instantly replied...
Conan Edogawa.
In order to gather information on the men in black,
I decide to free-load at Ran's house,
because I find out that her Father is a detective.
"The Mysterious New Student"
"Teitan Elementary School"
Hey, did you hear the news?
A new student's coming to class today.
Really?
We haven't had a new student, since Conan came, have we?
I wonder what kind of person is coming?
I hope she's cute.
No, no, whether it be a girl or boy,
the main thing is personality.
Hey, Conan?
What kind of person do you think will come, Conan?
I wonder.
Maybe a reticent bookworm type?
You think it's going to be a boy, then?
Ayumi, you didn't get to see the student in the teachers' room?
No, but I got the name.
It was Haibara.
Haibara?
Right. Haibara.
An unusual name.
Not as unusual as Conan's thought.
Leave me alone.
Here they come!
Oh, it's a girl!
She's cute...
Sit down, everyone!
Yes...
What's the big deal over a girl.
Hi, everyone, this is Ai Haibara,
who will be studying with us starting today.
Let's all welcome her to our class.
Yes...
How energetic you all are.
Where shall we seat you, Haibara?
Mrs. Kobayashi! Over here, the seat next to me is open!
Here.
-Hi. -Hi.
What's with her? She's so stuck up.
She sure is cool.
She's probably nervous.
All right, everyone. Class time!
Yes...
Haibara.
Haibara!
Let's go home together.
Okay?
Let her be! That stuck up chick.
But...
Where do you live? You moved here, didn't you?
Don't be hesitant, we'll walk you home.
Beika 2-22.
That 's where I live.
What?
What is it?
No, nothing.
Strange, Beika is my address.
But, there are no condos or apartments nearby.
I wonder if there was a residence called Haibara.
What's the matter?
Don't tell me you have eyes for that stuck up chick?
No way. No darn way!
The Youth Detective Squad?
-You're members? -Yeah.
We work day in and day out
solving difficult cases by request of our clients.
Why don't you join us too, Ai?
Is Conan a member, too?
Yeah, he's something like my henchman.
The requests all go into...
The requests are to be put in here.
We haven't told the teachers about it though.
They already know about it.
We get loads of mails from guys who have unsolved mysteries every day.
There's nothing inside.
Theres usually a lot of mails in here, but I guess not today.
You never have mail in there.
Let's hurry home and play soccer at the park.
Let's go, let's go.
Good idea.
Hey, wait for me.
A request!
Really?
It says that they'll be waiting for us in grade 1 class A.
Then, let's go.
To grade 1, class A!
Come with us too, Ai, quick!
What? Disappeared from home?
My brother suddenly disappeared.
Don't tell me he's been kidnapped?
Wait a minute.
There was a similar case once before.
Come to think of it, it really is.
Don't tell me that the brother of yours is a cat?
No! My brother who is 10 years older than me!
He disappeared a week ago at sundown,
saying he was going to drop by at his friend's house.
And he never came back since.
The police set out to search for him too, but couldn't find him.
I thought that maybe you guys could help me.
Have you received any threat calls?
Calls?
Nope, nothing like that.
Maybe he just ran away from home?
He would never run away from home!
Because...
Because me and my brother, we get along really well.
But, your brother may have had his reasons.
Let's go over to his house.
We'll talk later.
Thank you.
Okay. The Youth Detective Squad are on our way.
Let's go, Ai.
It's that house where the police car is parked.
Cool, a police car!
This is a standard police car.
But, it's been modified nicely like a police car.
Is that right? Which one's the radio?
See, it's the one by the passenger's seat.
I wonder if I can ask for eels over rice with that?
I'd like a pizza.
Hey, hey, what did you guys come here for?
All right, if something comes up, please contact the station.
Thank you.
My, Toshiya.
-Are they your friends? -Yes.
Hello...
Come on in.
Toshiya, would you like me to you something?
Oh, please don't bother, because we'll be leaving soon.
Oh, is that right?
I'll be in the kitchen, then.
I'm sorry. My mom's preoccupied about brother right now.
I know. Let's hurry to your brother's room.
All right.
It's so neat and clean.
Are we going to look for clues here?
Exactly.
This is...
This is cool. Take a look at this.
Super premium prices air shoes.
Don't you guys get something wrong?
Don't mess around too much.
-All right. -But now we know that Toshiya's brother
was knowledgeable of famous brand products.
Was your brother that kind of person?
I don't know.
But my uncle gave him those as a gift from the States.
I got one, too.
I see...
-Now we know that he wasn't. -That's right.
Hey, Conan, we're getting nowhere standing here.
See, so maybe he ran away from home after all?
No, that can't be.
See, this is your brother's wallet, isn't it?
Yes.
If he's going to run away from home,
he'd at least take his wallet, wouldn't he?
So then, where is he?
He either got into an accident
or got mixed up in some incident.
Gosh.
What's with these pictures?
There are many strange pictures under the bed.
Talk about the pits.
See.
Who drew this picture?
Picasso.
What?
Yes. That's a copy of Picassos Crying Woman.
Gogh, Monet, Gauguin, Utrillo.
They all look genuine.
My brother drew all of these.
He was in the art club of his high school,
and was good at copying other peoples paintings.
Hey, don't tell me he's been kidnapped
and being forced to draw pictures.
That's possible.
If the masterpieces are copied and exchanged for the real ones.
No, that's not possible either.
What?
His sketches are indeed good,
but he needs a bit more practice as to color and touch.
It's not good enough to be counterfeit yet.
And this is not a kidnapping for ransom either.
Because if it were so, it would be easier to kidnap you
than to kidnap your brother who is in high school.
What bothers me is this painting.
What? I've seen him somewhere before.
It's Soseki Natsume.
Yes. My brother was a great fan of Soseki!
He liked that painting so much
that he even entered it in the community exhibition.
But, everybody was complaining about it
because was a copy of his picture.
Only one weird woman praised it.
A weird woman?
Yes, she was wearing a broad-brimmed hat
and dressed in black from head to toe.
When was that? When did you see that woman?
About 10 days ago.
Were there any men dressed in black besides her?
Yes, there were two.
Don't tell me that...
What's the matter, Conan?
It couldn't be that...
That...
No...
Hey, take me to a place near here that your brother is likely to go.
His wallet and his train pass are in his drawer.
Even his bicycle is at the front door.
It's highly probable
that your brother was called out near here and kidnapped.
I see. So if we search the vicinity...
Maybe we'll find some clue.
Come on, hurry.
Hey, wait, Conan.
Conan!
A week ago at sundown?
I wonder...
I don't think she came
because I was at the shop all the time.
But, I don't remember seeing a woman dressed in black,
although I'm sure she'll stand out.
Darn. We've gone to all the places he may be called out to,
like coffee shop, game centers, department stores and back alleys.
There is nobody who saw him that day,
nor did anyone see the woman in black.
What am I getting all worked up for?
I'm sure the police already checked all the places he could be...
We have too little to go on.
Isn't there anything? Anything else...
Something will do.
Conan, would you mind if I stop by at the convenience store?
I'm thirsty.
It's so cool.
Thank you very much.
Hello, there.
It'll be 430 yen, please.
Thank you very much.
A Seven Mild.
Your change is 770 yen.
Thank you very much.
What's the matter, Conan?
He bought only one pack of the cigarette with a thousand-yen bill.
Strange.
Maybe he didn't have loose change?
If he had a thousand yen,
he could've bought it at the vending machine outside.
He didn't have to go through the trouble
of waiting at the check-out counter.
Maybe the cigarette he wanted was sold out.
Will you show me the thousand-yen bill that the man just gave you?
-What? -Just let me see it!
Hey!
There's no watermark.
Maybe he's...
What's with you anyway?
Conan? What's wrong?
Call the police. This is counterfeit.
What?
Hey, wait, sonny?
Wait, Conan!
Wait up!
Hey.
Conan, what's the matter?
What is it about the counterfeit
that you were talking about at the convenience store?
That man bought a cigarette with a thousand-yen, right?
He did so, although there was a vending machine right outside the store
and went out of his way to line up at the counter.
In other words, he used a thousand yen that the machine wouldn't accept.
A counterfeit that the human eyes are likely to overlook.
But that has nothing to do with brother disappearing, does it?
It has everything to do with him.
Do you remember
the portrait of a certain person that your brother had drawn?
Soseki Natsume.
Come to think of it,
the thousand-yen bill has the face of Soseki Natsume on it.
Then, is my brother...
Yes, maybe somebody saw through his talent for art,
and has him confined some place, forcing him to make counterfeit.
We can't be sure if that man is involved or not,
but maybe they're the guys who shrunk my body.
Those men in black.
Shrunk your body?
I'm only joking! Joking.
I was just teasing you guys.
What a fix.
I can't get them involved in such a dangerous case either.
I'll lose sight of the man if I don't hurry.
All right, then.
I'll use this, then.
Conan!
Hey, you over there!
You dropped something!
This is your thousand yen, isn't it?
Conan!
See. He dropped his money.
So, I came after him to give it back to him.
Oh...
It's no fun.
But what're you going to do about looking his brother?
It's getting late.
We've no choice but to come back and continue tomorrow.
You guys go on ahead to Toshiya's house and pick up your satchels.
I've got to stop by some place first.
What? Come back right away, okay?
Okay, see you.
Okay, then. I caught him.
That man took the thousand-yen with the transmitter on it.
All I have to do now is pursue him with these glasses.
Ai, hurry or we'll leave you behind.
He just may take me to where they... the men in black are.
The station.
A stand? No.
Yeah. That man wearing a black hat came here.
He bought a can of 110 yen coffee with a thousand-yen.
Gosh, just as I thought.
He wasn't friendly,
and besides there was a strange seal stuck on the bill.
He was a weirdo.
And do you know which way he went?
I'm not sure.
After he bought the can of coffee,
he was using the phone over there.
What?
He placed loose change on the phone,
and was talking on the phone until he used it all up.
For around 10 minutes.
Did he by any chance ask you to give him
the change in 100 yens and 10 yens?
Yes. But since I didn't have 100 yens,
I mixed 500 yen and gave him 890 yen.
The change that he got at the convenience store is 770 yen.
One 500-yen coin and two 100-yen coins,
one 50-yen coin and two 10-yen coins.
If the 890 yen change that he received at the stand is added,
the money that he can use to make the phone call
would be five 100-yen coins and eleven 10-yen coins.
That is, 610 yen all together.
If he had more loose change on him, it be more than that.
He used more than 610 yen for a call approximately 10 minutes long?
Was he making a long-distance call?
Could it be he went somewhere far away to the place
where his telephone partner is waiting?
No, if he calls from a public phone to a cellular phone,
it would cost 10 yen per 9 seconds.
There is still that possibility.
Hey, sonny.
Are you an acquaintance of the man wearing the black hat?
Yes, sort of.
Oh, great. Please give this to him.
What? 50-yen?
He was in such a rush that he forgot to take this 50-yen change
from the ticket vending machine.
Which ticket vending machine was it?
The one for the Tohto Line, over there.
Do you know which button he pressed?
I don't know.
He put in one 500-yen coin, and I saw a lot of loose change came out.
He put in one 500-yen coin, and I saw a lot loose change came out.
But I was more concerned about the rubbish at his feet
that I didn't notice anything else.
Thank you. I'll go after him.
-Bye. -Yes.
He probably got more than three coins as change.
If he inserted 500-yen,
and got chance that included a 50-yen coin and three more...
The station would be 500-yen minus 320 yen,
the answer is one 100-yen coin, one 50-yen coin,
and three 10-yen coins, making a total of 5 coins.
A change of 180 yen would come out.
It's Daitohma Station.
Daitohma! Daitohma!
No good. I've come to Daitohma Station,
but nobody has seen the man with the black hat.
What now? Their purpose is to make counterfeit bills.
Maybe I should start off by asking at a real estate agency.
-A warehouse? -Yes.
Haven't you rented out a warehouse that is inconspicuous,
in the suburbs and won't be suspected
no matter what is done there to anyone?
No. We haven't rented any warehouse out recently.
It could've been many years in the past.
Gosh. You're getting in the way of business.
Take your friends and go home.
Friends?
They're your friends, aren't they, sonny?
What?
You guys?
Do you think you can fool us every time with the same trick?
You really have a talent of running out on us, don't you?
How did you know I was here?
We came after you because Ai told us to.
She said that you were going to leave us behind
and pursue the man by yourself.
Right?
Mister.
-What is it? -Isn't there a novelist who lives near here?
A novelist? What do you mean?
After my brother disappeared, he called us once at home.
-What? -Why didn't you tell us sooner?
It's my grandmother who took the call.
She's hard of hearing and besides my brother talked so fast,
that she couldn't understand what he said.
All she could make out was,
his words, "I'm with a lot of people like Soseki".
He's with people like Soseki?
Soseki.
Did you tell the police about this?
Of course.
But they couldn't find anybody like that
no matter how hard they searched.
So, they said that maybe grandma made a mistake,
or that it was a crank call.
But, wasn't your brother a fan of Soseki?
If so, there's nothing to worry about, is there?
But grandma said my brother's voice was trembling
and cut off halfway.
I see. He somehow made the call while they weren't around,
but was caught after all and forced to hang up.
Come to think of it, a man who looks like Soseki does live near here.
What?
He's the owner of the bookstore on the corner.
His nickname is One-thousand-yen.
That's it...
Please...
-What? What do you mean? -Take us there...
No. I'd advise you not to go to his place.
What?
You've got to be kidding! Counterfeit my foot!
Stop playing jokes on adults.
Get out of here!
A thousand-yen, they said. I'm not that cheap.
Why isn't Soseki Natsume on the 10,000-yen bill.
He scared me.
That's why I told you not to come.
What's with that man, anyway?
He sure smells fishy.
No, he probably has nothing to do with the incident.
I checked the warehouse of the bookstore,
but there was no printer for printing out counterfeit bills.
Talking about printers,
the newspaper agency in front of the station was installing one.
A newspaper agency?
See, the building next to the police box. The agency is on the 3rd floor.
We handled that building 2 years ago, too.
What were the people in there like?
A lady who is always wearing a broad-brimmed hat
is the president of that small agency.
What?
But, they're printing out information magazines on this town,
not counterfeit bills.
They couldn't possibly do something like that here.
After all, it's right beside the police box.
So, that's the story.
I don't know what this is about, but it's already nighttime.
Quit playing detective already and head on home, you guys!
Could that newspaper agency be...
But, it doesn't have anything to do with Soseki, does it?
Rinse one's mouth with stone
and sleep with one's pillow in the water.
This is a famous ancient event that Soseki took his name from.
It means eccentric.
Normally we rinse our mouths with running water
and use stones for pillows, right?
But, to use it reversely, you'd have to be quite eccentric.
To make counterfeit bills,
one would usually want to go to the suburbs and avoid the eyes of others.
But, they deliberately situated their stronghold
in a bustling station front right beside a police box.
It may at first glance look to be the action of one who is eccentric.
But, there is no better way
than to use this advantageous location to blind the police.
Toshiya's brother probably wanted to relay this message.
Which means that brother is...
If it's as I have deduced,
he is probably inside that newspaper agency.
That's why I've been telling you.
His brother's been kidnapped
and is making counterfeit bills in there.
Hey! You've been watching too many gang movies, kids!
It's really true!
Please believe us!
Why would they believe kids talking like that? I wouldn't either.
Hey, you guys, don't move from there, no matter what.
You got me, right? Don't move!
Conan.
The more he tells us not to move...
The more you feel like moving, right?
What? Counterfeit bills?
Is that true, Shinichi?
Yes, although I have no proof yet, it's very likely.
And, please be careful when you raid the place.
They may threaten the hostages to save themselves.
A woman dressed in black.
Come to think of it, once...
once in the past...
No, Genta.
Conan said not to move, remember?
Shut up! I've got to find some kind of proof
or the police won't believe me.
What? There's nobody here.
There are no counterfeits anywhere.
Maybe Conan made a mistake?
All types of ink. They were trying it out here.
Please forgive me, boss.
I thought I told you not to use that
because it was just a prototype with no watermark!
It looked so real that I just couldn't help myself.
I'll let you use it until you get sick of it in time.
Something way better than this half-done, Soseki Natsume,
A 10,000 yen bill with Yukichi Fukuzawa on it.
I hope you bought the ink that I specified.
Yeah, I bought all there was left.
I tried all kinds, but this is the best for the watermark.
Hey! Somebody's in the room next door.
Kids, five kids!
-Toshiya! -What the... What?
You stay put!
So, he came all this way to look for his brother.
How cute.
What? They went inside the newspaper agency?
Yeah. All five of them saying that they'll come again
after they find proof.
-Darn! -Hey.
Those idiots.
They could be...
in the same organization as the men in black!
I see.
So, we still don't know where she is.
Sorry, we're trying the best we can, though.
I still can't believe it.
It's hard to believe he'd disappear from there.
If his corpse wasn't there, it just means that he wasn't killed.
We've got to look for her fast and bring her before me.
We can't afford her talking about us to anybody.
Of course, I don't care if you get him dead or alive.
What? They went inside the newspaper agency?
Yeah. All five of them saying that they'll come again
after they find proof.
-Darn! -Hey.
Those idiots.
They could be...
Of all things, the Youth Detective Squad made it into the site
of where counterfeit bills were being made.
The woman with the black hat
and the gun that is pointed at the children await their entry.
Is she really connected to the men in black in some way? Or...
Conan runs up the stairs to truth
in order to reveal the mystery of it all.
He runs to save his friends,
as well as to gain his real identity as Shinichi Kudo back.
Darn, Genta and the others.
After I told them not to move from in front of the police box.
Hey, Genta, let's go back already.
If somebody comes, we'll be scolded.
Shut up!
If you wanna go home, why don't you go home alone, Ayumi?
It's seems like everybody is safe yet.
Okay then, I'll have to get everybody out of here now.
That's it for your detective game, kid.
What?
Hey, look at this!
A lot of 10,000 yen bills.
That's cool!
God know how much eels over rice I can eat with that much money.
But, there's something strange about these 10,000 yen bills.
Yukichi Fukuzawa's left eye is not drawn in.
It's like the daruma doll.
We're drawing in both eyes when our wish is granted.
And when that 10,000 yen bill is perfected.
Who are you guys?
How's about a touching reunion of the two brothers?
Toshiya!
Brother! Brother!
Hey, cut it out, you guys!
That's right, I'll contact Conan.
-What do you think you're doing? -Let her go!
Shut up! You don't seem to know what this is, do you?
Don't you dare touch the children!
If you do, I won't cooperate with you anymore.
Don't worry, I'll save your little brother for last.
Bring the girl with the headband here.
Ayumi!
Hey, what're you going to do?
I'm going to make you speed your work up.
If they die one after the other,
maybe you'll want to work harder?
Help, Conan!
Conan?
If it's that boy with glasses that were loitering around the stairs,
he's already dead.
Conan's dead?
No way.
It's a lie!
There is only one way in and out of this building!
When can you kill him?
The surveillance camera was watching all of you all this time.
The outside stairway is also guarded.
You didn't know, did you?
I had Inuyama come all the way around to this entrance
from the emergency exit so that you guys wouldn't be able to run away.
Just then, the boy with the glasses came along, so I killed him.
Hey, come on, don't cry.
You'll be just fine. I'll let you go to him right away.
Bye, bye, young lady.
No!
Who is it?
Same as the daruma doll, you say?
What a laugh!
Yukichi Fukuzawa's eye is not drawn in
because the sculptor that was carving him got hurt.
What?
See, the man over there with the white beard and his hand wrapped up.
He's the real sculptor, isn't he?
You panicked and made Toshiya's brother take his place
because the sculptor got hurt just before completion.
After seeing his talent for art at the exhibition,
you lured him out and confined him here.
The ink beside the printer,
and the container with magnetic steel powder inside it.
Seeing that you've got all these prepared.
I'll bet you're going to put it through a machine next?
You plan to pass it through the counterfeit detection machine,
and use these counterfeits that are difficult to detect even by appearance
through the change machines of banks, game centers, and pachinko parlors,
to change them in large amounts.
By the time your deed is made public,
you plan to be some place far away.
Isn't that right, lady in the black hat?
Who...
who are you?
Conan Edogawa, a detective.
Conan!
It can't be. Inuyama got rid of you.
Oh, so this dog of a man is called Inuyama?
I'm sorry, but I put him to sleep with an anesthetic gun.
Anesthetic gun?
Oh, yes, yes.
The gun I threw at you a while ago was Inuyama's gun.
I kicked it right at you.
Kicked it?
Yes, with this super kick shoe.
There!
Ai Haibara?
Cool.
You're fantastic, Ai.
You're just too much.
This is the first time I've ever seen a real gun.
She...
Well, at any rate, I'm glad.
Brother!
Toshiya.
So, now I guess the case is closed.
I'm glad!
Aye! The Youth Detective Squad's great victory!
Is anything the matter?
Thanks for coming. The case has been solved!
This is the counterfeit, which is evidence.
And that's Toshiya's brother, the one who was kidnapped.
Hello.
They were telling the truth.
Leave it to the Youth Detective Squad,
and cases are solved in a jiffy...
Right, Conan?
Yes.
Being reckless like this, we'll need more than nine lives.
Twenty minutes later, Inspector Megure arrived.
They were all taken away,
and Toshiya's brother was set free.
And...
What a goof, to be arrested over such a measly crime.
You may as well spit it all out at the station.
About the big organization
that is pulling the strings behind the scenes.
Organization?
Don't play dumb with me.
You also had code names like "Gin" and "Vodka", didn't you?
Gin, Vodka?
I'm sorry, but I quit drinking quite some time ago.
Hey, hey, just what are you talking about, Conan?
These people are notorious for making counterfeit bills
and go by the name "Silver Fox".
Although she's fixed up a bit by plastic surgery,
I would never forget the face of this woman boss.
But, this time you'll have to serve for kidnapping,
possession of dangerous weapons, and firing a gun, too.
You'll be spending some time in jail this time.
My, I'm not the one who fired the gun.
It's that girl with the brown hair over there.
What?
What a dangerous thing to do?
But... Because...
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have scolded you.
So, she's a girl after all.
Hey, don't cry.
Your house is near here, isn't it?
Gosh, why me?
I'm thrower off finding out that those people dressed in black were not the people I was after,
and why do I have to baby-sit a crying girl,
moreover, walk her home.
Hey, you can go home alone from here, can't you?
See you tomorrow...
at school, then.
APTX 4869.
-What? -Do you know what it is?
It's the name of the medicine you were given.
What're you talking about?
I've never been given such a strange medicine.
Oh, I'm sure that the name of the medicine is not wrong
because I'm the one who made it...
by order of the organization.
Organization? Made it?
A child like you could never do.
I drank it just like you did.
Through the accidental effects of the self-destructive program of the cells,
everything from bone structure, muscles,
internal organs, to bodily hair, all but the nervous system,
regress to that of the childhood years.
It sure is a mystical poison.
Haibara, don't tell me you're...
It's not Haibara.
It's Sherry.
This is my code name.
Well? Surprised?
Shinichi Kudo.
Then, you're a member of the organization of the men in black.
You've got no time to be surprised, slowpoke detective.
What?
Didn't I tell you that I live at Beika 2-22 now.
Yes, next door to your real house.
You know where it is, don't you?
It couldn't be...
Dr. Agasa's house?
Hey, Dr. Agasa!
-Answer the phone! -No use.
No matter how much you call, you'll get a busy signal.
The phone is off the hook, he can't pick it up.
That's because he is no longer of this world.
Why you...
What did you do to him?
Will you be in trouble if he isn't around, after all?
That phone.
The super kick shoe.
They are all things that the doctor made for you, aren't they?
With the cooperation of the doctor,
you can be playing your role as youth detective with that body of yours.
In other words, Dr. Agasa is the lifeline
for the present Shinichi Kudo.
Is that why you killed him?
Well, I wonder?
If it bothers you,
why don't you go over to his house and see for yourself?
Darn!
Dr. Agasa, please be okay.
Maybe the men in black are still inside.
Nothing seems to be different from the usual.
It doesn't seem like the men in black are here.
Doctor!
Dr. Agasa!
I thought I heard Shinichi's voice?
Shinichi, what is it?
Do you need anything?
Dr. Agasa. So, you're okay?
Okay? What's up?
Oh, I'm really sorry, truly I am!
I've been into working with the computer recently,
that I guess the telephone line was busy.
I'm home.
Welcome back, Ai.
How was school?
It was quite fun.
That brat, she deceived me.
Well, you can't blame her
for the fact that you didn't know my address.
How should I know? I never sent anything to your house.
I even brought the New Year's greeting card over in person.
Never mind that. Who on earth is she?
What? Didn't she tell you?
That she is a member of the black organization,
drank the same poison as you and became small.
Strange.
She told me she'd tell you herself, so not to say anything to you.
Wait, Dr. Agasa.
Oh, I thought up the name Ai Haibara with her.
We took it from the name of a woman detective.
The "Hai" of her name meaning "gray" in Japanese,
was taken from Cordelia Gray.
"Ai" was taken from the "I" in Vioshosky.
I advised her that the Japanese character for love "Ai"
would be cuter than the "Ai" of the character for sadness.
That's not my question!
Why is a woman involved with the men in black living in your house?
I was collapsed...
outside your house in the rain,
when he...
Dr. Agasa found me.
In front of my house?
Did you know?
The organization had sent investigators to your house about twice.
Out of the people who drank that poison,
only your death wasn't verified.
I, the inventor of the poison, naturally came along on the investigation.
But, the house was dusty
and there didn't seem to be anyone living there,
so the first time, we left right away.
We went on our second investigation a month later.
It was a dusty as usual,
and it didn't seem different from what we saw before.
I was starting to think that you had died after all.
I got chicken skin when I saw the strange thing in your clothes drawer.
Your childhood days clothes that were in the drawer a month ago was gone.
A whole lot of it, too.
During the stage of animal experiment,
only one mouse regressed to childhood without dying,
so it was easy to establish the following hypothesis.
The possibility that Shinichi Kudo was given APTX 4869,
and regressed, becoming a child!
The guys of the organization know of my having become a child, then?
Thank me. I rewrote "Confirmed dead" on your data.
I decided to let you live
because you're a very interesting research material.
If I report you to the organization,
the chances of you being killed before getting to me are greater.
Well, if they find out that the one who rewrote your data
is me, the one who betrayed them,
they may start getting suspicious again.
Betrayed?
Yes.
One of the reasons why I gave that poison
that was still in the testing stage, to a human on my own accord,
was because I was getting sick of them.
But, an even greater reason, was my older sister.
Older sister?
She was killed.
She was killed by the hands of the men of the organization.
No matter how much I asked them,
they wouldn't tell me why they killed her.
And, I went against them saying that I was going to postpone my research
until they gave me a formal explanation.
Naturally, since I went against the organization,
they confined me to a certain room in the lab.
I was to wait until the higher-ups decided what to do with me.
Thinking that I may as well drink the poison
if I was going to be killed anyway,
I drank the APTX 4869 that I had hidden on me.
Fortunately, the poison I took in an attempt to kill myself...
transformed my body to that of a children's body,
and freed me from the handcuffs that were on me.
And, I escaped from the tiny dust Shute.
Having no place to go,
the only person I could think of going to
was you, Shinichi Kudo.
I figured since we were in the same boat,
you'd be able to understand my predicament.
You've got to be kidding!
Just how am I supposed to understand
somebody who made poison to kill people?
Hey, Shinichi.
Do you know what you did?
Are you aware of just how many people died
because of the poison you invented?
I couldn't help it.
I had no intention of making poison.
-What? -Well, come now.
She left the organization already.
Since she's the one who made the poison,
she could come up with an antidote without difficulty too, right?
The data for the poison is all in the research lab.
I couldn't possibly remember such a massive amount of data!
Darn.
Tell me where that research lab is, then.
No use.
Look at the evening paper three days ago.
This is about the mysterious fire
that burned down the pharmaceutical company.
So, there would be nothing left even if we go there.
My God.
The organization got rid of it
fearing that I would talk about it to someone.
At this rate, every facility that I was involved in would be closed down.
Which means that those guys are after you?
Yes, they're probably going berserk looking for me.
Without even knowing that I've transformed this way.
But, if they keep using this poison to kill people,
there is no guarantee that people
who will regress like us will eventually appear.
Then, the organization who has a picture of my childhood days
will definitely find me.
What will you do about it?
Will you chase me out of here because I pose a threat to all of you?
High school detective, Shinichi Kudo?
What will you do about it?
Will you chase me out of here because I pose a threat to all of you?
High school detective, Shinichi Kudo?
Yes. I made the poison and am an accomplice to murder.
The organization is also after me.
I am an extremely dangerous person to have around.
There's no reason why you should keep me near you.
Don't be silly. If they find out about you,
it'll be a matter of time before they find out about me,
I hate to impose on Dr. Agasa,
but I'll have you stay here as a grade schooled whether you like it or not.
It's more bothersome to have you hanging around outside.
Oh my, how nice of you.
How about the safety of your parents?
No need for worry, they are also members of the organization.
I was told they died of an accident soon after I was born.
Which means your family is?
Me and my older sister who I didn't get to see too often.
Unlike me, who was studying the States through orders of the organization.
My sister was constantly under surveillance
because she was living in Japan.
Yes, until my sister started working for the organization,
in an attempt to set me free of them,
she was going to an ordinary school,
had ordinary friends, went on ordinary trips.
Wait.
Come to think of it, several years before she was killed.
She sent me 2 or 3 floppies with pictures
of when she went on a trip.
I looked through them at the research lab
and sent it back to her right away,
but the floppy that I had the data of the poison in,
got lost after that.
I looked all over for it but couldn't find it.
I see.
So, the floppy with the data of the poison
may be mixed up among the floppies that you sent back to your sister.
So, if we search the place where your sister used to live.
No use. The condo that my sister was living in
was gotten rid of by the organization right after her death,
and everything was cleared out.
But she said that the person who put the pictures into the floppies,
was the professor that went on the trip together with her.
So, maybe...
You don't know who that professor is?
Masami Hirota of Nanyo University.
Masami Hirota?
But, I don't know where he lives.
All we have to do is ask at the university.
All right!
Let's get with it right away.
Hello.
Could you look up the phone number to Nanyo University, please?
What? The floppy with the picture of the trip in it?
Who are you?
Oh, well, you see, I'm...
What's your sister's name?
Akemi.
Akemi Miyano.
I'm an acquaintance of Akemi.
If it's the floppies with the pictures of the trip
that I went with them, she gave them back to me.
A strange floppy seems to have been mixed up among them, though.
A strange floppy?
No doubt about it! That's the one!
Is it all right for us to go and pick up that floppy from now?
Yes, I don't mind.
I'm expecting a few guests soon,
but if you don't mind coming after them.
Then, we'll be there in three hours.
What? You're going to stay over at Dr. Agasa's?
What on earth are you doing?
Dinner's ready, and we've been waiting for you to come home, Conan.
Dr. Agasa says that he made an interesting game
and wants me to play it with him!
I'll be home by tomorrow morning.
I'm sorry, Ran.
Wait.
You're sure good at acting like a child.
Yeah. But, I'm not as good as you who can fake crying like a baby.
It's 150 kilometers to Shizuoka.
I wonder if we can get there in three hours.
Hey, Dr. Agasa, be on your guard with that chick.
That chick? You mean Ai?
Yeah, although she's saying she fled from the organization,
she's not telling us her real name or age,
and even if we ask her what the organization is after,
she insists on not knowing a thing.
What she said a while ago
could be a lie to lure us into a trap.
She doesn't look that way, though.
And, another thing that bothers me is, Masami Hirota.
I've heard this name somewhere before.
Good evening.
Oh, Mr. Agasa.
My husband told me about you. Please come in.
Have your guests already left?
Yes, it seems that my husband's student was here just before you.
Dear!
Dear.
Strange, I wonder what he's doing inside with the door locked?
Darn, it won't open.
Do you have a spare key to this room?
No, I haven't.
Then, help me break this door open, Dr. Agasa!
What?
Quick.
Here goes!
One more time!
-Wait. -One, two, go.
One, two, go...
An accident you say?
Yes, we can't be 100 percent sure yet,
but it is very likely to be an accident.
Officer Yokomizo.
The cause of death seems to have been this object.
It may have hit him when he fell.
Just as I thought.
He fell?
In other words,
Mr. Masami Hirota wanted to take something that was on the bookshelf,
and placed his foot on the shelf.
He lost his balance and fell, bookshelf and all.
Then, he bumped the back of his head onto that object
that had already fallen to the floor,
and it killed him.
As proof of that, the door of this room,
and the windows located above the door were all locked securely.
Besides, the only key there is to this room,
was scattered over the floor with the books, under the notebook.
Professor Hirota, locked the door himself,
and died because of the accident, right after that?
Yes, no matter how you look at it...
He could've been killed by someone.
It was just made to look like an accident.
You're the boy that's staying with Mr. Mouri, right?
Oh, yes. That's right.
He's the son of a relative of mine.
See, look at this phone, it's toppled on the floor, right?
That's because the phone book fell together with the bookshelf.
Then, why is the receiver not off the hook?
Although the phone is upside down
and is camouflaged with the book on top of it,
someone has deliberately messed this room up.
Then, is this homicide?
Wait. If so, this would be...
a murder behind locked doors.
Murder behind...
Locked doors?
Right, the doors were all locked,
and the key to this room was found here.
Then who... who killed my husband?
Please calm down, Mrs. Hirota.
Were there any suspicious people who came to see him tonight?
He seems to have had 3 or 4 guests including Mr. Agasa.
Me?
An acquaintance of mine
told me that she had mistakenly given Professor Hirota her floppy,
I came to get it back.
So, I'm sure that it is besides that computer.
All the floppies are gone. A whole bunch of them.
What?
At this rate, maybe all the data in this computer is also erased.
What's with that girl?
She's also the child of my relative.
Hey, Ai, don't touch!
At any rate, I have nothing to do with this murder.
No one would be stupid enough to bring children along
when thinking of committing murder, right?
That's true.
Listen, little lady, I don't want you touching anything in this room.
Go to the room next door and wait there quietly with your grandpa.
Understand?
I'm still 52, too young to be called grandpa, don't you think?
Hey, don't tell me they took the floppies?
Very likely.
Because the lost record of the data of the poison,
as well as the record of the parcel
that I sent back to my sister about the same time,
are all left behind at the organization.
I see.
So, they could've predicted that since you fled from the organization,
you would stop by here to come get the data.
The organization came here to look for the data and suck in here,
but was seen by Professor Hirota, so they killed him.
Not good.
No, let's not jump to conclusions too fast.
First, let's ask about the people who came here tonight.
We'll think about everything else later.
You were at a community meeting?
Yes, together with a neighbor of mine,
from 20:00 to 23:00, for three hours.
Which means that you haven't met the guests
who have come to see your husband tonight?
No, all except the first person who came,
who came just when I was ready to leave?
My husband said it was one of his students.
I think he said the person's name was Hosoya.
Okay! Bring that person called Hosoya
who is a student of Professor Hirota, and was here tonight!
Yes, sir!
Do you know the names of the other people who came here?
I wonder.
I have no idea, except for Dr. Agasa who called
just before I was ready to leave.
Although, my husband did say 2-3 of his students were coming.
Which means that we have no choice
but to check on all of his students who were here.
Hey, blinking on this phone here.
This is an answer phone, isn't it?
We could find something out if we listen to this, right?
Yes.
You have thirteen messages.
Thirteen? There sure are a lot of before the phone messages.
Hello, this is Shirokura...
Professor Hirota, the promise was for tonight?
Who is this Mr. Shirokura?
I've met Mr. Shirokura before. He's still a young man.
Strange, why is the tape cut off here and there?
This is Morioka. What time am I supposed to go there tonight?
Who is he?
I know Mr. Morioka, too.
He is my husband's first student
and comes over a lot.
Do you have the address and phone number
of Mr. Shirokura and Mr. Morioka?
-Yes. -I'm Shirokura.
What's the matter? What's all this commotion about?
Did something happen here?
Professor Hirota has been murdered by someone.
What?
Hello, this is Shirokura...
I've got other matters to attend to tomorrow,
so I'll head on over there now.
You placed 10 messages in here and Mr. Morioka placed two messages.
Mr. Shirokura, you sure left a lot of messages, didn't you?
Like I'm telling you. I came here directly
because he wouldn't answer, no matter how many times I called.
All right.
But, why did something like this happen to him?
This is the 13th, and the last message.
This is black... life.
I'd like to come over to explain our new insurance plan.
What time should I over?
I will call again later.
An insurance agent?
No! Although the voice is a bit changed using a machine,
his way of talking is...
This voice is...
Vodka.
Now.
Hey, then this case involves those guys, after all?
No, the possibility of them having done anything have decreased.
If they had come here to get the floppy,
they wouldn't have done something as stupid
as to leave their voices on tape at the scene of a crime.
True, it would be a cinch for them to pick up the floppy
without even creating such a locked-in-room situation.
They left the message on the answer phone,
so that in case Professor Hirota was home,
it would ease his suspicion of them,
and make it easier for them to carry out their purpose.
I'll bet they're all panicky now
because they can't come to get the floppy.
Then, if so, then they'll be here soon.
Yeah. We were right to move your Volkswagen elsewhere.
They may be somewhere near here already.
What? Professor Hirota was killed?
That's ridiculous.
He was fine till just a while ago.
Mr. Hosoya, you came here just as Mrs. Hirota was going out, didn't you?
Yes.
My daughter is going to apply for Nanyo University,
so I came to have Professor Hirota write out a recommendation for her.
But the professor was so drunk, that I decided to leave for today.
Is it true that the was drinking?
Yes, from the evening.
Mr. Morioka, according to the message in the answer phone,
you were also supposed to meet Professor Hirota.
Yes.
To play chess. Professor Hirota and I play chess together.
He asked me to come over and play tonight, too.
See, chess pieces are scattered all over the floor.
We used to always play in this room.
I phoned twice because we didn't decide what time to start,
but the answer phone was set.
I came to check out what was happening because
he wouldn't answer the phone despite having called me from his side.
You came here tonight?
Yes, I came around 9:30 pm.
Although the front door was open, nobody answered the doorbell.
So, I thought he had forgotten about the game and went to sleep.
I went into the house.
But, when I knocked on the door of the study, nobody answered,
and on top of that, the door was locked.
So, I gave up and left.
I see. And Mr. Agasa arrived an hour later,
realized that something was wrong, broke the door open
and found the corpse?
Yes, that's right.
By the way, Mr. Shirokura, you came right after we got here, right?
I haven't asked you what you came here for yet tonight.
Yes, the fact is, I am working as a model.
I'm supposed be doing a column in a magazine entitled,
"The Unexpected Plain Face of a Model".
I took a picture of me dressed in woman's clothes
during a university festival, together with Professor Hirota,
and I came to get the floppy with the data of the picture from him.
He saved the data of the picture in a floppy?
Yes, my husband used to input all the pictures that he liked
into the computer.
He not only saved pictures.
He also saved the entrance exams of universities,
the grades of his students,
and even saved the process and results of the chess games
that he played with Mr. Morioka.
I see.
So, the killer stole all of those floppies
after killing Professor Hirota.
Which means that the criminal killed to get a hold of them.
Your daughter's going to be applying for Nanyo University, isn't she?
Yes.
If you got a hold of the floppies it with the entrance exams in them,
she would definitely get in, wouldn't she?
No, it never even crossed my mind.
Somebody else would've been here besides us, right?
Moreover, the professor was also using the computer at the university.
The professor himself could've taken all the floppies to the university.
It's possible.
He never writes anything on the label,
so he may've taken all the floppies to write the labels.
Besides, this room was locked from the inside, wasn't it?
Moreover, wasn't the key to this room
found here under the notebook that was on the floor?
Officer, no matter how you look at it...
Exactly.
All the possible places of entry were locked
and the only possible space
if any was between the door and the floor,
which only a key would slide through.
If a rubber band or a fishing string were used,
it may've been possible to kill Professor Hirota,
take the fishing string away,
lock the door from the outside and from the space beneath the door,
move the key to the center of the room.
It would be close to impossible to slide the key nicely
under the notebook.
What bothers me is
why despite all the books that were scattered around the room,
was there only the notebook in question on the floor
which was lined in a row from the door to the phone?
The tape of the answering phone is a bit out of shape
but this couldn't have possibly been used
to push the key under the notebook.
Conan Edogawa?
Remember, the boy in glasses I told you about last time.
You also said that you went to somebody's house at Beika Town?
You mean Shinichi Kudo?
Right, he's the boy of the Detective Office there.
He seems a bit different.
He's unusual cool-headed and very adultish for a child.
How about you, Akemi? Are you all right?
I heard that you were in hot water or something.
Don't worry, I'm doing fine.
I'm more worried about you, Shiho.
Cut out making poison
and go find yourself a lover or two.
I'm really okay.
Impossible to lock the door from the outside,
and slide the key to the center of the room,
much less to slide it under the notebook.
It would be impossible
even if the tape of the answer phone were to be used.
Although there are many queer points,
if the late Professor Hirota were wasted,
it's not all that strange if he fell together with the bookshelf,
and hit the back of his head.
Besides, it's too dangerous to stay here any longer,
as well as useless.
Forget it, Shinichi. Forget this case.
It's checkmate.
Checkmate?
Hurry, let's get out of here from the back door.
Hold it.
Don't you care to know the truth of this case?
Like I said. No matter how you look at it...
This is no accident. It's homicide!
After the killer murdered Professor Hirota,
he used a trick and locked this room up from the inside
to make it look like an accident.
I'll show you what the truth is, starting right this minute.
I'll show you that there is no case that can't be solved in this world.
It's an accident, an accident.
Professor Hirota was drunk, fell down together with the bookshelf,
hit the back of his head violently and died.
Judging from the circumstances at the scene,
it sure can be looked at in that way,
but there are several points that bother me.
I don't care about that.
The room was locked,
and moreover, the key was under the notebook among scattered books, right?
If there were a killer, how did that person lock the door?
That's why we're trying to figure that out.
I'm sorry, but I have some matters to attend to tomorrow,
-so if you will excuse me. -I'll be on my way, too.
I'm leaving, too.
Hey, wait.
Everybody, wait up.
I just...
Hey, what are you using my voice suddenly for?
I've figured it out.
How the trick of the locked door murder was carried out,
as well as who the killer is.
What?
Hey, Shinichi.
Never mind just move your mouth in keeping with my voice.
Seriously. Like I've been telling you,
no matter how you look at it.
No, no, that's why amateurs are no good.
An amateur.
And just who do you think you are?
The room was indeed locked from the inside.
No matter how you look at it, it looks to be an accident.
But, this trick of a locked room can be carried out perfectly
by using the cassette tape of the answer phone and the chess piece.
Cassette tape?
A chess piece?
Are you sure, Shinichi?
Hey, stop glancing at me.
Act more confident like a detective, will you?
Proof speaks more than words. Show us, will you?
The trick that you have imagined, right here, before us all.
Definitely.
I'll have Conan help me and replay how it was done.
Do you know what you're doing?
Yes, trust me. It'll work 100 percent.
Officer, do you happen to have a cellular on you?
Yes, I have one.
Lend me that glove, too.
Officer Yokomizo, I've brought the cassette tape.
It is the same as the one used in the telephone here.
Why? I asked for no such thing.
What? But just a while ago, this boy said...
Well, never mind, it's no big thing!
May I have the tape, officer?
First, pull out the tape to a certain length.
Hey.
Set the cassette into the phone.
Of course, the tape is left sticking out.
Next, straighten the tape that is sticking out, and pull it straight.
Go out of the door,
and pull the tape through the ring of the key.
Then leave that key outside the door, take the remaining tape
and go back to the place where the notebook was on the floor.
Next, place three pawns
that are of the same height in the shape of a triangle,
then hook the edge of the tape that is left,
onto the pawn that is closest to the phone,
and place the notebook on it.
What a joke.
You may be trying to knock the pawn over
with the force of the tape being pulled,
but that's just a paper plan.
The stand of the pawn is quite stable,
so the key will hook on to the pawn before it falls,
and come out from under the notebook.
It's the opposite.
I'm going to turn the pawn upside down after this.
Even if the head of the pawn is round,
so long as the cover of the notebook is firm like this,
it can be placed on.
You just wait and see. I'll do it for you right now.
First, the door is locked from the outside.
Then, the key is placed on the floor and a phone call is made.
The answer phone goes off, and the tape is wound.
The key is pulled in under the space of the door,
and moves under the notebook that is placed in the center of the room.
It will eventually bump into the pawn,
which will then lose its balance and the key...
will go under the notebook.
It went in.
I see.
So, if you keep on moving the answer phone,
the tape is wound, and the evidence vanishes.
Well? Did it work?
It was fantastic, Shinichi.
Oh, no. Well, it's just as I thought.
And if the pawn is place at a corner of the notebook,
it would make it more difficult from the pawn to roll under the notebook.
Well, even if it did, it wouldn't look very unnatural.
Which means that the one who called
and left 10 messages in the answer phone
in order to use the trick
is you, Mr. Akira Shirakura.
Then, are you the one who killed my husband?
Wait.
The tape was twisted here and there,
and that serves as evidence that the tape was used for the trick!
Is that right?
Just a minute, please.
I admit that the trick just now is really superb.
But, why do I turn out to be the one who set it up?
All I did was put a lot of messages in the answering machine.
In the first place, if I were the one who did it,
I wouldn't come all the way back here.
You came back to get something, didn't you?
Yes, you came to get the tape of the answer phone
because it had your fingerprints all over the place.
When I took a look at the tape a while ago,
I could tell in one glance.
There were the fingerprints of somebody all over the tape.
And I could also tell that this was an unprepared, impulsive murder.
You probably met Professor Hirota tonight and got into an argument.
You then, impulsively hit him on the head.
Fortunately, this trick crossed your mind,
and you were able to think up a locked door murder
which looked to be an accident.
But, since the murder wasn't planned ahead,
you didn't have gloves,
And you couldn't help getting your fingerprints on the tape.
Therefore, you decided to be the first to discover the corpse,
and after you made Mrs. Hirota confirm that the door was locked,
you were waiting for a time when you could switch tapes.
However, we found the corpse first,
and the police arrived sooner than expected,
so having no choice, you came here like you said in the tape.
You went out of the way to leave your name on the tape,
so that in case you couldn't grit the tape, back,
it would make it more difficult to see through the trick.
If there are many no-message recordings,
whether you like it or not,
attention would focus on the tape with your fingerprints on.
You can go ahead and check Mr. Shirakura if you like.
He's bound to have Professor Hirota's floppies on him somewhere.
After all, he couldn't have possibly checked the contents
of the large batch of floppies he took in such a short time.
Then, can we start by searching your house, Mr. Shirakura?
They're in the dashboard of my car
that is parked in front of this house.
All the floppies are there.
The one with the data of the pictures is there, too.
Pictures?
Didn't I tell you a while ago?
That I'm supposed be doing a column in a magazine
entitled, "The Unexpected Plain Face of a Model",
and that I took a picture of me dressed in woman's clothes
during a university festival, together with Professor Hirota.
But what he had sent me was a message that said,
"There is Nothing Better Than This Plain Face of Yours".
And a picture of my face in the past.
Your face in the past?
I had plastic surgery when I became a model.
I changed my name, too.
I thought it was just the picture.
My face wasn't all that clear because of the make-up and wig,
and with it being me dressed in woman's clothes,
I thought it would be a good joke.
I naturally couldn't give the editor a picture of the face of the past.
So, I came to ask the professor to lend me the picture.
But, he...
Oh, I forgot which floppy it was
that had the picture of you dressed in woman's clothes.
If it's the picture I sent to you, I can get it out right away.
I can send it directly to the editor's office if you like?
I got enraged at his words.
And when I snapped back to myself.
Professor Hirota was on the floor before me.
The rest is as he had explained.
Everything is right to the smallest detail.
Okay, please come to the station with us, then.
Hey.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Shirakura.
Maybe it's none of my business.
But I think that Professor Hirota sent you the picture of your past,
because he wanted you to have more confidence in yourself
as well as be true to yourself.
I would've liked to hear those words directly from Professor Hirota.
Too bad.
Well, that was a fantastic deduction.
Thanks to you, the case was solved, Mr. Agasa.
Well, no.
And I would like to have the floppy that I came to get, back right away.
No. We'll have to check out the evidence at the station first.
So, he says. What now?
Can't help it. I guess we'll get out of here for now.
Okay, then. We'll be heading home.
Take care.
Hey, come on, you too.
Why?
Why didn't you save my sister?
Your sister?
You still haven't realized?
Masami Hirota is an alias that my sister
took from Professor Hirota's name.
Don't tell me that the Masami Hirota of the 10 billion bank robbery
is your...
You can't go...
Ms. Masami Hirota.
You'll be killed if you go.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, Conan.
Who is behind the black curtain?
Where are you?
Show yourself!
Well done.
Masami Hirota.
Or should I said, Akemi Miyano.
Gunshot.
Ms. Masami.
Hold on there!
It's a large organization consumed by mysteries.
The only thing I know about the organization
is that it's color is black.
Black?
That's right.
The way the individuals of the organization can identify one another
is their black crow-like trench coat.
Take this.
Please, before they realize it.
I'll leave it to you, little detective.
So, she was your older sister.
That's right!
Hey.
With your power of deduction,
you could've easily seen through what my sister was up to!
Then why... why didn't you?
Why?
Her trembling, crying voice,
brought back memories of a painful and sad case
that I had almost forgotten.
The was probably the first time she showed her real self to me.
A week later, the floppy was sent to us from the police,
so we decided to take a look at it on the computer right away.
It's a wonder it made it through the investigation of the police.
All the floppies of the organization
are plain text files unless a password is entered.
They would never be suspected.
How is it? Will it come out?
Yes. And the data that is in here is not only of the poison.
The real name, address and code name of the person
who was working on the poison
before I was placed in my position is supposed to be in here, too.
The name of the person who invested in this research
should also be in here.
I see.
If we do it right, we make be able to strip them naked.
Gin, seems like the old man called Hirota dropped dead.
Yes, it saved us the trouble of killing him ourselves.
But, we still don't know the whereabouts
of the woman who got away.
They're checking to see
if somebody within the organization helped her escape.
And now, the places they may drop into
have all been gotten rid of.
I'm sure she'll come out from her side soon...
I heard that the floppy with information on the poison
was forfeited by the police.
That's nothing to worry about.
That floppy is a bit rigged.
What's happening?
What is this?
Computer virus, Night Baron.
What?
The floppy has been programmed so that if it is booted up with a computer
other than the organization's, a virus eats the data.
How careless of me.
Then, all the data is...
Yes. Everything has vanished.
Even the computer program.
What?
Darn.
It seems that we're going to be hanging around each other for a long time,
Conan Edogawa.