I guess we won't be seeing each other anymore.
Take care of yourself.
Ahh, it always touches my heart no matter how many times I see it.
Thank you for your hard work.
It's an old movie, but...
I wonder if young people like you
were able to enjoy it.
Yes, of course.
It was really interesting.
Mother, how about showing them
the room upstairs as well?
We have small props
that Mother used in her movies on display.
Oh! Then by all means.
♪~♪
The blackness of shadows, the density of darkness—
the light of reasoning cuts right through them.
A fire at a movie star's mansion.
The surprising secret hidden in a painting.
See through the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~♪
"A Diamond, Artwork and a Great Actress"
Oh my. Nothing but nostalgic movies.
It's like a little Shirakawa Misuzu memorial museum.
You're embarrassing me.
These are things my late husband collected.
I see.
This is the room where we've organized
the costumes and props from back then.
Oh!
Wow... amazing.
This is Mother's bedroom.
Memorable items and valuable things
are kept in this glass case.
Wow! Is this real?
Ah. Of course it is.
There's no way Misuzu-san would put fake things on display.
Is that one real too?
It's real. I thought it would be a shame
to keep it locked up in a glass case
all the time.
This is a painting from when we filmed the movie
"Vacation at Rokumeikan"...
but the finished painting didn't have the necklace,
so I thought,
why not?
(Sound) Hmm?
Ah... whoa!
Hey, Dad, be careful.
I know!
(Kogoro panicking) Ah...
Phew...
What are you doing?
Hey, Mama! Hmm?
What is the meaning of this?
What's all this noise?
Why did you cancel
my passing of the audition?
Young lady, please calm down.
I heard it from the production staff.
Mama called and had my passing of the audition cancelled.
Audition?
Saori was trying out for an audition for a movie.
Because, dear... you can't sing, and your acting is terrible.
It would be embarrassing to put you in front of people.
Mother!
Don't decide that on your own!
Be quiet.
I won't let anyone do anything that tarnishes my name.
You being an actress was a long time ago.
Nobody even remembers Shirakawa Misuzu anymore.
Saori. Leave her be.
Now then, let's have lunch.
Yuka, please escort everyone to the terrace.
Yes, ma'am.
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
Coming!
How about some jam?
I'll have some.
I'm sorry about earlier.
When it comes to acting, Mother is still...
strict. No, not at all.
Mother lives in a world of dreams.
The world back when she was a great actress.
Ah... you shouldn't say things like that, Kyosuke-san.
I apologize for earlier, Mouri-san.
You had to see such an embarrassing scene.
No, don't worry about it.
Well, no matter how old they get, children are still children.
It's like they say, "A parent's heart is unknown to their child."
Ugh...
Yuka.
Yes?
This isn't the usual
rose jam, is it?
I'm very sorry.
When I checked yesterday,
I thought we had two more bottles in stock.
Go buy some right now.
Mother, you don't have to get that angry over some jam.
At the studio, there was never anyone who forgot what my favorite things were.
That was a long time ago. Wha...
I'm sorry. I'll go buy some right away.
(Door opens)
(Door closes)
Kyosuke.
It's a little early, but it's time for your medicine.
Please get it ready.
Yes.
Well then, Mouri-san, please excuse me.
I'll see you later.
Haah...
(Door closes) I'm sorry.
It's just... No, not at all.
Oh, I'll excuse myself for a moment and go check on Yuka.
Ah, yes.
Haah... What is with this house? (Door opens)
I'm sorry for all the commotion.
Ah, no...
Huh? Chiharu is...
Ah, she went to check on Yuka.
I see.
Hey, is Misuzu-san sick or something?
Huh? Ah, it's a nap.
Huh?
A nap...?
Yes. Every day from 2 to 4 PM,
taking a nap is Mother's daily routine.
She even takes sleeping pills for it.
Apparently it's for her beauty and health.
(Brakes screech)
(Crash)
(Horn honking)
Ugh... ugh...
Yuka, are you okay?
What happened?
It's my fault. I wasn't paying attention.
I'm sorry. I was upset...
Oh man... you messed up.
I saw it.
Chiharu-neesan wandered out in front of the car,
and trying to avoid her, the car went plop.
It's not Yuka's fault. (Door opens)
You all! Ah...
What is all this commotion?
Hey, that car...
Please forgive me. It was my carelessness...
No, it was me...
That's enough.
Yuka, as of today, pack your things and leave.
Unbelievable.
Normally, you'd ask something like "Are you hurt?" first.
The car can just be fixed with insurance, right?
That's enough.
Why are you always so selfish, Mama?
Have you ever once thought about how other people feel?
Is that any way to talk to your parent?
I'm tired. I'm going to rest now.
Ugh... ugh...
It's okay, Yuka.
I'll talk to Mother later.
Well then, Mouri-san, please take care of it.
Mouri-san, thank you very much.
Oh, no need to thank me.
My father just stepped on the gas.
Ah, do you smell something burning?
The lady's room is... Mama.
Mother!
Misuzu-san!
Ugh... ugh...
Misuzu-san! Mother!
Kyosuke-kun, grab that side.
Yes. (Coughing)
This is...
Today at around 2 PM,
a fire broke out at the home of actress Shirakawa Misuzu,
and Shirakawa has passed away.
When Mouri-san entered the room,
Shirakawa was already...
Yes. She had taken sleeping pills before going to sleep,
so without noticing the fire,
she must have inhaled a large amount of smoke.
I see.
But the fire started from a strange place.
That's true.
Does your mother smoke?
No. Nobody in this house smokes, not just Mother.
This is...
Could it be...
That's it.
...Which means this is a murder case.
And the culprit is...
The culprit is that person.
Well then.
The sun is setting,
and since we can't determine whether it's an incident or an accident,
we'll head back to the station and wait for the forensics results...
Wait, please, Tamagawa-keiji.
Huh? Huh?
Is there a problem?
Ah, no, no.
(Tranquilizer dart hits) Ah! Whoa!
Dad? Mo... Mouri-san?
Could this be the Sleeping Kogoro?
What? Everyone.
This fire was intentionally set
to murder Shirakawa Misuzu-san.
Huh...
Are you saying this is a murder case?
That's right. And the culprit is among us.
Huh?
But, Dad,
everyone was by the pond at that time.
Ah, probably a type of convergent fire.
Hmm... convergent fire?
A convergent fire is a fire caused by water in a plastic bottle or something
acting as a convex lens.
In other words, Mouri-san,
sunlight was concentrated on the surface of that painting
and ignited it...?
But this room faces north. Sunlight doesn't come in.
Please look outside the window.
Huh?
That building with glass windows
that looks like it was cut diagonally with a knife.
Does seeing that remind you of anything, Kyosuke-san?
That's right.
When I rushed into this room...
But even if sunlight reflected off that building,
it would just hit the opposite wall... Ah!
A mirror!
No, even if it reflected off that mirror,
I still don't think the light would hit the portrait.
That does seem unlikely.
Then let's verify it.
Like this?
A little higher.
This much?
Okay.
Now, please turn on the switch.
Just as I thought.
The light went to the wall opposite the painting.
Now, Yuka-san.
Please return the mirror on the floor to its original position.
Okay.
It probably fell during the commotion of the firefighting efforts.
Can you see the marks carved into the base?
Um... Ah, there they are.
There are also marks on the glass case,
so please align them with those.
Yes.
Please also adjust the vertical angle.
Oh! The light is hitting the painting!
Please do the other two as well.
Oh!
Here's how it works.
The light reflected off the glass building
passes through the window and reflects off the full-length mirror on the wall,
then reflects off the three mirrors on top of the glass case,
and concentrated on a single point on the painting.
The culprit likely
meticulously determined the positions of the mirrors in advance.
But please remember.
When I was guided here before noon,
I accidentally knocked over a mirror.
In other words,
there's a high chance they were misaligned from the positions the culprit had set.
And yet,
the fire occurred exactly as the culprit intended.
That means...
Ah! That means the culprit readjusted the positions of the mirrors!
Yes.
And there is only one person who could have done that.
The one who slipped past us as we headed to the terrace
and remained in this room—Shirakawa Chiharu-san.
It can only be you.
That's...
No way...
Is it true, Chiharu? You killed Mother?
No, wait a moment.
Mother only had the window open for about two or three minutes.
Can a fire source really be created in such a short time?
Yes, it can.
Chiharu-san, after adjusting the mirrors,
didn't you apply a chemical to the painting that ignites easily...
probably a thinning agent used when painting with oils?
Thinning agent?
Yes.
Volatile solvents like turpentine and petroleum
have flash points below 50 degrees Celsius.
You were also the one who hid the rose jam, weren't you?
Just as you planned, Misuzu-san sent Yuka out to buy new jam.
And then you ran out in front of Yuka's car...
Ah!
(Crash)
You all!
What is all this commotion?
Hey, that car...
Have you ever once thought about how other people feel?
Is that any way to talk to your parent?
Is that true, Chiharu?
Is it true, sis? Chiharu-neesan killed Mama?
Evidence? Huh?
If you're going to go that far, Mouri-san,
then you'll have to show me proper evidence.
Evidence?
Yes. Everything you've said so far has just been speculation.
Just because I was the last to leave the room,
does that prove that I adjusted the mirrors?
Ridiculous.
Yuka-san.
Ah, yes.
There were lilies arranged in this room, weren't there?
Yes. Because the lady loved them.
And in the other rooms?
No, the only room that had lilies arranged
was this one.
Excuse me, Mouri-san, what exactly are you talking about?
About the evidence, of course.
Huh?
In other words,
I'm talking about the lily pollen
on the outside of your right sleeve.
Ha...
And what is that supposed to prove?
Why is pollen from lilies,
which were only arranged in this room,
on your right sleeve?
That's... I must have touched the lilies somehow.
So then...
I don't remember something like that!
Please think carefully.
The lilies were in a vase on top of the glass case.
Pollen on the outside of your right sleeve means
that you reached out your right hand to the left side of the lilies
and performed some kind of task.
So what was there?
Yes. There were the mirrors
used in the earlier experiment
to reflect and concentrate the light.
Ah...
Chiharu...
Chiharu-neesan, why? Why did you do that to Mama?
"Chiharu-san." Huh?
No matter how much time passed, she always called me
"Chiharu-san."
Even though she called you all "Kyosuke" and "Saori."
Just because of that? Hmph.
Mouri-san, I'm my father's stepchild.
When I heard that Father was going to remarry her,
I was very happy.
After all, she was a great actress I admired.
So I tried my best to get her to like me.
I never said anything selfish,
and I willingly helped around the house.
But what came back from her was always...
"Well done, Chiharu-san."
"Thank you, Chiharu-san."
"No, Chiharu-san."
Chiharu-san, Chiharu-san, Chiharu-san...
It was last week.
Ah, that girl doesn't matter.
It's fine, it's fine.
After all, that girl is just my husband's stepchild.
Yes, that's right. The only children who carry Shirakawa Misuzu's blood
are Kyosuke and Saori.
And I won't give a single yen of my fortune to anyone else.
Hohohoho...
Ugh... Hohohoho...
Chiharu-san.
This is just my personal opinion, but...
don't you think you tried too hard?
Ha...
A parent-child relationship isn't something you become by trying hard.
You probably could have been a little more selfish
as well.
From the very beginning,
you started off on the wrong foot.
Ugh... ugh...
(Crying)
♪~♪
Hey, Dad?
Huh? You went horse racing again, didn't you?
D... don't be stupid. There's no way that's true.
...Geez. And on top of that, you even ate curry,
so what am I supposed to do about dinner?
Huh? Wh... how did you...
Hmm... It's on your shirt.
A curry stain.
Ah, no... Ahahaha... (Clears throat)
Okay, I admit I ate curry.
But I didn't eat it at the racetrack...
Uncle. Hmm?
Your ear, your ear.
Ah!
Ah, huh? How did this thing get in my ear...
That's strange. Strange things do happen.
You're a sore loser. Allowance, 50% cut.
Huh? Ahaha... hee...
Your Honor! Oh, such injustice...
Haha. You're a detective,
so pay attention to the little details.
One stab in the chest with a blade, huh?
Did Kitajima-san do it?
Wasn't it Hiroto-san?
Huh?
I wondered who it was, but it's Hiroto-san. And Morishita-san too.
You two are the culprits, aren't you? Huh?
There's one natural thing of the same color in this room.
Everyone, which one is it?
That one! That one!
Next Conan...
"The Figure That Was Too Good"
Next Conan's Hint.
"Paint"
Are you going horse racing again?
Because it's the Year of the Horse.
A clever excuse.