Just as flowing water has no form
and the breeze is invisible.
Deductions take all shapes and styles in every case to be solved.
Happy New Year, everyone!
And to kick off the new millennium, a two-hour special!
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
It's the bottom of the ninth, the score's 3-2
with Chunichi leading by a point.
Ace relief pitcher, Komatsu,
is on the mound with two outs and runner, on second base...
Hey! Did you kill him?
Yes!
I shot him four times.
I'm sure he's dead.
So Saizo Kano, the Mastermind in the shadows,
is now drifting like seaweed in the sea.
Probably, the current in this area is strong.
Before the body floats up, it'll be food for the fishes.
But...
but why'd we have to kill him?
You fool! Do you think we could let that coward go?
He said we should turn ourselves in because we killed one lousy bank clerk.
Besides, the police had him identified.
Never mind him, now what're we going to do?
That money is hot.
Yes, he is right.
Out of the 400 million yen,
the cops have the serial numbers for 300 million, right?
Don't worry.
We already pulled off the big job.
All we have to do now is wait until the right time.
Here!
This is our farewell gift to you.
No grudges, okay?
Boss.
"Murder on The S.S. Symphony, 20 Years Vendetta"
Record...
-What? -The answer has got to be a record!
What are you talking about anyway?
This, here!
See!
Read this.
"Special Announcement" -Special announcement.
What?
Something important most people in Japan had during the Showa era.
Do you still have it?
Bring this valuable but increasingly obsolete item
-to join... -The next part...
Read the next part!
Don't bother me.
The first ten people who bring the correct item
will win an all-expense paid trip to the Ogasawara Dolphin Tour.
Let's give a try, come on.
There's still time, let's take a record down there!
Come on! Conan, you want to see the dolphins too, don't you?
Don't you, Conan?
Come on, you don't mind, do you?
We don't have anything to do this long weekend anyway.
Gosh. Forget it, the tour sounds boring.
Besides, your answer's wrong!
If it was records, they wouldn't have written "people in Japan".
All right. What's the right answer?
You stupid! That's what modern Japanese people have lost!
"Samurai spirit", no doubt about it!
How are you going to take bring something like that down there?
Besides, I've never had samurai spirit, and I doubt I ever will!
All right. Maybe it's a yoyo or bell bottom pants.
-How about that mushroom tea? -Designer brands or family computers?
Yes, I know what it is.
How about that frilled lizard?
It was pretty popular back then!
What is it anyway?
Excuse me.
I think the answer is...
You're right!
Right this way to the cruiser.
All right!
We did it! You were right, Conan.
I was just lucky!
Next contestant, step this way!
We sure were lucky we still one of the old bills!
Put that away right now, the others in the back will see it.
You're so stingy, Pops.
Don't worry. It's not something they pull out of their pockets so readily.
No way! It's not this? Unbelievable!
It's not the answer.
He was right.
Next contestant.
Wait!
This is real fancy!
I'm so excited!
Congratulations! This is a pamphlet for today's tour.
Thank you.
What number are we?
There's three in your party, but not counting the boy,
there's one more opening on the tour.
We just made it!
How lucky!
That's right. The maximum number for the tour was ten.
But this sure is a huge ship for such a small group.
Conan, we're going!
Okay, coming!
It's like a hotel!
Going to Ogasawara on this won't be bad!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
Party of three, are you one family?
Yes, sort of.
So I'll put you in a twin room. The room number is 101.
May I ask you a question?
Mr. Masaru Furukawa, the man who planned this tour,
is he on board this ship?
Excuse me?
I wanted to thank him for giving me the opportunity
to sail on this fantastic ship!
The thing is, none of us crew members have met him either.
You haven't met him?
No! The reservation for the cruise
as well as the method for selecting the passengers,
everything was done by phone.
The charter fee was also directly transferred through the bank.
I'm sure he'll be waiting for the ship at Ogasawara, though.
-I see. -By the way, sir,
may I please have your name?
Of course.
Actually, my name is Kogoro Mouri!
A former detective with the Metropolitan Police Department,
now an awe-inspiring well known private detective!
Isn't that right?
Oh... Police Superintendent Samezaki!
Hey, I'm not a Police Superintendent anymore!
"Toji Samezaki (62)" -I retired two years ago,
"Former Superintendent, Homicide Department" -I'm just an old fogey now.
It's been ages!
Is that you, Ran? You sure have grown up to be quite a beauty!
But what brings you here?
I just got a hankering to see the ocean.
Remember? Today's a special day!
A special day?
I don't blame you for forgetting,
after all you left the force 10 years ago.
By the way, how's that gorgeous wife of yours?
Don't tell me you two are still separated.
As a matter of fact, we are.
Never mind that, don't mention that woman.
Dad!
Well, excuse me.
What is it?
"Teruyoshi Kameda (45), Passenger" -Nothing, never mind.
A seal?
You dropped this.
Excuse me?
Thank you very much!
What? Thank you.
You picked up his seal, so why'd you thank him?
Never mind...
Hey!
What is it?
Are you talking to me?
"Korehisa Kanie (46), Passenger" -I've been waiting for you.
How about it?
Let's go have a drink over there.
Sir! Allow me to carry those!
No, thanks!
Party of one, sir?
Yes.
Excluding that boy, this man's number 10,
he's the last one.
All right, we can set out then, can't we?
We're already behind schedule.
Not yet! There's that old man who came at the beginning.
He left to go get something he forgot,
but hasn't come back yet.
What? That old man...
he was just here and said he wanted to take a short nap before dinner
so he didn't want to be disturbed.
What? When'd he gets back anyway?
Well, at any rate, we have the ten passengers.
I'm sorry, please send the rest of the contestants home.
All right! I'll go!
Now then, sir, you'll be in room 107.
Thanks!
Wait a minute!
Excuse me, but haven't we met somewhere before?
No.
"Minoru Ebina (42), Passenger" -You must be mistaken.
I've never seen you before today.
Did you find someone on the police wanted list, Superintendent Samezaki?
Thanks to you people, I'm certain we'll have a safe journey, Mr. Mouri.
What?
After all, he is a former police officer
and you are a private investigator.
There're three of you on board!
Three of us?
There's someone else besides us?
Yes! Another private investigator,
although he doesn't look it.
Thank you all for joining us today on the S.S. Symphony,
we will now leave the dock.
We are scheduled to arrive in Ogasawara tomorrow morning,
relax and have a pleasant journey!
I'm the king of the world!
She said she wanted to that once in her lifetime.
She's been watching too many movies.
What is she going to do if we really sink? What a bad omen!
Well...
"Sadao Kujirai (50), Passenger" -The mighty ocean glowing in the sunset.
With the fantastic view right in front of us,
I don't blame her for wanting to shout like that.
That felt good!
The sea certainly is wonderful.
It is! It makes you forget all the unpleasant things!
You're right.
The sea does do that.
It hides everything.
"Nagisa Isogai (27), Passenger" -Painful memories,
the uncertain future,
and even corpses.
What?
Did you say corpses?
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have said such a horrible thing.
My father drowned awhile back. I can't help thinking of it.
I'm sorry to hear that.
We've all got to be grateful to Mr. Furukawa got sponsoring this tour.
I know who he is!
Remember that seal I picked up?
That's when I saw it.
The name Furukawa was on it.
Conan, you saw it too, didn't you?
Yes.
So that's why you thanked him back then.
That's right!
You see!
That man with the seal is Mr. Furukawa!
I'm sure he intends to reveal his identity during dinner
and surprise everyone.
That's strange.
I asked him his name
and I'm positive he said it was Kameda.
You're kidding!
Hey, Mouri! They're announcing dinner!
All right, thank you!
So you're the famous Sleeping Kogoro.
That's right.
What an honour.
I'm going back to my room and rest for a bit.
You still get seasick, I see.
May I pour you more wine?
Yes, thank you!
This ship is so huge and there are so few passengers on board,
it seems like such a waste.
I agree with you!
Counting the two passengers resting in their rooms,
there's only eleven of you on board.
That's if you include me!
The two passengers you're talking about
is that the other private investigator and the old man?
-Yes! -I passed that old man in the corridor.
He seems to be the quiet type. What does he do?
Well, it seems he's a marine researcher
and his name is Saizo Kano.
Kano Saizo?
Where is his room?
His room number is 101.
Saizo Kano? I've heard that name somewhere before.
You idiot! How could you forget?
Many years ago, you and I both were after him,
he was the mastermind behind the 400 million yen heist.
"Saizo Kano" -He is Saizo Kano, the Mastermind in the shadows!
You have the master key, don't you?
Yes!
Listen, if it's him, he may have a gun.
As soon as you open the door, get out of the way!
Yes, sir!
Don't worry! Please calm down.
I've unlocked it.
Let's go!
What is this?
Strange, it looks like no one's been inside.
Are you sure this is the room?
Yes! There's no mistake!
Darn it!
I'll look on the lower deck!
Mouri, you check the upper!
Yes, sir!
"Engine Room"
Hey!
Where are you?
I know you're in here!
I read the letter!
Hey!
If he's not in the room, then he could be on the deck.
Who is in the room next door, 102?
It's the other private investigator's room.
He hasn't been out of his room since he boarded the ship.
That sounds pretty suspicious.
Excuse me, sir, may I come in?
Sir.
Here, let me do it.
Hey, you! I know you're in there!
Answer me! Hey!
Guess we have no other choice.
Will you unlock this door too?
Be quiet!
What's the entire racket about?
What? Mr. Mouri?
What are all of you doing here?
That's what I'd like to ask you.
Mastermind in the shadows?
Now that you mention it, my dad told me about it
when I was a kid.
His real name's Saizo Kano.
He was the mastermind behind the 400 million yen heist 20 years ago.
The plan was perfectly calculated, nothing went wrong.
The job went off without a hitch
and they escaped the police so smoothly.
He was called "Mastermind in the shadows".
He was a loner. He changed partners with every job.
His trademark was he never hurt anyone during the crime.
But then during the robbery 20 years ago,
he killed his first victim.
And since that incident, he was never heard of again.
You mean that fellow was sleeping in the room next to mine?
Yes, but when we got there, he was long gone.
Mr. Samezaki is looking for him now.
That's real strange, I'm sure he was dead.
They found his clothes washed up on some beach,
there were bullet holes in them and bloodstains too.
My father told me that.
He's not dead!
That coat was planted to fool the police.
He wasn't the kind of guy who'd die that easily, kid.
I thought that he and his partners
were out there counting their money somewhere.
Who would have thought...
he'd be on the same ship?
But the statute of limitations on that case ran out 5 years ago.
Even if you caught up with them, you can't do a thing.
Idiot! Did you forget?
The statute of limitation for murder is 15 years.
But in a civil case, the statute of limitations is 20 years!
If you're ordered to return the money, you have to!
That's right. Unfortunately,
the statute of limitations has run out for Kano's arrest,
but his three partners can still be arrested.
If we can find Kano and make him tell us where the others are,
we can get the money back somehow.
There's a possibility his partners are on this ship too, isn't there?
Then when we get to Ogasawara,
let's notify the police and get them to help us search the ship.
After all, we're out at sea,
they can't get away so easily.
You fool! There's no time!
Like I said, today's a special day.
Tomorrow is the 20th anniversary of that robbery!
At exactly midnight tonight,
the statute of limitations will run out and they'll be free men.
Nobody can touch them after that!
You mean, in just two hours...
The statute limitations on the crime will run out completely?
What? Is that you, Hattori?
Hi, Ran, long time no see.
What's going on?
I didn't know you were on this ship too.
Yes, I was sleeping peacefully in my cabin
when this old guy came banging on my door.
Is Kazuha with you too?
Why bring her name up? She's not my girlfriend or anything!
We're not as close as you two!
What? Who are you talking about?
Well, I mean you and your dad, you're so close.
Don't get personal!
Did you find him, Mr. Samezaki?
That shadow man you were talking about.
No, your father and I were just leaving to continue the search!
All right. We'll be in the restaurant downstairs!
Hey, wait a minute! We've got to help them.
What did you say? Are you telling me to wait all by myself
when there's a dangerous man lurking somewhere on board?
Well... no.
All right, Dad. I'll just wait for you.
Okay!
I'll be waiting!
I'll be waiting, Dad!
Darn it!
Is something wrong, sir?
No, it's nothing!
All right, let's start from the top deck and work our way down.
Sure.
I would never have thought
that you were interested in dolphins!
Dolphins?
Didn't you come here after reading the advertisement in the newspaper?
No, I'm here because I got a strange letter!
A strange letter?
Yes, about a week ago,
I received a letter telling me to come to Ogasawara for a case.
They enclosed 100,000 yen as an advance.
100,000 yen?
That's right, but it was pretty weird,
all the bills were the old design
and there was no return address.
What about a name?
Masaru Furukawa was written.
-Furukawa? -Furukawa?
You know who he is?
What are you talking about?
Furukawa is the name of the man who planned this whole tour!
Is that so?
I had no idea.
The letter told me I'd be able to get aboard
if I showed the bill at the gate. That's all.
So you were invited on board to work as a private investigator.
I've never taken a job where I got paid first,
so I intended to return the money personally.
That's why I got on board.
Besides, I was pretty interested in what kind of case it was.
But what a coincidence!
Here we are, all on the same ship!
Actually, I called you when I got to Haneda Airport.
I thought I'd ask Kudo...
I mean, Mr. Mouri to come with me.
But no one answered the phone.
We must have just left.
But here we are anyway.
That's why they say monkeys will attract monkeys
and private investigators will attract their lot too!
Right, kid?
So you're the other private investigator?
You're awfully young.
Well, yes!
So, have you found that so called Saizo Kano fellow?
No, I think they're still looking for him.
Hey!
You want to use this?
Thanks, I appreciate it.
No problem.
Hey, why don't we all play some poker?
We can go to the lounge over there.
Good idea, but what about cards?
Don't worry, I brought a deck with me.
How about you fellows?
You look like you need some entertainment.
-Find him? -No, he isn't anywhere.
Where'd this jerk disappears to?
Darn, we have less than an hour.
-Mouri. -Yes!
I'm not giving up.
Not on this case, not until the very last second.
I swear!
Superintendent Samezaki! Let's search one more time!
Yes, you're right.
Let's go over the ship one more time, Mouri!
Yes, sir!
Full house!
Gosh, you won again.
All right...
After the next game, whoever has the lowest score
will change places with Mr. Kujirai.
Excuse me, do you know what time it is?
Yes, it's 11:55 pm.
You've been asking the time so many times,
are you expecting something?
It's just that tomorrow is a very special day.
There, two pairs aces and nines.
Wait...
I'm the loser.
All right, Mr. Kujira's turn.
All right, miss, be gentle with me.
Hey, when you said tomorrow's a special day,
did you mean the anniversary of your girlfriend's death?
What?
Your cocktail.
It's a Bloody Mary, isn't it?
Don't tell me it's the day a Princess you adored passed away.
No, nothing like that!
Dad! Did you find him?
He's nowhere to be found.
Where's the former Superintendent of Police?
He says he'll search until times up.
Would you like something to drink?
Water.
Yes, sir.
I guess I'll be calling it quits soon.
That's it for me too.
Yes, me too.
All right, after we're done,
I'll fix the cards and bring them to your room later.
I'd appreciate that.
How much is my bar tab?
-Let's see. You had two martinis. -I'll pay my bill too.
What? My wallet's...
Could this be yours?
Yes, it is. That's mine.
It was on the floor in the corridor, so I picked it up!
Come on! I haven't taken anything!
Sorry, but I just want to be sure.
Are you quitting too, Mr. Kujirai?
No, I'm just going to the toilet.
Let's take a break, I'll be back soon.
Time's run out.
We can't touch that case now.
But since I retired two years ago,
I have no authority anyway.
Sir.
Can I still get a drink?
Sure, no problem.
Give me a beer.
Yes, sir!
You did your best, sir.
Mouri!
Come on!
Mouri, let's drink up!
All right! I'm with you all the way!
The drinks are on me!
-Gosh, that's generous of you. -I realise it was his case
but isn't he taking it a little too personal?
But just like always...
What was that?
It came from outside. The upper deck!
A gunshot?
Mouri! What time is it?
12:08 am!
The flag!
The flag's burning!
Hey, what was that?
It sounded like fireworks.
Hey, Kudo.
Do you think this just some prank?
No. Look at that, Hattori.
What?
What is this?
Something's written on it!
Don't touch the knife!
Who are you talking to? I'm no amateur!
Excuse me, go and get me a plastic bag.
Yes, sir!
Do you always carry those things around?
Old habits are hard to break!
What's written on it?
"Poseidon, the God of the Sea gave me life,"
"thus my shadow is resurrected."
-Mr. Kujirai? -He... he's alive.
I knew it. That guy is...
That guy is...
alive!
-What is that? -What is that?
What's happened?
Captain! Explosion on the stern!
Stop all engines! Extinguish the flames!
Stop all engines!
What happened?
There was an explosion at the stern this time!
-What? -What's on fire?
This is the box the emergency escape ladder is kept it.
But why would anyone do this?
A body!
Somebody's being burned!
Darn, it's burnt to a crisp.
It's so bad we determine the time of death or identify the victim.
It's possible the victim is Saizo Kano,
the man who disappeared from the ship.
We can't say for sure until we do a thorough investigation.
I think it could be Mr. Kanie.
Look at the wristwatch he's wearing.
When I asked him for the time,
I'm pretty sure that was the watch he had on.
Now that you mention it.
Although it's badly burned, that looks like the sweater he was wearing.
Those slacks look like the ones he was wearing.
How awful. Why would anyone kill Mr. Kanie?
It's pretty funny though.
Funny?
Just look at him, looks how he's posed.
His upper body and his arm is raised,
it looks like he's deliberately trying to show us his watch.
-Let me explain... -It's heat stiffening!
When a body is burning,
the heat causes the skeletal muscles to coagulate and shrink.
"Heat Stiffening" -The result is heat stiffening!
There are more muscles to bend the arms and legs
rather than stretch them.
And the joints begin to bend halfway
and the result is the body looks like it's in a boxer's fighting position.
So you see, the body gets into that position quite naturally!
Is that so?
But the important question is his watchband.
Watchband? What about it?
Take a good look, it's unbuckled, isn't it?
That doesn't mean anything. See the can near the victim's feet?
That explosion was probably set off with the gasoline in this can.
The explosion was powerful enough to destroy the can,
it probably blew the watch loose.
You're probably right.
It was must've also blown the plastic sheet off.
Plastic sheet?
Well, when we came here looking for Kano,
it was on the box.
Just like that one.
And then? You did look inside the box, didn't you?
No, as you can see, the box is tied securely from the outside,
I didn't think anyone could hide inside.
Besides, no one was inside the box.
When I got back to the lounge, Mr. Kanie was still there.
Hey, Mouri.
Who is that smart aleck kid?
His name is Heiji Hattori.
His father is the Chief of Police of the Osaka Metropolitan Police.
You mean, he's Heizo's kid?
No wonder he knows so much.
So you know the Chief of Police?
Yes, we sparred with each other quite often during kendo practice.
But I was no match for him.
Hey, Hattori!
Look at that strange thing on his face.
What?
It... It's silicone!
Yes, the material is polygemethylcyclosun,
commonly known as silicone!
The fire warped it but these things are widely used in plastic surgery
to heighten the bridge of the nose.
So that means this fellow had changed his looks.
Yes, I'm sure about it!
Excuse me.
We'll cover him with this.
Why would he have plastic surgery?
Well, maybe he is one of the four
who pulled off the 400 million yen robbery.
He could've been part of the gang.
If the victim really is Mr. Kanie,
then there's a strong possibility Mr. Kameda is also part of the gang.
They seemed to get along so well.
It seemed like a get-together between friends who'd had plastic surgery
and hadn't seen each other since then.
Which means the other partner is...
it could be Kujirai, he seemed so interested in the case
and he looks very nervous.
He seems a likely candidate.
You may be right.
He acted a little strange when Mr. Kanie gave him his lighter.
And another thing bothers me,
it's what he shouted on the upper deck.
He is alive.
That guy is alive!
It was so obvious, he panicked when he saw the knife through the bill!
The writing on the bill said,
"Poseidon, the God of the Sea gave me life,"
"thus my shadow is resurrected."
The "shadow" is referring to Saizo Kano,
the Mastermind in the shadows
and "resurrected", means he was once killed somewhere!
He was probably killed by his three partners in that robbery
and then he took on the identity of the mysterious old man.
But I don't understand,
not just about the identity of the old man
who disappeared from the ship,
but why do all three of the men involved in the robbery
have to be on the same ship on the day the statute of limitations runs out?
And putting out that strange advertisement to boot?
And I'm curious about that fellow,
Masaru Furukawa who put out that advertisement.
Is that the real name of one of the robbers? Or is it...
Anyway, that old man holds the key to the mystery.
I'll bet we'll find a lot of skeletons when we rattle the closet.
Yes.
What? You don't remember?
I hear you very clearly on the upper deck!
You said "I knew it, that guy is alive!"
Did I say that?
Don't play games with me!
Come on, tell the truth, you'll feel better.
You meant Saizo Kano, didn't you?
I... I don't know.
I don't know anything!
I really don't!
We're not getting anywhere!
Sir!
I've talked to the crew members!
And, how did it go?
All their alibis are perfect.
At the time of the explosion,
excluding us passengers, all the crew members,
including the Captain were always working in a group.
And since the explosion took place
after we heard what sounded like a gunshot
and ran up to the upper deck,
it means the only person capable of starting the fire
is someone who wasn't with us on the deck.
So it must be Saizo Kano,
he's the only one we can't account for.
No, there's one other person, isn't there?
Well, Mr. Kameda, he went back to his cabin
because he wasn't feeling well.
No one's seen him since then.
Now that you mentioned it...
Hurry down to his cabin right now and bring him here!
Yes, sir!
Okay! I'm going with him!
-Me too! -Wait...
Wait for me! I'm going with you!
Yes, I understand.
I'll see you there then.
Yes, sir!
Continue on to Ogasawara!
Aren't we turning back, Captain?
No, they're sending a helicopter out first thing in the morning.
Our ship is loaded with cargo, they need on the island.
And as soon as they're ready,
the Coast Guard will also send their boat out.
So those detectives will have to do their best until help arrives.
Start engines! Raise speed up to 20 knots!
-Start engines! -Start engines!
Mr. Kameda.
Seems like he's not in. Hey! Go and borrow the master key again.
What? It's not locked.
Mr. Kameda, I'm coming in.
What's this?
It looks like no one's in.
If so, we'd better hurry and report this to Mr. Samezaki.
Isn't that right, Heiji?
Hey, where are you?
Hattori? Conan?
How'd it go? You find anything?
Yes, in the engine room below.
There was a little blood on the floor
and I found empty shell casings
and this strange letter.
I found a suspicious piece of paper too.
It was crushed up and thrown away though.
Where'd you find it?
You know the toilet at the entrance to the restaurant,
it was in the trash can inside.
Inside the toilet's trash can?
And then? What does the letter say?
"Waiting in the engine room. Masaru Furukawa."
Masaru Furukawa again.
Blood stains and an empty shell casing?
There it is! One shot to the temple!
There's no doubt about it, it's a gunshot wound!
The victim came to the engine room because of this letter.
And he was shot in the head, then put inside the box.
Yes, I think that's reasonably correct.
What about that piece of paper you found?
It was probably written on the same word processor as yours.
"Meet me at the stern, Masaru Furukawa."
This is proof that someone lured that fellow Mr. Kujirai out!
How do you know it was Mr. Kujirai?
Two of the crew members saw him.
It was past midnight, that guy looked scared
and they heard he was yelling, "Hey, I'm here!".
And when the crew called out to him, the fellow got shook up.
Please don't tell anyone you saw me here.
That's what he said.
Then it seems he went back to the lounge where we all were.
Those crew thought someone might show up there,
so they kept watch but no one came.
And just when they were about to return to their posts,
they said they heard gunshots from the upper deck.
And was that box burning?
Of course not!
And there didn't seem to be any timing device either.
What this means is, the killer fired a shot on the upper deck,
then set the flag on fire
and when he saw everyone was on the upper deck,
he snuck down here and set the box on fire.
If that's true, then Mr. Kujirai's fear is understandable.
Yes. After all, if he was unlucky,
he'd have been killed and set on fire here too.
One problem remains,
is it possible for the killer to fire the shot on the upper deck,
then come here without being seen by anyone?
Well, I have an idea who the killer is,
and in time, I'll be able to prove it.
You've figured it out too?
You mean you have too?
Then shall we compare notes?
First, the mysterious old man calling himself Saizo Kano.
Like you said, he left the ship
and no one noticed that he returned,
but somehow he was on board, then.
That's a trick set up by the killer.
-A fake! -A fake!
"Fake: To make it seem like. To pretend."
There are only two people who could've done it.
That's right!
What we have to look at very carefully here is
the heat stiffened body's elbows were in front of his face
and the fact that his knees were completely bent!
It proves both arms were raised
when the body was put in the box and shifted!
Only one person had a reason for doing that!
But that too was a ruse!
The real killer faked his death
and is still hiding somewhere on this ship.
What? What are you talking about?
Look at this! This watch is the proof.
What are you talking about?
That's the killer's trump card.
This is very interesting.
How unusual. Our deductions aren't the same.
Yes, this has only happened once when we first met.
All right.
Let's see whose deduction is correct.
Shall we make a contest of this?
-Hey! Wait up! -Oh, yeah!
Fix that watch, will you?
What?
Are you telling me to get this burnt up watch moving again?
Of course not! I mean put it back where it came from.
I see.
What? Kameda wasn't in his cabin?
Yes, we looked for him for a while.
You fool! I don't know so many people can just disappear!
Out of my way! I'll look for him!
I'm off to search for him too,
so I'd like all of you to wait here for just a little longer...
I refuse. You're a private detective
and the other man is a former police officer, isn't that right?
I don't think either of you have any right to keep us here.
But...
Sorry, but I'm going back to my room and rest.
I'm going too.
-Me too. -Wait!
You could put yourselves danger if you act rashly!
No need to worry.
We can take care of ourselves.
Right?
It has to be here!
If my deduction is right,
there has to be a place someone can hide without being discovered.
It can't be.
A good hiding place?
You have an idea don't you?
Some place that you usually can't get into.
Some place that's off limits!
You little troublemaker. There's a a killer on board
and you go gallivanting!
It was strange.
Where's Hattori?
You didn't run into him?
It's wrong!
Kudo and I were both wrong!
Captain!
The ship's route is clear for the next 30 kilometers!
Okay! Raise speed up to 293 points, 30 knots!
Speed to 30 knots!
Who is it?
Who is the real killer?
Hey, didn't you hear a strange water noise?
Strange water noise?
A bonito probably jumped.
I know I heard it!
It sounded like something fell into the ocean,
it's very suspicious!
Like I told you, it was probably the sound of fish jumping!
I hear there are a lot of bonito and flying fish in this area.
Excuse me! Did you see that boy who speaks with a Kansai accent?
Kansai accent?
He came here to borrow a flashlight.
Flashlight?
That means there's a good chance
he went out on the deck to look for something!
Then...
That sound... No way!
It can't be!
Wait!
It's impossible! He'd never let that happen!
Hattori!
Where are you?
Answer me!
Hattori.
It can't be true! It can't!
Hattori!
Hey, kid!
You've got to be careful!
You could've fallen over.
-But... -He's right, kid!
The ocean is extremely vast.
If a person were to fall in, a mere human being
would be helpless death is a certainty.
Conan!
What in the world are you doing?
But Heiji is...
That boy again.
He's probably off somewhere looking for clues!
Dad's right!
Don't worry, he'll pop up soon.
Yoshimi.
Well...
Your voice sounded just like someone I knew.
Never mind that, what's going on here?
What are you three doing here?
She asked us to help her look for something.
You were looking for something?
My pendant.
I noticed it was gone just when I was going to bed,
I was looking all over for it, then I ran into these fellows.
They didn't look like they had anything to do,
so I asked them to help me.
There's a better chance of finding it with three
rather than one person searching.
Well, are you talking about this locket with the photo in it?
What?
The clasp was unhooked,
I found it on the bow.
Yes, this is it, thank you.
I must have dropped it this evening when I was up there.
Then is the little girl in the picture, you, Nagisa?
Is that your father carrying you?
Yes.
For goodness sakes, why didn't you return it to her earlier?
But there was a hole in her father's face
and I didn't know who it belonged to!
After all, it could have been someone else carrying their daughter.
I intended to ask who it belonged to during dinner but I forgot!
I'm sorry, I didn't realise there was a hole in it.
It's all right.
It's an old photo taken over 20 years ago.
This is the only thing I have left
to remind me of my late father.
Are you all out of your minds?
A killer is on board and you're all wandering around!
"Toji Samezaki (62)" -Mouri!
Why did you let them out of the restaurant?
Well...
They said they wanted to go back to their cabins and rest.
That's right!
You have no right to give us orders!
Besides, I didn't want to stay here anymore!
"Nagisa Isogai (27)" -Especially not with a hysterical old man!
What did you say?
If you say being alone is dangerous,
it'll be better to lock myself in my room
and spend the night playing cards with these kids.
Isn't that right?
Well...
"Sadao Kujirai (50)" -I don't think
"Minoru Ebina (42)" -it's a good idea to split up.
I think it's safer if we all stay together in one place.
By the way, have you found Mr. Kameda you were looking for?
No, he seems to have disappeared!
Along with Mr. Kano!
Have you seen Heiji Hattori?
No way! Are you telling me Heizo's son is also missing?
Darn, what's happening on this ship?
All right then! I don't anyone of you to go anywhere alone!
The killer could be someone outside this group
or it could be one of us.
The killer could be lying in wait for us to be alone!
He may be right.
When we heard the first gunshot,
Mr. Samezaki was with us in the lounge
and Mr. Kujirai had just returned from the restaurant.
And right after we all ran to the upper deck,
there was an explosion at the stern
and the box with the body inside was set on fire.
We all ran up to the deck together
and even Mr. Ebina and Ms. Isogai who joined us later
wouldn't have been able to start the fire.
Which means that
since we can't at present identify the fire victim,
the only ones capable of setting the fire
were the men not on the deck with us,
Mr. Kameda, Mr. Kanie
and the old man calling himself Saizo Kano.
But something's bothering me,
it's the strange behaviour of the people in this group.
And Mr. Samezaki's almost fanatical reaction.
What happened?
What happened during that robbery 20 years ago?
I'm going to the toilet,
please wait for me!
Darn it all! If only Hattori were here,
he'd easily be able to ask Pops about the case.
Where in the world'd he got off to?
"Dr. Agasa's home"
Hello? Hey, how are things going?
What? The 400 million yen robbery 20 years ago?
"The statute of limitations of" -We were just watching
"400 million yen robbery is running out today" -a special on that case!
The statute of limitations is running out
so they've been doing a lot of specials on it since last night!
I thought you'd probably want to see it,
so we're recording it.
Did they mention something about the thieves?
Wait a second.
I'm sure there was something!
They identified the ringleader, Saizo Kano,
but as for the remaining three,
all they had were montages and no names!
Did they mention whether Kano died or not?
Yes, his blood stained coat with a bullet hole
and it washed up on shore,
so the police deduced he was killed
by his three accomplices after a falling out!
But how did they know it was Kano's coat?
In the inside pocket of the coat,
they found a photo that he always carried on his person.
It was a picture of him carrying his daughter.
What?
It certainly was a tragic case.
The alarm went off and it scared one of the robbers,
he panicked and fired wildly.
One of the bullets hit and killed a teller named Samezaki.
What? You mean someone was shot?
A female teller, her name was Yoshimi Samezaki.
The poor thing, she was still so young.
Yoshimi Samezaki?
It can't be. But it's just too much of a coincidence.
Why are there so many people connected to that case here on this ship?
Who is this Masaru Furukawa who sponsored the tour?
"Masaru Furukawa" -Who in the world is he anyway?
What was that?
I have to go now!
Call me if you think of something!
Hey...
Where'd that come from?
The stern, I think!
All right! I'll go from the left,
you go around from the right!
Yes, sir!
Hey! Conan!
No one's here.
That's impossible!
-Look around! -Yes, sir!
Hattori, what's happened?
Why don't you show yourself?
If you'd heard that sound, you'd be the first one here.
What's happened to you, Hattori?
Sir! Do you suppose he went this way back inside?
It's Kano.
Kano is the killer, I just know it!
He's trying to confuse us by firing shots all over the ship!
But what is he trying to do?
It's... it's me.
He's...
he's trying to kill me.
I...
don't want to die.
I don't want to die yet.
Please! Protect me, please!
I'll tell you everything.
Yes, that's right.
I was one of Kano's accomplices
in the that robbery 20 years ago.
I came aboard this ship
because the three of us wanted to celebrate
the end of 20 years of hiding out.
One of the others sent me a letter.
He said there was no chance of being caught once the ship sailed
because the statute of limitations would run out.
There was an old 10,000 bill in the letter,
but it'd been so long since we'd seen each other.
We'd all changed our faces and our names,
so we didn't know who was who
until Kanie called out to me.
And he told me our other accomplice was Kameda.
And? So who's the one trying to kill you?
Well...
I don't know who it is.
You're lying.
It's Saizo Kano, isn't it? The man you and the others double-crossed.
That's impossible!
One of the others shot him to death 20 years ago.
Then it's probably one of the others.
He wants all the money for himself!
You haven't used that money yet, have you?
That's what I thought at first
but something's strange.
It just doesn't make any sense!
What was that?
Everyone! Get down!
Are you all right?
Kujirai!
Where? Where were you shot?
Don't move!
You've been shot!
Darn! Where'd the shot come from?
Hey, kid! Get down!
Somebody's out there!
There! On the bow!
You jerk!
-I'm not letting him get away this time! -Sir!
Hey! You've nowhere to run!
Throw your gun down and surrender yourself.
Hey, Kano! Are you listening to me?
You are Saizo Kano, aren't you?
Hey! Say something!
This is... Kanie?
That's impossible!
One shot to the head.
He died instantly.
Yes.
The body's still warm.
His blood hasn't coagulated yet.
There're powder burns on his temple, indicating he placed the gun,
there and pulled the trigger.
When the gunshot was heard,
everyone except Kanie was in the restaurant.
There's no other explanation Kanie shot himself in the head,
which means Kanie who was hiding out on the bow of this ship,
was so upset to hear his old partner
blab about the robbery 20 years ago
that he tried to shoot him
but failed to kill him!
But realising he could not escape,
he gives up and commits suicide.
What a fool!
But...
Doesn't that seem strange to you?
The burnt body at the bow
was wearing Mr. Kanie's clothes and his wristwatch, wasn't he?
Then whose body is that anyway?
Well, it's either Kameda,
another of the accomplices who disappeared earlier
or Saizo Kano.
Either way, Kanie here was the killer.
He disguised the body to look like him
and set it on fire to make it appear he was dead.
The question is, how Kanie managed to evade our search
and hide out here.
What's this?
There's something weird tied behind this guy.
This is...
A rope ladder!
No one would find this hiding place
if you were playing hide and seek!
I get it.
Kanie hid here, hanging on to the ladder.
There's some rope marks on his arms and legs.
So I'm sure you're right.
But I don't understand.
Why go to all the trouble of making it look like you died
and then hide out here?
The only explanation I can think of is
he wanted to surprise his next victim by appearing suddenly
before him filling the guy with fear.
But who was Kanie trying to kill
that he had to go through so much trouble?
Kujirai, who just got shot was one of his old buddies, wasn't he?
You're right.
Look at all the blood.
It looks like an artery's been damaged.
He needs medical attention right away.
Ran's gone to get the first aid kit.
You are a very lucky person,
you got off with only a hole through your coat and arm.
Hey, Mouri, I found it!
I found where the bullet passed through.
I'm pretty sure Kanie fired the gun from the bow
and it passed through the window here.
Now all we have to do is find the bullet
which should be embedded somewhere.
Well, do you mean this?
Yes, no doubt about it, this is it!
What a sharp shooter.
He missed his target
but he fired the shot from way over there with a pistol.
Have you forgotten? One of the men Kano hired
to help pull off the job was very handy with firearms.
That's right, we were able to learn
he probably served in some foreign army,
but that was about it.
Yes, so that must have been Kanie!
Dad!
You got the first aid kit!
We've got to stop the bleeding.
What? Where's Conan?
What?
Isn't he somewhere around there?
What? A boy with a Kansai accent?
He came to borrow a flashlight but never returned.
He hasn't come to the bridge either.
It's strange. Where could he have gone?
Could you search everyone's cabin just to make sure?
Sure but I doubt we'll find him.
That's right...
When we were looking for that Kameda fellow with Mr. Samezaki,
we went through all the cabins too.
Well, did you happen to notice
if he might been searching for something somewhere?
He is a private detective too.
I didn't notice anything.
Besides, all the cabins were locked, except for Mr. Kameda's.
Come to think of it, there is one cabin we didn't search!
That's right, it was so neat.
-What? -You know, that guy with the glasses,
Mr. Ebina, it was his room.
There was only a trunk in the middle of the room,
the bed looked like it hadn't even used.
It looked like he hadn't even unlocked his trunk.
Can you show me where that cabin is?
Mr. Mouri asked me to look inside!
Conan?
Conan!
Hey, kid.
Are you sure Mr. Mouri wanted it like this?
Yes! And he also said he didn't want anyone else to know about it.
Quick, let's get back inside!
That body is giving me the creeps.
Yes, you're right.
Go back to where the others are, kid!
Okay!
This tour sure turned into a nightmare.
I heard the killer committed suicide though.
And that guy Furukawa who planned this tour,
I'll bet he is waiting at Ogasawara for the ship to dock.
Masaru Furukawa,
the man who planned this tour.
All the mysteries start here.
If the killer is Kanie
and this Masaru Furukawa is also Kanie,
then all the pieces to this case will fit,
but I'm still not convinced.
There's the watch the body had on
and that Furukawa seal Mr. Kameda had is another puzzle.
Darn it, I wish I at least knew who this Masaru Furukawa is.
Excuse me.
Did you see a kid that wearing glasses?
Don't tell me...
Masaru Furukawa is...
A burn mark?
And the paint's coming off on the other side.
Maybe...
Conan!
Here's another!
And other here!
I've got it.
That's how you can control the time and everyone's movements.
And that's where Hattori's role as private detective fits in.
But why Hattori?
He's famous in Osaka but that's all.
Why hire a private detective all the way from Osaka?
Gosh!
You're always wandering around and making us worry!
I... I was just about to go back.
That's why I...
I'm begging you.
Don't leave me alone.
Conan, you know what a scared cat I am.
If you get lost,
I'll have to search this spooky ship all by myself!
I... I'm sorry.
By the way, where'd you get this tennis ball?
I found it under the table at the restaurant just now
while I was looking for you.
I asked who it belonged to but no one came forward.
Did Mr. Samezaki say something when he saw it?
Because he and dad went off somewhere before seeing it.
They were talking very loudly.
It was something about an old bullet wound
they found on Mr. Kanie's body.
Where was everyone when Pops and the others
left the restaurant the first time to look for Mr. Kano?
They all left too, separately.
But when they came back with Heiji,
the others were already back.
I see.
I've figured everything out.
I've solved the mystery behind this strange case!
I've figured it all out, now all I have to do is prove it.
Excuse me.
We're looking the boy who speaks with a Kansai dialect.
That kid asked us the same thing and we've been looking for him too.
But we can't find him anywhere.
Sorry, Dr. Agasa.
I can't talk now.
I'll call you later...
What did you say?
We'll get the entire crew to search the ship again.
I'd appreciate that.
Gosh. What are you doing here?
Well, nothing.
I'm getting worried, where did he go to anyway?
Who are you talking about?
Are you serious?
Hattori, of course!
Him?
He's probably swimming with the fishes somewhere.
Mouri.
This guy might just be...
Yes, I know what you mean...
Dad?
Pops? What's wrong?
Pops?
What're you doing?
Dad?
Ran, tell all the others to come here!
What?
I've figured everything out.
Go on, hurry!
What?
Is that true? You've solved the case?
That's right.
I've figured everything out
the entire truth behind this case.
You're not going to say that Kanie is not the killer, are you?
No, Kanie is the killer.
Like you said, he pretended to be dead
then lay in wait for a chance to kill his victim.
Mr. Kujirai, that was you!
Then whose body is that, that was set on fire?
It's Mr. Kameda.
First,
Mr. Kanie lured Mr. Kameda out and shot him,
then hid the body inside the emergency ladder box at the bow
and returned to join the others.
Then he set the flag on the upper deck on fire,
when everyone ran up to the deck, he set fire to the box.
The reason why he didn't change Mr. Kameda's clothes
as soon as he was put in the box is
he was waiting for the superintendent to give up
the search for the old man named Kano.
It takes a long time to dress someone
and he couldn't risk being seen by the superintendent.
And the proof is the way the victim's arms
were up beside his face!
If you raise the arms when putting the body into the box,
even after rigor mortis sets in,
dressing the body is easy.
And the reason the watch wasn't clasped was
his watch probably didn't fit Mr. Kameda.
Before setting the fire,
Mr. Kanie called Mr. Kujirai out to the stern
and was tried to set him up as the killer.
Because the first person found hanging around a crime scene
usually viewed as a strong suspect.
But why? Why did he have to make it look like he was dead?
He wanted to surprise his next victim, which was Mr. Kujirai,
and fill him with fear.
He wanted vengeance against the men who betrayed him 20 years ago.
Betrayed?
Yes!
That old man named Kano was also a ruse to scare the men,
the old man did not really exist.
Look at the wound on Mr. Kanie's body.
This old bullet wound is the very proof!
You... don't mean...
That's right! This is the Mastermind in the shadows,
the man everyone thought died 20 years ago,
Saizo Kano.
You're lying...
I don't believe you.
You're lying.
This man couldn't possibly be Saizo Kano.
Because Kano is... Kano is...
He is my father!
Your father?
That's right.
Saizo Kano, the Mastermind in the shadows,
is my real father.
The reason I joined this tour is
I wanted to find him who was rumoured he was killed 20 years ago
by his accomplices.
I thought that maybe he was still alive,
but no one here reminded me of him.
But what if he'd had plastic surgery and changed his appearance?
Don't be ridiculous!
I'd recognise him no matter how he looked!
Do you think I couldn't recognise my own father?
And it'd be the same with him!
If he saw me, you'd know by his reaction!
20 years may have gone by, but it we'd know each other.
That's exactly what I wanted to hear.
Forgive me, Nagisa.
I had my suspicions but I needed proof.
So that I could completely destroy the killer's plan.
The killer's plan?
Yes, the killer rigged it to look like Mr. Kanie shot Mr. Kameda,
dressed him in his clothes and set him on fire.
This would make us think he faked his death.
Then he hid somewhere firing shots leading us on wild goose chases.
After failing in his attempt to kill Mr. Kujirai,
he realised he could not escape, so he killed himself.
That was the scenario.
It was all a ruse to make us believe Mr. Kanie was Saizo Kano
and that the killings on this ship
were to carry out a vendetta against the men
who betrayed him 20 years ago.
Then, you mean the killer is...
That's right. It's someone else
and he is right here!
No way!
Hey... What are you talking about, Mouri?
You know for yourself.
When the explosion went off at the bow,
all the passengers here were on the upper deck!
And all the other crew members have alibis.
Besides, you said so yourself,
you'd need a timing device to have set it off...
I found it!
I found the timing device!
You found it? In there?
He used a cigarette.
He put a can of gasoline in the box,
then placed a lighted cigarette on the lid of the box.
If you wind it with thread,
it'll take about ten minutes for the thread to burn.
The cigarette will fall inside
and a fire will start automatically.
But then, how do you explain the four shots
that came from the bow and the two from the prow?
Even then all of us here were...
He used a cigarette then too.
He probably taped some fireworks
and a cigarette to the railing.
After it explodes, the evidence will fall into the ocean.
There were burn marks on the railing
and some paint had been off, that proves my theory!
By the way, regarding the flag burning on the upper deck,
he used the same trick, first soaking the flag in gasoline,
then attaching the cigarette and fireworks.
Which means, by using this method,
anyone could have committed the crime.
So who did it?
Who did all that?
It's...
It's too late!
-What was that? -There was an explosion in the rear!
Stop all engines! All stations check for damages!
Yes, sir!
Lower deck! Any damages?
No damages!
No need to worry.
The bomb just went off about 100 meters behind the ship.
100 meters behind the ship?
Was that a bomb?
Just to be on the safe side,
we put it on a rubber boat which we tied a rope to the other end
was attached to the railing on the bow,
then we let it out on the ocean.
Mr. Ebina.
It was the bomb we found in your trunk.
-What? -Trunk?
How did you know?
Your room was very clean, even your sheets were unwrinkled
and your trunk looked like it hadn't even been opened,
then when I noticed how concerned you were about the time,
it made me suspicious.
That bomb was probably meant to kill
all the members of that robbery 20 years ago,
you prepared it a long time ago, didn't you?
You wanted to avenge the death of your co-worker, didn't you?
Co-worker?
The distinctive way he counted money,
indicated he worked in a bank.
Also, he whispered the name of the female bank teller
who was killed in the robbery.
Yoshimi Samezaki.
She wasn't just another co-worker,
she was...
she was the most important thing in the world to me.
You're the one who cried so loudly at my daughter's funeral?
Yes, that's right!
After the funeral, I quit the bank
and I've been going from job to job ever since,
looking for those killers in my own way!
Even after the statute of limitations ran out!
I see. So it was you.
So you're the special person she asked me to meet.
If only you...
If only you... that day...
If only you'd come to the bank like you promised!
She... she'd probably...
Forgive me.
One of my men was stabbed that day.
I heard about what happened when I was at the hospital.
You saw that advertisement in the newspaper
and joined the tour too, didn't you?
Yes, I thought this might be it.
If I was wrong,
I intended to throw the trunk into the ocean before the bomb went off.
So it was you?
Did you kill all those men involved with the robbery?
What? No!
I didn't do it!
I just brought a bomb with me!
I didn't know anything about the guns!
It's the truth! Please believe me!
It's all right. I know it.
I know you're not the killer.
Like I said before, to set Mr. Kanie up as the killer,
one had to make this seem like Saizo Kano's act of vengeance,
or it wouldn't seem plausible.
The reason the killer disguised himself as an old man,
then left the ship and returned as someone else is,
he wanted to create the illusion that Saizo Kano was alive.
He left a message on the bill hinting of Kano on the upper deck.
This was all part of his plan to make us think
Kano was trying to scare the men who betrayed him.
And all of this was so that we would think that
the gunshot wound on Mr. Kanie's body was the wound Mr. Kano got
when he was shot by one of his accomplices 20 years ago!
You mean that wound...
He probably got that when he served in the foreign army long ago.
Do you remember? One of the suspects
was reported to have served in an foreign army.
And he was one of the accomplices...
So that means...
Yes, the only one who could use that fact in this scheme
is someone who knew about Mr Kanie's wound.
You don't mean...
One of his old partners, Mr. Kujirai!
You're the only one, aren't you?
That's insane.
First, you saw Mr. Kameda leave the restaurant,
then you mentioned Saizo Kano's name.
In the excitement, you went to the engine room
where you had told Mr. Kameda to wait and you shot him!
Then you hid his body in the box on the stern.
He was killed in the engine room?
Yes, I've already found blood stains, a shell casing
and the letter he used to lure Mr. Kameda in the engine room.
You probably slipped the letter under the cabin door.
Mr. Kujirai came back to the lounge
and waited for the superintendent to call off the search for Kano,
then went to meet with Mr. Kanie,
probably in the toilet next to the restaurant.
Mr. Kanie was probably already asleep due to being drugged,
then you stole his clothes and his wristwatch
and put them on Mr. Kameda and set up that timing device.
After that, you deliberately called attention to yourself
so that you had the crew to witness the box was not on fire yet,
and give us the impression you were called out there to meet someone.
The reason why you left the note in the toilet's trash can
was to pretend to be afraid of Kano
so that Kanie would approach you.
You were probably going to say that it was in that book of matches.
It was all to make us believe Mr. Kanie was behind everything
and that he had lured you out.
You set the cigarette device on the flag
before you changed the clothes on the body.
That way, you could run up with everyone
when we heard the explosion
and we would be your alibi.
You moved Mr. Kanie who was sleeping from the toilet to the prow
while we were all concentrating on the burning body at the stern.
Then you watched our movements and after some time had passed,
you placed another device at the stern.
After hearing the sound and we went running,
you went back to the prow
and pulled Mr. Kanie back up and shot him.
And then you shot yourself and fired another shot
through the window into the restaurant.
After that, all you had to do was set two more devices!
You came back to the stern
and had us all gather in the restaurant
where you gave us your false confession
and waited for the explosions to go off.
If you fell at the first explosion,
it would look like the shot came from the prow!
Wait a minute, Mouri.
I was with him when he fell and I saw the wound right then.
If he shot himself earlier, there'd be more blood.
He used a tennis ball!
Before he shot himself in the arm,
he had the tennis ball pressed against his artery,
it was to stop the flow of blood!
He held it there tightly until the explosion went off.
Ran found the ball under the table in the restaurant.
He probably threw it there in the confusion
after the second explosion.
But why didn't he kill Mr. Kanie when he first took him to the prow?
If Mr. Kanie committed suicide right after we found the burned body,
the killer's trick would seem unnatural.
The trick with disguising the body with Mr. Kanie's clothes!
The reason he raised the body's arms
and unclasped the watch was to create an illusion!
That's also why he hired Heiji Hattori, a private detective from Osaka.
Of course, Mr. Kujirai probably figured to hire us as instead.
But you hired a private detective from Osaka
because you lived in Kansai area, didn't you?
When people who live in the Kanto area
put cards back into the case,
we don't use the term "fix".
I see.
Now all we need is evidence.
You'll probably find it
when you check the area around the shattered glass.
You'll get a luminal reaction.
There'll be just a trace but you'll find some smears
from when he wiped the blood that splattered
when he shot himself.
No! It wasn't me!
This is a trap!
Someone set this trap to frame me!
You jerk! Don't try to fool us!
That star sure is beautiful.
What?
What? What is that?
What is that strange star approaching from the left?
What is that?
That is...
Hattori!
That's right.
He can testify that you knocked him out and threw him overboard
when he found Mr. Kanie tied to the prow.
You can't deny anything anymore, can you?
Mr. Kujirai.
But how did you figure it all out?
That Kanie wasn't the real killer?
The watch...
The watch's stem is on the opposite side
because it's made for a right handed person
but it was put on his left hand.
At that point, I crossed Mr. Kanie off as a suspect.
You tried to make him look like you
but you were made a big mistake by putting the watch on wrong.
You were done in by your partner's expensive watch.
By the way, it was also Mr. Kujirai
who put the advertisement for this tour in the newspaper.
You all probably decided 20 years ago
that on the day the statute of limitations runs out,
you'd place an advertisement in the newspaper
under the name of Masaru Furukawa.
The reason the three got together was
they were going to get the money
they put into a safe deposit 20 years ago.
"Masaru Furukawa" -To take the money
out of the safe deposit box you rented 20 years ago,
you needed the key, the seal and the signature.
You three each had one of the items
and it would also be your identification
when you met each other after all those years
and after having plastic surgery done.
Mr. Kujirai who was in charge of the signature,
saw the seal and key Mr. Kameda and Mr. Kanie displayed nonchalantly,
so he knew right away who they were
and he immediately set his plan in motion.
I see.
After killing them and stealing the key and seal,
he intended to take the money all for himself.
What a fool.
The statute of limitations had run out
and he went through so much trouble.
I wanted to win.
I thought up a perfect plan,
but that Saizo Kano...
20 years ago, he said, "Your plan is full of loopholes."
I wanted to beat the Mastermind in the shadows!
But I don't understand!
Why are there so many people involved with that case all over this ship?
I didn't even mention the name Kano once in the advertisement.
Don't you know what Masaru Furukawa meant?
It's the nickname Kano used,
he said there were just a few strokes and it was easy to remember
so we were to use it when we needed to contact each other.
No one except us is supposed to know about it.
This is hilarious!
Turn the name sideways!
It becomes Saizo Kano, doesn't it?
That's why I joined this tour.
And also the statute of limitations ran out of that day.
I had my doubts.
Masaru Furukawa was Kano's alias
which he picked intending to be funny!
No way...
You were never any match for Kano never.
After all, for the past 20 years,
Kano had you by the coat tails.
What? You fell in the ocean?
You're kidding.
It's no joke! Someone pushed me from behind and I fell in!
Didn't you notice I was gone?
You're cold!
But you were lucky, you're alive.
I was floating in the ocean
and that fishing boat captain found me!
It was awful! I had to take all my clothes off
and use my flashlight to signal ships sailing faraway.
Worry a little!
You took your clothes off?
Of course!
You can try it!
Wet clothes soak up so much water and they're heavy!
If I didn't take them off, I would have drowned!
The only thing I kept was my pants
and the thing I have no idea when it had in my pocket...
"Don't forget it, you fool!" -this amulet.
I don't know whether it really works or not, though.
What are you staring at me for?
Come on now, don't play dumb!
You were looking at the amulet Kazuha gave you all dreamy eyed.
No, I wasn't.
This amulet's bad luck, I was thinking of throwing it away!
But I didn't want something bad to happen,
that's why I'm holding on to it!
Then don't you ever forget it?