(crowd cheering)
Whoa!
Wow...
Awesome!
What!
Nice one!
Aah!
Huh?
Hyah!
Ohh!
Damn it!
♪~
Slicing through the black shadows
and the darkness, the light of deduction.
Sanada's wild, all-out shot...
turning into an unexpected case?
He sees the one and only truth.
A child in appearance, with the mind of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan!
~♪
"Promise with the J-Leaguer"
Aww...
Big Osaka just can't get a goal, huh.
What? Weren't you three...
anti-Big in the first place?
Oh, no, no. We're just
Spirits fans, that's all...
But since we got to know
Sanada at the soccer clinic...
the three of us decided we'd at least
cheer for Sanada, right?
And yet...
Big Osaka's just no good
without Higo, huh.
Can't be helped.
Higo's playing in the World Cup,
so he can't take part in this tournament.
Alongside Hide, he's
one of Japan's top strikers, after all.
So that's why Sanada's
playing in Higo's place.
Sanada's just Higo's backup.
Though, to us...
Hey! I'm not a backup!
I'm a super sub. Remember that.
...is what he told us, anyway.
(all laughing)
But that shot just now
was so close, huh.
He kicked it with his right foot.
He was trying to get past
the defender's block, I'd guess.
The aim was good, I thought.
Was it though?
Huh?
At that timing, there was no need
to cut back with a feint.
If he'd just shot with his left foot,
aiming for the left of the goal...
it would've gone in for sure.
Then why would he bother...
I don't know, but
it was the same earlier too.
Earlier?
You know, that perfect cross
to Sanada when he dove in front of the goal?
I figured he'd take a volley
with his left foot, but...
(crowd booing)
Hmm... come to think of it,
he shot with his right foot
and sent it way over the crossbar.
That time too, I wondered
why he'd bother shooting
with his right foot,
which isn't his dominant one.
Maybe he was trying to show the coach
that he can shoot
with his right foot too?
Though it seems to be backfiring.
And there's one more thing.
This has been bugging me too...
Every now and then, Sanada
looks over at the stands...
Ah, there it is again.
See? He's looking over that way.
I wonder who he's looking at.
Who knows. From here
I can't tell, but...
he's definitely watching someone.
Don't tell me... someone's threatening him,
and he's missing shots on purpose?
Huh?
Hm?
...Just kidding. No way that's it.
Why would you think that?
Huh?
Was there
a similar case before, maybe?
Oh, no. Nothing like that.
Sorry. I'm overthinking it.
Let's just watch the game.
Mm...
(Still, Sanada's play
is clearly off.)
(Something's definitely going on.)
Ayumi-chan.
Hm?
Genta-kun.
Conan-kun's deduction...
maybe it's actually right.
You mean Sanada's being threatened
and missing shots on purpose?
Yes.
Conan-kun must have a reason
for thinking so.
He's just hiding it from us.
If that's true...
let's save that guy ourselves!
Yes.
Conan-kun.
Hm?
We're gonna run to the restroom for a bit.
Oh, okay. Hm?
Ah... hey, that guy.
He looks really suspicious.
Yeah. Let's get closer
and take a look.
Go, Sanada-kun!
Let's go, Sanada!
Clear it! Push the line up!
Won't go in...
Ohh...
Sanada-kun!
Don't mind, don't mind.
That old guy...
He seems to be watching Sanada
and that lady cheering for Sanada.
Suspicious, huh.
If it isn't Conan-kun!
Hm?
Oh, Kaoru-san.
Watching the game today
with your girlfriend?
Huh? Uh, no...
I'm not.
Oh, is that so?
My apologies, then.
You're not working today, right, Kaoru-san?
You're not wearing a press bib.
That's right. I'm off today.
That scoop photo got me
back into the social affairs desk.
And after that whole string of cases,
I got personally interested in Sanada Takahiro...
Hyah!
So I'm still following him.
Hmm. Hey.
Doesn't Sanada seem
a little off today?
Yeah. He's not like
his usual self.
Two days ago, when Big was on their
Tokyo road trip, I went to the field
near the Nishishiba Hotel,
where they always stay,
and got photos of Sanada
doing his early-morning solo practice.
Back then, was he practicing
shots with his right foot?
No. He was practicing PKs,
but he kicked every one
with his left foot.
And with a hard, straight shot,
aiming for the upper left corner of the goal.
He kept drilling that one course
over and over.
(Just as I thought.
So why is he using his right foot today...)
Ah! So close.
...Anyway, this field
brings back memories.
What, you've been here before?
Yeah. Nishishiba Sports Park.
There was a soccer tournament here
back in middle school.
A few days before that tournament,
I wanted to check the turf and stuff,
so I was kicking a ball around alone.
At the end, I tried a few PKs too.
Just like Sanada...
I aimed for the upper left corner
with a hard, straight ball.
But I put too much into it...
Heh. So the super
high-school-level soccer kid
missed a PK with no keeper.
I said it was in middle school!
Hmm.
Huh? Middle school?
Uh... what?
You just said "in middle school."
Ah, no. It's a story
about a guy I know...
Hmm.
(crowd cheering)
Sanada-kun, you can do it!
Huh? What's that?
That thing by his knee...
What is that? Looks like
a black tube...
Ah, it's a gun!
Huh?
Could that be a gun barrel...
Is a gun barrel
really that thick?
It's a silencer.
A device you attach to a gun
so the sound can't be heard.
You see them a lot
in spy movies.
Here's the truth.
That woman cheering
for Sanada...
is Sanada's girlfriend,
and he's being threatened that if he
doesn't want her killed,
he has to miss his shots.
That's why he's deliberately shooting
with his right foot, not his dominant one!
Whaat?
Wh... what do we do, Mitsuhiko?
Hmm... hm?
Let's tell a security guard.
(crowd cheering)
Hmph!
Ah...
(crowd cheering)
Good job, Takahiro.
Ah! Oh no.
(crowd cheering)
Kyaa!
This is bad!
He scored!
Ah! Watch out!
Stop!
Whoa! What the... who are you kids?
Let go!
We won't let go!
You're threatening Sanada, aren't you?
Ayumi-chan, get a guard, quick!
Hey, you two.
It doesn't seem to be a gun.
Huh?
Hey, you kids.
Hey, let go.
What are you doing, you guys?
We were sure it was
a gun silencer...
That's a video camera.
A hidden one, at that.
Wh... what are you talking about?
I don't know anything. Ah...
Ah! That man... he's Yuki's stalker.
Ohh...
Those women weren't
Sanada's girlfriends...
they were just fans, it seems.
Geez. Good thing
that was a video camera.
If it'd been a real gun,
who knows what
might've happened to you.
But thanks to that,
I got some interesting photos.
Thanks.
As a thank-you, I'll buy you
something at the stand.
It's halftime anyway.
Yay! Haha...
Geez.
Don't "geez" me, okay?
You're the one who said all that,
so those kids...
Well, true enough, I guess.
But there's no doubt
something's going on with Sanada.
Ah...
Ah... hmph.
I'm gonna hit the restroom.
You okay? Want me to come with you?
- Fukazawa Shingo (40), convenience store owner.
- Watanabe Kou (10) Nishishiba primary school 4th grader.
I'm fine.
(So he was watching that kid.)
Hm?
Ah...
Hey, mister.
Hm... huh?
What happened to
that kid's right foot?
Oh, he fell off his bike
and twisted it.
Hmm. Are you
that kid's dad?
Ah... no, I'm not.
You don't look like
his soccer club coach either, but...
Is that kid friends with Sanada?
Why do you ask?
Because Sanada was
sending him some kind of signal.
Hey, does that kid
falling off his bike
have something to do
with Sanada?
Why would you think that?
When Sanada comes to Tokyo,
the field where he always does
his solo practice is in Nishishiba.
And it was written
on that kid's jacket too.
"Nishishiba Soccer Club."
(sigh)
I run a convenience store
in Nishishiba,
and the other morning I was taking
a walk through the nearby sports park...
(ball being kicked)
Hm?
(brakes screeching)
(crash)
Ah!
Ngh...
Whoa?
Ugh...
You okay? I...
My leg...
Ah, sorry, sorry!
I was practicing PKs
and the ball flew over the goal...
ah.
Aah...
Did you get hurt?
So I took him to
a nearby hospital I knew...
With this leg, I can't
play in the game.
It's fine. Give it ten days
and you'll be running again.
But I won't be able to shoot.
That's not true. And if you
can't shoot with your right,
just shoot with your left.
Then, Sanada-san,
can you shoot with your right,
even though it's not your dominant foot?
Uh... of course I can!
I'm a J-Leaguer, after all.
My right's perfect too.
Then in your next game,
score a goal with your right foot.
If you do, I'll work hard too.
Whaat?
(So Sanada...)
Later on, Sanada
sent us tickets for today's game.
But Ko's parents were busy,
so I came in their place.
Thanks, mister.
(whistle)
Unbelievable.
No matter how guilty he felt
about injuring the kid,
what J-Leaguer makes
such a ridiculous promise?
Well, that's just
so very Sanada...
Maybe it's what's good about him?
I wanna see Sanada score
in the second half too.
Not some lame shot
like before.
I want him to nail it big.
(What bugs me more, though...)
(phone ringing)
Yes, Nishishiba Sports Park
management office.
Huh? Mouri? You mean
the famous Detective Mouri?
Hm?
I heard the story
from Fukazawa-san.
Cut Sanada some slack, will you?
No way. A promise is a promise.
But your injury isn't
Sanada's fault.
What are you talking about?
The ball he kicked...
Hm?
Can you show me where
you fell off your bike?
Huh? Oh, sure.
Around here, I think.
You're sure?
Yeah. It was right after I
passed the crosswalk.
Which direction did
the ball come flying from?
From diagonally behind me.
Sanada was kicking from this spot,
toward the upper left corner of the goal,
a hard, straight ball.
But he put too much into it,
and the ball flew way over the goal.
If that ball flew over Fukazawa-san's head
and out onto the road in front...
See? A ball aimed at
the upper left of the goal
couldn't possibly come flying
from diagonally behind
at Ko, who'd just passed
beside the crosswalk.
Huh? Then how...
There's only one possibility.
First, the ball Sanada kicked
didn't fly over
Fukazawa-san's head...
it hit Fukazawa-san.
Right in the face, in fact.
Huh?
Fukazawa-san, those glasses
seem to be in bad shape.
Look closely and the arm's
slightly bent...
Didn't a ball hit them?
No... that's not what happened.
Ah, wait a second.
If the ball hit Fukazawa-san
like you say,
then how did the ball
end up reaching me...
Right. There's no way the ball
should've reached Ko.
Unless Fukazawa-san,
hit in the face by the ball,
got angry and threw it
toward the street out front.
N... no.
I saw the ball
well before that,
and it definitely flew
over my head.
The course of Sanada's
kicked ball is wrong to begin with.
Try to remember carefully.
The ball came from the side,
not from diagonally behind, right?
Ah... um...
Fukazawa-san.
Did you know there's
a security camera
right here at that field?
Huh?
I called the park
management office earlier
and had them check
the footage from that day.
Ugh...
Damn it.
Why would you go that far...
It's not that I wanted to
expose your crime, Fukazawa-san.
You're not a bad person, after all.
I just had to bring out the truth.
For Sanada's sake,
and for Ko's sake.
Huh...
It's a foul!
PK! PK!
Nobu, it's on you.
You got it.
(If I kick it left-footed
on that course like in practice,
I'll score for sure.)
(But if I do that,
then my promise with that kid...)
Hm?
Ow! Ah...
Mm.
Ah...
Yeah.
Haha.
(whistle)
Aah...
Aww...
Unbelievable.
Just another lame shot, huh.
Damn...
Don't mind, don't mind.
No time to sulk, man.
Idiot.
Don't say it yourself.
Thanks.
Well, that's so very Sanada.
♪~
~♪
So it was the ball
you threw?
I'm sorry I lied.
Sanada-san. Ko.
I'm truly sorry.
It's okay, mister. I'm gonna
work hard in my next game.
Mm...
Ah.
Wh... whoa, Sanada-kun?
I'm sorry.
Huh?
Even if you were the one
who threw the ball,
it doesn't change that my kick
got Ko injured.
And on top of that, I hit you
in the face... forgive me.
Sanada-san...
Hm? Ah.
(Ko laughing)
But you'd normally
make that PK, huh.
(rain falling)
Heh.
A woman's body found
near the scene from earlier?
H... hey. Don't tell me...
No way...
What the heck.
The pain finally woke me up.
This case isn't over yet.
Mouri-san, what do you mean
"isn't over"...
Next Conan:
"Coincidences Come in Twos"
Next Conan's Hint:
"A brand new skirt"
Reds' Makino, take it away.
Go, Japan!