Invited by Sonoko, Kyogoku
visited the Suzuki residence...
but ended up being disliked
by Sonoko's mother, Tomoko.
And then, seeing Sonoko
get all excited about Kaito Kid...
Lord Kid.
What is it?
Ad... Advisor.
My name is Kyogoku Makoto.
I am a humble young man...
who has the honor
of dating Miss Sonoko.
Well, well, well.
So you're Sonoko's boyfriend.
And what brings you here?
I've heard that you possess
the jewel...
that kaito kid is after.
If that's the case, I humbly ask
that you allow me...
to join the ranks
of your security detail.
(phone ringing)
What kind of man is he?
I hear he's a karateka, but...
He's no ordinary karateka.
Four hundred world matches, undefeated.
The unbeatable
Prince of Kicks.
F... Four hundred and undefeated?
Huh? Keep security out
of the jewel exhibit room?
Kaito Kid is coming to steal it!
He says they'd interfere with
the latest security system.
Advisor Suzuki
just called me about it.
Ugh...
One man is surrounded
by guys aiming pistols at him.
Sure, they're BB guns,
but at this range, with this many...
And the man in the middle...
is wearing a gas mask
that blocks his vision.
You'd think there's no way
he could dodge them all, right?
(gunshots)
Apparently he's the world's
strongest security system.
But Tomoko to Kyogoku...
and Kid to Sonoko...
had each proposed
a certain wager.
Sun blazing down,
shrugging off the heat,
a slick and stylish
deduction show.
Kaito Kid's surprise scheme...
where will the security battle lead?
Seeing through
the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid,
mind of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"Thief Kid vs. Makoto Kyogoku (Part 2)".
Do your best, Makoto.
Ah... yes.
I...
I believe in you.
Yes. I'll protect it,
no matter what.
I stake these fists on it.
Come on, Sonoko.
I believe in you too.
That you'll keep
that promise of yours.
Yes.
Of course.
Good. I'll be looking
forward to it.
Would you care to make
a wager with me?
A wager, you say?
Yes. If you manage to
protect the jewel splendidly,
then I'll accept it
as fate...
and approve of your
relationship with Sonoko.
But if that fails, and you're
bested by that thief...
then you'll give up
on Sonoko for good.
Do we have a deal?
Uh...
(crowd) Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid!
What? A letter from Kid
arrived at this museum?
And it's addressed
to this man again?
Y... Yes. About a hundred
of them, all at once.
A... A hundred?
Looks like invisible ink again.
Hey, hey, we can't heat
a hundred letters one by one
with a lighter.
Then could you prepare
a candle...
and a candlestick for me?
Heating them that way
should save us some trouble.
Hmm.
Hey, somebody bring
a candle and a candlestick!
Wh... What is this?
"The prey I target never escapes...
the world's greatest thief."
"Nothing is impossible
for the magician under the moon."
"The world's strongest security
system? That's hilarious."
...None of these
say anything important.
Step back, step back.
Please move back a bit more.
Don't come any closer.
Heh heh. This isn't even
an exhibit anymore.
Whoops.
But what's the deal
with all these letters?
To rattle Kyogoku, who's
guarding the jewel?
Or maybe...
(crowd) Kid! Kid! Kid!
(announcement) It is now
closing time.
(crowd) Kid! Kid! Kid!
Thank you so much...
for visiting us today.
We look forward to seeing you again.
It is now closing time.
Thank you so much
for visiting us today.
Heh heh heh.
Come whenever you like,
Kaito Kid.
Today, I'll show you
what I'm made of.
You will, that is.
Nwa ha ha ha ha!
I've got a bad feeling.
Like we're being neatly
played by him somehow...
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
You've got such a scary face on.
Ran-neechan. Huh?
Hee hee.
What do you think of this outfit?
I picked the most modest one.
It... It looks good on you.
Really? I'm glad.
Ah ha ha.
M... Modest? The neckline's
way too open.
Ah.
Makoto.
Hm?
I'm wearing an outfit
like this, so don't forget it.
Ah... no. Yes.
Now then, five minutes
until the time on the notice.
Everyone, please leave
this exhibit room.
From here on, until this
is over, anyone who enters...
will be regarded as an enemy...
and subdued with everything
I have.
Eh...?
A... All right.
Understood.
I'm counting on you
for the rest.
All right, we won't let
a single soul into this room either!
Yeah!
Ah... I'm gonna hit
the bathroom real quick.
Hey.
Those are the letters
that came from Kid, right?
Yeah.
If there are that many...
did someone from the post office
deliver them straight to
the museum office?
Nah. Miss Sonoko...
got them handed to her
directly by the mail carrier.
Sonoko did?
Was she wearing that outfit then?
Good work out there.
Yeah. She finished changing
first and stepped out to check
on things outside...
and happened to run into
a mail carrier she knew.
Let me see one of those letters.
I won't take it out of the bag.
H... Hey.
Just as I thought...
no reaction to the black light.
...Which means, don't tell me,
Sonoko...
A... A blackout?
I'm sorry, Makoto.
(crowd chanting "Kid")
(timer ticking)
(time signal)
A... A blackout?
Something's glowing.
And quite a lot of them, too.
Fluorescent paint?
Huh? Looks like something
rolled over here.
Ah, this is bad.
Ran-neechan, get away!
Uwaah!
Whoaa!
Don't panic!
It's the usual knockout gas.
As long as we've got
gas masks on, this is nothing...
Oh...
Ah... damn it.
Whoa!
Curse you, Kid... Oh...
Kyaaah!
Ah... that voice, it's Sonoko.
(knocking on door)
Makoto, can I come in?
Ah...
Makoto.
Sonoko, what on earth happened?
Kaito Kid suddenly
cut the power...
and filled the whole place
with knockout gas.
I had this gas mask that
a guard gave me, so...
I managed not to
get knocked out, but...
the other guards had their masks
knocked off by Kid's card gun...
(everyone sleeping)
What in the world...
The gas masks...
had something like fluorescent
paint on them, so...
in the dark, Kid must have
used that glow as a guide...
Then he must still be
nearby!
No.
I think he's already
escaped.
Because before the blackout,
a card from Kid arrived...
saying he'd already
"received the jewel."
That's impossible.
The jewel's been around
my neck this whole time...
Anyway, let's check
in a bright place...
whether that jewel
is the real thing.
Hmm. The moonlight through
the skylight alone isn't enough
to tell.
Then...
By candlelight.
Oh, right.
There was a candle
for the invisible ink.
I'm pretty sure the real one
was green, right?
Ah... red? It's glowing red.
So Kid did swap it
with a fake after all.
B... But...
when, and how on earth?
For now, this fake...
I'll go hand over
to the inspector.
Ah... yes.
Makoto, please tend to
the guards who were knocked out.
Hm?
You... you're not Sonoko,
are you?
Wh... What are you saying?
I'm the real one.
It's the jewel that's the fake.
The jewel is real.
C... Conan-kun?
Alexandrite...
under strong sunlight
rich in the blue-green spectrum...
or under the fluorescent lights
in this museum, looks dark green.
But under incandescent light
or candlelight, rich in the red
spectrum...
it turns a vivid red.
In other words...
the reason for sending all those
pointless invisible-ink letters...
in such huge numbers...
was to get a candle
prepared here on the spot.
And those letters...
were things hidden in advance
somewhere in this museum...
handed over while
disguised as Sonoko, right?
If you carelessly went through
the post office and they got
heated somewhere...
the invisible ink would
develop early.
The proof is, the barcodes
the post office uses for sorting...
weren't on any of the letters.
Invisible ink that reacts
to black light, that is.
So Kid stripped me
of my clothes...
and used them
for his disguise?
No.
Sonoko took off her own clothes
and handed them to Kid.
To make the wager
with Kid happen.
A wager?
Tch.
Yeah.
Whether Kyogoku could
see through Kaito Kid...
when he impersonated her.
Tch, he dodged it.
(crumbling)
Ah, crap.
Where is he?
Where'd he go?
Ha!
Ha ha ha!
I've claimed
the Green Emperor.
Tch.
Well, curse your own
incompetence at not being able
to fly...
Mr. World's Strongest
Security System.
You bastard...
Get back.
Eh?
Hmph!
Hyah!
Huh?
He split a pillar with karate?
N... No way. Is he planning
to break the pillars and bring
the ceiling down?
(guards sleeping)
Scary. I'd better
get out of here fast.
Haa!
Ah...
Hmph.
No way.
Y... Yikes!
H... He flew?
A... As expected
of the world's strongest.
Now, hand them back
to me, won't you?
Both the jewel
and Sonoko's heart.
Ah, since it wasn't what I was after,
I can return the jewel.
But the young lady's heart,
that I can't.
Wh... What?
Heh. There's nothing to return,
since I never took it
in the first place.
Ah...
From the moment I proposed
this wager.
F... Fine. I'll take you up
on that wager, but...
don't injure him.
Makoto's got a big tournament
coming up next week.
W... Who's there?
K... Kaito Kid?
Good grief. It seems
I can't keep the fact...
that I was here a secret,
so tell your friends a suitable lie.
Especially that boy
with the glasses.
But... well, unfortunately...
it seems I did let him take
a small injury or two.
The wager is completely...
your win, young lady.
Heh.
♪~
~♪
What?
You were stripped of everything
and locked in the bathroom?
Is that true, Sonoko?
Y... Yeah, well.
He shows no mercy,
even to a woman.
Hmph. Kid told you
to say that, didn't he?
So you wouldn't be
an accomplice.
Then don't tell me, the one who put
fluorescent paint on the gas masks...
Good work out there.
Ugh...
was back then.
Damn that Kid.
Still, you did a fine job
protecting the treasure.
No. In the end,
I let Kid get away.
My apologies.
No, no, it's fine.
The contest is carried over
to next time.
And next time...
Yes. Next time, without fail.
Well said.
That's the world's strongest
security system for you.
Gah ha ha ha!
He's quite a reliable
young man, isn't he?
Yes. Earnest, plainspoken...
polite, and a tough,
sturdy man.
Heh heh.
He'll be such fun to torment.
Scary.
Sorry, Makoto.
For pulling a stunt to test you.
Ah... no.
So anyway...
when did you figure it out?
That that was Kid in disguise.
Eh?
Was it because I'm
prettier, maybe?
Hey, hey, it was, right?
Ah... no.
Actually...
Hm?
Ehh?
Unlike me, Kid's ring finger
was longer than his index finger?
You seriously figured it out
from that?
Yes.
I've gotten into the habit of instantly
spotting an opponent's physical traits.
Wasn't there anything else?
Like how I had a more
pure vibe or something.
P... Pure?
You know, innocent,
unsullied, that kind of thing.
Hmm.
You're hesitating!
S... Sorry.
Oh, come on.
Well, due to hormones, women's
index fingers tend to be longer
than their ring fingers...
and for men it's the opposite,
so they say.
There are quite a few
exceptions, though.
Ah, my ring finger's long!
Heh heh.
Was there some kind
of accident over there?
If so, those flowers...
It's gone.
That thing is.
Eh...?
Gone? Don't tell me...
That smell from earlier,
just as I thought.
It's embarrassing,
so don't tell anyone.
Ah... yes. Of course.
Next Conan,
"Detective Love Story at MPD Headquarters (Confession)".
Next Conan's Hint:
"Masked Yaiba".
Boy, that was close!
There's another master of Karate.
I know her really well.