I'm Mouri Kogoro. Private detective.
Yes... my trade is digging up people's dirt.
To soothe a heart sickened
by such work...
Most detectives keep
a secret bar of their own.
Alright!
Young people shouting and whooping...
Having their fun with billiards and darts.
This place...
Is, regrettably,
not my bar, but...
When the client is the bartender here,
what can you do?
Here you go, Detective.
For now, please have this.
Her name is
Fukui Yuzuki, 26 years old.
The bartender
at this establishment.
She's probably
in love with me.
The proof of that is
this pale green cocktail...
She's treating me
to a gimlet.
She must see me
as that detective...
Philip Marlowe.
No doubt about it.
Hm...
Hey, this is green tea!
Sorry... I figured if you got drunk
you couldn't do your job.
Ah, right...
Well, hold on, hold on. From the top.
I'm Mouri Kogoro. Private detective.
This is a pool bar where the client
works as the bartender.
What soothes my soul...
Is the offbeat jazz rhythm
flowing through this place...
Hey! Old man!
A brat's voice.
Huh?
Huh... Wait, what are you
doing here?!
Well, Ran-neechan said...
Dinner's getting cold,
so hurry up and bring him back.
I told you I'm here for work!
And I told her, you probably just said that
so you could come drink.
It is for work, right? A tough case?
Uh... Yes.
See? Told you.
What kind of case?
There's this strange sound
while I'm working.
A "pop"... like the sound
of uncorking a champagne bottle.
The sound of uncorking
a champagne bottle?
♪~
Black shadows and pitch-black darkness...
The light of deduction cuts right through.
Pool Bar "Blue Parrot"...
Where drinks invite disaster.
Seeing through the one and only truth...
A child's appearance, an adult's mind...
His name is Detective Conan!
~♪
"Kogoro is at the Bar (Part 1)"
Ah!
Whoa, whoa...
See? That sound.
Well, that was literally
the sound of uncorking champagne...
But at that time, we weren't serving
any champagne to customers...
Couldn't a customer have
snuck some in?
Wine bottles have corks too.
I thought the same thing...
So I kept a close eye
on the customers, but...
Nobody was drinking
champagne or wine...
And after the sound,
I also heard something like something falling...
I looked around while cleaning
after closing, but...
No cork had fallen anywhere.
But there was a strange smell...
A strange smell?
Hm?
Don't tell me... the smell of gunpowder
from some kind of explosion?
Oh, no... It was like
the scent of yuzu.
Just a faint whiff of it, though.
Since my name has "Yuzu" in it...
I've always been sensitive
to the smell of yuzu.
We don't use yuzu in this bar,
so I thought it was strange...
And that's why I consulted Mouri-san.
Couldn't a customer have spilled
a cocktail that uses a similar citrus?
Like, a gimlet uses lime juice...
Or a screwdriver,
or a white lady...
Hmm... I really thought
it smelled like yuzu, though.
That sound... it happened more than once?
Yes. 2 or 3 times on different days.
Was there a customer who was always here
when the sound happened?
There is. As it happens,
right now at the table behind us...
That group of four.
They're the ones.
Alright, I'm taking the shot!
Okay, cheese!
Ah, Chief! The film's run out!
- Kogure Monpei (28), employee.
It's fine, it's fine.
I've got two or three spare film rolls stocked up myself too.
- Usuda Chikafumi (51), department manager.
And I had them stock up on plenty more so we're good.
Right?
Ah... Yes.
Here, Kogure-kun.
Ah...
But Chief... An analog camera these days... Isn't that just a hassle?
- Hatsumura Kensaku (31), employee.
Hmph. I hate digital.
(hiccup)
Remember... (hiccup) there was one guy in our department too, wasn't there?
All smug about how
he was a digital whiz...
A useless geek.
You mean Yoshikuwa-kun?
Yeah, Yoshikuwa. Yoshikuwa.
When you dive that deep
into digital like that guy...
You lose touch with reality, become a shut-in... (hiccup) ..
And in the end you go and hang yourself.... (hiccup)
Oh, that reminds me... Kishiura-kun...
I heard you and that guy were pretty close?
If you're lonely without a boyfriend...
- Kishiura Mika (30), employee.
I wouldn't mind
keeping you company.
Oh, no... I'll pass.
What? No need to be shy.
Considering how close we are...
Hey, Chief!
Hm? What is it, Hatsumura?
I bought that billiard cue
you asked for.
A top-of-the-line ebony model
was on sale at a discount, so...
Oh, really? Thanks, Hatsumura-kun.
It's the best gift ever.
Oh, a gift?
This is my birthday present,
right?
Huh? Uh... Yeah.
I brought these too.
Your personal darts, Chief.
Soft darts with plastic tips
are pretty common...
But tracking down
these metal hard darts...
Was a real pain.
Is that so? Good, good.
You two really are useful.
O-Of course... I was planning
to give these as a present too.
Kogure, do you know why I wanted the steel darts?
N-No...
It's because...
Ah... Ahh!
See? You can't scare someone
like that with plastic ones.
Hahahaha! Ahahaha...
Oh, looks like the billiard table
just opened up.
Since you went out of your way to get the cue for me,
I guess I may as well try it out!
(clears throat)
Ah... Anyway! Just go home already and tell Ran this:
Kogoro-san has taken on
a very difficult case...
And won't be home for a while.
...And with that settled, Yuzuki-chan,
fix me a gimlet, would you?
Uh... Can you really work
if you're drinking?
It's fine, it's fine.
Don't come crying to me later.
Hey, old man... Let's just go home.
Ran-neechan was furious.
...Geez, you're annoying.
How many times are you gonna come back?
I told you, I'm working!
You're just drinking.
Ugh... Yuzuki-chan,
one more gimlet.
Come on, please think about the case!
Once this mystery's solved,
I want to post about it on my blog!
Heh... No worries.
I've pretty much solved it already.
Huh? Really?
Seriously?
The culprit probably
spilled some ponzu.
With yuzu in it, no less.
Hm... Ponzu with yuzu?
Hey...
Which means, in other words...
In other words?
In other words, yuzu go "pop."
Yuzu went pop!
Just kidding!
Bahahaha...
This old man is hopeless.
Ahahaha... Hehehe...
In the end, the chief
passed out, huh?
Yeah... He can't hold his liquor
but always wants to drink.
More importantly, my wallet hurts.
That billiard cue
cost 100,000 yen.
And the darts I bought,
with the case, were 60,000.
Kishiura's lucky...
Just five or six rolls of camera film, right?
I told you...
Because it was his birthday,
he made me buy an idol poster...
Off an online auction.
Oh yeah, you gave it to him at the office.
It was autographed,
so it cost 30,000 yen.
Can I take a quick look?
Don't get it dirty.
I'll get yelled at by the chief.
I know, I know.
Oh wow, it's Okino Yoko!
So, before we head home,
want to grab another drink?
Sure.
Hey, you've just been making
highballs all night. You've barely had any, right?
Hmm... Now that you mention it.
Seems like you were just
crushing ice with that thing the whole time.
So how about that champagne
we had at the start?
Yeah, that was good stuff.
What do you think?
Sounds good.
Excuse me... A bottle of champagne.
Right away.
And three glasses.
Hey... That guy at the counter...
Isn't that Mouri Kogoro?
What? No way...
The famous detective?
Hm? I feel like
I'm being watched...
Get a photo, get a photo!
Just some lookalike, right?
Yeah... Can't be
a drunk like that.
Hahaha...
(straining sounds)
I'm really no good
at this kind of thing.
Hey, hey... Don't point that at me.
Ugh... Kogure-kun, please.
When it comes to brute strength,
Kogure's the man.
Yeah, yeah... Leave it to me.
(straining sounds)
Huh? What the...
This thing is seriously stuck.
Hey, don't let it spray over here!
I know, I know!
(straining sounds)
Ah! It's spraying!
You idiot... It got on the poster!
That really was the sound
I've been hearing...
That was champagne too, right?
The edge of the poster's all wet!
Th-This is bad...
Ah... Sorry...
Three hand towels, please.
Right away.
What about that sound just now?
The hand towel wrapper opening?
Is it different from the sound
you heard, miss?
Yeah...
I think that cork popping sound
from before was closer.
Hey, some of it got
on the chief, too!
Whoa, crap... Hm? What?
There's a red dot or something
on the chief's neck.
You're right.
Wait, more like...
Th-The chief isn't breathing...
N-No way...
Huh? Chief? Chief?!
Ah!
Huh? Chief!
Huh?!
Are you okay?!
Hey, what's wrong?!
Th-The chief...
He won't wake up. He looks dead!
What?!
No... Not "looks dead."
This one really is dead.
I'm Mouri Kogoro. Private detective.
I took a case from Fukui Yuzuki-chan,
the bartender who's in love with me...
And came to the pool bar
where she works, but...
As it turns out, the one
with an obsession for me...
Seems to be trouble itself.
We can't say for certain
without an autopsy, but...
The cause of death is likely
asphyxiation due to a neurotoxin.
P-Poisoned?!
Yes. From the wound at the back of his neck,
it seems he was stabbed with something sharp like an awl, that had been coated with poison.
But if someone stabbed him with that...
He'd have thrashed around and screamed.
I believe he died in his sleep.
Huh?
The victim appears to have died while drunk.
...Wait. You again?
Yes, Inspector.
Don't tell me you just happened to be at another murder scene again?
Well, yeah... I just happened to be here.
Indeed... A detective has
a duty of confidentiality.
No matter what happens, he must never tell others about his clients.
To ensure no suspicion falls upon Yuzuki-chan...
I shall keep my lips sealed about my client.
On my pride as a detective.
I'm the one who called him here.
What?!
There's a mystery
I wanted Mouri-san to solve.
A mystery?
While I'm working,
there's this popping sound.
Like the sound of uncorking
a champagne bottle.
Huh?
Of course, at those times...
We weren't serving champagne
to any customers...
And even after cleaning up
after closing...
We never found anything
like a cork.
Just a faint
yuzu-like scent.
By the way, how much
did you take this case for?
She said she'd wipe my tab clean.
But of course, I do intend
to properly pay...
For the gimlets I had tonight.
Huh? R-Really?
So? The people drinking
with the victim...
Those three, correct?
Yes.
I asked them a few things
before you arrived, Inspector.
From the right:
Kishiura Mika-san, 30 years old.
Hatsumura Kensaku-san, 31 years old.
Kogure Monpei-san, 28 years old.
All three work at the same company
as the murdered Usuda-san...
And tonight they were celebrating
his birthday here...
Since he was their department chief.
I see.
So one of these three...
Held a grudge against their boss
and poisoned him.
H-Hold on a minute.
We just came here to celebrate his birthday...
We didn't poison anyone!
Couldn't the three of you
have done it together?
You kept glancing at me,
the detective...
And whispering to each other.
That was about you...
We were saying you looked
like "Sleeping Kogoro."
Didn't think it was really you.
Besides, we don't even have a motive.
But, I mean...
After the chief passed out drunk,
you three were talking, right?
About how you were forced to buy
super expensive birthday presents...
And how mad you were about it.
Y-You were listening, kid?
Yeah... I've got good ears.
Also, about how the chief
was making fun of that guy...
Yoshikuwa-san, and how
he committed suicide...
And how you and that Yoshikuwa-san
were lovers.
Is that true?
Yeah... It is.
But if you're saying that,
Hatsumura-san was his senpai in college...
And Kogure-kun joined the company
the same year he did.
Besides, if we hated someone
enough to kill them...
We wouldn't play billiards
or darts with them.
You played games with the victim?
Yeah. The three of us
took turns playing him...
Hey, did the chief really
play with those three?
Ah... Right.
You kept going home,
so you didn't see, Conan-kun.
The chief was a real handful.
The dartboard here
is for soft darts...
But he tried to use
the hard darts he'd been given...
So he got into it
with the other customers.
Those three stepped in
and managed to calm things down...
And until the chief sobered up...
They seemed to be letting him
rest at the table.
So what about after that?
For a while, the three of them
were playing billiards and darts.
Like, the loser swaps out.
So when two of them
were playing...
The remaining one was alone
with the drunk chief.
In other words, each of you three
had an opportunity...
To be alone with the chief.
Anyway, we'll be conducting
a body check and searching your belongings.
Hmm. A billiard cue, huh?
Certainly looks expensive.
Yeah... A 160,000 yen item...
Was on sale for 100,000,
so I got it for the chief.
O-Of course... Like the kid heard,
I never planned...
On giving such an expensive present...
So I was a bit annoyed.
But do you really think
I'd commit murder over that?
But...
Huh?
If you attached a poison needle
to the tip of this cue...
You could stab him from a distance,
even away from the table.
What?!
Something that conspicuous...
Someone would remember it.
Right? I didn't do
anything like that.
No.
Once the chief passed out,
he put it back in its case right away.
I see. And this?
The darts that caused
the trouble with the other customers...
I didn't buy those on purpose
to cause trouble!
The chief told me
to buy hard darts...
I got an antique dartboard
that belonged to my grandfather...
And when I gave it to the chief,
he told me to buy darts for it...
I don't play darts
at all myself...
That reminds me... The chief
pretended to throw a dart at you...
You were pretty terrified.
Ah... Ahh!
Yeah, that seriously
freaked me out...
So couldn't you have coated the tip
with poison and thrown it from a distance...
And just stabbed him?
I told you,
I'm terrible at darts.
Besides, rather than
throwing from far away...
It'd be way easier and more reliable
to just stab him up close.
Well, that's true...
If you suspect me,
then just check them!
Go over those dart tips
thoroughly.
Of course, I intend to.
And you... A few rolls
of camera film...
And an idol poster?
Rather cheap compared
to the other two.
Hey, that poster was autographed...
It cost 30,000 yen!
Well, he kept saying he wanted it...
Over and over, right next to my desk...
So I didn't have much choice
but to buy it.
Ah...
Hm? This wet spot
on the poster... It smells.
This scent... Is it yuzu?
Th-This is...
So the old man noticed too.
It's a poster
of Yoko-chan!
And what's more, the legendary
Western bikini shot!
That's your takeaway?!
...And don't get it wet!
A beautiful woman, all soaked!
And a pun... really?
When Kogure-kun uncorked the champagne,
it sprayed everywhere.
More importantly...
You took quite a lot of photos, didn't you?
Did your boss like taking photos?
Yeah he liked taking them for his blog.
Though the ones picking the photos and uploading them
Were us.
The chief was digitally illiterate.
Yet he wanted to seem cool by having a blog...
Well I guess at least after everything that's happened we won't have to pick out photos.
It was a blessing in disguise.
Ah... B-But we wouldn't
commit murder over hating that, okay?
Ahah...
By the way, who was in charge of mixing up and diluting the whiskey?
That was mostly me...
Then I'll have this
checked out as well.
The ice pick is sharp and pointed too, just like the tips of the darts.
It's very close to the shape of the murder weapon.
I'm Mouri Kogoro. Private detective.
It seems my very nature
as a detective...
Has brought calamity to this pool bar...
Which should have been
a place of solace.
Good grief.
It seems tonight as well...
This case won't let me sleep.
♪~
~♪
No traces of poison
were found?!
...Geez. No murder weapon...
It's just like that pickpocket case
the other day.
Hm? This is...
Why is there clay
on the bottom of that thing...
Then the culprit is, after all,
the customer who fought with the victim?
No way...
Next Conan:
"Kogoro is at the Bar (Part 2)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Clay"
There's no clay
in a bar.
Mouri-kun...
Are you drunk?
Old man, you're fine
staying at the bar forever.