Conan and Ran...
were supposed to have a meal
with Ran's mother, the lawyer Kisaki.
We were waiting at the apartment building
where Ms. Kisaki had a work appointment.
And there, by chance,
we ran into Masumi Sera.
At Sera's request, Ran ended up
helping her with an investigation.
As part of it, we were searching
for one of the building's residents...
Ah... Wak! Ms. Wakana!
Stay with me!
Ms. Wakana! Ms. Wakana!
Wa... ka...
♪~
Cutting through the dark shadows and gloom,
the light of deduction shines.
Sera's deduction and one more mystery,
a clever trick you can't even watch unfold.
Seeing through the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
~♪
"The Restroom Where Ran Also Collapsed (Part 2)".
A detective?
Wh... what's going on here, Rumi?
- Kenya Settsu (22), University student
There was a rumor that you were still seeing Wakana...
- Rumi Kitao (21), University student
behind everyone's back,
so I...
Rumi, you...
I'm... I'm sorry.
Anyway...
Argh...
The situation is, one of you... is the culprit. That's what I'm saying.
- Mitsuaki Kaga (22), University student
Uh...
That's true, certainly...
but there's another possibility too.
Hey, Ms. Rumi.
Hm... huh?
I found this photo in the living room...
In the picture, all four of you
are wearing glasses,
so why isn't anyone wearing them now?
That's a photo from about two years ago.
Everyone switched
to contacts since then.
Huh...
What? The murder weapon was found?
Yes. There was a golf club
in the living room...
and it tested positive for blood.
Also, from the kitchen sink drain...
a small bottle of chloroform
and a syringe.
And from the bathroom drain...
a liquid that looked like red paint.
Ah... red paint?
Why would that be there?
Hmm... And the shower being
left running in the tub...
is strange too.
If you wanted to fudge the time of death
without lowering the rectal temperature...
you'd normally run it over the body.
Just what the hell
is going on with this case?
Hey, Ran.
The one who used the spare key
to open the door to this room...
was Ms. Rumi, right?
Uh... yeah.
Did she fumble with it at all?
No, it was pretty normal.
She seemed used to coming in.
But you know, when you take the key
out of your pocket like this...
Ah!
Ahh!
Hm?
Sorry! Could you grab it?
...Geez.
What a handful.
Ah... sorry.
Thanks for picking it up.
Here you go.
Don't go dropping it again.
Hm...
I knew it... So that's how it is.
If I figured it out,
then she probably did too...
Huh? A phone call?
With who?
Hey, is my deduction wrong?
In any case...
the only ones who could have bludgeoned
the owner of this place, Wakana Hashitani,
to death in the bathroom...
are the man who dated the victim
until six months ago and still had
a spare key, Mr. Settsu, and...
the man who was drinking here with
the victim until five this morning,
who may have taken the key,
Mr. Kaga.
Just you two.
You were both supposed to meet...
the victim in the building lobby
at noon...
to have lunch together,
apparently...
Mr. Settsu got up to use the restroom
30 minutes before the meeting time,
and Mr. Kaga showed up
in the lobby in the early afternoon,
but his movements before that
are unknown.
Now, spit it out.
One of you two did it, didn't you?
W... wait a second.
Wakana was found collapsed
in a bathroom...
full of chloroform, right?
If we were the culprits,
why would we leave the bathroom
in a state like that?
Hmph.
Ah...
To knock out Ms. Rumi, who'd come
to fetch the victim later,
and delay the discovery
of the body, right?
The more it's delayed, the wider
the estimated time of death becomes.
And this Rumi here claims she was...
with some so-called detective
right up until she went to fetch Wakana,
but who knows if that's even true.
Ke... Kenya.
If it's Rumi, who used to share
this room with Wakana,
she might still have a key,
and she could be in cahoots with that
detective, getting their stories straight.
It's all way too convenient.
Suddenly butting in, claiming Rumi
has an alibi because they were...
together the whole time...
What a load of nonsense.
No. I never said Ms. Rumi had an alibi.
Huh?
If Ran, who went with her
to fetch Ms. Wakana,
was the one who found
Ms. Wakana's body,
then I'm simply saying the culprit
is one of you two men.
But if that body
wasn't Ms. Wakana's...
then that's another story.
Huh?
Ah...
Wh... what did you say?
But I really did see
Ms. Wakana's body...
You just think you did,
don't you?
You'd never met Ms. Wakana
before, right?
That's true, but...
And the body was face-down...
with a face mask on,
a towel wrapped around the head,
and on top of that, the bathroom was
hazy with steam from the shower, right?
Even if someone else
was impersonating her,
I don't think you'd have noticed.
Right? You think so too,
don't you, Conan?
Huh... yeah.
Could this girl possibly...
Impersonating her, you say...
Who exactly are you saying
was pretending to be Wakana?
She was collapsed
in nothing but a bath towel, right?
Ah, yes. I'm sure it was a woman,
there's no doubt about that.
In that case, the only one
who could have done it...
is the one who came to fetch
Ms. Wakana with Ran...
There's no one but Ms. Rumi.
Huh?!
Huh?
Ah...
In other words, when Ms. Rumi
came here with Ran,
she pretended she was
heading to the living room,
and sent Ran toward the bedroom
on the opposite side,
having her search for Ms. Wakana.
Then, watching for her chance,
she slipped into the bathroom,
stripped down to a single bath towel,
put a mask on her face,
wrapped a towel around her head...
and dripped red paint near her head...
to make herself look dead.
Then, timing it for when Ran
would come to search the bathroom,
she sprayed out the chloroform
she'd loaded into the syringe,
letting it vaporize...
Are you okay...? Ah, Ms. Wakana.
And when Ran entered the bathroom...
she knocked her out.
Of course, she held her breath
the entire time.
Hold on. Where was the victim
during all this...?
Sleeping in the living room,
wouldn't you say?
You know, Ms. Wakana
got drunk before too...
and fell asleep on the balcony...
off the living room,
remember her saying that?
If Ms. Rumi knew that Ms. Wakana
and Mr. Kaga had been drinking here...
until this morning...
then she could have called once
she figured Mr. Kaga had left,
lured her out to the balcony
to sober up,
and gotten her to fall asleep
right there.
That's right.
After Ran was knocked out,
Ms. Rumi left the bathroom...
aired out the chloroform for a while,
washed away the red paint,
got dressed again, woke Ms. Wakana
who was sleeping in the living room,
and told her "some girl I don't know
has collapsed," sending her to the bathroom.
Then, as Ms. Wakana
stood there startled...
by Ran lying collapsed, she bludgeoned her
from behind with the golf club...
stripped her down to a bath towel,
put a mask on her face,
wrapped a towel around her head,
and once again filled the bathroom
with chloroform...
This time, she really breathed it in
and passed out,
waiting for them
to come rushing in.
After all, who would think
that the person who went...
to fetch the victim...
had played dead
in such a short time?
N... no, I didn't do anything like that...
A... and the reason I went
to the living room...
was because Kenya called me...
But even without the call,
you were planning to look for
Mr. Settsu's lost item there, weren't you?
Uh... yeah.
Even without the spare key
you got from Mr. Settsu,
you were planning to use the key
from when you shared the room...
with Ms. Wakana, saying something
like "I'd been meaning to...
return it today," weren't you?
And if you hired me
as a detective...
to have someone witness you
playing dead in the first place,
then it all adds up.
Though this time, you ended up
making Ran fill the role.
(phone ringing)
The little sister who was actually
supposed to come to the dinner today...
could have played the part too,
but with your sister, there'd be
too much risk of being found out,
so you decided to have
a stranger do it instead, I'd say.
N... no, I didn't...
Inspector.
Ah.
There were fingerprints
on the chloroform bottle.
Huh?
Hey.
Don't tell me they're
Rumi Kitao's fingerprints?
Y... yes.
Huh?
A splendid deduction.
Not bad, kid.
Ah... yeah.
That deduction...
Doesn't it sit a little uneasy with you?
Huh?
S... sit uneasy?
Wh... what are you talking about?
Ah, no, it's not me...
Shinichi heard about the case
from Conan,
and he told me to say that
over the phone...
Ah, I'll put it on speaker now.
Shinichi Kudo...
I don't know who the hell you are,
but outsiders should stay out of...
There are three things
that don't sit right.
Hmph...
Hm...
You said she led the victim...
to sleep in the living room
as had happened before,
but that was just something
that happened once in the past.
You can lure someone to the living room
over the phone,
but I doubt you could conveniently
get them to fall asleep.
And even if she did happen
to fall asleep,
whether she'd stay asleep...
until Rumi came to fetch her
is also doubtful.
The doorbell at the entrance
could have woken her up.
Then what if Ms. Rumi
came here well before...
I arrived with her,
and had already put Ms. Wakana
to sleep with chloroform?
That way, a doorbell wouldn't
wake her, right?
That's the second problem.
Huh?
If that were the case,
why would Ms. Rumi
lock the front door...
at all?
Ah.
If Mr. Settsu...
hadn't happened
to hand over the spare key,
she'd have been forced to use
the key she'd failed to return to Ms. Wakana,
and as the one holding it,
she'd be the first to be suspected, right?
And if she'd put Ms. Wakana
to sleep beforehand,
it would be safer...
to have the sleeping Ms. Wakana herself
play the role of the body.
There's no need for her to go
to the trouble of holding her breath...
and playing the corpse herself.
Hmm...
Ah...
And the third...
is that the body was lying face-down
in nothing but a bath towel.
No one can fully picture
what they look like from behind.
There could easily be a mole or birthmark
even you don't know about.
If Ran saw it and realized it didn't match
the real person, it'd be over.
For impersonating someone, it's the worst
possible outfit and the worst possible pose.
B... but the body
had a mask on...
and the culprit made it hard to see
with the steam.
No matter how you look at it...
That's exactly it.
Ah.
If the body's face is hidden
and the view is obscured,
people will suspect
it might have been someone else.
That was precisely
the culprit's aim.
Leaving the body in nothing but a bath towel
and lying it face-down...
was to make the discoverer think
the body's face was being hidden,
while also making it instantly clear
that the body was a woman.
That way,
whoever was impersonating
the body would have to be a woman,
removing himself as a suspect,
and pinning the crime on Ms. Rumi.
Isn't that right?
Thirty minutes before the meeting time,
you pretended to go to the restroom
and came up here,
bludgeoned Ms. Wakana to death
and staged it with that trick...
her ex-boyfriend...
Ah.
Huh?
Kenya Settsu.
Ah...
Wh... what?
That's right.
When you came here,
you caught Ms. Wakana off guard, made her
breathe the chloroform, and put her to sleep...
You carried Ms. Wakana
to the bathroom,
stripped her down
to a single bath towel,
put a mask on her face,
wrapped a towel around her head,
and then bludgeoned her
with the golf club.
After that, you just had to pour
the red paint down the bathroom drain,
and fill the room with chloroform.
You called Ms. Rumi,
who went to fetch her,
sent her to the living room,
and created a window of time as if
she'd been impersonating the body...
Then, after the crime, if Ms. Rumi's
fingerprints turned up...
on the chloroform bottle
you'd hidden away,
the police would fall
for the fake. That's the plan.
By the way, the bottle
with her fingerprints on it...
was probably something you got
Ms. Rumi to handle beforehand.
If the two of you were dating,
just leaving it on the spice rack...
would make it easy
to get her to touch it.
H... hey, I don't know
who you are,
but that trick could've been
pulled off by Kaga too...
That's why I had Conan test it.
Hm?
T... test it?
Remember when I had you guys
pick up that loose change?
At that moment, I held out my palm
and gestured for you to hand it over, right?
Mr. Kaga placed it
right in my palm,
but Mr. Settsu put the change
in his own palm...
and held it out for me to take, right?
That's how I knew.
Mr. Settsu couldn't judge
the distance,
so he couldn't place the change
in my palm,
and even though I was
holding my palm out,
he set things up so I'd be the one
to grab the change.
Well, Mr. Settsu also failed to hand
the spare key to Ms. Rumi...
for the same reason,
so it's no wonder
he did it that way.
Wh... what on earth
are you talking about...
Contacts.
The contact lens in one of
Mr. Settsu's eyes has fallen out.
It probably came out...
when Ms. Wakana resisted as he tried
to make her breathe the chloroform.
He frantically searched the floor
where it fell, but couldn't find it.
Because...
Ms. Wakana, who'd collapsed on the floor
after being made to breathe the drug,
picked it up and hid it
as her consciousness faded.
Hid it? Where?
The victim was stripped naked
afterward, you know.
You said it yourself, didn't you, Inspector?
That the body was strange.
Ah! I see... a wink.
The victim hid it
inside her own eye.
Check the body immediately.
Yes, sir.
Even if a contact lens turned up
in the room later,
you were planning to play dumb,
claiming you dropped it back when...
you were dating and never found it,
weren't you?
But with it inside her eye,
and not in yours,
it's undeniable evidence.
And being a contact lens,
your fingerprints are probably on it too.
Hey, you've got to be kidding, Settsu.
Why would you even kill Wakana...
Weren't you two broken up?
Yeah. So I could date
the chairman's daughter.
Th... the chairman's daughter?
That first-year?
Can you blame me? Wakana's parent
is just a managing director.
She's the daughter of the chairman
of that company's affiliate group.
If I could marry into that,
talk about marrying up.
I'd already gotten a job offer there too,
so my career was set.
But if you'd already broken up,
you didn't need to kill her, did you?
Wakana was blackmailing me.
Huh?
If I made the other girl mine,
she'd expose all my past misdeeds
to her.
Before I dated Wakana, I'd made
quite a few women cry.
Then what was I?
Why did you even date me?
Hmph. If a girl got killed
right after we broke up,
I'd be the one under suspicion,
wouldn't I?
By dating you...
and spreading a rumor that I still
hadn't cut things off with Wakana,
I'd have a motive for you to kill her
out of jealousy.
Well, you got to date me, the great me,
for a whole six months.
Make it a fond memo... ngh!
Oh.
Ah.
Ah, my bad.
When I hear such trash talk...
my head starts to itch,
and my elbow just slipped.
If you keep up this trash talk...
my...
Eek!
this time my backside might start itching,
and my knee just might slip out too.
Would that be all right with you?
No, sir...
(Rumi sobbing)
But I'm impressed.
Seeing through that fake,
that's something.
It wasn't me, it was Shinichi.
Ah, no way. Shinichi's call
got cut off at some point.
Ah, n... now that you mention it,
Shinichi said something.
Mascara had run
from the corner of Ms. Wakana's eye,
and that's how he noticed the fake.
If you're going to put a mask on,
you have to remove the makeup,
so the culprit realized that
and wiped off the lipstick,
but if the culprit had been a woman,
there's no way she'd overlook the mascara.
I'm sure since Sera...
has never worn mascara herself,
she couldn't have noticed.
I see.
Shinichi's...
never worn mascara either, though.
♪~
~♪
What? You got caught up
in a murder case?
Why didn't you tell me, your mother?
Well, the detective Sera was there too,
and in the end,
Kudo solved it for us.
Ah...
Well then, I'll be going.
Oh, that girl...
Huh? Do you know Sera?
Yes. Actually, I came down
to this lobby before noon...
to tell you two that the meeting
was running long.
But you two hadn't arrived yet,
and that girl was on the phone...
Huh? On the phone? With who?
Who knows. She was adding "-nii"
after a name when she talked,
so maybe it was her older brother?
(whistle and crowd cheering)
Whoa!
Wow...
Watching a soccer game today...
with your girlfriend?
And then, player Sanada...
aiming for the same upper-left corner
of the goal, fires a hard straight ball.
Ahh~
Sanada!
Don't mind, don't mind!
That old guy...
sure is suspicious.
Next Conan,
"Promise with the J-Leaguer".
Next Conan's Hint:
"Sanada Takahiro".
Kudo, the genius of make-up.
It's deduction based knowledge.
Somehow I feel more upset.