(three yawns)
Spending their summer vacation
absorbed in a new game...
the three Detective Boys.
At a convenience store,
they happened to meet a boy
from the same Teitan Elementary,
and ended up going to play games
at the home of his relative.
Something about that house
felt off to me,
and then Toshinari found
a gruesome body in the next room.
Meanwhile, between
detectives Sato and Takagi...
It's gone. That thing.
Huh? G-g-gone... you don't mean...
It's embarrassing,
so don't tell anyone.
M-Miwako's having a baby.
Congratulations are in order!
Sun blazing,
undaunted by the heat,
a slick and stylish
deduction show.
Detective Takagi, a papa?
A shocking trick stuns them both.
Seeing through
the one and only truth,
a child in appearance,
a grown-up in mind,
his name is Detective Conan!
♪~
~♪
"Detective Love Story at MPD Headquarters (Truth)"
(detectives murmuring)
(Chiba humming)
Oh?
I'm back. Huh?
Wh-what's with this?
This ominous mood.
Ah, well, the thing is, Chiba...
Here it is, found it.
A boxed lunch
made on August 13th,
and an August 13th newspaper.
Well, I buy a newspaper
every day, so...
But even if you're only
looking after him for a week,
feeding a child nothing but snacks,
convenience store lunches and cup noodles...
shouldn't you think
a little more about his diet?
Noriya's still growing.
S-Sato's showing
a mother's instincts.
And, and the papa is me.
Ugh...
Hey, Takagi?
Huh?
Did you go to the store and check?
Oh, yes.
He was clearly caught
on the store's security camera.
Yesterday, August 13th,
around 6 p.m.,
there was Yasutomi,
doing his shopping.
And of course, at the same time,
Toshinari shopping too,
along with Noriya.
Right.
Oh, and one more thing...
near that store,
on the road in front
of that flower shop,
there was a traffic accident
about six months ago.
A traffic accident?
Yes.
Apparently, to avoid a woman
who suddenly ran out into the road,
the driver swerved hard
but couldn't avoid her, hit her,
then crashed into the guardrail
in the oncoming lane and lost consciousness.
Thanks to someone nearby
who called an ambulance,
the driver survived,
but the woman who was hit...
her clothes got caught
and no one noticed she was under the car,
so treatment came too late
and she passed away.
According to the driver,
the woman ran out into the road
as if something
were chasing her.
And? What does that accident
have to do with this murder?
Well, apparently
the store clerk saw it...
Yasutomi running away
from the accident scene.
And the woman who was hit...
Yes. The one who died
in that accident...
was my older sister, Mika.
Ever since the day
of that accident,
I've gone to lay flowers
at the scene every day.
I-I see.
But... as an offering,
those flowers seem
a bit flashy.
My sister loved the color pink,
so I thought flowers like that suit her now and then.
I-I see.
Hey, mister.
Huh?
Did your sister have
any troubles or worries?
Huh?
Like, for example...
A stalker?
Huh?
Was there?
No, my sister never mentioned
anything like that to me.
I knew it.
The one who killed Yasutomi...
is this man, Toshinari Shiga.
But this man has an alibi.
During the time of the crime,
August 13th, from 7 p.m. to 9 p.m., two hours,
he says he was with Noriya
the whole time.
Hey, let's air out
the room a bit.
No way, it's already getting dark.
We have to head home.
Seriously? I already opened
the bag of snacks.
Genta, you're spilling them.
Don't you have a plate or something?
I think there were
some paper ones.
Huh? What happened to your leg?
Huh?
There are marks
like you pinched it.
A-a mosquito bite,
I think I scratched it too much.
Hey, that Yaiba movie
you watched last night... could it be...
Yeah, that's right.
I watched it holding in
my pee the whole time.
If that's the case,
then that newspaper...
Could it be...
C-Conan?
Just as I thought.
Only the August 12th
newspaper is missing.
No doubt about it.
The culprit is this man.
This man bent time
to complete his alibi trick.
Bending even
Noriya's feelings along with it.
Anyway, during the time of the crime,
last night from 7 to 9,
in this room next to
the murder scene,
if Toshinari and Noriya,
who were here the whole time watching a movie on TV,
heard nothing suspicious,
then all we can do is ask
the other residents.
But this apartment is scheduled
for demolition next year,
so the only other residents are
the elderly couple on the second floor,
and last night they were apparently
staying at their grandchild's place.
Is that so?
Hey, Haibara, look after everyone.
Sure.
All right, everyone,
let's stay at the professor's tonight
and play games all night.
Then let's play
"Titan Hunter"!
Yeah, let's!
Then I'll...
go grab the game from my house.
Noriya, will you come too?
About the games...
I want to ask you a lot.
Huh?
Besides, you don't want to sleep
next to a room where a murder happened, right?
Y-yeah.
Aren't you going?
Yeah. More importantly...
why would you move into
an apartment that's getting
torn down next year?
I wanted to completely
change the mood.
Before, I lived with my sister,
and she died in a traffic accident.
But you moved in
a month ago, right?
Then you'd think you'd buy
pots and pans and all sorts of things,
but there's nothing
in this room.
Ah, I'm bad at cooking,
so no kitchen tools.
But you know,
at the sink...
there's no detergent,
no scrub brush, no sponge,
which means you don't have
any dishes or cups either, right?
Ah, I was planning
to buy more soon.
Oh, is that so.
And here I assumed it was because
the moment you killed your neighbor Yasutomi,
you planned
to move out right away.
W-wait, Conan,
what do you mean?
Toshinari was watching TV
during the time of the crime,
last night from 7 to 9.
Together with Noriya.
But Noriya told me...
that while watching the movie,
he held in his pee the whole time.
That means for two hours,
the movie was never
interrupted once, right?
Yeah.
I-I see, a rental DVD.
A rental DVD?
Yes. If it's airing
on TV around now,
then the rental of that movie
must have started, and it'd be on sale too.
I see. He got hold of
that movie in advance,
put it in the player,
and at the right moment, hit play,
making the kid think
it was airing on TV right then.
But Toshinari, on the night
of the crime, August 13th,
besides the movie, you said
you were playing games with Noriya
the whole time, didn't you?
Yes.
Before and after the movie.
I see...
Then the crime
really would be impossible...
Was it really
August 13th?
A-ah, that day,
he had Noriya check
the date on the newspaper
he bought at the store, apparently.
R-right?
Y-yeah.
See, that day was definitely
August 13th.
Oh, my mistake then.
Convenience stores don't sell
tomorrow's future newspaper, after all.
Ah... a tabloid.
Huh?
You mean an evening paper...
those carry
the next day's date.
If he bought one of those
and had Noriya check it,
he could make him
mistake the date.
Come to think of it,
only the August 12th paper was missing.
I see.
The evening paper dated the 13th,
bought on August 12th,
he got rid of it.
In other words, the night
you watched the movie
on TV with Noriya
was August 12th.
On the night of the 13th,
the day after the murder,
there was plenty of time
to commit the crime, wasn't there?
W-wait a minute.
Noriya said it, didn't he?
That he watched the movie
on TV yesterday.
Even a child can tell the difference
between yesterday and the day before, don't you think?
If you don't believe me, call Noriya
back here and ask him.
He'll tell you today is the day
after he watched the movie.
Come to think of it,
Noriya said this.
On August 13th,
in the evening after coming back
from the store, he played games until the movie started,
then after the movie,
played games again until late at night,
woke up early in the morning
and played games,
then around 6 he went with Toshinari
to the store to buy breakfast,
played games again until around noon,
then took a nap,
woke up and played more games,
and since he got hungry,
he went to the store just now
and met us.
Ha. Noriya said that
the whole time he was gaming,
he was always with me,
didn't he?
Yeah. But he said that after
buying and eating breakfast at the store,
you went out
for a little while.
You told him to put on headphones
and play games during that time.
Ah...
Went out? Where?
I-I just stepped outside
for a smoke,
and besides,
that was this morning.
Time-wise, it has nothing
to do with the crime, right?
Speaking of time...
this room doesn't have
a single clock, does it?
The only one who can tell time
is Toshinari, who's wearing a watch.
And, the windows have
thick curtains over them.
If you're gaming the whole time
while eating snacks,
you don't get hungry either,
so you lose track of what time it is, right?
I think you should buy
at least a clock.
Y-yeah.
I see, so this
is what happened.
The day before the crime, August 12th,
you bought an evening paper at the store,
made Noriya think it was the 13th,
and that night,
had him play games
until, say, past 10,
then said it was movie time
and showed him the DVD until around midnight,
then had him play games
until morning,
and said "it's already morning"
to wake him, but it was past noon on the 13th.
You had him game until evening,
then said "let's go buy breakfast,"
and the trip to the store was actually
6 in the evening on the 13th.
I-I see, this time of year,
both 6 a.m. and 6 p.m.
have the sun up and it's bright.
And after he ate
that breakfast,
if you said you were stepping out
and went outside,
you had plenty of opportunity
to kill Yasutomi.
At that time, Noriya
was wearing headphones
and couldn't hear the sounds,
it seems.
After that, you returned
to your own room and again
had Noriya play games
until morning, then urged him to nap,
and let him sleep soundly until noon
today, August 14th.
So to Noriya,
the two days of the 13th and 14th
felt like just a single day.
Well? Anything wrong?
You're Wrong... but why would I kill my neighbor...
Whoa.
Ah!
Your sister sure was
a beauty, Toshinari.
H-hey, kid.
But, that's strange.
In the later photos,
nobody's facing this way,
and there's some kind of
hole at the top.
You really loved
your sister, didn't you?
You had these secretly taken photos
of her lined up and pinned somewhere, right?
Th-that means...
A stalker.
Ah.
Come to think of it,
forensics mentioned something.
In Yasutomi's room too, there was
a board with photos pinned to it,
but most of them were out of line
with the sun-faded marks.
Then, what was pinned
to that board
was really these photos, and after
the crime, to erase the link to yourself,
you peeled them all off
and instead
pinned up Yasutomi's photos
that were in that room.
In that case, the data for these photos
might still remain
on the laptop that was
on Yasutomi's desk.
Check it right away.
It may already be erased, though.
Yes.
It should still be there.
Ah.
I didn't think
that far ahead,
and besides, the reason
I peeled off my sister's photos
was simply that I didn't want
my sister's photos
displayed in that stalker
bastard's room any longer.
Then it really was Yasutomi
who was stalking your sister.
Yes.
I realized it
two months ago.
As usual, while I was laying flowers
at the scene of the accident,
that guy spoke to me.
"Were you a fan of hers too?"
he said.
It bothered me, so I followed him,
and I saw it through the window.
Dozens of my sister's photos
pinned to a board,
and that man muttering,
"It's your fault for running away."
So when your sister
ran out into the road
as if something
were chasing her...
Yes. My sister was
chased by that man,
ran out into the road,
and was hit by the car.
Before I killed that man,
I confirmed it with him directly.
Why did you run away then?
Why didn't you tell the rescue team
that my sister was
under the car?
If you had,
maybe my sister
might still
be alive.
That man just...
just said he was scared.
So you moved in next to Yasutomi's room
and carried out this plan?
Yes. I'd been asked beforehand
to look after Noriya
for a week.
Though I never thought
Noriya would be fooled
this easily.
What are you saying?
Huh?
It worked because Noriya
pinched his own leg, fought off his sleepiness,
and played games
for long hours.
His mother asked him
to stay with you
and cheer you up.
Otherwise, there's no way
a plan like this would work.
Heh. I see.
So the one being looked after
was me, all along.
♪~
~♪
So? What did Noriya say
he's going to do now?
Until his mother comes back,
Professor Agasa will look after him.
For now, the mother told him
over the phone
that Toshinari is going away
on a trip for a while.
I see. ...Now,
won't you tell me already?
Just who were you trying
to give those flowers to?
Why, it's you, obviously, Sato.
Those were actually meant
as a surprise, along with a ring...
I was going to give you
those obedient plant flowers.
A ring and flowers, for me?
Before you give me that, hand over
your red badge, Takagi.
A-a red badge, you mean the one
issued to the First Investigation Division
of the Metropolitan Police,
this one?
But why?
You said you'd
take responsibility...
didn't you?
Huh?
You know, the other day,
when a suspect
you had cuffed
was about to escape,
and I pinned him down
for you, right?
In the scuffle, it seems
I dropped my badge.
Afterward I noticed it was gone
and went back to the scene,
searched all over,
but couldn't find it.
Th-then I picked it up
and put it in my left trouser pocket.
Huh?
Sorry, I forgot to mention it.
No way, seriously?
Whoa.
Hey, hey, Sato.
That's...
Found it.
My red badge.
Thank goodness.
Well, I usually wear it,
but it's fine even without it,
and if I tell the higher-ups,
they'd issue me a new one right away.
Oh, really? Here I assumed
it'd mean a written apology,
and I was so embarrassed,
I've been down about it
this whole time.
U-um, so the thing Sato said
was missing was...
Yep, this red badge.
Phew. Whew, that was close.
Hey, what are you
feeling down about?
We caught the real culprit
in no time,
so straighten up,
straighten up.
Haa.
For a while now,
the two of us...
are being watched,
aren't we?
Miwako.
Yumi, and Chiba too.
Hey, Yumi, everyone's
staring at us.
Ask your own heart.
Huh?
Miwako, I hear
that thing of yours is gone?
Oh, right, right.
I found it.
You found it?
See, Takagi here
had picked it up.
If he'd told me sooner,
I wouldn't have gotten so down about it.
Ah.
D-don't tell me...
Yeah, yeah.
Huh? What?
(seizing sound)
21:36, Wataru Takagi apprehended.
We will now escort him
to the interrogation room.
Roger.
Huh? Whaaat?
Ah... hey, wait.
Oh boy. Takagi,
you've done something again, haven't you.
Sorry, it's a misunderstanding,
just a little mix-up.
No, the one who's mistaken is me...
Ah, Sato!
Wow, amazing.
Yeah, the two of us
get along really well, but...
All right!
Kyahaha!
Oh no, he's drowning.
Is there something important
captured in this footage?
Next Conan,
"The Man Betrayed by the Sea".
Next Conan's Hint:
"Necklace".
Next week, the broadcast will be on break.
Going somewhere?
Yeah!
It's for homework, right?