Haah...
Sorry I'm late.
You're already late.
Here.
Huh? What's this?
Ah, hey!
Please don't open it until you have all seven.
Wha... so what?
I'll contact you when you have them all.
It's a promise.
Yumi-san!
Yumi-san! Yumi-san!
Assistant Inspector Miyamoto Yumi!
Hah...
Come on, please don't doze off during patrol.
(Yawn)
♪~♪
The blackness of shadows, the density of darkness—
the light of reasoning cuts right through them.
Assistant Inspector Yumi Miyamoto's secret?
A new character appears with sharp deductions.
See through the one and only truth.
Looks like a kid, but has the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
♪~♪
"The Neighbor at the Site is an Ex-Boyfriend (Part 1)"
(Yawn)
Yumi-san, did something happen last night?
Sorry.
I played mahjong all night with some detectives from the Violent Crimes unit.
Staying up all night playing mahjong isn't good for you. For your work or your skin.
Yeah, yeah.
More importantly, what is this about "when you have all seven"?
Gah... Did I say that?
Yes. In your sleep, you said things like "When will that ever be complete?"
Haah... Hmm?
It's something my ex-boyfriend said.
When I said, "I'm becoming a police officer, so let's break up,"
he forced this strange envelope on me and said, "Wait until I have all seven."
Huh...
But he never once contacted me, so I dumped him.
I couldn't wait anymore, and I didn't want to see his face
or hear his voice.
So... where did you meet him?
In a train, when I was in college.
He lived in a nice area, so maybe he was some rich kid?
But what were those "seven" things?
Who knows? Probably something stupid...
Was he a sailor?
He wanted you to wait until he conquered
the seven seas: the North Atlantic, South Atlantic, North Pacific,
South Pacific, Indian Ocean, Arctic Ocean, and Antarctic Ocean.
Co... Conan-kun.
Was he tanned?
No, he was pale. He looked like a shut-in NEET.
He seemed to go out often,
but it was irregular, and it didn't look like work.
Then maybe he was visiting the Seven Gods of Fortune?
That's the thing where you go around to shrines and temples on New Year's
and collect the seven deity dolls, right?
My mom does that every year.
That would be complete quickly, wouldn't it?
Another possibility is the Seven Deadly Sins.
Huh? Hmm?
Pride, envy, wrath, sloth,
greed, gluttony, and lust.
...the seven sins.
What would anyone do with those?
But the Seven Gods of Fortune might be possible.
He told me that on Christmas, after all.
...Why am I even telling you kids all this?
Ahahaha... Geez.
So what happened to that envelope?
That thing? It ended up somewhere.
You're the one who crashed into me!
What did you say?
You got a problem?
Could you back up and pull over to the shoulder?
Ah, yes.
Hey. What do you two think you're doing?
Phew...
Yumi-san had a boyfriend?
Strangely, it doesn't feel like the first time...
Huh?
Seeing you.
You, by any chance...
Ah, yes.
You're the one who gave me a parking ticket in Haido Town the other day.
You've completely forgotten, haven't you, Chiba-kun?
Don't cross! Huh?
Once you spoil yourself and break a rule,
it becomes a habit.
Even if you want to stop a habit, you can't.
Don't you understand that?
Ugh...
Ah... (Young Naeko crying)
(Cell phone rings) Hmm?
Ah... from Sakurako?
What? I'm at work right now.
Huh? Someone died?
B-but I'm not a detective...
Hey, is that nearby?
Uh... yes.
Hmm?
Hey, listen...
Anyway, don't touch anything. I'll be there soon.
What's with those kids? They looked pale...
I just got a call from my friend saying someone died.
Huh? Where?
At the Chateau Beika Mansion near here.
Ah, Cha... Chateau Beika Mansion?
So it was here.
Um, have you been here before?
No, I haven't.
A mansion like this where only rich people live.
Ah, Miyamoto-sama! Long time no see.
Hello.
You have been here before, haven't you?
Shut up.
So... which floor?
The 18th floor. Huh?
No way, no way...
What, so he was my neighbor?
Haah...
Oh, the mini-patrol ladies are here too?
Huh?
Huh? But Yumi-san, you're with the Traffic Division.
This kind of case isn't really your jurisdiction...
Leave it to us.
You guys aren't in jurisdiction either.
I just came to bring you kids back...
Huh? Hmm?
But Conan-kun isn't here...
He's inside.
He told us to wait out here.
No way, he went inside?
Who is this boy?
Is he someone the housekeeper knows?
Ah, yes. I believe his name is...
Edogawa Conan.
We met at the scene of a murder case before.
Sakurako Yonehara-san.
Uh... yes. During that optical illusion case.
Hey, little boy.
Isn't your way of speaking different from earlier?
Because when you were with everyone else, you acted like a normal kid, but
now you sound just like a detective.
Ah, no, that's...
I've been working as a live-out housekeeper here
since last week, but...
again, something like this...
Sa... Sakurako.
Ah, Nae-chan.
Sorry, I panicked and called Nae-chan without thinking.
It's okay. We called the detectives.
Haah...
Well, it certainly doesn't look like a murder case, but...
I suppose we should hear what happened.
Ye... yes.
About an hour ago, I had a huge fight with my wife, Chiyoko.
To let her cool down, I left her alone
and decided to step outside with the housekeeper.
That's right.
Yes. We hadn't bought
the ingredients for dinner yet,
so I went to the nearby supermarket with the master.
My wife broke her wrist and couldn't do housework,
so we reluctantly hired a housekeeper, but she had another hysterical fit and started throwing things—
I was worried her injury would get worse.
My eye was also in this condition.
What happened to that bruise?
When my wife gets angry, she often throws things.
Thanks to that, I had to take the day off from work today.
So... when you came back, your wife had committed suicide?
No. We finished shopping in about 30 minutes,
came back with the master, and when we opened the front door,
we heard the door to this bedroom slam shut.
So I thought she was still alive at that point.
We knocked on the door and called out to her, but there was no answer.
It seemed she was still angry.
So I had the housekeeper make some coffee,
and after about 30 minutes of small talk...
we knocked on the bedroom door again.
When we went inside...
this is what we found.
I never imagined a simple argument would make my wife so distraught.
I see... So?
This note at the wife's feet?
It's a suicide note. It's in my wife's own handwriting.
She wrote about my injury, our son's exam,
and even about my sister's daughter, who will be celebrating her Shichi-Go-San this year.
She wrote about all of them.
"Please forgive me for leaving you so suddenly."
(Crying)
This is clearly a suicide.
No. Hmm?
It might be murder. Huh?
Huh?
That suicide note—
she would have written it in that notebook on the desk and torn it out, right?
But look closely. The middle binding ring still has
the torn remains from the two holes at the bottom of the notebook,
but the note has three torn holes. Don't you think that's strange?
Wait, seriously?
Y... you're right.
Besides, the handwriting on the note is quite distorted.
See, your wife seems to have used that notebook
to leave messages often,
but she always ended them by writing only her first name.
Yet, this note has her full name written on it.
That seems very strange to me.
That's true.
Was the front door locked?
Ah, yes.
I was the one who opened it, and it was properly locked.
Then who has spare keys?
Only myself, my wife, the housekeeper, and our son, Yasue.
Where is your son now?
I think he's at driving school.
He said he has an exam soon.
Ah... also, there's supposedly a spare key
kept in the mailbox on the first floor.
That mailbox has a lock on it, of course?
Yes, it's a combination lock.
I didn't think anyone else could open it easily...
Left 7, right 2, then left 3.
Ah! There's one more person. Someone who knows
the combination. Huh?
Yesterday, when I was trying to get the mail from that mailbox,
I forgot the note with the combination and was struggling,
and that person told me the numbers.
H... how does he know the combination?
When you tried to open the mailbox before,
you dropped the note with the combination, right?
I picked it up. Don't you remember?
B... but that was just a moment—
I don't think even a second passed.
That's plenty of time for me.
I'm good at remembering things like that.
Huh?
Maybe the best in Japan... no, in the world.
Is that person a resident of this mansion?
Y... yes. He's the neighbor.
He always has an unshaven beard and is kind of unkempt.
I think his name was...
If he's next door, it's faster to just go.
Uh... yeah. Ah, hey...
(Door opens) Hmm?
Wha... wait a minute.
(Doorbell) Huh?
Yes. What is it?
Hmm? Ah!
Ah!
Ah! Yumi-tan!
Huh? Yu... Yumi-tan?
So you know him?
Uh... yes.
He's my ex-boyfriend.
Huh?!"
Ha, ahaha, haha...
So, to summarize the situation...
To let his angry wife cool down,
the husband went grocery shopping with the housekeeper for about 30 minutes...
When they returned and opened the front door,
they heard the door to this bedroom close.
They knocked and called out, but there was no answer.
So they waited another 30 minutes,
chatting with the housekeeper in the kitchen to pass the time...
Then they knocked again, and this time when they entered,
the wife, Chiyoko-san, had hanged herself
with an electrical cord.
Yes.
What caused the argument?
Stocks.
Stocks? Hmm?
My wife has been really into stocks lately.
When I told her to be careful, she had a fit.
I see.
Well, our son, who's about to graduate from university,
hasn't been able to find a job yet,
so I think the stress was also a factor.
So you have a son?
Yes.
But since he started living alone in an apartment near his university,
he rarely comes to visit.
Ah, but he did call the other day.
He said that once he gets his license, he wants me to buy him a car,
so he'll bring a catalog next time.
I see, a catalog.
But my wife
yelled that a car is out of the question when he hasn't even found a job yet,
and hung up on him.
Oh? You're... from that optical illusion case, aren't you?
Yes. My workplace turned into another incident like this...
Haah... Just make sure you don't end up like Mouri-kun,
someone who attracts death.
In... Inspector.
(Clears throat)
But why did the report come from Traffic Division's Miike-kun?
Ah, that's...
Sakurako-san saw the body and called her friend,
Police Officer Miike Naeko.
When I heard about it, I came here too.
Co... Conan-kun.
No wonder the kids were at the front door.
But Conan-kun, how did you get inside this mansion?
There was someone with children entering the mansion,
so I pretended to be their friend's friend and went in.
Th... that's not good.
...Geez.
So, Naeko, was the housekeeper your classmate?
No, she's a childhood friend who lived in my neighborhood.
I'm one year older than Sakurako.
Hmm?
Well, anyway, only the husband,
wife, and housekeeper were here, correct?
Yes. I haven't seen my son in over a year.
Hmm... Then who is the man behind Yumi-kun?
Hmm? Ah, this is...
I live next door.
Yumi-ta... Hmm!
Ah, I am currently
going out with Yumi-san.
My name is Shukichi Haneda.
Huh? Huh?
He's my ex-boyfriend. We already broke up.
B-but why is your boyfriend here?
Ah... this "ex" boyfriend
said he remembered the combination for the mailbox
that had the spare key to this room, so I dragged him here.
Huh? I feel like I've seen you somewhere before too.
Come to think of it, I feel like I've heard that name too.
Hmm? Don't tell me you saw it on a wanted poster?
Don't be stupid.
Hmm... Ahaha.
But well, there's a suicide note at the victim's feet,
so it's probably a suicide.
Ah, but Conan-kun said
that it might not be a suicide.
What? Hmph.
I see. Th... that's true.
The torn edges of this note and the notebook don't match.
The note says:
"I'm sorry for injuring you. I pray for your speedy recovery."
"Yasue-san, do your best on your exam. I know you'll pass."
"For Ichiko-chan's Shichi-Go-San,
please dress her in my furisode."
"Please forgive me for leaving you so suddenly."
"Itami Chiyoko."
Is there anything suspicious about this content?
Uh... yes.
As you can see, last night
my wife threw an ashtray that hit me in the eye,
leaving this bruise.
And my son, Yasue, said he has
his written driver's license exam soon.
Also, my sister's daughter
is turning seven this year, so...
Shichi-Go-San, then.
But why the ashtray?
When my wife gets angry, she often throws things.
I saw that too.
So I thought the cell phone found in front of the bedroom might have been thrown by her as well.
There was a cell phone on the floor?
Huh? Yes.
When we returned from shopping
and first knocked on the bedroom door, I noticed it.
Where is that phone now?
I have it. Hmm?
I was planning to give it back once she calmed down.
Hmm... It doesn't look like there are any calls or messages from today.
If this was a murder, I thought it might have been used in some trick,
but it seems unrelated to the case.
But still, the lady of the house didn't commit suicide after all.
Hmm? "After all"?
Because she said so herself.
"I am loved by God. I'm a lucky person."
A lucky person?
What do you mean?
Years ago, the plane my wife was on nearly crashed,
but miraculously, she survived.
Oh?
So were you on that plane too?
Ah, no. I was supposed to go,
but I broke my leg on a ski trip right before.
So a wife like that, just because of an argument,
I can't imagine her committing suicide.
But that was just something she always said.
Besides, that suicide note is also strange.
Huh? In what way?
The lady of the house...
caught a bad cold when she was seven and couldn't do her Shichi-Go-San,
and she told me that she had no connection to kimono
until her Coming of Age ceremony.
Huh? Hmph... I see.
Hmm? Hmm?
So that's what you meant by "the one outfit you prepared"?
What are you talking about, Chuukichi?
I told you, she didn't have a kimono made.
Th... that's why I said it's Shukichi.
How many times do I have to tell you I'm not Chuukichi?
Chuukichi suits you better.
Looking so unkempt...
"The one outfit you prepared."
That's... if I remember correctly...
Ah, I see.
If you think about it that way, even the unnatural parts of that note...
We still don't have enough for the full picture,
but if we piece it together one move at a time...
Right?
Shukichi Haneda-san.
Hmm... This suicide note is still suspicious.
Yes, it seems we need a handwriting analysis.
Ah, and it also bothers me that someone
with a broken wrist would choose hanging,
which is difficult to do with one hand, as a method of suicide.
That's true. (Door opens)
Chief Megure. Hmm?
We have an eyewitness account of a suspicious person.
What? Hmm?
According to the concierge in the first floor lobby,
a suspicious person with their face hidden by a hat, mask, and glasses
entered and left the mansion.
♪~♪
Wow! Chi... Chiba-kun. Huh?
Let go, ugh...
It's not like I'm suspicious or anything...
They say the culprit returns to the scene.
Before you found the wife's phone,
you heard the bedroom door close,
didn't you, Sakurako-san?
Uh... yes.
You can't say that.
It's a woman. You were meeting some woman, weren't you?
Next Conan,
"The Neighbor at the Site is an Ex-Boyfriend (Part 2)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Cell phone cover".
Chuukichi? Yumi-tan!
That's what you're interested in?
Another new couple, huh?